import{_ as g,o as i,c as t,a as n,m as h,t as l,C as c,M as y,U as b,F as w,p,e as f,f as v,q as j}from"./chunks/framework.B1z0IdBH.js";const q={name:"PoemCard",props:{poem:{type:Object,required:!0}}},z={class:"poem-container"},A={class:"review"},T={class:"review-title"},x={class:"review-content"};function C(e,a,s,m,o,r){return i(),t("div",z,[n("div",A,[n("div",T,[a[0]||(a[0]=n("span",{class:"icon"},"question:",-1)),h(l(s.poem.question),1)]),a[2]||(a[2]=n("div",{class:"divider"},null,-1)),n("p",x,[a[1]||(a[1]=n("span",{class:"icon"},"answer:",-1)),h(l(s.poem.answer),1)])])])}const N=g(q,[["render",C],["__scopeId","data-v-ac5b588e"]]),S=JSON.parse(`[{"question":"வினா:சேர நாடு உள்ளடக்கிய பகுதிகள் எது?","answer":"விடை: கோவை, கேரளம் "},{"question":"පහත ගීතය සම්පුර්ණ කරන්න. ලඳු ඕවිටි කලල් මතින් සුසුම් ගඟක් ගලනවාබාධක ගිරි ශිඛර මැදින් කුස ගින්දර නිවෙනවාඅලුත් පාර හැදෙනවා","answer":"ලඳු ඕවිටි කලල් මතින් සුසුම් ගඟක් ගලනවාබාධක ගිරි ශිඛර මැදින් කුස ගින්දර නිවෙනවාඅලුත් පාර හැදෙනවාහිරු පායා අපේ හිසට සෙවණ ගෙනෙනවාපොළොව දැවී අපේ පයට සිහිල සදනවාදූවිලි මද පවන් හමා ගිමන් නිවනවාදෑතේ කර ගැට දෙතොලට පවන් සලනවාඅපේ ශ්‍රමය කළු ගල් වී බිම වැතිරෙනවාරන් දහදිය තාර වෙලා උඩින් ගලනවාමැති උතුමන් නමින් පාරෙ කඩුළු ඇරෙනවාපාර අයිනෙ අපි හැමදා බලා ඉන්නවාඑඩ්වඩ් ජයකොඩිකුමරදාස සපුතන්ත්‍රිරෝහණ වීරසිංහ "},{"question":"Чордону деген эмне ?","answer":"Чордону дегени бул - Борбору"},{"question":"नेपालको संविधान, १९६२ के हो?","answer":"राजा महेन्द्रले पञ्चायतको संविधान स्थापना गरे जसमा स्थानीय सभाहरू गठन गर्ने व्यवस्था थियो। यद्यपि, यो व्यवस्थामा राजाको मात्र अधिकार थियो। लोकतन्त्र सीमित थियो र कसैले राजनीतिक दल बनाउन सकेन ।"},{"question":"Parí ìròyìn yìí:O ṣẹlẹ, ọjọ ori mẹta ọtọọtọ ni iwe-ẹri Tinubu niỌkan lara awọn aṣiri to fara han ninu awọn akọsilẹ ati iwe-ẹri ti Fasiti Chicago ti olori orileede wa, Aarẹ Bọla Ahmed Tinubu, ti kawe, iyẹn Chicago State University, to wa lorileede Amẹrika, ko kalẹ fun Atiku Abubakar, gẹgẹ bii aṣẹ ile-ẹjọ giga Illinois, ni ọrọ ọjọ-ọri baba agbalagba naa.Ọjọ kọkandinlọgbọn, oṣu Kẹta, ọdun ni Tinubu maa n ṣayẹyẹ ọjọọbi rẹ. Eyi to ṣe lodun yii lo si fi sọ pe ẹni ọdun mọkanlelaaadọrin loun pe loke eepẹ.Eyi lohun to wa ninu akọọlẹ ati awọn ẹri ti Tinubu ko kalẹ fun ajọ eleto idibo ilẹ wa, Independent National Electoral Commission, INEC, tori March 29, 1952 lo kọ silẹ labẹ ibura pe wọn bi oun.Amọ ninu awọn akọọlẹ Fasiti Chicago to tẹ Atiku Abubakar lọwọ bayii, March 29, 1954 lo wa lakọọlẹ gẹgẹ bii ọjọ-ibi rẹ. Eyi fihan pe ẹni ọdun mọkandinlaaadọrin ni Tinubu jẹ lọdun yii, eyi ko si dọgba pẹlu ti INEC, o fọdun meji yatọ sira.","answer":"Siwaju si i, ninu awọn akọsilẹ kan ti fasiti naa tun ko kalẹ, eyi ti Tinubu fun wọn lasiko to fẹẹ wọle sileewe naa, ati lawọn igba to n kawe nibẹ nibẹrẹ, March 29, 1955 lo wa ninu awọn iwe-ẹri naa gbogbo. Eyi tun fi ọdun mẹta yatọ si sabukeeti to wa lọdọ INEC, ati eyi to gba jade ni Fasiti Chicago gan-an.Ni bayii, awọn akọsilẹ yii fihan pe Aarẹ Tinubu yoo jẹ ẹni ọdun mejidinlaaadọta, tabi mọkandinlaaadọta, tabi kẹ, ẹni ọdun mọkanlelaaadọta.Latari eyi, Oluranlọwọ pataki si Atiku Abubakar lori eto ibanisọrọ, Ọgbẹni Phrank Shaibu, fi ẹfẹ sọ ninu atẹjade kan to fi lede lọjọ Iṣẹgun, Tusidee, ọjọ kẹta, oṣu Kẹwaa yii pe: “Ninu gbogbo ẹda t’Ọlọrun da, Tinubu nikan lo jẹ ọkunrin, to si tun jẹ obinrin lẹsẹ kan naa, oun nikan lo ni ọjọ-ibi meji, mẹta lẹẹkan naa. Akanda ẹda kan to wa latọrun lọkunrin yii maa jẹ o, tabi ko jẹ pulanẹẹti Jupiter lo ti ja bọ saye,” gẹgẹ bo ṣe wi."},{"question":"Viết tiếp đoạn văn sau: Hội thảo có phần thảo luận nhóm chuyên sâu ở 5 lĩnh vực: điện gió, điện mặt trời, vai trò của phụ nữ trong ngành năng lượng, hiệu quả năng lượng và giao thông xanh. Các đại biểu đến từ khu vực công - tư cùng thảo luận, phân tích và đề xuất các giải pháp đột phá cho quá trình chuyển dịch năng lượng công bằng ở Việt Nam.Các chuyên gia khẳng định rằng cần phải có các giải pháp phát triển kỹ năng và thúc đẩy việc làm để hiện thực hóa tiềm năng việc làm trong lĩnh vực này. Đồng thời cần lưu tâm đến vấn đề bình đẳng giới và nâng cao vai trò của phụ nữ trong quá trình chuyển dịch năng lượng.Ông Tạ Đình Thi, Phó chủ nhiệm Ủy ban Khoa học, Công nghệ và Môi trường của Quốc hội khẳng định: \\"Việt Nam cùng với cộng đồng quốc tế cam kết phấn đấu đạt mục tiêu trung hòa carbon vào năm 2050 và theo đuổi quá trình chuyển đổi năng lượng công bằng. Chúng tôi nhận thức được tầm quan trọng của việc phát triển các kỹ năng cần thiết và sẵn sàng học hỏi từ các điển hình tốt trên thế giới; đồng thời, đánh giá cao mối quan hệ Hợp tác Việt - Đức và tin tưởng mối quan hệ này sẽ đóng góp tích cực vào quá trình chuyển đổi năng lượng công bằng và tương lai xanh, phát triển bền vững cho Việt Nam\\".","answer":"Hội thảo kỳ vọng tạo ra một diễn đàn để đưa chủ đề chuyển dịch năng lượng gắn liền với chuyển dịch việc làm đến gần với công chúng, và quan trọng hơn hết là Việt Nam có những quyết sách đúng đắn và phù hợp để chuyển dịch năng lượng một cách công bằng và bền vững."},{"question":"क्वान्टम कम्प्युटिङको विकासमा \\"क्वान्टम सर्वोच्चता\\" र यसको महत्त्व व्याख्या गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"क्वान्टम सर्वोच्चता त्यो बिन्दु हो जसमा क्वान्टम कम्प्युटरले केही कामहरू क्लासिकल कम्प्युटरहरू भन्दा छिटो गर्न सक्छ, क्वान्टम कम्प्युटिङको प्रगतिमा महत्त्वपूर्ण माइलस्टोन चिन्ह लगाउँछ।"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"asal sabut terapung-apung, asal batu tenggelam\\"?","answer":"Kalau nasib baik selamat, kalau nasib malang celaka"},{"question":"以下の段落に関連する内容を記入しなさい： 秋田県由利本荘市の畑で5日、雪の下にあるキャベツをとるイベントがありました。270人ぐらいが集まりました。 キャベツは去年の秋にとることができる大きさになりましたが、雪が降る冬もそのままにしました。キャベツを雪の下に置いておくと、甘くなります。かむと、しゃきしゃきと音がしておいしいです。","answer":"畑には5000個ぐらいのキャベツが残っていました。家族などが道具を使って、雪の下から1つ1つとっていました。子どもと来た女性は「子どもにもいい経験になると思いました。宝物をさがすようで楽しかったです」と話していました。 イベントを開いた人は「農業を経験しながら、みんなで楽しんでほしいと思って始めました。寒いところで甘くなったキャベツを食べてほしいです」と話していました。"},{"question":"ஈ. வெ. இராமசாமி  அவர்களின்மேற்கோள்  சிலவற்றை தரவும்.","answer":"பக்தி என்பதற்கு முட்டாள்தனம், பேராசை, தன்னலம் என்பவை தவிர வேறு சொற்கள் தமிழில் இல்லவே இல்லை.பகுத்தறிவு என்பது மனிதனுக்கு உயிர்நாடிமூடநம்பிக்கையும் குருட்டுப் பழக்கமும் சமூகத்தின் முதல் பகைவன்விதியை நம்பி மதியை இழக்காதே!மக்களின் ஒழுக்கத்தையும் மதியையும் கெடுப்பது மது.மனிதப் பண்பை வளர்ப்பதே என் வாழ்நாள் பணி.பிறருக்கு தொல்லை தராத வாழ்வே ஒழுக்க வாழ்வு.பக்தி என்பது தனிச் சொத்து. ஒழுக்கம் என்பது பொது சொத்து.பக்தி இல்லாவிட்டால் இழப்பில்லை. ஒழுக்கம் இல்லாவிட்டால் பாழ்.தீண்டாமை ஒழிய வேண்டுமானால், சாதி ஒழிய வேண்டும்வாழ்க்கை அவனவன் வாழ்வதற்கு என்று மட்டும் கருதக் கூடாது மற்றவர்கள் நலனுக்கும் என்று கருத வேண்டும்.கல்வி அறிவும், சுயமரியாதை எண்ணமும், பகுத்தறிவுத் தன்மையுமே தாழ்ந்து கிடக்கும் மக்களை உயர்த்தும்.ஒரு நாடு சுபிட்சத்துடன் வாழ வேண்டுமானால், அந்நாட்டு மக்கள் ஒழுக்கமுள்ளவர்களாக இருத்தல் அவசியம்.ஒழுக்கக் குறைவுக்கும் மூடநம்பிக்கைக்கும் எப்படிப்பட்ட கலையும் பயன்பட்டு விடக்கூடாது.ஒருவன் தன்னிடம் பிறர் எப்படி நடந்து கொள்ள வேண்டுமென எதிர்பார்க்கிறானோ, அப்படி எல்லாரிடமும் தான் நடந்து கொள்வதே ஒழுக்கமாகும்.எனது சீர்திருத்தம் என்பதெல்லாம் பகுத்தறிவை கொண்டு ஆராச்சி செய்து, சரியென்று பட்டபடி நட என்பதேயாகும்.மற்றவர்களிடம் பழகும் வித்தையும் ஒழுக்கத்தையும் சிறு வயதிலேயே நன்றாக ஒருவன் கற்றுக் கொண்டானானால் அவனே வாழ்க்கையில் பெரிய மனிதன் ஆவான்.பொதுவாழ்வில் இருப்பவர்களுக்கு அளவுக்கு மீறிய நாணயமும், கட்டுப்பாடும், உறுதியும், தியாக உணர்வும் வேண்டும்.என்னைப் பொறுத்தமட்டில், நான் ஒழுக்கத்துடன் நடந்தால், உண்மையை ஒழிக்காமல் எதையும் நேர்மையுடன் கடைப்பிடித்தால், அதற்கு தனிசக்தி உண்டு என்பதை நம்புகிறவன்."},{"question":"Iza no filohan'ny Repoblika Malagasy voalohany indrindra?","answer":" I Tsiranana Philibert no filohan' ny Repoblika Malagasy voalohany tamin' ny 1 Mey 1959 hatramin' ny 11 Ôktôbra 1972."},{"question":"በዓለማችን ምን ያህል የዋዝንቢት ዝርያዎች አሉ?","answer":"900"},{"question":"Jawab soalan yang rumit ini: Ahli manakah dari kolej perlembagaan Universiti Oxford di England dan kolej keempat tertua di Universiti, adalah Profesor Fizik di Universiti Oxford?","answer":"Andrew Martin Steane"},{"question":"أكمل العبارة التالية:  قوائم المنتخبات المشاركة في كأس الأمم الأفريقية لكرة القدم 2015 ","answer":"التي أقيمت في غينيا الاستوائية في الفترة بين 17 يناير و8 فبراير 2015."},{"question":"Ndàx mbind mii jub na?[Fàttalikuleen], ba nu wóllaranteek yéen ne buleen tuur seeni deret, buleen génneyante ci seeni kër. Ngeen nangu te seede ko.","answer":"Déedet; jubul cocc ba coset. Mbeqi ma a ngii:[Fàttlikuléen], ba nu wóllarantee'k yéen ne buléen tùur séen i deret, buléen génneyante ci séen i kër. Ngéen nangu te seede ko."},{"question":"Na paragraf dị mkpirikpi atọ, gwa m banyere Fatima Yusuf ","answer":"Fatima Yusuf-Olukoju (a mụrụ n'ụbọchị nke 2 n'ọnwa Mee afọ 1971 na Owo,dị na Ondo steeti) bụ nwaafọ Naijiria bụ onye egwuregwu ị gba ọsọ lagoro ezumike nka, onye sọrọ mpi ọkachasị na mita 400 n'oge ọrụ ya. Ọ meriri n'ọsọ mita 400 na 1991 All-Africa Games ma bụrụ onye nke abụọ na mita 200. Ọ lụrụ Adewale Olukoju .O mechara soro sọọ mpi mita 200 na World Championship na Spen ebe ọ gbara ọsọ 22.28. Ọ bụkwa nwanyị Afrịka mbụ gbara ọsọ n'okpuru sekọnsụ 50 na mita 400. Ọ gbara 49.43 na 1995 African ChampionshipỌ sọrọ Naịjirịa asọmpi na 1996 Summer Olympics e mere n'Atlanta, n'Amerịka na mita 400 nke ọ gbatara onye nke 6 na oge nkesekọnsụ 49.77 na mita 4 x 400 ebe o meriri nrite ọla ọcha ya na ndị otu ya Bisi Afolabi, Charity Opara na Falilat Ogunkoya n'azụ mba Amerịka. Ọ gara Mahadum nke Azusa Pacific ."},{"question":"Đọc đoạn văn sau và đưa ra một tiêu đề phụ hợp với nội dung: Mới đây, Trường Đại học Kinh tế - Đại học Quốc gia Hà Nội đã tổ chức lễ trao bằng tốt nghiệp cho tân cử nhân. Lễ tốt nghiệp vinh danh gần 700 sinh viên tốt nghiệp, trong đó có 9 sinh viên tốt nghiệp Xuất sắc; 165 sinh viên tốt nghiệp loại Giỏi; 6 sinh viên có nhiều đóng góp trong hoạt động. Điều đáng nói, buổi lễ không tổ chức bình thường như những trường khác mà tổ chức long trọng theo phong cách hoàng gia. Có sinh viên đi đầu rước cờ truyền thống, mang logo thương hiệu của trường, hiệu trưởng cầm quyền trượng bước vào... PGS.TS Nguyễn Trúc Lê, Hiệu trưởng Trường Đại học Kinh tế - ĐHQG Hà Nội đã bày tỏ: \\"Ngày hôm nay là dấu mốc kỷ niệm đẹp, là thời khắc ghi nhận mọi nỗ lực học tập của các em, ghi nhận mọi thử thách mà các em đã chinh phục, là cột mốc đánh dấu sự trưởng thành của các em đối với gia đình, với xã hội. Các em có quyền hãnh diện về những thành tựu đạt được trong học tập và rèn luyện sau những năm tháng dưới mái Trường danh giá này. Cảm ơn gia đình các em đã đưa các em đến với trường để yêu cuộc sống nơi đây và để được yêu, để cho đi, mà không nghĩ mình sẽ được nhận lại\\". Hình ảnh về buổi lễ đang thu hút sự chú ý của mọi người. Chia sẻ với PV báo Dân Việt, thầy Lê Trung Thành, Trưởng phòng Đào tạo, Trường Đại học Kinh tế, cho biết: \\"Lễ tốt nghiệp trao bằng cho các tân cử nhân năm nay cũng theo truyền thống thực hiện từ nhiều năm trước đó là hiệu trưởng cầm quyền trượng. Đây không phải là mới mẻ của trường nhưng năm nào cũng thu hút sự quan tâm của mọi người\\". Liên quan đến buổi lễ trao bằng theo phong cách khác lạ này, chuyên gia giáo dục Tô Thụy Diễm Quyên, CEO Innedu STEAM cho hay: \\"Trường Đại học Kinh tế thuộc Đại học Quốc gia Hà Nội, là một trường thuộc hệ thống công lập. Tôi thấy trường đang cố gắng vươn mình, tạo cho sinh viên thấy đang được học tập trong một môi trường hiện đại, được trân trọng trong buổi lễ truyền thống. Qua hình ảnh chia sẻ, tôi thấy các sinh viên rất vui vẻ, hào hứng, chứng tỏ các em sinh viên rất tự hào về trường và đón nhận buổi lễ\\". Chia sẻ thêm về các buổi lễ tốt nghiệp hiện nay, bà Quyên cho biết: \\"Các trường hiện nay tổ chức lễ tốt nghiệp rất sang trọng. Họ coi trọng việc trao bằng vì khoảnh khắc đó mỗi em sinh viên cố rất nhiều cảm xúc. Bao nhiêu công sức học hành của các em được trân trọng, vinh danh giúp các em vui vẻ hơn, hạnh phúc hơn và tự hào về môi trường mình được đào tạo hơn. Mặc dù Ban tổ chức rất vất vả vì tổ chức nhiều ngày nhưng tạo cho các em khoảnh khắc riêng vô cùng ý nghĩa\\". ","answer":"Một trường đại học ở Hà Nội tổ chức lễ trao bằng tốt nghiệp theo phong cách rất \\"lạ\\""},{"question":"Slutför den här frasen: Tierna Davidson, född den 19 september 1998, är en amerikansk fotbollsspelare som spelar för Chicago Red Stars i USA. Hon gjorde sitt första landslagsmål den 31 augusti 2018 i en landskamp mot Chile. Davidson gjorde mästerskapsdebut när","answer":"hon var en del av USA:s lag under VM i Frankrike 2019."},{"question":"Бешиктин шимеги дегенде кандай түшүнөсүз?","answer":"Бешиктин шимеги  – заара агып, күлтүккө түшүүгө ыңгайлашкан буюм. Шимекти адатта койдун шыйрак сөөгүнөн жасашкан. Учурда жыгачтан жасашат. Жыгачтан жасалган жаңы шимекти кызып турган майга салып, бир кайнатып алуу керек. Андан соң күнгө жакшылап кургатат. Ошондо жыгачтын майда таарындылары жоголуп, сыйда болот. Шимек эркек балага өзүнчө, кыз балага өзүнчө жасалат."},{"question":"Amin'ity fehezanteny manaraka ity, vinavinao ny anjara asan'ny teny tsirairay : \\"Mianatra ny zaza hendry \\".","answer":"Ny anjara asan'ny teny tsirairay amin'io fehezanteny \\"Mianatra ny zaza hendry\\" io dia :\\"Mianatra\\" : matoanteny\\"ny\\" : mpanoritra\\"zaza\\" : anarana\\"hendry\\" : mpamari-toetra"},{"question":"请回答以下问题：问题：在17世纪的艺术中，巴洛克建筑风格在哪个国家得到了广泛发展？","answer":"答案：巴洛克建筑风格在意大利、法国和德国等国家得到了广泛发展。"},{"question":"வினா இரைப்பை அழற்சிக்கான சிகிச்சை முறைகள்  யாவை ?","answer":"இரைப்பை அழற்சியின் நோயறிதல் உறுதிசெய்யப்பட்டவுடன், சிகிச்சையைத் தொடங்கலாம். சிகிச்சை ஓரளவிற்கு இரைப்பை அழற்சிக்கான காரணத்தை சார்ந்துள்ளது. இரைப்பை அழற்சிக்கான சிகிச்சை பொதுவாக பின்வருமாறு அடங்கும்1.இரைப்பை அமிலத்தைக் குறைக்க ஆன்டாக்சிட்களை எடுத்துக்கொள்வதுஎச். பைலோரி நோய்த்தொற்றால் ஏற்படும் இரைப்பை அழற்சிக்கு, உங்களுக்கு பல நுண்ணுயிர் எதிர்ப்பிகள் மற்றும் அமிலத் தடுப்பு மருந்து பரிந்துரைக்கப்படுகிறது.2.தீங்கு விளைவிக்கும் இரத்த சோகை இரைப்பை அழற்சிக்கு காரணமாக இருந்தால், வைட்டமின் பி 12 ஊசி போடப்படும்3.ஊறுகாய், மிளகுத்தூள் மற்றும் மிகவும் உப்பு நிறைந்த உணவுப் பொருட்கள் போன்ற சூடான மற்றும் காரமான உணவுகளைத் தவிர்த்தல்4.லாக்டோஸ் மற்றும் பசையம் போன்ற எரிச்சலூட்டும் உணவை உங்கள் உணவில் இருந்து நீக்குதல்5.காஃபின், மதுபானங்கள், சிட்ரிக் அமில பானங்கள் மற்றும் குளிர்பானங்கள் ஆகியவற்றைக் குறைக்கவும்.உங்கள் வயிற்றை ஓவர்லோட் செய்யாதீர்கள்.6.ஒரு எளிய காய்கறி சூப் உங்களுக்கு மிகவும் உதவியாக இருக்கும்.அடிப்படைக் காரணத்தைக் கண்டறிந்து சரிசெய்யும் போது, நோயாளியின் வயிறு காலப்போக்கில் குணமடைகிறது.இரைப்பை அழற்சிஇரைப்பை அழற்சி என்பது பொதுவான ஒரு விஷயத்துடன் கூடிய நிலைமைகளின் தொகுப்பாகும்: வயிற்றின் புறணி வீக்கம் மற்றும் வீக்கம். இரைப்பை அழற்சியின் வீக்கம் பெரும்பாலும் வயிற்றுப் புண்களை ஏற்படுத்தும் அதே பாக்டீரியத்தின் தொற்று காரணமாகும். காயம், சில வலி நிவாரணிகளின் வழக்கமான பயன்பாடு மற்றும் அதிகப்படியான மது அருந்துதல் ஆகியவை இரைப்பை அழற்சிக்கு வழிவகுக்கும்.இரைப்பை அழற்சி எதிர்பாராத விதமாக ஏற்படலாம் (கடுமையான இரைப்பை அழற்சி), அல்லது அது ஒரு குறிப்பிட்ட காலத்திற்கு (நாள்பட்ட இரைப்பை அழற்சி) ஏற்படலாம். சில சந்தர்ப்பங்களில், இரைப்பை அழற்சி புண்களை ஏற்படுத்தலாம் மற்றும் வயிற்று புற்றுநோயின் அபாயத்தை அதிகரிக்கும். இருப்பினும், பெரும்பாலான மக்களுக்கு, இரைப்பை அழற்சி சிகிச்சையுடன் விரைவாக குணமடைகிறது.அறிகுறிகள்இரைப்பை அழற்சியின் அறிகுறிகள் மற்றும் அறிகுறிகள் பின்வருமாறு:அடிவயிற்றின் மேல் பகுதியில் எரியும் வலி (அஜீரணம்) காலப்போக்கில் மோசமாகவோ அல்லது சிறப்பாகவோ ஆகலாம்வாந்திஉட்கொண்ட பிறகு மேல் வயிற்றில் வீக்கம் போன்ற உணர்வுஆபத்து காரணிகள்இரைப்பை அழற்சியின் அபாயத்தை அதிகரிக்கும் காரணிகள் பின்வருமாறு:பாக்டீரியா தொற்று: ஹெலிகோபாக்டர் பைலோரி தொற்று மிகவும் பொதுவான நோய்த்தொற்றுகளில் ஒன்றாக இருந்தாலும், பாதிக்கப்பட்ட சிலருக்கு மட்டுமே இரைப்பை அழற்சி அல்லது அதுபோன்ற வயிற்றுக் கோளாறுகள் ஏற்படுகின்றன. பாக்டீரியம் பாதிக்கப்படுவது மரபுவழியாக இருக்கலாம் அல்லது புகைபிடித்தல் மற்றும் மன அழுத்த அளவுகள் போன்ற வாழ்க்கை முறை தேர்வுகளால் ஏற்படலாம் என்று மருத்துவர்கள் நம்புகின்றனர்.வலி நிவாரணிகளின் வழக்கமான பயன்பாடு: பொதுவான வலி நிவாரணிகள் - ஆஸ்பிரின், இப்யூபுரூஃபன் போன்றவை கடுமையான இரைப்பை அழற்சி மற்றும் நாள்பட்ட இரைப்பை அழற்சி இரண்டையும் ஏற்படுத்தும். வலி நிவாரணிகளைப் பயன்படுத்துவது வயிற்றின் பாதுகாப்பு புறணியைப் பாதுகாக்க உதவும் ஒரு முக்கியமான பொருளைக் குறைக்கலாம்.வயது முதிர்ந்த வயது: வயதானவர்களுக்கு இரைப்பை அழற்சி ஏற்படும் அபாயம் அதிகமாக உள்ளது, ஏனெனில் வயதுக்கு ஏற்ப வயிற்றின் புறணி மெல்லியதாக இருக்கும் மற்றும் இளையவர்களை விட வயதானவர்களுக்கு தன்னுடல் தாக்கக் கோளாறுகள் ஏற்படுவதற்கான வாய்ப்புகள் அதிகம்.அதிகப்படியான ஆல்கஹால் பயன்பாடு: ஆல்கஹால் வயிற்றுப் புறணியை எரிச்சலடையச் செய்யும், இது செரிமான சாறுகளால் வயிற்றை அதிகம் பாதிக்கும். தேவையற்ற ஆல்கஹால் பயன்பாடு கடுமையான இரைப்பை அழற்சிக்கு வழிவகுக்கும்.மன அழுத்தம்: கடுமையான மன அழுத்தம் கடுமையான இரைப்பை அழற்சியை ஏற்படுத்தும்.நோய் கண்டறிதல்ஏறக்குறைய அனைவருக்கும் சில சமயங்களில் அஜீரணம் மற்றும் வயிற்று எரிச்சல் இருந்தது. அஜீரணத்தின் பெரும்பாலான நிகழ்வுகள் தீங்கற்றவை மற்றும் மருத்துவ கவனிப்பு தேவையில்லை. கடுமையான சந்தர்ப்பங்களில் சோதனைகள் பின்வருமாறு:எச். பைலோரிக்கான பரிசோதனைகள்: உங்களிடம் எச்.பைலோரி என்ற பாக்டீரியம் இருக்கிறதா என்பதைத் தீர்மானிக்க, மருத்துவர் பரிசோதனைகளை பரிந்துரைக்கலாம். நோயாளி எந்த வகையான சோதனைக்கு உட்படுத்தப்படுகிறார் என்பது சூழ்நிலையைப் பொறுத்தது. எச்.பைலோரி இரத்தப் பரிசோதனை, மல பரிசோதனை அல்லது சுவாசப் பரிசோதனை மூலம் கண்டறியப்படலாம்.எண்டோஸ்கோபி: எண்டோஸ்கோபியின் போது, ​​மருத்துவர் ஒரு எண்டோஸ்கோப்பை வாய் வழியாகவும் உணவுக்குழாய், வயிறு மற்றும் சிறுகுடலுக்குள் அனுப்புகிறார். எண்டோஸ்கோப்பைப் பயன்படுத்தி, அவர்கள் வீக்கத்தின் அறிகுறிகளைத் தேடுகிறார்கள், மேலும் H.pylori இருப்பதைச் சரிபார்க்க பயாப்ஸிகளையும் எடுக்கிறார்கள்.மேல் செரிமான அமைப்பின் எக்ஸ்ரே. சில நேரங்களில் பேரியம் விழுங்குதல் அல்லது மேல் இரைப்பை குடல் தொடர் என அழைக்கப்படுகிறது, இந்த எக்ஸ்-கதிர்களின் தொடர் உணவுக்குழாய், வயிறு மற்றும் சிறுகுடல் ஆகியவற்றின் உருவங்களை அசாதாரணங்களைக் கண்டறிய உருவாக்குகிறது.சிகிச்சைஇரைப்பை அழற்சிக்கான சிகிச்சையானது சரியான காரணத்தைப் பொறுத்தது. ஸ்டெராய்டல் அல்லாத அழற்சி எதிர்ப்பு மருந்துகள் அல்லது ஆல்கஹால் ஆகியவற்றிலிருந்து உருவாகும் கடுமையான இரைப்பை அழற்சி, அந்த பொருட்களின் பயன்பாட்டைக் கட்டுப்படுத்துவதன் மூலம் குணப்படுத்தப்படலாம்.பெரும்பாலான சந்தர்ப்பங்களில், வயிற்று அமிலத்தைக் குறைக்கும் மருந்துகள் பரிந்துரைக்கப்படுகின்றன, வயிற்று அமிலத்தை நடுநிலையாக்கும் ஆன்டாக்சிட்களும் பரிந்துரைக்கப்படுகின்றன. வாழ்க்கை முறை மாற்றமும் பரிந்துரைக்கப்படுகிறது."},{"question":"Odpowiedz na pytanie. Kto jest autorem dramatu \\"Motyl na antenie – sztuka telewizyjna\\" z 1968 roku?","answer":"Odpowiedź: Autorem tego dramatu jest Václav Havel."},{"question":"Hãy tiếp tục đoạn văn sau: \\"Kharkov đã hứng một trận pháo kích suốt đêm. Hôm nay lại xảy ra hàng loạt vụ nổ. Theo thông tin sơ bộ, một số tòa nhà đã bị hư hại\\", ông Terekhov tuyên bố trên Telegram hôm nay 31/7. Vị thị trưởng Ukraine nói thêm rằng thông tin về các cuộc tấn công khác - bao gồm cả vị trí các địa điểm đã bị tấn công - đang được xác minh. Cùng ngày, Bộ chỉ huy tác chiến phía Nam của Ukraine cho biết, lực lượng hàng không của nước này đã thực hiện 6 cuộc không kích hiệu quả vào quân đội Nga. Cụ thể, máy bay cường kích của Ukraine đã ba lần tấn công vào các thành trì và nơi tập trung lực lượng cũng như thiết bị quân sự của quân","answer":"đội Nga ở thành phố Berislav tỉnh Kherson. Trong khi đó, một cặp máy bay trực thăng cũng tấn công các cứ điểm - nơi Nga tập trung binh lực ở tất cả các quận/huyện thuộc Kherson và Mykolaiv. Ngoài ra, các đơn vị tên lửa và pháo binh của Lực lượng vũ trang Ukraine cũng làm giảm lực lượng và trang thiết bị quân sự của Nga. Tổn thất của quân đội Nga trong 24h qua đã được Ukraine xác nhận: 33 lính Nga, 2 pháo Msta-B, một hệ thống tên lửa phóng loạt Grad, một hệ thống tên lửa chống tăng, 3 đơn vị xe bọc thép và xe cơ giới, cũng như 2 kho đạn khác ở quận Berislav theo Pravda. Trong một diễn biến liên quan, các quan chức Vương quốc Anh mới đây bình luận rằng, Nga đang \\"cạn kiệt sức chiến đấu\\" và \\"ngày càng tuyệt vọng\\" đồng thời cho rằng \\"cuộc chiến của nước này với Uraine đã \\"phản tác dụng\\". Bộ Quốc phòng Anh ngày 29/7 tuyên bố rằng, hàng chục nghìn quân Nga đã bị giết hoặc bị thương kể từ xung đột ở Ukraine vào cuối tháng Hai. Bộ cho biết, vì thiếu nhân lực, Nga đang phải \\"đẩy lính đánh thuê, trong đó nhiều người vốn là tội phạm ra tiền tuyến\\". Bộ này cho biết thêm rằng \\"vài nghìn xe bọc thép tiền tuyến của Nga cũng đã bị phá hủy\\"."},{"question":"Slutför den här frasen:  Den 5 december 2017 stod det klart att han skulle representera Österrike i","answer":"Eurovision Song Contest 2018 i Lissabon med låten \\"Nobody but You\\". Bidraget slutade på tredje plats i finalen. Sampson har tidigare körat bakom Bulgariens bidrag (2016 och 2017) i tävlingen."},{"question":"ప్రశ్న : వేరు వ్యవస్థకు, పత్రంలోని ఈనెల వ్యాపనానికి గల సంబంధం ఏమిటి?","answer":"వేరు వ్యవస్థ మరియు పత్రంలోని ఈనెల వ్యాపనంనకు మధ్య సంబంధం కలదు.ఎ) తల్లి వేరు వ్యవస్థ కలిగిన మొక్కలు జాలాకార ఈనెల వ్యాపనం కల్గి ఉంటాయి.బి) గుబురు వేరు వ్యవస్థ కలిగిన మొక్కలు సమాంతర ఈనెల వ్యాపనం కల్గి ఉంటాయి."},{"question":"ලෝකයේ මුහුදු මට්ටමට පහළින් පිහිටි , විශාලතම නගරය කුමක්ද ?","answer":"ලෝකයේ මුහුදු මට්ටමට පහළින් පිහිටි විශාලතම නගරය අසර්බයිජානයේ අගනුවර වන බාකු නගරයයි. "},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਪਉੜੀ ॥ਸਿਸਟਿ ਉਪਾਈ ਸਭ ਤੁਧੁ ਆਪੇ ਰਿਜਕੁ ਸੰਬਾਹਿਆ ॥ਇਕਿ ਵਲੁ ਛਲੁ ਕਰਿ ਕੈ ਖਾਵਦੇ ਮੁਹਹੁ ਕੂੜੁ ਕੁਸਤੁ ਤਿਨੀ ਢਾਹਿਆ ॥ਤੁਧੁ ਆਪੇ ਭਾਵੈ ਸੋ ਕਰਹਿ ਤੁਧੁ ਓਤੈ ਕੰਮਿ ਓਇ ਲਾਇਆ ॥ਇਕਨਾ ਸਚੁ ਬੁਝਾਇਓਨੁ ਤਿਨਾ ਅਤੁਟ ਭੰਡਾਰ ਦੇਵਾਇਆ ॥ਹਰਿ ਚੇਤਿ ਖਾਹਿ ਤਿਨਾ ਸਫਲੁ ਹੈ ਅਚੇਤਾ ਹਥ ਤਡਾਇਆ ॥੮॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 85 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਮਰਦਾਸ ਜੀ ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਵਾਰਾਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਸਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"(ਹੇ ਹਰੀ !) ਤੂੰ ਆਪੇ (ਸਾਰਾ) ਸੰਸਾਰ ਰਚਿਆ ਹੈ, ਅਤੇ (ਸਭ ਨੂੰ) ਰਿਜ਼ਕ ਅਪੜਾ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈਂ (ਫਿਰ ਭੀ) ਕਈ ਜੀਵ (ਤੈਨੂੰ ਰਾਜ਼ਕ ਨਾਹ ਸਮਝਦੇ ਹੋਏ) ਵਲ-ਛਲ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਢਿੱਡ ਭਰਦੇ ਹਨ, ਤੇ ਮੂੰਹੋਂ ਕੂੜ ਕੁਸੱਤ ਬੋਲਦੇ ਹਨ(ਹੇ ਹਰੀ !) ਜੋ ਤੇਰੀ ਰਜ਼ਾ ਹੈ ਸੋਈ ਉਹ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ, ਤੂੰ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਉਹੋ ਜਿਹੇ ਕੰਮ (ਵਲ-ਛਲ) ਵਿਚ ਹੀ ਲਾ ਰੱਖਿਆ ਹੈ  ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਹਰੀ ਨੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਸੱਚੇ ਨਾਮ ਦੀ ਸੂਝ ਬਖ਼ਸ਼ੀ ਹੈ, ਉਹਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਇਤਨੇ ਖ਼ਜ਼ਾਨੇ (ਸੰਤੋਖ ਦੇ) ਉਸ ਨੇ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਹਨ ਕਿ ਤੋਟ ਹੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਆਉਂਦੀ (ਅਸਲੀ ਗੱਲ ਇਹ ਹੈ ਕਿ) ਜੋ ਜੀਵ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨੂੰ ਯਾਦ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਮਾਇਆ ਵਰਤਦੇ ਹਨ, ਉਹਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਫਲਦੀ ਹੈ (ਭਾਵ, ਉਹ ਤ੍ਰਿਸ਼ਨਾਤੁਰ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੁੰਦੇ) ਤੇ ਰੱਬ ਦੀ ਯਾਦ ਤੋਂ ਸੱਖਣਿਆਂ ਦੇ ਹੱਥ (ਸਦਾ) ਅੱਡੇ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ (ਭਾਵ, ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਤ੍ਰਿਸ਼ਨਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਮਿਟਦੀ) ।੮।\\""},{"question":"Trả lời câu hỏi sau: Edgar Selwyn và Chantal Akerman làm việc trong ngành gì?","answer":"Edgar Selwyn và Chantal Akerman cùng làm trong ngành nghệ thuật, cụ thể là làm việc tại rạp hát và các xưởng phim."},{"question":"Mubvunzo: South Africa yakakunda makwikwi eWorld Cup kanokwana kangani? Mhinduro:","answer":"zero"},{"question":"Menene sunan malamin na 4 da aka ambata a cikin nassi? Bisa ga tambayar da ta gabata, ka rubuta mahallin da ke ɗauke da amsar. Zai iya zama jumla 1 - 20. Abubuwan da ke ciki,","answer":"Wasu masana na zamani, kamar Fielding H. Garrison, suna da ra'ayin cewa asalin kimiyyar ilimin ƙasa za a iya ganowa zuwa Farisa bayan da Musulmai suka gama cin nasara. Abu al-Rayhan al-Biruni (973 zuwa1048 CE) na ɗaya daga cikin masana ilimin ƙasa na Farisa na farko, wanda ayyukansa suka haɗa da rubuce-rubuce na farko game da ilimin ƙasa na Indiya, suna tunanin cewa yankin Indiya ya taɓa zama teku. Da yake zanawa daga littattafan kimiyya na Girka da Indiya waɗanda ba a lalata su ba ta hanyar mamayewar Musulmai, masanin Farisa Ibn Sina (Avicenna, 981<unk>1037) ya ba da cikakken bayani game da samuwar duwatsu, asalin girgizar ƙasa, da sauran batutuwa masu mahimmanci ga ilimin ƙasa na zamani, wanda ya ba da tushe mai mahimmanci don ci gaban kimiyya na gaba. A kasar Sin, masanin ilimin kimiyya Shen Kuo (1031 <unk> 1095) ya gabatar da wata ka'ida game da tsarin samar da ƙasa: bisa ga lura da burbushin halittu na dabbobi a cikin wani geological stratum a cikin dutse daruruwan mil daga teku, ya yanke shawarar cewa an kafa ƙasar ta hanyar lalata duwatsu da kuma ta hanyar zubar da laka."},{"question":"Apakah cara yang terbaik untuk merebus pasta?","answer":"Pasta merupakan makanan yang diperbuat dari tepung semolina gandum durum. Pasta yang diimport masuk ke Malaysia adalah pasta kering. Ia datang dalam berbagai bentuk dan setiap bentuk ada namanya sendiri. Antara pasta yang popular ialah spaghetti dan vermicelli (berbentuk silinder seperti mee); macaroni dan elbow (tiub bengkok); lasagna (kepingan nipis empat segi); penne (serupa straw yang dipotong serong); fettuccini (serupa kuey teow); fusilli (berpintal) dan bermacam-macam lagi.Cara-cara memasak atau merebus pasta tidak susah, tetapi jika mengikut cara yang betul pasta akan melekat, terlalu lembik atau masih keras. Berikut adalah cara yang betul untuk memasak pasta kering.Bahan: 1 paket 500gm pasta, 2 sudu besar garam, 5 liter airCara memasak:1. Masak air sehingga menggelegak. Gunakan periuk yang dalam dan besar supaya dapat memberi ruang kepada pasta semasa merebus.2. Bila air menggelegak, masukkan garam dan bila garam larut, masukkan spaghetti. Kacau spaghetti tiga atau empat kali semasa tempoh memasak supaya pasta tidak melekat dan masak sekata.3. Sekiranya resipi memerlukan anda menyambung masak di dalam sos, pasta hendaklah dimasak sehingga al dente. Al dente ialah keadaan di mana pasta sudah masak sepenuhnya tetapi bahagian dalamnya masih sedikit keras. Ini kebiasaannya dicapai dengan memasak kurang 2 minit dari tempoh memasak yang dinyatakan pada bungkusan pasta.4. Sekiranya anda ingin hidang terus (dengan sos dituang di atas pasta), pasta hendaklah dimasak mengikut tempoh masa yang dinyatakan pada bungkusan.5. Setelah masak, simpan sedikit air rebusan untuk dimasukkan ke dalam sos, kemudian tuskan.Tip:1. Jangan masukkan minyak bila merebus pasta. Ia akan menyebabkan sos susah melekat pada pasta.2. Jangan bilas pasta selepas merebus. Ia akan menanggalkan kanji dari pasta. Kanji sebenarnya bertindak semacam gam yang membantu sos melekat pada pasta.3. Masukkan sedikit air rebusan pasta ke dalam sos/kuah. Kanji dalam air rebusan membantu memekatkan dan memantapkan sos/kuah pasta. (Biasanya garam tak perlu dimasukkan ke dalam sos. Memadai dengan masin air rebusan)"},{"question":"在加拿大，第二G2司機，駕駛時酒精在血液中的含量是0.00%，除此之外可以？","answer":"在任何時間，任何公路上駕駛乘客的數量不允許超過安全帶的數量12個月後參加G2-G路考，合格後才能取得全面駕駛執照G牌"},{"question":"Libianca","answer":"Libianca Kenzonkinboum Fonji,tí wọ́n mọ̀ sí Libianca, jẹ́ ọ̀kọrin Afrobeat ti won bí sí Kameroon tí ó sì ń kọrin ní ìlú Amẹ́ríkà. Ó wà lára àwọn tí wọn díje lórí ètò tí wón ń pè ní The Voice èyí tí o jẹ́ Ìràn kàn ní ìlú Amẹ́ríkà ní ọdún 2021. Ó ti ìpasẹ̀ orin àkọ́kọ́ tí tí ó pè ní \\"People\\" tí ó fí di olókìkí ní ọdún 2022, èyí tí ó jẹ́ pé Cyclothymia ní ó wù lórí. Orin \\"People\\" jẹ́ orin tí òkiki rẹ kàn dé bi ó wà ní nípò Kejì lórí Billboard kan ní orílẹ̀-èdè Amẹ́ríkà tí wón ń pè ní U.S Billboard Magazine tí ó jẹ́ tí àwọn orin Afrobeat beats tí ó sì jẹ́ ohun tí ó tán ká lórí èrò Social Media.Wọ́n bí sí Minneapolis ní Ìlú tí wọ́n pè ní Minnesota, sùgbọ́n Libianca wà láti orílè èdè Kamẹrúùn.  Ó díje nínú 21st season tí NBC tí wọn pè ní \\"The Voice \\", níbi tí Blake Shelton tí jẹ́ Olùkọ́ni rẹ̀. She made her way to the top 20 before being eliminated. Ó jẹ́ ọ̀kọrin ní ilé-iṣẹ́ orin tí wọn pè ní 5k Records and RCA Records."},{"question":"வினா :  நவீன தாவரவியலின் தந்தை என அழைக்கபடுபவர் யார் ?","answer":"விடை : கார்ல் லின்னேயஸ் 1.கார்ல் லின்னேயஸ் 2. கரோலஸ் லின்னேயஸ்3. கார்ல் வொன் லின்னே4.கார்ல் லின்னே\\" போன்ற பல்வேறுபட்ட பெயர்கள்வழி இவர் குறிப்பிடப்படுகின்றார்.கரோலசு இலின்னேயசு சுவீடன் நாட்டைச் சேர்ந்த, உயிரினங்களைப் பற்றி ஆய்வு செய்த முன்னோடி அறிவியலாளர். இவர் தாவரவியலாளராகவும், விலங்கியலாளராகவும், மருத்துவராகவும் திகழ்ந்தார். புதிய, தற்கால அறிவியல் வகைப்பாட்டு முறைக்கும், பெயர்முறைக்கும் அடிப்படையை உருவாக்கியவர் இவரே"},{"question":"Su’aal: Sheeg Badda Ugu Gunta Dheer Adduunka?","answer":"Jawaab: Waa Badda Loo-Yaqaano Baltic Sea."},{"question":"ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਦਿ ਡਰਟੀ ਪਿਕਚਰ’ ਦੀ ਸਫ਼ਲਤਾ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਹਰ ਪਾਸੇ ਸਿਰਫ਼ ਵਿਦਿਆ ਬਾਲਨ ਦੀ ਹੀ ਚਰਚਾ ਹੈ। ਇਹ ਵੀ ਸੁਣਨ ’ਚ ਆ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਵਿਦਿਆ ਨੇ ਇੱਕ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ’ਚ ਭੂਮਿਕਾ ਨਿਭਾਉਣ ਲਈ 7 ਕਰੋੜ ਰੁਪਏ ਮੰਗਣੇ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਕਰ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਹਨ। ਵਿਦਿਆ ਬਾਲਨ ਆਪਣੀ ਨਵੀਂ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਕਹਾਣੀ’ ਕਾਰਨ ਵੀ ਅੱਜ ਕੱਲ੍ਹ ਚਰਚਾ ਵਿੱਚ ਹੈ। ਜ਼ਿਕਰਯੋਗ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਇਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ’ਚ ਵਿੱਦਿਆ ਨੇ 6 ਮਹੀਨੇ ਦੀ ਗਰਭਵਤੀ ਔਰਤ ਦਾ ਕਿਰਦਾਰ ਨਿਭਾਇਆ ਹੈ। ਇਹ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ 9 ਮਾਰਚ ਨੂੰ ਰਿਲੀਜ਼ ਹੋਵੇਗੀ। ਇਸ ਸਬੰਧੀ ਵਿਦਿਆ ਨਾਲ ਹੋਏ ਸਵਾਲ-ਜਵਾਬ ਪਾਠਕਾਂ ਦੀ ਦਿਲਚਸਪੀ ਲਈ ਪੇਸ਼ ਹਨ:ਸਵਾਲ: ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਕਹਾਣੀ-ਏ ਮਦਰ ਆਫ਼ ਏ ਸਟੋਰੀ’ ਟੈਗ ਲਾਈਨ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਮਤਲਬ ਹੈ?ਜਵਾਬ: ਅਸਲ ’ਚ ਇਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ’ਚ ਕਈ ਰਹੱਸ ਹਨ। ਦਰਸ਼ਕ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ’ਚ ਆਉਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਰਹੱਸਮਈ ਮੋੜਾਂ ਬਾਰੇ ਕਲਪਨਾ ਵੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਕਰ ਸਕਦਾ। ਜਦੋਂ ਸੁਜਾਏ ਘੋਸ਼ ਨੇ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਦੀ ਕਹਾਣੀ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਸੁਣਾਈ ਤਾਂ ਲੱਗਿਆ ਕਿ ਇਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਆਉਂਦੇ ਰਹੱਸ ਉਲਝਣ ਪੈਦਾ ਕਰ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ। ਜਦੋਂ ਮੈਂ ਇਹ ਗੱਲ ਸੁਜਾਏ ਨਾਲ ਸਾਂਝੀ ਕੀਤੀ ਤਾਂ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਦੀ ਕਹਾਣੀ ਨੂੰ 2-3 ਵਾਰੀ ਪੜ੍ਹਨ ਲਈ ਕਿਹਾ, ਜਦੋਂ ਮੈਂ ਦੁਬਾਰਾ ਕਹਾਣੀ ਪੜ੍ਹੀ ਤਾਂ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਇਹ ਕਾਫ਼ੀ ਰੌਚਿਕ ਲੱਗੀ।ਸਵਾਲ: ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਕਹਾਣੀ’ ਨੂੰ ਸਾਈਨ ਕਰਨ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਕਾਰਨ ਸੀ?ਜਵਾਬ: ਵੇਖੋ, ਇਹ ਇੱਕ ਰਹੱਸਮਈ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਹੈ। ਹਿੰਦੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ’ਚ ਲੰਮੇ ਸਮੇਂ ਤੋਂ ਅਜਿਹੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਨਹੀਂ ਬਣੀ, ਇਸ ਲਈ ਮੈਂ ਇਹ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਕਰਨ ਦਾ ਮਨ ਬਣਾਇਆ। ਦੂਜੀ ਗੱਲ ਇੱਕ ਮਾਂ ਦੀ ਕਹਾਣੀ ਹੋਣ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਹ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਵਧੀਆ ਲੱਗੀ। ਤੀਜੀ ਗੱਲ ਇਹ ਡਰਾਉਣੀ ਸੋਚ ਕਿ ਇਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਤੁਹਾਡਾ ਕੋਈ ਨਜ਼ਦੀਕੀ ਗਾਇਬ ਹੋ ਚੁੱਕਿਆ ਹੈ ਪਰ ਕਿੱਥੇ? ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਪਤਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਲੱਗ ਰਿਹਾ। ਸਾਰੇ ਲੋਕ ਕਹਿ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ ਕਿ ਅਰਨਵ ਬਾਗਚੀ ਜਿਹਾ ਕੋਈ ਆਦਮੀ ਹੈ ਹੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਜਦੋਂਕਿ ਤੁਸੀਂ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਬੱਚੇ ਦੀ ਮਾਂ ਬਣਨ ਵਾਲੇ ਹੋ। ਇਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਨੂੰ ਕਰਨਾ ਵੱਡੀ ਚੁਣੌਤੀ ਸੀ। ਦਰਸ਼ਕ ਵੀ ਪੂਰੀ ਉਤਸੁਕਤਾ ਨਾਲ ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਦੇਖਣਗੇ।ਸਵਾਲ: ਇਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ’ਚ ਤੁਹਾਡਾ ਕਿਰਦਾਰ ਕਿਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਦਾ ਹੈ?ਜਵਾਬ: ਮੈਂ ਇਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ’ਚ ਵਿੱਦਿਆ ਬਾਗਚੀ ਦਾ ਕਿਰਦਾਰ ਨਿਭਾਇਆ ਹੈ, ਜੋ ਇੱਕ ਆਮ ਔਰਤ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਛੇ ਮਹੀਨੇ ਦੀ ਗਰਭਵਤੀ ਹੈ। ਉਹ ਲੰਦਨ ਤੋਂ ਕੋਲਕਾਤਾ ਸ਼ਹਿਰ ਆਪਣੇ ਪਤੀ ਦੀ ਤਲਾਸ਼ ’ਚ ਆਉਂਦੀ ਹੈ। ਉਸ ਲਈ ਕੋਲਕਾਤਾ ਸ਼ਹਿਰ ਦੇ ਲੋਕ ਅਜਨਬੀ ਹਨ ਪਰ ਉਹ ਵਿਚਾਰੀ ਜਾਂ ਦੁਖਿਆਰੀ ਔਰਤ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੈ।ਸਵਾਲ: ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਕਹਾਣੀ’ ਦੇ ਹੀ ਵਿਸ਼ੇ ਵਾਲੀ ਇੱਕ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਮੈਰਿਡ ਟੂ ਅਮਰੀਕਾ’ ਵੀ ਰਿਲੀਜ਼ ਹੋਈ ਹੈ। ਉਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਵੀ ਇੱਕ ਪਤਨੀ ਅਮਰੀਕਾ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਹਾਰ ਦੇ ਦਰਭੰਗਾ ’ਚ ਆਪਣੇ ਪਤੀ ਦੀ ਤਲਾਸ਼ ਵਿੱਚ ਆਉਂਦੀ ਹੈ।ਜਵਾਬ: ਮੈਂ ਇਹ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਦੇਖੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੈ ਪਰ ਇਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਬਾਰੇ ਜਾਣਕਾਰੀ ਜ਼ਰੂਰ ਇਕੱਠੀ ਕੀਤੀ। ਪਤਾ ਲੱਗਿਆ ਕਿ ਉਹ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਭ੍ਰਿਸ਼ਟਾਚਾਰ ਨਾਲ ਸਬੰਧਤ ਹੈ ਜਦੋਂਕਿ ‘ਕਹਾਣੀ’ ਮਨੁੱਖੀ ਭਾਵਨਾਵਾਂ ’ਤੇ ਆਧਾਰਤ ਹੈ।ਸਵਾਲ: ਇਹ ਵੀ ਸੁਣਨ ’ਚ ਆਇਆ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਤੁਸੀਂ ਬਹੁਤ ਮੁਸ਼ਕਲ ਨਾਲ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਨੂੰ ਕਰਨ ਲਈ ਹਾਮੀ ਭਰੀ, ਕਿਉਂ?ਜਵਾਬ: ਅਸਲ ’ਚ ਮੈਂ ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਰਹੱਸਮਈ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਦੀ ਕਹਾਣੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਪੜ੍ਹੀ ਸੀ। ਜਦੋਂ ਮੈਂ ਪਹਿਲੀ ਵਾਰ ਇਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਦੀ ਸਕਰਿਪਟ ਪੜ੍ਹੀ ਤਾਂ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਇਹ ਲੱਗਿਆ ਕਿ ਸ਼ਾਇਦ ਮੈਂ ਇਹ ਸਭ ਨਹੀਂ ਕਰ ਸਕਾਂਗੀ ਪਰ ਨਿਰਦੇਸ਼ਕ ਸੁਜਾਏ ਘੋਸ਼ ਨੇ ਮੇਰੀ ਪ੍ਰਤਿਭਾ ’ਤੇ ਯਕੀਨ ਕਰਦਿਆਂ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਇਹ ਕਿਰਦਾਰ ਕਰਨ ਲਈ ਕਿਹਾ ਤਾਂ ਮੈਂ ਹਾਮੀ ਭਰ ਦਿੱਤੀ।ਸਵਾਲ: ਇਹ ਵੀ ਸੁਣਨ ’ਚ ਆਇਆ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਤੁਸੀਂ ਇਸ ਦੀ ਸਕਰਿਪਟ ’ਚ ਕਾਫ਼ੀ ਬਦਲਾਅ ਕਰਵਾਇਆ ਹੈ?ਜਵਾਬ: ਗ਼ਲਤ, ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਕੋਈ ਗੱਲ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੈ। ਅਕਸਰ ਸੁਜਾਏ ਘੋਸ਼ ਦ੍ਰਿਸ਼ ਲਿਖਣ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਫੋਨ ਉੱਤੇ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਸੁਣਾਉਂਦੇ ਸਨ। ਉਸ ਸਮੇਂ ਮੈਂ ਆਪਣੀ ਰਾਇ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਦਿੰਦੀ ਸੀ।ਸਵਾਲ: ਇਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਵਿਚਲੇ ਕਿਰਦਾਰ ਨੂੰ ਕਰਨ ਲਈ ਕਿੰਨੀ ਕੁ ਮਿਹਨਤ ਕਰਨੀ ਪਈ?ਜਵਾਬ: ਦੂਜੀਆਂ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ਦੀ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਮੈਂ ਇਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਲਈ ਵੀ ਬਹੁਤ ਮਿਹਨਤ ਕੀਤੀ ਹੈ। ਇਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਲਈ  ਲਗਾਤਾਰ 64 ਦਿਨ ਸ਼ੂਟਿੰਗ ਕਰਨੀ ਪਈ ਸੀ। ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਦਾ ਬਜਟ ਘੱਟ ਸੀ ਅਤੇ ਸਮੇਂ ਦੀ ਵੀ ਘਾਟ ਸੀ ਪਰ ਇਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਲਈ ਅਸੀਂ ਇੱਕ ਦੂਜੇ ਨੂੰ ਪੂਰਾ ਸਹਿਯੋਗ ਦਿੱਤਾ।ਸਵਾਲ: ਸੁਜਾਏ ਘੋਸ਼ ਦਾ ਦਾਅਵਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਇਹ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਤੁਹਾਨੂੰ ਚੌਥਾ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਫੇਅਰ ਐਵਾਰਡ ਦਿਵਾਏਗੀ?ਜਵਾਬ: ਮੇਰੇ ਲਈ ਦਰਸ਼ਕਾਂ ਦੀ ਪਸੰਦ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਅਹਿਮੀਅਤ ਰੱਖਦੀ ਹੈ। ਐਵਾਰਡ ਕਲਾਕਾਰ ਨੂੰ 40 ਸਾਲ ਬਾਅਦ ਇਹ ਯਾਦ ਕਰਵਾਉਂਦੇ ਹਨ ਕਿ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਕਦੇ ਚੰਗਾ ਕੰਮ ਕੀਤਾ ਸੀ ਜਿਸ ਲਈ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਐਵਾਰਡ ਮਿਲਿਆ ਸੀ। ਮੈਂ ਐਵਾਰਡ ਬਾਰੇ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਸੋਚਦੀ।ਸਵਾਲ: ਤੁਹਾਡੇ ਲਈ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਦੀ ਵਪਾਰਕ ਸਫ਼ਲਤਾ ਕਿਸ ਹੱਦ ਤਕ ਮਾਅਨੇ ਰੱਖਦੀ ਹੈ?ਜਵਾਬ: ਬਹੁਤ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ। ਮੈਂ ਚਾਹੁੰਦੀ ਹਾਂ ਕਿ ਮੇਰੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਤੋਂ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਦਰਸ਼ਕ ਦੇਖਣ।ਸਵਾਲ: ਸਿਨੇਮਾ ’ਚ ਆਏ ਬਦਲਾਓ ਬਾਰੇ ਕੀ ਕਹੋਗੇ?ਜਵਾਬ: ਦੁਨੀਆਂ ਬਦਲ ਰਹੀ ਹੈ, ਇਸ ਬਦਲਾਓ ਦਾ ਪ੍ਰਭਾਵ ਸਿਨੇਮਾ ਉੱਤੇ ਵੀ ਪੈ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ। ਜੋ ਕੁਝ ਸਮਾਜ ’ਚ ਵਾਪਰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਓਹੀ ਸਿਨੇਮਾ ’ਚ ਦਿਖਾਈ ਦਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ।ਸਵਾਲ: ਕੀ ਤੁਸੀਂ ਫਿਲਮ ਨਿਰਮਾਣ ਦੇ ਕਿਸੇ ਵੀ ਪੱਖ ਨਾਲ ਜੁੜਨਾ ਚਾਹੁੰਦੇ ਹੋ?ਜਵਾਬ: ਜੀ ਨਹੀਂ। ਮੈਂ ਫਿਲਮ ਨਿਰਮਾਣ ਦੇ ਕਿਸੇ ਕਾਰਜ ਨਾਲ ਜੁੜਨਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਚਾਹੁੰਦੀ। ਨਾ ਹੀ ਮੈਂ ਨਿਰਦੇਸ਼ਕ ਬਣ ਸਕਦੀ ਹਾਂ ਅਤੇ ਨਾ ਹੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਨਿਰਮਾਤਾ।ਸਵਾਲ: ਕਿਹਾ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਤੁਹਾਨੂੰ ਦਰਸ਼ਕਾਂ ਦੀ ਨਬਜ਼ ਦੀ ਪਛਾਣ ਹੋ ਗਈ ਹੈ?ਜਵਾਬ: ਪਤਾ ਨਹੀਂ, ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਮੈਂ ਕੁਝ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਕਦੀ। ਦਰਸ਼ਕਾਂ ਦੀ ਨਬਜ਼ ਤੇਜ਼ੀ ਨਾਲ ਬਦਲਦੀ ਰਹਿੰਦੀ ਹੈ। ਹੁਣ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਚੱਲ ਰਹੀਆਂ ਹਨ ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਵੱਖ-ਵੱਖ ਵਿਸ਼ਿਆਂ ’ਤੇ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ਬਣ ਰਹੀਆਂ ਹਨ। ਦਰਸ਼ਕ ਵੀ ਹਰ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀਆਂ ਫਿਲਮਾਂ ਦੇਖਣਾ ਚਾਹੁੰਦੇ ਹਨ। ਪ੍ਰਸ਼ਨਃ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਕਹਾਣੀ-ਏ ਮਦਰ ਆਫ਼ ਏ ਸਟੋਰੀ’ ਅਦਾਕਾਰਾ ਕੌਣ  ਹੈ?","answer":"ਉੱਤਰਃ   ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਕਹਾਣੀ-ਏ ਮਦਰ ਆਫ਼ ਏ ਸਟੋਰੀ’ ਅਦਾਕਾਰਾ  ਵਿਦਿਆ ਬਾਲਨ ਹੈ।"},{"question":"Qual é a capital das Ilhas Marshall?","answer":"A capital das Ilhas Marshall é Majuro, o seu atol mais populoso. As Ilhas Marshall, oficialmente República das Ilhas Marshall, são um país da Micronésia, cujos vizinhos mais próximos são Quiribáti, a sul, os Estados Federados da Micronésia, a oeste, e a Ilha Wake, pertencente aos Estados Unidos, a norte.Independente, o país desfruta de uma livre associação com os EUA, que são responsáveis pela segurança e pela defesa das Ilhas Marshall."},{"question":"வினா: கவிதை எழுத அறிய வேண்டுவனவாகச் சுரதா கூறுவனவற்றை விவரிக்க.","answer":"விடை:வானம் என்பது ஒன்று. வானத்தில் இயங்குகின்ற நிலவு, சூரியன், மேகம் என்பது வேறு. எனவே வானம் வேறு, அதில் இயங்குபவை வேறானது. மண் என்பது பூமியை குறிக்கும். அப்பூமியின் மீது கலந்திருக்கும் மணல், பனித்துளி, மழை இவை எல்லாம் வேறு. எனவே மண் வேறு, அதில் கலந்திருப்பவை வேறு. புண் என்பது அடிப்படுதல். வீரர்களுக்கு ஏற்படுவது விழுப்புண் வேறு வேறானது. புகழும், செல்வாக்கும் வேறுவேறானது. உடம்பில் உள்ள கண்ணும், கல்விக் கண்ணும் வேறு கற்றவரின் கவிநடையும், உரைநடையும் வேறுவேறானது.சமைக்கும் முன்வரை அரிசி என்றும் சமைத்த பின்பு அதனையே சோறு என்றும் சொல்கின்றோம். பூக்களை, பூப்பதாலேயே பூ என்கிறோம் அதற்கு முன் அரும்பு என்றழைக்கிறோம். சொல்கள் சேர்கின்ற போது எதுகை, மோனை என்றும், சேராமல் அடிகளாக மாற்றாமல் எழுதுவதை வசனம் என்றும் யாப்பை சேர்த்து எழுதினால் கவிதை என்றும் அழைக்கின்றோம்.பழம் பழுத்து இருந்தால் சாறுகிட்டும். வயலில் நீர்பாய்ந்திருந்தால் ஏர்கள் வரும் அதேபோல் எழுத்திருந்தால் அசைகள் வரும்.இரண்டு சீர் இடைவெளியில் தளைகள் வரும். தளைகள் சேர்ந்தால் அடிகள் வரும் அடிகள் பல அடுக்கிவந்தால் தொடைகள் வரும்.தொடைகள் நன்குழு செழித்திருந்தால் பாக்கள் வரும் இவை எல்லாம் தெரிந்து கொண்ட பின்னர் ‘ கவிதை எழுதத் தொடங்க வேண்டும். தேமாவும், புளிமாவும் மரத்தில் காய்க்கும். சீர்களிலும் அக்காய்கள் நன்கு காய்க்கும். ஏமாந்தால் சீர்கள் தளையைத்தட்டும். வெள்ளைப் பாட்டின் இறுதிச்சீரில் காசு தரும். பூத்த பூவில் வண்டு வருவதுபோது நல்லபுலவர்களின் பாடல்களுக்கு கீர்த்தி தங்கும். சாதாரண மக்களுக்கும் விளங்கும் வண்ணம் தமிழ்க்கவிதை தரவேண்டும்.எருவினாலே பயிர்கள் விளையும். சிறந்த கேள்வி எழுப்புவதால் நல்ல ஆராய்ச்சி விளையும். நடு இரவில் குளிர்விளையும். ஆழ்ந்து, நுணுங்கதோடே பொருளும் உள்ளத்தில் விளையும். மிஞ்சும் அறிவினிலே புகழ்விளையும். இவற்றை எல்லாம் பெரும்பாலும் அறியாமல் எழுதுவோர்க்கும் புகழும், சிறப்பும் எங்கே விளையக்கூடும்."},{"question":"Lihatlah bagian di bawah ini dan kemudian jawab pertanyaan setelahnya dalam Bahasa Indonesia:  Teks: Springsteen telah merekam dua album rock dan karya yang menceritakan tentang suramnya kehidupan masyarakat. Album studionya yang paling sukses, Born to Run (1975) dan Born in the U.S.A. (1984), menceritakan tentang masyarakat yang menemukan kesenangan dalam perjuangan hidup Amerika sehari-hari. Springsteen telah menjual lebih dari 135 juta rekaman di seluruh dunia dan lebih dari 64 juta rekaman di Amerika Serikat, menjadikannya salah satu artis terlaris di dunia. Dia telah mendapatkan banyak penghargaan untuk karyanya, termasuk 20 Grammy Awards, dua Golden Globes, Academy Award, dan Tony Award (untuk Springsteen di Broadway).  Pertanyaan: Berapa juta rekaman yang telah Springsteen jual di seluruh dunia?","answer":"Berdasarkan teks tersebut, Springsteen merupakan artis yang telah merekam berbagai macam album rock dan berhasil meraih berbagai macam penghargaan untuk karyanya. Springsteen berhasil menjual rekaman di seluruh dunia sebanyak lebih dari 135 juta."},{"question":"Formule uma resposta a esta pergunta elaborada: \\"When a Woman Loves\\" é o primeiro single do cantor R. Kelly de seu décimo primeiro álbum de estúdio com qual nome?","answer":"\\"Love letter\\""},{"question":"வாழ்க்கைப் போரில் வெற்றி பெறுவதற்கான வழிகளைக் கமுகுமரம் வாயிலாக ந. பிச்சமூர்த்தி ஆசிரியர் எவ்வாறு உணர்த்துகிறார்?","answer":"கமுகு பிறந்த இடம்:அடர்ந்த இருள் போன்ற நிழல் பரப்புகின்ற பெருமரங்களின் இடையே கமுகு பிறந்தது. பெருமரங்களின் நிழல் என்னும் இருள் அதன் வளர்ச்சிக்குத் தேவையான ஒளியமுதைத் தடுத்தது. பெருமரங்களின் நிழலை வெறுத்த கமுகு தான் வளரத் தேவையான ஒளியமுதைப் பெற்று உயிர்ப்புப் பெற போராட துவங்கியது.கமுகின் போராட்டம்:கமுகு மரம் கடுமையாகப் பெருமரங்களுடன் முட்டிமோதும் முயற்சியைத் தொடங்கியது. விண்ணிலிருந்து வரும் தன் உயிர்ப்பாகிய ஒளியமுதைத் தேடியது. மீண்டும், மீண்டும் உயர முயற்சித்தது. கதிரவனின் ஒளிக்கதிர்களாகிய விரல்களின் அழைப்பைக் கண்டது. பெருமரங்களின் இருட்டில் இருந்து கொண்டே தன் கிளையை வளைத்து ஒளியை நோக்கி நீட்டத் தொடங்கியது; வளர்ந்தது. பெரு மரங்களை முட்டி மோதும் துணிச்சலையும், முயற்சியையும் பெற்றதால் கமுகு வளைந்து, நெளிந்து, நீண்டு வளர்ந்தது. மலர்ச்சி பெற்றது.வாழ்க்கைப் போர்:வாழ்க்கையிலும் இருள் போன்ற நிழல் சூழ்ந்த நிலைகள் ஏற்படலாம். ஒளியமுதை நம்பி, வேண்டி, கமுகு துணிச்சலான முயற்சியில் ஈடுபட்டது போல, நாமும் வாழ்க்கைப் போரில் நம்பிக்கை தன்முனைப்பு, விடாமுயற்சி, உடையவர்களாய் இருந்தால் வாழ்வு மலர்ச்சி பெறும்.முடிவுரை:“பெருமரத்துடன் சிறுகமுகு போட்டியிடுகின்றது, அதுவே வாழ்க்கைப் போர். முண்டி போதும் துணிவே இன்பம் உயிரின் முயற்சியே வாழ்வின் மலர்ச்சி”. இயற்கையின் போராட்டங்களையும், வாழ்வின் அனுபவங்களையும் இணைத்து அறிவுத் தெளிவுடன் வாழ்க்கைப் போரைச் சந்திப்போம்; முயல்வோம்; வெற்றி பெறுவோம்."},{"question":"নিম্নলিখিত অনুচ্ছেদ সংক্ষিপ্ত করুন:পশ্চিম তীরে বসতি স্থাপন নিয়ে বিতর্ক রয়েছেওই প্রস্তাবটিতে পার্লামেন্টের ৬০ সদস্যের মধ্যে ৫২ জন 'হ্যাঁ' ভোট দেন।নতুন এই প্রস্তাবে পশ্চিমতীরে বসতি নির্মাণের জন্য অধিকৃত ফিলিস্তিনি জমির মালিকদের অর্থ কিংবা বিকল্প জমি দিয়ে ক্ষতিপূরণ দেওয়ার কথা বলা হয়েছে।ফিলিস্তিনের পশ্চিমতীরে বসতি স্থাপনের বিষয়টিতে যুক্তরাষ্ট্রের নতুন প্রেসিডেন্ট ডোনাল্ড ট্রাম্পের অবস্থান তাঁর পূর্বসূরি বারাক ওবামার তুলনায় অনেকটাই নরম। আর এই সুযোগকে কাজে লাগিয়ে ফিলিস্তিনে বসতি স্থাপনের বিষয়ে আন্তর্জাতিক নিন্দা ও চাপকেও উপেক্ষা করছে ইসরায়েল।ট্রাম্প প্রশাসনের হাতে ক্ষমতা যাওয়ার পর গত কয়েক সপ্তাহে বেশ কয়েকটি এলাকায় বসতি স্থাপনের প্রস্তাব অনুমোদন করেছে ইসরায়েল। অন্যদিকে ফিলিস্তিনি কর্তৃপক্ষ বলছে এই আইন পাশের মাধ্যমে তারা তাদের জমি চুরিকে বৈধ করলো এবং এটা কোন রাজনৈতিক ফয়সালার পথকে রুদ্ধ করে দেবে। আরও পড়ুন:ক্যাথলিক চার্চে যৌন নিপীড়নের শিকার হাজারো শিশুকুমিরের বাচ্চা ‘উধাও হবার’ রহস্যের সমাধানসিইসি হচ্ছেন সাবেক সচিব নুরুল হুদাসুপ্রিম কোর্ট চত্বরের ভাস্কর্য অপসারণ চায় হেফাজত|","answer":"ইসরায়েলের পার্লামেন্ট এমন এক বিতর্কিত আইন পাশ করেছে, যার ফলে পশ্চিম তীরে ফিলিস্তিনিদের ব্যক্তি মালিকানার জমিতে তৈরি চার হাজার ইহুদী বসতিস্থাপনকারীর বাড়িঘর তৈরিকে বৈধতা দেবে।"},{"question":"પબ્લિક ડોમેન વિષે જણાવો.","answer":"પબ્લિક ડોમેન અથવા જાહેર સંપદામાં એ તમામ જ્ઞાન તથા રચનાત્મકતા (ખાસ કરીને સાહિત્ય, કલા, સંગીત, અને આવિષ્કાર)નો સમાવેશ થાય છે જેની ઉપર કોઇ પણ વ્યક્તિ કે સંસ્થા પોતાની ખાનગી માલિકી જાહેર ન કરી શકે.આ જ્ઞાન અને રચનાત્મકતાના ગણને માનવતાનો સાંસ્કૃતિક તથા બૌદ્ધિક વારસો ગણવામાં આવે છે જેને સામાન્ય રીતે કોઇ પણ વ્યક્તિ કોઇ પણ હેતુ માટે વાપરી શકે છે.કોઇ ચીજ જાહેર સંપદામાં ન હોવાનું કારણ તેની પર કોઇકે કરેલો પ્રકાશનાધિકાર કે પેટન્ટનો દાવો હોઇ શકે છે. અવી ખાનગી માલિકીની વસ્તુઓનો સામાન્ય જનતા સામાન્ય રીતે ફક્ત મર્યાદીત ઉપયોગ કરી શકે છે. જોકે જ્યારે પ્રકાશનાધિકાર કે અન્ય બૌદ્ધિક સંપદાને લગતાં બંધનોનો સમય પુરો થાય ત્યારે આ રચનાઓ જાહેર સંપદામાં પ્રવેશે છે અને કોઇપણ વ્યક્તિને તેનો ઉપયોગ કરવાની છૂટ મળે છે."},{"question":"The Divine Comedy\\" හි කතුවරයා කවුද?","answer":"Dante Alighieri"},{"question":"Cad iad roinnt na buntáistí a bhaineann le gairdín greille in ionad gairdín féar? ","answer":"Tá roinnt cúiseanna ann chun greille a bheith níos fearr le féar, mar shampla tá sé níos frithsheasmhaí i gcoinne damáiste feithidí agus is féidir é a chothabháil ar chostas níos ísle. Éilíonn greille níos lú cothabhála. Is minic a éilíonn féar leibhéil níos airde fertilization agus rialú lotnaid ná greille."},{"question":"Thời gian gần đây, tôi thường nhận được cuộc gọi mời làm thẻ tín dụng từ các ngân hàng. Ban đầu cảm thấy phiền, nhưng nghe họ chào mời liên tục với nhiều ưu đãi, tôi lại thấy khá hấp dẫn.Một người bạn của tôi cũng dùng 2-3 thẻ tín dụng, từng kể rằng mỗi tháng được hoàn tiền hàng trăm nghìn, được tích điểm đổi quà, tích điểm dặm bay... Liệu tôi có nên làm một thẻ tín dụng cho mình không? Tiêu chí lựa chọn thẻ phù hợp ra sao và cần lưu ý điều gì? Về tình hình tài chính, tôi có lương quanh 25 triệu đồng, không nợ nần và đang có sổ tiết kiệm 500 triệu.","answer":"Trước hết, chúng ta cần hiểu rằng bản chất của thẻ tín dụng là một sản phẩm tài chính tiện ích giúp cho việc tiêu dùng được thuận lợi và dễ dàng hơn. Với một hạn mức tối đa được cung cấp hàng tháng, chúng ta không nhất thiết phải có tiền mặt vẫn có thể chi trả một sản phẩm, dịch vụ nào đó, hay nói cách khác là nhà phát hành thẻ cho chúng ta sử dụng tiền của họ và miễn lãi suất trong một thời hạn nhất định.Hết thời hạn, chúng ta phải hoàn trả lại số tiền, nếu không sẽ bị tính lãi suất ở mức cao, ngoài ra còn có thể bị ảnh hưởng xếp hạng tín dụng. Hệ thống của các tổ chức tín dụng có lưu trữ dữ liệu lịch sử trả nợ để đánh giá \\"thái độ trả nợ\\" của một người. Nếu bạn có các khoản nợ quá hạn, điểm tín dụng sẽ bị đánh giá thấp, dẫn tới hệ lụy xấu như không được xét duyệt khoản vay hoặc phải trả lãi suất cao khi vay so với người có điểm tín dụng tốt.Trong bài này, chúng ta hãy cùng phân tích việc sử dụng thẻ tín dụng ở ba khía cạnh: sự tiện dụng, các chương trình ưu đãi hấp dẫn và phương pháp quản lý chi tiêu.Sự tiện dụngĐầu tiên, với thẻ tín dụng, chúng ta không phải mang theo tiền, đổi tiền, giữ tiền lẻ và tránh được một số phiền phức nhất định. Đây là điều ai cũng có thể thấy được.Thứ hai, thao tác quẹt thẻ vô cùng dễ dàng, nhưng đằng sau lại là lý thuyết về tài chính hành vi thú vị. Nghiên cứu tâm lý cho thấy, tiền bạc là một trong những \\"tử huyệt cảm xúc\\" của con người. Đồng thời với cảm giác vui mừng khi sở hữu sản phẩm hoặc dịch vụ yêu thích, việc trả tiền tạo ra sự \\"mất mát\\" nhất định trong não bộ. Bởi vậy chúng ta thường cân nhắc, đắn đo khá nhiều khi trả tiền, đặc biệt là tiền mặt.Tuy nhiên, khi các loại thẻ ra đời, thay vì phải đưa tiền cho người bán, chúng ta chỉ cần quẹt thẻ. Do đó cảm giác \\"mất mát\\" giảm đi rất nhiều, chúng ta rút ngắn sự cân nhắc, đắn đo và chi tiền thoải mái hơn, hào phóng hơn. Như vậy, việc dùng thẻ tín dụng có thể là nguyên nhân dẫn đến chi tiêu nhiều hơn, tiết kiệm ít hơn.Ngoài ra, sự tiện dụng này còn có mặt trái sinh ra do việc làm mất thẻ hoặc mất thông tin bảo mật, khiến kẻ gian có thể sử dụng thẻ để chi tiêu. Việc giải quyết các giao dịch gian lận này luôn mất thời gian và không phải lúc nào chủ thẻ cũng lấy lại được số tiền đã mất.Các chương trình ưu đãiNhư đã phân tích ở trên, thẻ tín dụng có chức năng quan trọng là kích thích tiêu dùng. Để thực hiện được chức năng trên, trước hết người tiêu dùng cần chấp nhận dùng thẻ. Từ đó, các chương trình miễn phí thường niên và các chương trình hoàn tiền (cashback) được đưa ra để chào mời khách hàng sử dụng.Thị trường ghi nhận rất nhiều chương trình, nếu được sử dụng một cách hợp lý sẽ mang lại lợi ích trực tiếp cho chủ thẻ như hoàn tiền khi đi siêu thị, đóng học phí, trả phí bảo hiểm, mua sắm trên các sàn thương mại điện tử.Phương pháp quản lý chi tiêuDùng thẻ tín dụng là sử dụng một khoản nợ tiêu dùng. Sẽ có hai loại gồm nợ tốt và nợ xấu, tùy vào mục đích và phương pháp của người sử dụng. Việc quyết định dùng thẻ tín dụng hay không, điều căn bản không nằm ở sự tiện dụng hay các chương trình ưu đãi dành cho thẻ, mà nằm ở phương pháp quản lý chi tiêu.Ngay khi nhận được thu nhập, việc đầu tiên cần làm là trích ra khoản tiết kiệm hay còn gọi là \\"trả cho mình\\" trước khi mang đi chi tiêu, hay còn gọi là \\"trả cho người khác\\". Khoản này nhiều hay ít tùy thuộc vào mức thu nhập và số người phụ thuộc. Sau đó, phần dành cho chi tiêu nên được phân loại thành chi tiêu thiết yếu và khoản chi nhu cầu. Chi tiêu thiết yếu là những khoản bắt buộc như tiền học cho con, tiền chợ, tiền nhà, tiền điện nước, tiền bảo hiểm. Khoản chi nhu cầu là các khoản mang tính hưởng thụ như ăn uống bên ngoài, du lịch, làm đẹp, mua sắm các đồ dùng không thiết yếu khác.Với các khoản chi tiêu thiết yếu, dù chi bằng tiền mặt hay bằng thẻ vẫn không khiến chúng ta \\"tiêu hoang\\" hơn. Do đó, bạn có thể dùng thẻ tín dụng, miễn sao nhớ được thời hạn thanh toán (ngân hàng phát hành sẽ có email, tin nhắn nhắc nhở về việc này). Chưa kể, các chương trình ưu đãi của thẻ tập trung khá nhiều vào các khoản chi thiết yếu như đi siêu thị, đóng học phí, đóng bảo hiểm.Tuy nhiên, càng dễ dàng với chi tiêu thiết yếu bao nhiêu, chúng ta càng phải cẩn trọng bấy nhiêu khi dùng thẻ tín dụng để thanh toán cho các khoản chi hưởng thụ. Một số bí kíp để hạn chế các khoản chi này là định sẵn ngân sách tối đa không vượt quá 15% thu nhập, hoặc chờ đợi thêm một vài ngày để chắc chắn về sản phẩm, dịch vụ chọn mua và dùng tiền mặt thay vì dùng thẻ để hạn chế mua sắm chỉ vì tiện lợi.Như vậy, nếu là một người quản lý chi tiêu tốt, biết phân bổ ngân sách hợp lý cho chi tiêu thiết yếu và chi tiêu nhu cầu, bạn hoàn toàn có thể tận dụng những lợi thế do thẻ tín dụng mang lại và hạn chế những điểm bất cập của việc dùng thẻ.Để tạo thành thói quen chi tiêu và trả nợ đúng hạn, bạn nên bắt đầu với một thẻ, hạn mức có thể từ 1-2 lần thu nhập theo tháng của mình. Về việc lựa chọn loại thẻ nào, bạn nên xem khoản chi nào chiếm tỷ trọng lớn trong ngân sách để lựa chọn thẻ có ưu đãi đối với lĩnh vực đó."},{"question":"నీవు తరగతిలోకి రావచ్చు – ఇది ఏ రకమైన వాక్యం?A) సామర్ధ్యార్థకంB) అనుమత్యర్థకంC) నిషేధార్ధకంD) విధ్యర్థకం","answer":"B) అనుమత్యర్థకం"},{"question":"\\"ستاروں سے سرگوشی کرتے ہوئے، مجھے کائناتی شان و شوکت میں سکون ملا۔\\"مندرجہ بالا بیان کس طرف اشارہ کر رہا ہے؟","answer":"بیان کا مفہوم: بیان استعاراتی طور پر کائنات کی وسعت سے جڑ کر سکون تلاش کرنے کے ذاتی تجربے کو بیان کرتا ہے، جس کی علامت ستاروں سے سرگوشی کرتے ہیں۔جواب: یہ غیر معمولی بیان خود شناسی اور کائنات کے ساتھ تعلق کا احساس دلاتا ہے۔ یہ ستاروں کے ساتھ بات چیت کرکے سکون حاصل کرنے کے اسپیکر کے عمل کی تصویر کشی کرتا ہے، جو انسانی جذبات اور کائناتی وسعت کے درمیان گہرا تعلق تجویز کرتا ہے۔ \\"ستاروں کی طرف سرگوشی\\" کا استعاراتی عمل کائنات کے ساتھ رابطے کی ایک شکل پر دلالت کرتا ہے، جہاں خلا کی وسعت اور اسرار غور و فکر اور خود عکاسی کے لیے ایک آرام دہ اور پرسکون پس منظر فراہم کرتا ہے۔ یہ بیان خلا کی حیرت انگیز نوعیت اور کائنات کی شان و شوکت میں سکون اور معنی تلاش کرنے کی صلاحیت کو حاصل کرتا ہے۔"},{"question":"請回答這個問題：英國最為著名的傳統早餐中包括哪些食物？","answer":"答案：英國最為著名的傳統早餐中包括煎蛋、煙熏培根、香腸、烤番茄、烤豆和黑布丁等食物。這種豐盛的早餐常被稱為\\"英式早餐\\"，是英國的一個重要飲食文化特色。"},{"question":"Ano ang paksa ng talatang ito? \\"Ang bawat koponan sa ay futbol binubuo ng 11 manlalaro. Isa sa kanila ang nagsisilbing goalkeeper o bantay sa pithaya o tunguhin (goal sa Ingles). Siya lamang ang maaaring humawak sa bola kung nasa loob lamang ng kanilang penalty area. Magsisilbi namang outfield player o outfielder ang sampu. Ginagamit nila ang kanilang mga paa upang galawin at ipasa ang bola. Maaari rin nilang gamitin ang ulo at katawan upang makakuha ng isang goal. Ang koponan na may pinakamaraming goal pagkatapos ng laro ay tatanghaling panalo. Kung sakaling magkapareho ng lamang ang dalawang koponan pagkatapos ng laro, maaaring tabla o magkakaroon ng labis na oras (o extra time sa Ingles) at/o isang penalty shootout batay sa mga panuntunan ng paligsahan. Ang Laws of the Game ay orihinal na sistema sa Inglatera ng The Football Association noong 1863. Ang futbol ay pandaigdigang nasasaklaw ng Fédération Internationale de Football Association o \\"FIFA\\" na nagpasimula ng FIFA World Cup na ginaganap tuwing apat na taon.\\"","answer":"Tungkol sa batas at mekanika ng larong futbol ang talata. Nilalarawan nito ang tungkulin ng bawat miyembro ng koponan upang manalo sa futbol.  Binanggit din sa talata kung sino ang namamahala ng mga batas na ito noon at ngayon."},{"question":"السؤال: ألمانيا ربحت كأس العالم 4 ديال المرات ولكن شحال من مره دارتها كدولة موحدة؟","answer":"الإجابة: مرة واحدة (2014)"},{"question":"Жең ичинен сүйлөшүү- дегенди кандай түшүнөсүң? ","answer":"Жашыруун башкаларга билдирбей, эки кишинин өз ара сүйлөшкөнү. Бул накыл кептин келип чыгышы– базарда сатылуучу малдын ээси менен алуучунун ортосундагы далдалчынын жеңдин ичине беш манжасын сойлотуп, алуучуга да, сатуучуга да бармактар менен бааны билдиргенине барып такалат. Мына ушундан улам – ар бир жашыруун сүйлөшүүлөрдү – «жең ичинен сүйлөшүү» деген накыл кеп менен атай турган болгон. «Далдалчы» - арабдын жана кыргыздын сөзү. «Далдал» - «даллал» деген сөздөн өзгөргөн, «арачы», «эки ортодо мал соодасын кылуучу» деген мааниде.(Х.Карасаев)"},{"question":" सॉक्रेटिसचा शिष्य कोण होता ?","answer":" सॉक्रेटिसचा शिष्य प्लेटो होता."},{"question":"Menene yaren mutanen Trinidad?","answer":"Harshen hukuma na Trinidad da Tobago Ingilishi ne kuma duk ayyukan gwamnati da na kasuwanci ana gudanar da su cikin Standard English (United Kingdom). Trinidadians da Tobagonians sukan yi magana da sauri kuma suna haɗa nassoshi na gida da Creole (harshen gida, patois da Hindustani) cikin tattaunawar yau da kullun."},{"question":"مدت زمان یک باز فوتبال چقدر است؟","answer":" بازی فوتبال در دو نیمه ۴۵ دقیقه‌ای انجام می‌گیرد، مگر این‌که داور و دوتیم بر تغییر مدت زمان بازی توافق کرده‌باشند. هرگونه توافق برای تغییر مدت زمان بازی (برای مثال کاهش هرنیمه به ۴۰ دقیقه به‌دلیل نبود نور کافی) باید پیش از انجام بازی، صورت گرفته‌باشد."},{"question":"Ile-ẹjọ sun igbẹjọ Nnamdi Kanu si ọjọ kọkanlelogun, oṣu kẹwaa","answer":"Ọjọ kọkaknlelogun, oṣu kẹwaa, ọdun yii, ni wọn sun ẹjọ ajijagbara ọmọ ilẹ Ibo nni, Nnamdi Kanu si bayii. Eyi ko ṣẹyin bi ọkunrin naa ko ṣe yọju sile-ẹjọ nitori pe agbẹjọro rẹ, Ifeanyi Ejiofor, sọ pe awọn ti kọwe si kootu pe ki wọn gbe ọkunrin to n ja fun idasilẹ orileede Biafra naa kuro ni akata DSS, ki wọn gbe e lọ si ọgba ẹwọn ki awọn to ba fẹẹ ri i le maa ni anfaani lati ri i. Nidii eyi ni ọkunrin naa  ko fi wa gẹgẹ bi agbẹjọro rẹ ṣe sọ.Ṣugbọn agbẹjọro ijọba, M.B Abubakar, sọ pe oun ṣetan lati tẹsiwaju ninu ẹjọ naa, ki oun si wi awijare toun bo tilẹ jẹ pe ẹni ti wọn fẹẹ ba rojọ ko si nile-ẹjọLẹyin eyi ni Adajọ Binta Nyako to yẹ ko gbọ ẹjọ ọhun sọ pe niwọn igba ti Nnamdi kanu ko ti si ni kootu, igbẹjọ ko le waye. Lo ba sun ẹjọ naa si ọjọ kọkanlelogun, oṣu kẹwaa, ọdun yii.Tẹ o ba gbagbe, laipẹ yii ni wọn ṣu ajijagbara Biafra naa rugudu lati orileede Kenya wa si Naijiria, ti wọn si ni ko waa jẹjọ ẹsun ọdaran, ipaniyan idaluru ati bẹẹ bẹẹ lọ ti wọn fi kan an Ọdun 2017 ni wọn ti n ba a ṣẹjọ naa ko too di pe o sa kuro ni Naijiria, ti ko si pada wa titi oṣu keje, ọdun yii, ti wọn gbe e wale lati orileede Kenya"},{"question":"Lebelela temana e lego ka mo tlase gomme o arabe potšišo ka morago ka leleme le le swanago le temana:  Temana: Ka se-China, Letšatši la Baratani le bitšwa monyanya wa baratani (Se-China se se nolofaditšwego: 情人节; Se-China sa setšo: 情人節; Semandarini: Qīng Rén Jié; Hokkien: Chêng Lîn Chiat; Se-Cantonese: Chìhng Yàhn Jit; Se-Shanghai Xin Yin Jiq). \\"Letšatši la Ma-China la Baratiwa\\" ke Monyanya wa Qixi, wo o binwago ka letšatši la bošupa la kgwedi ya bošupa ya khalentara ya ngwedi. Ke segopotšo sa letšatši leo ka lona modiši wa dikgomo yo a tumilego le ngwanenyana wa go loga ba dumeletšwego go ba gotee. Setšong sa ma-China, go na le monyanya wa kgale wo o tswalanago le baratani, wo o bitšwago \\"Bošego bja Bašupa\\" (Se-China: 七夕; pinyin: Qi Xi). Go ya ka kanegelo, naledi ya Modiši wa Kgomo le naledi ya Mosetsana wa Mothudi ka tlwaelo di aroganywa ke Milky Way (noka ya silifera) eupša di dumeletšwe go kopana ka go e tshela ka letšatši la bo-7 la kgwedi ya bo-7 ya khalentara ya China. Nywageng ya morago bjale, go bina Letšatši le lešweu le gona go fetogile mo go tlwaelegilego gare ga bafsa ba bangwe.  Potšišo: Bošego bjo bo kgethegilego bjoo go ya ka nonwane ya China, modiši wa dikgomo le ngwanenyana wa mologi ba dumeletšwego go kopana bo bitšwa eng?","answer":"Bošego bja Bošupa"},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਸਾਜਨ ਸੰਤ ਕਰਹੁ ਇਹੁ ਕਾਮੁ ॥ਆਨ ਤਿਆਗਿ ਜਪਹੁ ਹਰਿ ਨਾਮੁ ॥ਸਿਮਰਿ ਸਿਮਰਿ ਸਿਮਰਿ ਸੁਖ ਪਾਵਹੁ ॥ਆਪਿ ਜਪਹੁ ਅਵਰਹ ਨਾਮੁ ਜਪਾਵਹੁ ॥ਭਗਤਿ ਭਾਇ ਤਰੀਐ ਸੰਸਾਰੁ ॥ਬਿਨੁ ਭਗਤੀ ਤਨੁ ਹੋਸੀ ਛਾਰੁ ॥ਸਰਬ ਕਲਿਆਣ ਸੂਖ ਨਿਧਿ ਨਾਮੁ ॥ਬੂਡਤ ਜਾਤ ਪਾਏ ਬਿਸ੍ਰਾਮੁ ॥ਸਗਲ ਦੂਖ ਕਾ ਹੋਵਤ ਨਾਸੁ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਨਾਮੁ ਜਪਹੁ ਗੁਨਤਾਸੁ ॥੫॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 290 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਹੇ ਸੱਜਣ ਜਨੋ! ਹੇ ਸੰਤ ਜਨੋ! ਇਹ ਕੰਮ ਕਰੋ, ਹੋਰ ਸਾਰੇ (ਆਹਰ) ਛੱਡ ਕੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਜਪਹੁ; ਸਦਾ ਸਿਮਰੋ ਤੇ ਸਿਮਰ ਕੇ ਸੁਖ ਹਾਸਲ ਕਰੋ; ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਆਪ ਜਪਹੁ ਤੇ ਹੋਰਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਭੀ ਜਪਾਵਹੁ । ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਭਗਤੀ ਵਿਚ ਨਿਹੁਂ ਲਾਇਆਂ ਇਹ ਸੰਸਾਰ (ਸਮੁੰਦਰ) ਤਰੀਦਾ ਹੈ, ਭਗਤੀ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਇਹ ਸਰੀਰ ਕਿਸੇ ਕੰਮ ਨਹੀਂ । ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਭਲੇ ਭਾਗਾਂ ਤੇ ਸਾਰੇ ਸੁਖਾਂ ਦਾ ਖ਼ਜ਼ਾਨਾ ਹੈ, ਨਾਮ ਜਪਿਆਂ (ਵਿਕਾਰਾਂ ਵਿਚ) ਡੁੱਬਦੇ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਨੂੰ ਆਸਰਾ ਟਿਕਾਣਾ ਮਿਲਦਾ ਹੈ; ਸਾਰੇ ਦੁੱਖਾਂ ਦਾ ਨਾਸ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ । ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ! ਨਾਮ ਜਪਹੁ, (ਨਾਮ ਹੀ) ਗੁਣਾਂ ਦਾ ਖ਼ਜ਼ਾਨਾ (ਹੈ) ।੫।\\""},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe kaontinenta?","answer":"Ny kaontinenta dia faritra midadasika izay matetika voahodidin'ny rano. Misy kaontinenta fito eto an-tany: Azia, Afrika, Amerika Avaratra, Amerika Atsimo,  Antarktika, Eoropa ary Oseania."},{"question":"રાજેન્દ્ર શાહ ની \\"ના બોલાય રે ના બોલાય\\" કવિતા લખો.","answer":"ના બોલાય રે ના બોલાયએક અમી ભરપુર ઉરે તવ સોમલ કેમ ઘોળાય રે..ના બોલાય રે..તારે હાથે પ્રીય મેં જ ધર્યો હતો મહેંદી એ રંગીન હાથ,અંગથી અંગ અડાડી ભર્યા નીલ કુંજ મહીં ડગ સાત.રંગ સુગંધની સોડ તણી અવ વાદ કેમ ખોલાય રે..ના બોલાય રે..સ્હેજ અડી મૃદુ આંગળી ત્યાં રણકે મધુરો ઝણકાર,એજ વીણા તણી તાંત તૂટી, બનીયો મુક રે અવતાર.પાણી મહીં નહીં, આસું મહીં નહીં ઠાલવું અંતર આજ,આગની સંગ ઉમંગ ભર્યો લહુ જીવનનો અનુરાગ.પ્રેમપ્રીયા તવ પૂજન ભૂલશો આજમાં કેમ રોળાય રે..ના બોલાય રે.."},{"question":"Tulis sebuah karangan yang bertajuk \\"Hari Kebangsaan di Sekolah Saya\\".","answer":"Semua murid sampai ke sekolah dengan awal pada hari Jummat itu.  Saya telah membuat persiapan seminggu sebelum hari itu sampai.  Dewan perhimpunan dibersihkan dan dikemaskan.  Kerusi-kerusi untuk para guru telah diatur.  Semua guru juga diberitahu tentang program Hari Kebangsaan.  Dengan itu setiap guru serta murid diberi satu program tentang aturan Hari Kebangsaan.Saat-saat yang dinantikan telah sampai, saya dengan rakan sedarjah yang lain turut berhimpun bersama murid yang lain.  Terlebih dahulu kami mengalu-alukan kedatangan guru besar serta guru-guru dengan tarian Melayu, Cina dan Iban.  Diikuti oleh nyanyian 'Negaraku.  Selepas bacaan doa, guru besar memberi sepatah dua kata.  Beliau meluahkan rasa gembira merayakan hari kebesaran ini.  Kami turut bersorak and bertepuk tangan tanda gembira juga.  Hari ini menurut Guru Besar adalah untuk mengingatkan kita berasal dari satu rumpun bangsa.  Tidak ketinggalan juga untuk mengingatkan kita tentang pengorbanan askar-askar.  Sebab itu hari kebangsaan juga dikenali sebagai hari kemerdekaan.  Selain mengingatkan kita bahawa kita telah berdikari dari penjajahan Bristih, ia juga merupakan hari di mana kita merayakannya pada hari ini. Beberapa persembahan  yang berkaitan dengan hari kebangsaan diadakan.  Pantun Melayu dipersembahkan oleh murid-murid tahun 6.  Kumpulan koir tahun 5 & 6 dipersembahkan kemudian.  Semua ketua darjah dari setiap kelas turut mempersembahankan sebuah lagu. Program hari itu diakhiri dengan nyanian 'Ibu Pertiwi' yang diketuai oleh ketua pengawas sekolah.  kami semua balik ke rumah dengan awal pada hari itu."},{"question":"வினா:சரியான விடையைத் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கவும்:செல்வச் செவிலி – இலக்கணக் குறிப்புத் தருக.(1) உவமை                                                   (2)எண்ணும்மை  (3) அடுக்குத்தொடர்                                 (4) உருவகம்.","answer":"சரியான விடை:செல்வச் செவிலி – இலக்கணக் குறிப்பு(4) உருவகம் ஆகும்.உருவகம்:உவமையாக உள்ள பொருளுக்கும் உவமிக்கப்படும் பொருளுக்கும் வேறுபாடு தோன்றாமல் இரண்டும் ஒன்று என்ற உணர்வு தோன்ற இரண்டையும் ஒற்றுமைப்படுத்துவது. இதில் உவம உருபு தோன்றாது."},{"question":"Motor City là tên gọi khác của thành phố nào của Mỹ?","answer":"Motor City là tên gọi khác của thành phố Detroit.Detroit là thành phố lớn nhất bang Michigan, Mỹ. Là cái nôi của nền công nghiệp ôtô thế giới, Detroit từng có thời gian phát triển mạnh mẽ và có nền kinh tế thịnh vượng. Cái tên \\"Motor City\\" hay \\"Motown\\" gắn liền với thành phố Detroit vì lý do này."},{"question":"ጥያቄ፦በአንጎል ውስጥ ምን ዓይነት ሴሎች ይገኛሉ? ","answer":"መልስ፦ ኒውሮንስ"},{"question":"आधुनिक समाजमा प्रविधिको प्रयोगको वरिपरि नैतिक विचारहरू छलफल गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"प्रविधिको व्यापक प्रयोगले गोपनीयता मुद्दाहरू, डाटा सुरक्षा, र उदीयमान प्रविधिहरूको जिम्मेवार विकास सहित नैतिक चिन्ताहरू खडा गर्छ, सावधानीपूर्वक विचार र नियमन आवश्यक छ।"},{"question":"Qor madadaalo ah in asxaabtayda ay ka heli doonaan funny?","answer":"Waan arkaa. Puns waa nooc ka mid ah majaajilada oo loo isticmaalo ereyo isku si si isku mid ah laakiin leh macneyo kala duwan, ama erayo macne badan leh, si ay u abuuraan erayo isku mid ah. Tusaale ahaan:Maxaad ugu yeereysaa kalluun xiran bowtie? Sofishticated.Sidee ayaad u tuurtaa xaflad goob-bannaan? Waxaad ku aasaan.Maxaad ugu yeereysaa mas mas dowladda u shaqaysa? Waa mad-habar rayid ah."},{"question":"Microsoft අයිති කාටද?","answer":"මයික්‍රොසොෆ්ට් හි හිමිකම තනි පුද්ගලයෙකු හෝ ආයතනයක් අතේ සංකේන්ද්‍රණය වී නොමැති නමුත් පුළුල් පරාසයක කොටස් හිමියන් අතර විසිරී ඇත. මෙම කොටස් හිමියන් විවිධ පසුබිම්වලින් පැමිණෙන අතර තනි ආයෝජකයින්, ආයතනික ආයෝජකයින්, අන්‍යෝන්‍ය අරමුදල්, විශ්‍රාම වැටුප් අරමුදල් සහ වෙනත් ආයතන ඇතුළත් වේ."},{"question":"ఈ క్రింది పేరా చదివి ప్రశ్నకు సమాధానము వ్రాయండి.ప్రపంచంలో అత్యధిక జనసాంద్రత గల దేశాలలో భారతదేశం ఒకటి. 2011లో భారతదేశ జనసాంద్రత చదరపు కిలోమీటరుకు 382 వ్యక్తులు. ఈ సాంద్రతలో తేడాలు పశ్చిమ బెంగాల్ లో 904 నుండి అరుణాచల్ ప్రదేశ్ లో 13 వరకు ఉన్నాయి.ప్రశ్న పశ్చిమ బెంగాల్ లో జనసాంద్రత ఎక్కువగా ఉండటానికి, అరుణాచల్ ప్రదేశ్ లో జనసాంద్రత తక్కువగా ఉండటానికి గల కారణాలు ఏమిటి?","answer":"పశ్చిమ బెంగాల్ రాష్ట్రం సారవంతమైన గంగానదీ పరీవాహక ప్రాంతంలో ఉంది.ఈ ప్రాంతం వ్యవసాయానికి, పరిశ్రమలకు అనుకూలంగా ఉండటం వల్ల నివాసయోగ్యంగా ఉన్నది.అరుణాచల్ ప్రదేశ్ రాష్ట్రం ఎక్కువ భాగం పర్వత ప్రాంతం మరియు మంచుతో కప్పబడి ఉన్నది.కావున అరుణాచల్ ప్రదేశ్ అధిక జనాభాకు అనుకూలంగా లేదు."},{"question":"Qual a velocidade da luz?a) 300 000 000 metros por segundo (m/s)b) 150 000 000 metros por segundo (m/s)c) 199 792 458 metros por segundo (m/s)d) 299 792 458 metros por segundo (m/s)e) 30 000 000 metros por segundo (m/s)","answer":"Alternativa d: 299 792 458 metros por segundo (m/s).A primeira medição real da luz foi feita pelo astrônomo Ole Romer, que em 1676 chegou a um número próximo da velocidade da luz. Hoje, sabe-se com precisão que a velocidade da luz é 299 792 458 metros por segundo."},{"question":"Yasunan mahaifin manzon Allah (SAW)","answer":"Sunan mahaifin Annabi Muhammad (SAW) Abdullahi bn Abdul-Muddalib."},{"question":"Apakah jawapan untuk teka-teki berikut: Apakah nombor yang paling suka berjudi?","answer":"Jawapan: tujuh"},{"question":"Kung i-multiply mo ang numerong ito sa anumang iba pang numero, magiging pareho ang sagot. Anong numero ito?","answer":"Ang numerong ito ay 0."},{"question":"Complete o seguinte extrato: Desde o início, o governo alemão perguntou repetidamente a Viatcheslav Molotov se a União Soviética cumpriria a sua parte no acordo da divisão. As forças soviéticas mantiveram-se firmes ao longo de seus pontos de invasão designados, aguardando a finalização da guerra não declarada de cinco meses com o Império do Japão no Extremo Oriente, o fim bem-sucedido do conflito para a União Soviética, que ocorreu nas","answer":"Batalhas de Khalkhin Gol. Em 15 de setembro de 1939, Molotov e Shigenori Tōgō concluíram seu acordo que encerrou o conflito, e o cessar-fogo de Nomonhan entrou em vigor em 16 de setembro de 1939. Agora livre de qualquer ameaça de \\"segunda frente\\" dos japoneses, o primeiro-ministro soviético Josef Stalin ordenou que suas forças entrassem na Polônia em 17 de setembro. Foi acordado que os soviéticos abririam mão de seus interesses nos territórios entre a nova fronteira e Varsóvia em troca da inclusão da Lituânia na \\"zona de interesse\\" soviética."},{"question":"Zer da antropologian ritua, eta nola ulertzen du gizarte batean errepikatzen den ekintza simbolikoa?","answer":"Ritua da gizarte batean errepikatzen den ekintza simbolikoa, gizartearen baloreak, sinismenak edo tradizioak adierazteko. Ritualak ulertzen ditu gizartearen kultura eta identitatea."},{"question":"கேள்வி :உலகின் சிறிய கடல் எது?அ) ஆர்டிக் கடல்ஆ) பசிபிக் கடல்இ) அன்டார்டிகா கடல்ஈ) அட்லான்டிக் கடல்","answer":"பதில் :அ) ஆர்டிக் கடல்"},{"question":"கொல்லேறு பறவைகள் சரணாலயம் (\\"Kolleru Bird Sanctuary\\") என்பது இந்தியாவின் ஆந்திராவில் உள்ள ஒரு பறவைகள் சரணாலயம் ஆகும். இது 673 சதுர கிலோமீட்டர் பரப்பளவைக் கொண்டுள்ளது. இச்சரணாலயம் \\"1972 ஆம் ஆண்டு வனவிலங்கு பாதுகாப்புச் சட்டத்தின்\\" கீழ் நவம்பர் 1999இல் நிறுவப்பட்டது. இந்த சரணாலயம் கொல்லெறு ஏரி ஈரநிலத்தின் ஒரு பகுதியைப் பாதுகாக்கிறது. இது 2002ஆம் ஆண்டில் சர்வதேச முக்கியத்துவத்திற்கான ராம்சார் சாசனம் அடிப்படையில் ராம்சார் ஈரநிலமாக அறிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.","answer":"ராம்சார் சாசனம்"},{"question":"ডিজিটাল বাংলাদেশ নিয়ে একটি অনুচ্ছেদ রচনা করো।","answer":"ডিজিটাল বাংলাদেশ একটি উজ্জ্বল সম্ভাবনার নাম। বর্তমানে বাংলাদেশে এ ধারণাটি বেশ আলোড়ন সৃষ্টি করেছে। ডিজিটাল বাংলাদেশ বলতে মূলত বোঝায় দেশকে তথ্যপ্রযুক্তিনির্ভর হিসেবে গড়ে তোলার একটি সুনির্দিষ্ট প্রত্যয়কে। ২০২১ সালে উদ্যাপিত হবে বাংলাদেশের মহান স্বাধীনতার সুবর্ণজয়ন্তী। এ সময়ের মধ্যেই 'ডিজিটাল বাংলাদেশ' গড়ে তোলার লক্ষ্যমাত্রা স্থির করা হয়েছে। আধুনিক বিশ্বব্যবস্থার সঙ্গে তাল মিলিয়ে চলার জন্য এটি নিঃসন্দেহে একটি সময়োচিত পদক্ষেপ। তবে এ বিষয়ে স্বপ্ন দেখা যতটা সহজ তাকে বাস্তব রূপ প্রদান করা ততটাই কঠিন । একটি দেশকে তখনই ডিজিটাল দেশ বলা যাবে যখন তা পরিপূর্ণভাবে ই-স্টেট-এ পরিণত হবে। অর্থাৎ ওই দেশের যাবতীয় কার্যাবলি, যেমন: সরকারব্যবস্থা, শাসনব্যবস্থা, ব্যবসা-বাণিজ্য, শিক্ষা ও চিকিৎসাব্যবস্থা ইত্যাদি তথ্যপ্রযুক্তির মাধ্যমে পরিচালিত হবে। ডিজিটাল বাংলাদেশ গড়ে তুলবে একটি আধুনিক জ্ঞানভিত্তিক সমাজব্যবস্থা। শাসনব্যবস্থার প্রতিটি ধাপে কম্পিউটার ও ইন্টারনেটের ব্যবহার নিশ্চিত করা হবে। সুতরাং, ডিজিটাল বাংলাদেশ গড়ার মূলভিত্তি হলো তথ্যপ্রযুক্তির শক্তিশালী কাঠামো। বাংলাদেশ ধীরে ধীরে এই লক্ষ্য বাস্তবায়নে অগ্রসর হচ্ছে। তবে এখনো অনেকগুলো গুরুত্বপূর্ণ বিষয়ে আমরা কাঙ্ক্ষিত অগ্রগতি লাভ করতে পারিনি। সমগ্র দেশের বিদ্যুতের ব্যবস্থা এখনো নিরবচ্ছিন্ন করা যায়নি। তথ্যপ্রযুক্তির সঙ্গে সংশ্লিষ্ট বিষয়গুলো এখনো সাধারণ মানুষের নাগালের বাইরে রয়ে গেছে। তথ্যপ্রযুক্তিকে উত্তমরূপে করায়ত্ত করার জন্য ইংরেজি ভাষায় দখল থাকা একান্ত জরুরি। এ বিষয়েও আমাদের দুর্বলতা রয়েছে। আশার কথা হলো, বাংলাদেশে তথ্যপ্রযুক্তির উন্নয়ন বেশ দ্রুত ঘটছে। জীবনের নানা প্রয়োজনীয় কাজে আমরা ধীরে ধীরে প্রযুক্তিনির্ভর হয়ে পড়েছি। এই ধারাবাহিকতা বজায় থাকলেই আমাদের ডিজিটাল বাংলাদেশ গড়ার স্বপ্ন বাস্তবে রূপ লাভ করবে।"},{"question":"Mycobaterium leprae නමැති බැක්ටීරියාව මඟින් බෝවන රෝගය","answer":"ලාදුරු"},{"question":"Madaxa Lalbaad: Xuquuqda, Xorriyaadka Aasaasiga Ah Ee Qofka Iyo Xaddidaadooda.Qodobka 20aad. Xorriyadda Kulanka, Bannaanbaxa, Cabashada iyo Codsi-wadareedka.","answer":"Qodobka 17aad. Xorriyadda Diinta iyo Caqiiddada. Qodobka 20aad. Xorriyadda Kulanka, Bannaanbaxa, Cabashada iyo Codsi-wadareedka.(1) Qof kastaa wuxuu xaq u leeyahay in uu abaabulo, kana qaybglo kulammo ama bannaabax oo si xasilooni ah cabasho loogu muujinayo, iyada oo aan oggolaansho loo bahnayn. (2) Qof kastaa wuxuu xaq u leeyahay inuu cabasho qoraal ah u gudbiyo hay'adaha Dawladda."},{"question":"Waxaad  Sheegtaa wadamada Carabta asal ahaan maxay Lacag u Isticmaali Jireen?","answer":" Wadamada Carabta Waxay Isticmaali Jireen Lacagta Roomaaniyiinta."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਪਉੜੀ ॥ਯਯਾ ਜਾਰਉ ਦੁਰਮਤਿ ਦੋਊ ॥ਤਿਸਹਿ ਤਿਆਗਿ ਸੁਖ ਸਹਜੇ ਸੋਊ ॥ਯਯਾ ਜਾਇ ਪਰਹੁ ਸੰਤ ਸਰਨਾ ॥ਜਿਹ ਆਸਰ ਇਆ ਭਵਜਲੁ ਤਰਨਾ ॥ਯਯਾ ਜਨਮਿ ਨ ਆਵੈ ਸੋਊ ॥ ਏਕ ਨਾਮ ਲੇ ਮਨਹਿ ਪਰੋਊ ॥ਯਯਾ ਜਨਮੁ ਨ ਹਾਰੀਐ ਗੁਰ ਪੂਰੇ ਕੀ ਟੇਕ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਤਿਹ ਸੁਖੁ ਪਾਇਆ ਜਾ ਕੈ ਹੀਅਰੈ ਏਕ ॥੧੪॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 253 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ!) ਭੈੜੀ ਮਤ ਤੇ ਮਾਇਆ ਦਾ ਪਿਆਰ ਸਾੜ ਦਿਉ, ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਤਿਆਗਿਆਂ ਹੀ ਸੁਖ ਵਿਚ ਅਡੋਲ ਅਵਸਥਾ ਵਿਚ ਟਿਕੇ ਰਹੋਗੇ । ਜਾ ਕੇ ਸੰਤਾਂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨੀ ਪਵੋ,ਇਸੇ ਆਸਰੇ ਇਸ ਸੰਸਾਰ-ਸਮੁੰਦਰ ਵਿਚੋਂ (ਸਹੀ ਸਲਾਮਤ) ਪਾਰ ਲੰਘ ਸਕੀਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਜੇਹੜਾ ਬੰਦਾ ਇਕ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਲੈ ਕੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਪ੍ਰੋ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਮੁੜ ਮੁੜ ਜਨਮ ਵਿਚ ਨਹੀਂ ਆਉਂਦਾ ।ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ! ਪੂਰੇ ਗੁਰੂ ਦਾ ਆਸਰਾ ਲਿਆਂ ਮਨੁੱਖਾ ਜਨਮ ਵਿਅਰਥ ਨਹੀਂ ਜਾਂਦਾ । ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੇ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਇਕ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਵੱਸ ਪਿਆ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਨੇ ਆਤਮਕ ਆਨੰਦ ਹਾਸਲ ਕਰ ਲਿਆ ਹੈ ।੧੪।\\""},{"question":" Sheeg Isbitaalkii Ugu Horeeyey Ee Somaliya Ku Yaala Oo Wiish Lagu Kari Jiray?","answer":"Wuxu Ahaa Isbitaalka Digfeer"},{"question":"من هو صاحب الهجرات الثلاث؟\\t","answer":"أبو موسى الأشعري رضي الله عنه."},{"question":"İki savaş arası dönemde(1918-1939) hangi Avrupa ülkesi, kim tarafından, krallıkla fakat kralsız yönetilmiştir?","answer":"I. Dünya Savaşı'ndan sonra Avusturya-Macaristan İmparatorluğu'nun dağılması ile ortaya çıkan Macaristan Krallığı, Naib Miklós Horthy de Nagybánya tarafından iki savaş arası dönemde ve ülkenin Nazi Almanya'sı tarafından 1944'te işgaline kadar yönetilmiştir. Dünya Harbi sonunda imzalanan barış antlaşmalarından ötürü Habsburg Hanedanından bir varisin Macaristan tahtına dönmesi engellenmiştir ve Macaristan Parlamento'su Mart 1920'de Naib olarak Horthy'i seçmiştir."},{"question":"ጥያቄ፦ የትኛው የአሜሪካ ግዛት ነው ትልቁ (በአካባቢ)? መልስ፦ ","answer":"አላስካ"},{"question":"Кичинеңизде асманда самалёт учуп баратса жердеги балдардын абалы кандай болгон?","answer":"Абдан кубанчубуз колубузду жайып🧍самалётко окшош анан дагы чуркап ырдачу элек.Самалёт самалёт ✈️Кайда учуп барасыңЧөнтөгүңө салат кетКапитандын баласын. Балалык доор кайра кайтып келсе."},{"question":"බොහෝ අය මයික්‍රොසොෆ්ට් මෘදුකාංග භාවිතා  කරන්නේ ඇයි?","answer":"භාවිතයේ පහසුව, ප්‍රවේශ්‍යතාව, අන්තර්ක්‍රියාකාරීත්වය සහ බොහෝමයක් මෙහෙයුම් පද්ධති සඳහා අනුවර්තනය වීමේ හැකියාව නිසා මයික්‍රොසොෆ්ට් මෘදුකාංග වැඩසටහන් ලොව පුරා බහුලව භාවිතා වන මෙවලම් බවට පත් වී ඇත. සංගණනයන්ට අනුව, මයික්‍රොසොෆ්ට් ඔෆිස් නිෂ්පාදන භාවිතා කරන්නන් බිලියන 1.2 කට වඩා සිටින බව අනාවරණය කරගෙන ඇත."},{"question":"පෘථිවියට ආසන්නතම ග්‍රහලෝකය නම් කරන්න?","answer":"පෘථිවියට ආසන්නතම ග්‍රහලෝකය බුධ (Mercury) ය."},{"question":"வினா எத்தனை  வகைப்படும் ?  விடை எத்தனை  வகைப்படும் ?  அவற்றைச் சுட்டுக.","answer":"வினா 6  வகைப்படும் . அவை1 .  அறிவினா  2.  அறியா வினா3. ஐய வினா 4.  கொளல் வினா5 . கொடை வினா 6.  ஏவல் வினாவிடை எட்டு வகைப்படும் . அவை1 . சுட்டு விடை 2 . மறை விடை3 .நேர் விடை  4. ஏவல் விடை5. வினா எதிர் வினாதல் விடை6. உற்றது உரைத்தல் விடை7. உறுவது கூறல் விடை 8 . இனமொழி.  "},{"question":"س187- من هو الإمبراطور الذي قام ببناء سور الصين العظيم ؟","answer":"ج187- هوانغ تي"},{"question":"Qual é a capital dos Emirados Árabes Unidos?","answer":"Abu Dabi (ou Abu Dhabi)."},{"question":"Iza no tanàna renivohitry ny Fanjakana Romanina Tandrefana mandra-paharavany tamin’ny 476 aorinan'i Jesosy Kristia?","answer":" I Roma no renivohitry ny Fanjakana Romanina Tandrefana hatramin’ny nianjerany tamin’ny 476 aorinan'i Jesosy Kristia."},{"question":"دست زیرآب کرال سینه چه مراحلی دارد؟","answer":"در دست کرال سینه، مرحله گرفتن آب که پس از ورود دست انجام می‌شود. دراین مرحله دست شما شروع به خم شدن می‌کند و کف دست به سمت پایین کشیده می‌شود درحالی که آرنج شما خم شده و بالا باقی مانذه است ،دراین مرحله بدن شما چرخیده است به گونه‌ای که یک طرف کشش اندکی به سمت پایین وطرف دیگر اندکی به سمت بالاقراردارد، این مرحله از تکنیک شبیه یک سرخوردن قدرتی است که سرعت شما را حفظ می‌کند و آن را افزایش نمی‌دهد مرحله بعد مرحله کشش است، در مرحله کشش سرعت افزایش پیدا می‌کند، اکثر شناگران کشش را در یک مسیرمنحنی شکل انجام می‌دهند، کشش داخلی دست آنها از خط شانه به داخل خط خارجی بدنشان می‌باشد و سپس دوباره به سمت خارج و درحالی که شست‌های آنها به لگن و یا ران آنها برخورد میکند ازآب خارج می شود، شناگران دیگر معتقدند که احساس کشیدن آب در مسیر مستقیم به سمت عقب موثرتر می‌باشد، اگرچه چرخش بدن آنها به نحوی است که در واقع آب را در مسیر مستقیم به عقب نمی کشند. منبع: کتاب تکنیک بهتر، شنای سریع‌تر"},{"question":"Iru ki waa leleyii, ileetura ni Teslim wa tawọn adigunjale fi yinbọn pa a n’Ibadan","answer":"Awọn adigunjale tun da kun ipenija eto aabo ti ipinlẹ Ọyọ n koju lọwọ bayii pẹlu bi wọn ṣe yinbọn pa ọkunrin alafẹ igboro Ibadan kan to n jẹ Teslim Akinpẹlu.Ileetura kan ti wọn n pe ni Town Hotel, laduugbo Iyaganku, n’Ibadan, lawọn adigunjale ẹlẹni mẹrin ọhun ti fibọn ja awọn eeyan lole owo ati dukia wọn mi-in lọjọ Àbámẹ́ta, Satide, to kọja.Otẹẹli yìí ni Teslim atawọn ọrẹ ẹ ti lọọ ṣe faaji to fi ba iku ojiji pade ni nnkan bíi aago mẹwaa alẹ ọjọ naa.Awọn adigunjale yii ti n fi otẹẹli ọhún silẹ ki Teslim toun naa fẹẹ kuro nileetu náà lati maa pada sile ẹ ni nnkan bíi aago mẹwaa alẹ too pade wọn. Gẹgẹ b’ALAROYE ṣe gbọ, ọkunrin alafẹ yii ko mọ pe awọn adigunjale náà ṣì wa nitosi. Nibi to ti n ba ẹnikan sọrọ lọwọ lori ẹrọ ibanisọrọ lawọn jagunlabi ti yinbọn fun un.Agbẹnusọ fun ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Ọyọ CSP Olugbenga Fadeyi, fidi ẹ mulẹ pe. O ni, “Awọn òṣìkà eeyan yii dibọn bíi ẹni to fẹẹ gba yara ninu iteetura naa titi ti wọn fi wọle sí awọn alejo to gba yara nileetura naa lara ni.O ni yara ti wọn n ṣe oku lọ́jọ̀ sí nileewosan kan nigboro Ibadan ni wọn gbe oloogbe naa lọ ko too di pe wọn sinkú ẹ̀ nilana Musulumi."},{"question":"Tambaya: Yaya ake yin kaffarar rantsuwa?","answer":"Amsa: da farko ya kamata mu sani cewa rantsuwa ya rabu kashi uku. Akwai wanda ake masa kaffara, akwai kuma wanda ba’ayi masa komai."},{"question":"Amir ________kesakitan apabila doktor mencuci lukanya.","answer":"Mengerang"},{"question":"ക്യൂബയുടെ തലസ്ഥാനം ഏതാണ്?","answer":"ക്യൂബയുടെ തലസ്ഥാനവും പ്രധാന തുറമുഖവുമാണ് ഹവാന. വെസ്റ്റ് ഇൻഡീസിലെ ഏറ്റവും വലിയ നഗരമാണിത്. "},{"question":"O maa ṣe o! Olori oṣiṣẹ lọfiisi gomina Kwara ti ku o","answer":"Iroyin kan to tẹ wa lọwọ sọ pe Alhaji Aminu Logun ti i ṣe olori awọn oṣiṣẹ lọfiisi gomina ipinlẹ Kwara ti jade laye.Ileewosan kan niluu Ilọrin ni wọn lọkunrin naa ku si lonii, ọjọ Iṣẹgun, Tusidee.Ohun ta a gbọ ni pe o ṣee ṣe ko jẹ arun Korona lo pa a."},{"question":"Iléeṣẹ́ reluwé Nàìjíríà jáwe lọ rọọ́kún nílé fún àwọn òṣìṣẹ́ tó gba owó lọ́wọ́ èrò ọkọ̀ dípò tíkẹ́ẹ̀tì","answer":"Ileeṣẹ to n ri irinna ọkọ oju irin ni Naijiria, NRC, ti jawe lọ rọokun nile fun awọn oṣiṣẹ rẹ kan ti wọn gba owo lọwọ ero ọkọ oju irin kan lati ilu Ibadan si Eko, kaka ki wọn fun ta tikẹẹti ijọba fun wọn.Ṣaaju ni fidio idunadura laarin awọn oṣiṣẹ NRC naa atawọn ero ọkọ ti ọrọ kan ti kọkọ gbode lori ikanni X, lẹyin ti ọkunrin kan ti iṣẹlẹ naa ṣoju rẹ sọrọ soke.Lẹyin ti fidio aṣemaṣe awọn oṣiṣẹ naa fa oju opo X ya ni ileeṣẹ ọhun ṣeleri lati da seria fun awọn oṣiṣẹ rẹ to ṣe aṣemaṣe.Ninu atẹjade kan ti igbakeji agbẹnusọ NRC, Yakub Mahmood, fi lede lo ti kede pe ki awọn oṣiṣẹ ti ọrọ naa kan lọ rọọkun nile fun igba diẹ titi ti iwadii awọn lori ọhun to ṣẹlẹ yoo fi pari.Mahmood ni “A fẹ ki gbogbo araalu mọ pe ileeṣẹ NRC koro oju si iwa aibọwọ fun ofin ati alakalẹ ti awọn oṣiṣẹ naa wu, paapaa lasiko yii ti ijọba apapọ n tiraka lati tun ileeṣẹ naa ṣe.”“Iwa ti wọn wu ba wa ninu jẹ, ko bojumu bẹẹ ni ko ṣe itẹwọgba nitori o lodi si alakalẹ ileeṣẹ wa.”“Nitori naa, ileeṣẹ wa ti jawe lọ rọọkun nile fun awọn oṣiṣẹ ti oje ọrọ naa ṣi mọ lori titi ti esi iwadii to n lọ lọwọ yoo fi jade.”“A fẹ fi da awọn onibara wa ati gbogbo araalu loju pe a ko fi ọwọ yẹpẹrẹ mu ọrọ yii, ati pe eyikeyi oṣiṣẹ wa to ba mu ẹrẹ ba orukọ ileeṣẹ wa ko ni lọ lai jiya to tọ.”NRC sọ siwaju si pe gbogbo awọn to lọwọ ninu ibajẹ naa ni awọn yoo fi imu wọn danrin.Lẹyin naa lo ke si awọn araalu lati maṣe fun ẹnikẹni ni owo ọkọ oju irin, kaka bẹẹ, ki wọn maa bere tikẹẹti lọwọ awọn oṣiṣẹ awọn.Mahmood fi kun pe awọn eeyan yoo le maa ra tikẹẹti naa funra wo lori ayelujara titi opin oṣu Kẹwaa, ọdun 2023 yii."},{"question":"1996 ලෝක කුසලාන ක්‍රිකට් තරඟාවලිය පැවති ක්‍රීඩාංගනය ?","answer":"ලාහෝරයේ ගඩාෆි ක්‍රීඩාංගනය"},{"question":"Berikut adalah isu sosioekonomi yang dihadapi semasa DEB dilancarkan.\\"Jurang sosioekonomi antara bumiputera dengan bukanbumiputera\\"Jelaskan usaha kerajaan mengatasi isu tersebut.","answer":"Skema jawapan:F1 Menggalakan Pemilikan Modal SahamH1a Menambah pemilikan modal saham bumiputeraH1b Dalam sektor korporatH1c Penubuhan Pemodalan Nasional Berhad (PNB)H1d Melancarkan Amanah Saham Nasional (ASN)H1e Melancarkan Amanah Saham Bumiputera (ASB)H1f Pengenalan Amanah Saham Malaysia untuk bukan bumiputeraF2 Pengenalan Industri kecil dan sederhana (IKS)H2a Menggalakkan pembuatan baranganH2b Menggunakan modal yang kecilH2c Mengusahakan industri desaH2d Meningkatkan kelahiran usahawan baharuC2a Best Farm Co. / Nurul Food Industri Enterprise / Ramly FoodProcessing Sdn. BhdF3 Membaiki taraf hidup rakyatH3a Menambah daya pengeluaranH3b Mendapat bantuan daripada bank tempatan / pinjaman / khidmatnasihatC3 Bank Bumiputera / Bank Pertanian / Agro Bank / Amanah IkhtiarMalaysiaH3c Membawa kemunculan usahawan mudaF4 Membuka Pendidikan tenaga kerja mahirH4a Bagi menampung bidang pertanian / perindustrianH4b Diperkenalkan matapelajaran Kemahiran HidupH4c Dimulakan jurusan vokasionalH4d Dibuka pelbagai institusi teknik dan vokasionalC4 Maktab Perguruan Teknik / Politeknik / UTM / Universiti Teknologi MaraH4e Ditawarkan pelbagai kursus kemahiranH4f Memenuhi permintaan pasaran pekerja mahir"},{"question":"Liste 3 músicas populares do Fall Out Boy.","answer":"\\"Sugar, We're Goin Down\\", \\"Thnks fr th Mmrs\\", \\"Centuries\\"."},{"question":"வினா:                  ஆய கலைகள்  பற்றி விரிவாக எழுதுக?.  ","answer":"  விடை:                                                                                                                                                                                   1. சிற்பம் கல்லைக் குடைந்து செதுக்கியும் கோயில் கலையை வளர்த்த பல்லவர்கள் சிற்பக்கலையையும் வளர்த்தார்கள்மகேந்திரவர்மன் காலந்தொட்டே சிற்பக்கலை வளர்ந்து வருகிறதுபல்லவர் காலத்தில் கோயில் சிற்பங்கள், திறந்தவெளி சிற்பங்கள் எனவும் புடைப்புச் சிற்பங்கள், தனிச்சிலைகள் எனவும் வளர்ந்தனமண்டகப்பாட்டு, திருச்சிச் சிவன் கோயில், தளவானூர், சீயமங்கலம், மாமல்லாபுரம், காஞ்சி கைலாசநாதர் கோயில், வைகுந்த பெருமாள் கோயில் போன்ற இடங்களில் பல்லவர்காலச் சிற்பங்கள் உள்ளனசோழர் காலச் சிற்பங்கள் தனிச் சிறப்புடையன. அதனால் உலகெங்கும் உள்ள பொருட்காட்சிகளில் இடம் பெற்றுள்ளனசைவம் , வைணவம், சமணம், பௌத்தம், சிறுதெய்வ வழிபாடு என அனைத்துச் சமய தெய்வங்களுக்கும் சோழர் காலத்தில் சிற்பங்கள் வடிக்கப்பட்டனகி.பி.7ஆம் நூற்றாண்டு முதல் 13 நூற்றாண்டு வரை சோழர்கள் சிறந்த ஆட்சி செய்தனர். இவர்கள் காலத்தில் சிற்பக்கலையும் வளர்ந்ததுகும்பகோணம், தக்கோலம், தஞ்சாவூர், கங்கை கொண்ட சோழபுரம், தாராசுரம் போன்ற இடங்களில் சோழர் காலச் சிற்பங்கள் உள்ளனதொடக்கத்தில் கோயில் கட்டுவதற்கு முதன்மை கொடுத்த சோழர்கள், பின் சிற்பங்களுக்கு முதன்மை கொடுத்தனர்சிற்பங்களின் ஆடை ஆபரணங்கள் அளவாக இருந்தது பொய் மிகை அலங்காரச் சிற்பங்கள் தோன்றினமூன்று பக்கங்களிலும் புடைப்பு மிகுதியாக இருக்கும்இலக்கியம், சமயம் சார்ந்த சிற்பங்கள் மிகுதியாகச் செதுக்கப்பட்டனகோயில் கட்டுவதில் மிகுத்த ஆர்வம் காட்டாத நாயக்கர்கள் சிற்பக்கலையில் மிகுந்த ஈடுபாடு கொண்டார்கள்மீனாட்சி அம்மன் கோயில் ஆயிரங்கால் மண்டபம், பேரூர்பட்டிப் பெருமாள் கோயிலின் கனகசபை, இராமேஸ்வரம் தூண்சிற்பங்கள் போன்ற இடங்களில் நாயக்கர் காலச் சிற்பங்கள் உள்ளனபல்லவர் காலச் சிற்பத்திற்கு சிறந்த எடுத்துக்காட்டாக விளங்குவது மாமல்லபுரத்தில் உள்ள ஒற்றைப்பாறைச் சிற்பம் உலகப் புகழ் பெற்றதாகும்கட்டடக் களையும் சிற்பக்கலையும் கொழிக்கும் ஊர் கும்பகோணம்அரிசிலாற்றின் தென்கரையில் தாராசுரம் என்னும் ஊர் அமைந்துள்ளது.2.ஓவியக்கலைஓவியம்:எல்லைகளையெல்லாம் கடந்து எங்கும் பரந்து வாழும் மக்கள் மனங்களைக் கொள்ளை கொண்டு வியக்க வைக்கும் விந்தை மொழி ஓவியம்.காண்பவரைக் கவர்ந்திழுத்து உள்ளங்களைத் தன்வயப்படுத்தும் உயர்ந்த கலை ஓவியக்கலை.கோட்டோவியங்கள்:சுமார் 2000 ஆண்டுகளுக்கு முன்னர் இருந்த மக்கள் மலைக்குகைகளிலும் பாறைகளிலும் கோட்டோவியங்கள் வரைந்தனர்.தமிழகத்தில் 25க்கும் மேற்பட்ட இடங்களில் (மான், போர் செய்தல், விலங்கு வேட்டை ஆகியவற்றை குறிக்கும்) குகை ஓவியங்கள் கண்டுபிடிக்கப் பட்டுள்ளன.கண்ணெழுத்து:தமிழ் நாட்டில் சங்க காலத்திற்கு முன்னரே ஓவியங்கள் வரையப்பட்டன.தாம் வரைந்த ஓவியங்களை முதலில் \\"கண்ணெழுத்து\\" என்றே வழங்கினர்.எழுத்து:எழுத்து என்பதற்கு ஓவியம் என்றும் பொருள் உண்டு என பரிபாடலும், குறுந்தொகையும் கூறுகின்றன.கோட்டோவியங்கள்:ஓவியம் வரைவதற்கு நேர்கோடு, கோணக்கோடு, வளைகோடு முதலியன அடிப்படை.இவ்வாறு வரையப்படுபவை \\"கோட்டோவியங்கள்\\" எனப்படும்.நடுகல் வணக்கம்:தொல்காப்பியம் நடு கல் வணக்கம் பற்றிக் கூறுகிறது.நடுகல்லில் போரில் வீரமரணம் எய்திய வீரனது உருவம், பெயர், பெருமைக்குரிய செயல் முதலியவற்றைப் பொரிக்கும் பழக்கம் இருந்தது.ஓவியக்கலையின் வேறுபெயர்கள்:ஓவியம்சித்திரம்படம்படாம்ஓவியக் கலைஞனின் வேறு பெயர்கள்:ஓவியர்ஓவியப்புலவன்கண்ணுள் வினைஞன்சித்திரகாரர்வித்தக வினைஞன்வித்தகர்கிளவி வல்லோன்நச்சினார்கினியர் இலக்கணம்:நச்சினார்க்கினியர் தம் உரையில் ஓவியருக்கு, \\"நோக்கினார் கண்ணிடத்தே தம் தொழில் நிறுத்துவோர்\\" என இலக்கணம் வகுத்துள்ளார்.ஓவியக் குழுக்கள்:ஓவிய கலைஞர் குழுவை \\"ஓவிய மாக்கள்\\" என்று அழைத்தனர்.ஆண் ஓவியர் = சித்திராங்கதன்பெண் ஓவியர் = சித்திரசேனாசிலப்பதிகாரம்:ஆடல் மகள் மாதவி, \\"ஓவியச் செந்நூல் உரை நூற்கிடக்கையும் கற்றுத்துறை போகப் பொற்கொடி மடந்தையாக இருந்தனள்\\" எனச் சிலம்பு பகிர்கிறது.வரைகருவிகள்:வண்ணம் தீட்டும் கோல் தூரிகை, துகிலிகை, வட்டிகை எனப்பட்டது.வண்ணங்கள் குழப்பும் பலகைக்கு \\"வட்டிகைப் பலகை\\" எனப் பெயர்.வரைவிடங்கள்:ஓவியம் வரையப்பட்ட இடங்கள் = சித்திரக்கூடம், சித்திரமாடம், எழுதுநிலை மண்டபம், எழுதொளில் அம்பலம்இறை நடனம் புரிவதற்கே \\"சித்திர சபை\\" ஒன்றை ஏற்படுத்தி உள்ளனர்.புறநானூறு:\\"ஓவத்தனைய இடனுடை வனப்பு\\" - புறநானூறுஇவ்வாறு வீட்டின் அழகை ஓவியத்திற்கு ஒப்ப வைத்துக் கவிஞர் போற்றுகிறார்.ஓவிய எழினி:நாடகமேடைகளில் பல வண்ணங்களில் கவின்மிகு காட்சிகள் தீட்டப்பட்ட திரைச்சீலைகள் தொங்குகினவற்றை \\"ஓவிய எழினி\\" கொண்டு அறிகிறோம்.புனையா ஓவியம்:வண்ணம் கலக்காமல் கரித்துண்டுகளால் வடிவம் மட்டும் வரைவதைப் புனையா ஓவியம் என்பர்.இன்றும், இது மென்கோட்டு ஓவியமாக நடைமுறையில் உள்ளது.நெடுநல்வாடை:ஆடு முதலான 12 இராசிகளையும், விண்மீன்களையும் வரைந்த செய்தி, நெடுநல்வாடை கூறுகிறது.தமிழரின் ஓவிய மரபு:ஓவியங்களில் \\"நிற்றல், இருத்தல், கிடத்தல்\\" ஆகிய மனித இயல்புகளையும்\\"வீரம், சாந்தம், சினம், வியப்பு, உவகை\\" ஆகிய மெய்ப்பாடுகளையும்\\"உத்தமம், மத்திமம், அதமம், தசதாளம், நவதாளம், பஞ்சதாளம் முதலிய அளவுகளையும் வலியுறுத்துவது தமிழருக்கே உரிய ஓவிய மரபுகளாக விளங்குகின்றன.மகேந்திரவர்மப் பல்லவன்:சங்கக் காலத்தில் செழித்திருந்த ஓவியக்கலை இடைக்காலத்தில் சிதைந்து மறைந்துபோகத் தொடங்கியது.மறைந்து கொண்டிருந்த ஓவியக்கலைக்கு மீண்டும் புத்துயிர் ஊட்டியவர்கள் பல்லவர்கள்.7ஆம் நூற்றாண்டில் தமிழகத்தை ஆண்ட முதலாம் மகேந்திரவர்மப் பல்லவன் சிறந்த ஓவியன்.கல்வெட்டுகள் இவனைச் \\"சித்திரகாரப்புலி\\" எனப் புகழ்கின்றன.\\"தட்சிணசித்திரம்\\" என்னும் ஓவிய நூலுக்கு இம்மன்னன் உரை எழுதியுள்ளான்.சித்தன்னவாசல் – ஓவியக் கருவூலம்:திருநந்திக்கரையில் சேரர் கால ஓவியங்கள் கிடைத்துள்ளன.புதுக்கோட்டைக்கு அருகே சித்தன்னவாசல் என்னும் குகைக்கோவில் ஓவியங்கள் ஓவியக் கருவூலமாக வைத்து போற்ற தக்கது.கி.பி.9ஆம் நூற்றாண்டில் \\"அவனிப சேகர ஸ்ரீவல்லபன்\\" என்ற பாண்டிய மன்னன் காலத்தில், மதுரை ஆசிரியர் \\"இளம்கௌதமன்\\" இவ்வோவியங்களை வரைந்தார் என கல்வெட்டுகள் கூறுகிறது.சோழர் கால ஓவியங்கள்:சோழர்கால வனப்புமிக்க ஓவியங்களைத் தஞ்சைப் பெரியகோவிலில் காணலாம்.அதில் கவின்மிகு கயிலைகாட்சி உள்ளது.3.பேச்சுக்கலைபேச்சுக்கலை:நுண்ணிய நூல்பல கற்றவற்கே அமையத்தக்க அரியதொரு கலையே பேச்சுக்கலை.மேடைப்பேச்சில் நல்ல தமிழ்:மேடைப்பேச்சில் நல்ல தமிழை கொண்டு மக்களை ஈர்த்தவர்கள் திரு.வி.க, அண்ணா, ரா.பி.சேதுபிள்ளை, நாவலர் சோமசுந்தர பாரதியார், குன்றக்குடி அடிகளார்.பேச்சும் மேடைப்பேச்சும்:பேச்சில் உணர்ந்ததை உணர்ந்தவாறு தெரிவித்தால் போதுமானது; ஆனால், மேடைப்பேச்சிலோ உணர்ந்ததனை உணர்த்தும் வகையிலும் தெரிவித்தல் வேண்டும்.பேச்சில் கேட்கின்றவனைக் கேட்கின்றவனாகவே மதிக்கலாம். ஆனால், மேடைப்பேச்சிலோ கேட்கின்றவனை மதிப்பிடுவோனாக மதித்தல் வேண்டும்.பேச்சுக்கலையில் மொழியும் முறையும்:மேடைப்பேச்சுக்கு கருத்துகளே உயிர்நாடி என்றாலும், அக்கருத்துக்களை வெளியிடும் மொழியும் முறையும் இன்றியமையா இடத்தைப் பெறுகின்றன.கருத்தைக் விளக்க மொழி கருவியாக உள்ளது.முக்கூறுகள்:பேசும் பொருளை ஒழுங்குமுறைக்குக் கட்டுப்படுத்திக் தொடக்கம், இடைப்பகுதி, முடிவு எனப் பகுத்துக் பேசுவதையே பேச்சுமுறை என்கிறோம்.இதனை எடுத்தல், தொடுதல், முடிதல் எனவும் கூறலாம்.எடுத்தல்:பேச்சை தொடங்குவது எடுப்பு.தொடக்கம் நன்றாக இராவிட்டால் கேட்பவர்களுக்குப் பேச்சினை குறித்த நல்லெண்ணம் தோன்றாது.சுருக்கமான முன்னுரையுடன் தொடங்க வேண்டும்.தொடுத்தல்:தொடக்கவுரைக்குப் பிறகு, பொருளை விரித்துப் பேசும் முறை தொடுத்தல் எனப்படும்.இடையிடையே சுவைமிக்க சொற்களும் குணமிக்க கருத்துகளும் பிணைத்துப் பேசுவதே தொடுத்தல் எனப்படும்.பேச்சின் அணிகலன்:எண்ணங்களைச் சொல்லும் முறையால் அழகு படுத்துவதே அணி எனப்படும்.கேட்போர் சுவைக்கத்தக்க உவமைகள், எடுத்துக்காட்டுகள், சொல்லாட்சிகள், பல்வேறு நடைகள், சிறுசிறு கதைகள் முதலியன அமையப் பேசுவதே சிறந்த பேச்சாகும்.உணர்த்தும் திறன்:உணர்ச்சி உள்ள பேச்சே உயிருள்ள பேச்சாகும்.பேச்சாளர், தாம் உணர்ச்சிவயப்படாது, கேட்போரின் உள்ளத்தில் தாம் விரும்பும் உணர்ச்சியை ஏற்படுத்தும் வகையில் பேசுதல் வேண்டும்.முடித்தல்:பேச்சை முடிக்கும்போது தான், பேச்சாளர் தமது கருத்தை வற்புறுத்தவும் கேட்போர் மனதில் பதியுமாறு சுருக்கிக் கூறவும் கூடும்.பேச்சின் சுருக்கத்தைக் கூறி முடித்தல், உணர்ச்சியைத் தூண்டும் முறையில் முடித்தல், பாராட்டி முடித்தல், பொருத்தமான கவிதையைக் கூறி முடிதல் என முடிக்கும் முறைகள் பல உள்ளன.4.திரைப்படக்கலைதிரைப்படத்தின் சிறப்பு:உலகில் பல்வேறு மொழிகள் இருப்பினும், மக்கள் அனைவரும் எளிதில் புரிந்துக்கொள்ளும் உலகமொழி திரைப்படம்.அது உதடுகளால் பேசும் மொழியன்று; உள்ளத்தால் பேசி, உணர்ச்சிகளால் உருவாகும் மொழி.திரைப்படத்தின் வரலாறு:ஒளிப்படம் எடுக்கும் முறையை 1830ஆம் ஆண்டு கண்டுப்பிடித்த பின்னர், எட்வர்ட் மைபிரிட்சு என்ற ஆங்கிலேயர் முதலில் ஓடும் குதிரையை இயக்கப்படமாக எடுத்து வெற்றிபெற்றார்.ஈஸ்ட்மன் என்பார் படச்சுருள் உருவாக்கும் முறையைக் கண்டுபிடித்தார்.எடிசன், ஒருவர் மட்டும் பார்க்கும் படக்கருவியைக் கண்டுபிடித்தார்.பிரான்சிஸ் சென்கின்சு என்ற அமெரிக்கர் 1894இல் ரிச்மண்ட் என்னுமிடத்தில் இயக்கப்படத்தைப் பலரும் பார்க்கும் வகையில் வடிவமைத்தார். புதிய படவீழ்த்திகள் உருவாக, இவருடைய கருத்துகளே அடிப்படையாக அமைந்தன.திரைப்படம்:நடிப்பாற்றலை எடுத்துக்கூறிச் சில நேரங்களில் தாமே நடித்தும், காட்சிகள் அமைத்தும் படம் முடியும்வரை உழைக்கும் நுண்மாண் நுழைபுலம் உடையாரை இயக்குனர் என்பர்.கதைப்படங்கள் மட்டுமின்றிக் கருத்துப்படங்கள், செய்திப்படங்கள், விளக்கப்படங்கள், கல்விப்படங்கள் எனப் பல வளர்ச்சி நிலைகளைத் திரைப்படத்துறை அடைந்துள்ளது.திரைப்படச்சுருள்:திரைப்படம் எடுக்கப் பயன்படும் படச்சுருள் செல்லுலாய்டு என்னும் பொருளால் ஆனது.படம் எடுக்கப் பயன்படும் சுருள், எதிர்ச்சுருள் எனப்படும்.படம்பிடிக்கும் கருவி:இது ஒளிப்பதிவு செய்யப் பயன்படுகிறது.படப்பிடிப்புக்கருவியில் ஓரடி நீளமுள்ள படச்சுருள் 16 படங்கள் வீதம் ஒன்றன்பின்ஒன்றாகத் தொடர்ச்சியாக எடுக்கப்படும்.ஒலிப்பதிவு:நடிகர்களின் நடிப்பையும், பாடும் பாடல்களையும் உரையாடல்களையும் ஒலிப்பதிவு செய்வர்.திரைப்படக்காட்சிப் பதிவு:ஒளிஒலிப்படக்கருவி என்னும் கருவி திரையரங்குகளில் திரைப்படம் காட்டப்பயன்படுகிறது.இக்கருவியில் மேற்பக்கம் ஒன்றும், அடிப்பக்கம் ஒன்றுமாக வட்டமான இரு பெட்டிகள் இருக்கும்."},{"question":"Biby mampinono an-dranomasina ve ny feso?","answer":"Eny, ny feso dia biby mampinono an-dranomasina izay mifoka rivotra ary miteraka zaza velona."},{"question":"भारतातील सर्वांत रुंद नदी कोणती आहे?(A) गोमती नदी(B) ब्रह्मपुत्र नदी(C) गंगा नदी(D) चंबल नदी=>","answer":"(B) ब्रह्मपुत्र नदी – ब्रह्मपुत्र ही भारतच नाही तर संपूर्ण आशिया खंडातील सर्वात रुंदनदी आहे, या नदीची रुंदी पावसाळ्यात 38 किमीपर्यंत जाते."},{"question":"உழைப்பே உயர்வு என்ற தலைப்பில் ஒரு கட்டுரை வரைக.","answer":"முன்னுரை:ஒருவரை வாழ்வில் உயர்த்துவது அவரது உழைப்பு தான். உழைப்பு தன்னையும் தன் நாட்டையும் உயர்த்தும். உழைப்பின் சிறப்பினைக் காண்போம்.உழைப்பின் பயன்:நாம் செய்யும் ஒவ்வொரு செயலையும் மிகுந்த ஈடுபாட்டுடன் செய்தால் மட்டுமே வாழ்வில் முன்னேற முடியும். இறைவனால் முடியாத காரியம் கூட உழைப்பாலும் முயற்சியாலும் செய்ய முடியும் என்கிறது திருக்குறள். உழைப்பால் உடலும் உள்ளமும் வலுப்பெறுகிறது.உழைப்பின் சிறப்பு:உழைப்பே உயர்வு தரும் என்பது பழமொழி. உழைப்பால் வரும் பொருளே என்றும் நிலைத்து நிற்கும். விலங்குகளும் பறவைகளும் தமக்குத் தேவையான உணவைத் தாமே உழைத்து தேடிப் பெற்றுக் கொள்கின்றன. உழைப்பில்லாமல் வரும் செல்வத்தை விட்டுவிட்டு உண்மையான உழைப்பால் வரும் செல்வத்தை நாம் அனுபவிக்க வேண்டும்உழைப்பால் உயர்ந்தவர்கள்:தாமஸ் ஆல்வா எடிசன், ஐன்ஸ்டின், ஜி.டி. நாயுடு, டாக்டர் அப்துல் கலாம் ஆகிய எண்ணற்ற அறிஞர்கள் தம்முடைய கடின உழைப்பால் வாழ்வில் முன்னேறி இருக்கிறார்கள் என்பதை அவர்களின் வாழ்க்கை வரலாறு நமக்கு உணர்த்துகிறது.முடிவுரை:உழைப்பின் உயர்வினை உணர்ந்து, நாம் அனைவரும் நல்வழியில் கடின உழைப்பு செய்து வாழ்வில் முன்னேற வேண்டும்."},{"question":"வினா: சுங்கம் தவிர்த்த சோழன் என பெயர் பெற்ற மன்னன்?","answer":"விடை: முதலாம் குலோத்துங்க சோழன் "},{"question":"Qual metal foi descoberto por Hans Christian Oersted em 1825?","answer":"O metal descoberto em 1825 por Christian Oersted foi o alumínio."},{"question":"Ayat 1: Selepas kematiannya, janda Kellow Mary Hope Kellow berpindah ke Sydney dengan anak perempuannya Mary. Ayat 2: Selepas kematiann Kellow, Mary Hope Kellow dan anak perempuannya Mary berpindah ke Sydney. Soalan: Adakah ayat 1 dan ayat 2 menyatakan makna yang sama? Ya atau tidak?","answer":"Ya, betul."},{"question":"esezingithathele lowo msebenzi?(Ujabhile) Kanti-ke akumele neze uze uzihluphe ngalowo mcabangomkami. Iqiniso elisalayo nje lisekutheni izinsuku lezi zoMdalikazefani. Ngingaphuma lisabalele lapha ekhaya kepha ngibuyeselihosha umoya obandayo ohambisana namakhaza ashubisaumnkantsha. Kanjalo futhi singehlukana ekuseni ngihleka kukuhlekunjeyaya kodwa lishone sengikhala.Yingakho nje nencwadiyomShumayeli eBhayibhelini esahlukweni sesithathu ikubeka kucacelokhu engikushoyo ngaphansi kwesihloko esithi konke kunesikhathisakho lapha phansi komthunzi welanga.(Ubukeka esekhathazekile) Ngiphuthume baba. Ngabesekwenzenjani?1. Chaza kafushane ngamaphuzu AMATHATHU ukuthi indaba eyethulwanguManqina kuMaMlanduli kulesi siqeshana iyithuthukise kanjani indikimbayalo mdlalo.","answer":"Emuva kokuba uManqina echazele uMaMlanduli ngodaba lokudilizwaemsebenzini. UMdaluli ube eseba nodlame ekhaya nasemphakathini.UMdaluli uhlukumeza uMaMlanduli uyamshaya efuna indabandaba ngenkaniuxosha nezingane. UMdaluli uthakatha uChivenga, umlalela unyendleuyamshaya ngoba ecabanga ukuthi nguyena omthathele umsebenzi ngobaengowokufika"},{"question":"Diniho ity fanambarana manaraka ity: \\"Ireo mpiasan'ny fahasalamana ireo dia tsy mahay; tsy afaka manao ny asany izy ireo.\\" Misy resaka fankahalana ve ilay fanambarana?","answer":"Eny, ity fanambarana ity dia mampiroborobo ny teny fankahalàna amin'ny fanehoana tsy ara-drariny ny mpiasan'ny fahasalamana rehetra ho tsy mahay."},{"question":"في أي دولة تقع دار أوبرا سيدني؟","answer":"تقع في دولة استراليا."},{"question":"Ọkada okoolenirinwo (420) la gbẹsẹ le laarin ọsẹ kan l’Ekoo, a o si ni i sinmi – Jẹjẹloye","answer":"Bawọn ọlọkada to n tẹ ofin irinna ilu Eko loju ba lawọn o ni i gbọ, awọn agbofinro to n mu wọn naa ti lawọn ko ni i gba, wọn ni ṣinkun lawọn yoo maa fọwọ ofin mu wọn, tawọn yoo si maa gbẹsẹ le ọkada ati irinnṣẹ wọn, yatọ si pe awọn ọlọkada bẹẹ maa foju bale-ẹjọ.Igbimọ amuṣẹya tijọba gbe kalẹ lati maa ri iwa irufin awọn ọlọkada naa sọ pe laarin ọsẹ kan pere, ọkada okoolenirinwo (420) ni awọn gba nidii awọn to gun un tabi awọn to ni wọn, tawọn si gbẹsẹ le wọn, latari bawọn ọkada naa ṣe n rin awọn ọna tijọba ti ka leewọ fawọn ọlọkada.Ọga agba Lagos State Environmental and Special Offences Unit (Taskforce), CSP Ṣhọla Jẹjẹloye, sọ l’Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee, ọsẹ yii, pe lọjọ kan ṣoṣo pere, ọjọ kejilelogun, oṣu kẹsan-an yii, ọkada aadọfa lawọn mu, tawọn si gbẹsẹ le fun rirufin irinna tijọba ṣe, bẹẹ awọn ti mu eyi to ju ọọdunrun ọkada lọ lọjọ marun-un sẹyin.Jẹjẹloye ni eyi to pọ ju lọ ninu awọn ọkada naa lọwọ ba ni agbegbe Isọlọ, Ojodu si Berger, Ọjọta, Erekuṣu Eko, Surulere, Festac, Rainbow keji, ati titi marosẹ Sango si Oṣodi. O lo jẹ nnkan iyalẹnu pe bawọn ṣe n fi pampẹ ofin gbe awọn ọlọkada naa to, bẹẹ ni awọn arufin naa n kọti ikun si aṣẹ ijọba si i, ṣugbọn awọn o ni i kaaarẹ lati maa mu wọn.Ọga agba naa parọwa sawọn araalu lati jawọ ninu gigun awọn ọkada loju ọna tijọba ti ka leewọ fun wọn, o ni akoba ni ọpọ ero toju n kan maa n ṣe fawọn ọlọkada naa, awọn ni wọn si tubọ n ki wọn laya lati maa tasẹ agẹrẹ sofin ijọba.O ni anfaani araalu ni ofin tijọba ṣe wa fun, awọn o si ni i sinmi lati mu aṣẹ ijọba ṣẹ."},{"question":"¿Es Cloud Strife el protagonista de Final Fantasy 7?","answer":"Sí, Cloud Strife es el protagonista principal de Final Fantasy VII. Es un personaje icónico y uno de los más reconocidos en la serie de juegos de Final Fantasy. En el juego, Cloud es un ex-soldado de élite que se une al grupo de resistencia conocido como AVALANCHA para luchar contra la malévola corporación Shinra y su control sobre la energía Mako. A medida que avanza la trama, Cloud se convierte en un personaje central en la lucha contra el poderoso antagonista, Sephiroth, y juega un papel crucial en la historia del juego. Su diseño, personalidad y arco narrativo lo han convertido en un personaje querido por muchos fanáticos de la serie y de los videojuegos en general."},{"question":"أكمل العبارة التالية:  في نوفمبر 2009، أصبح دجيكو أول سفير يونيسيف بوسني. وقد زار عدة مدارس في المناطق الفقيرة من البوسنة والهرسك وساعد الأطفال الذين مروا بتجارب مؤلمة تتعلق بالحرب في البوسنة","answer":"وغيرها من الحالات."},{"question":"Slutför den här frasen: Strax därefter kom den hittills mest omfattande flyktingströmmen från Tjeckoslovakien i samband med Pragvåren och","answer":"Warszawapaktens invasion av Tjeckoslovakien 1968. Officiella svenska källor uppskattar antalet flyktingar till omkring 3 000."},{"question":"Ipa rondedzero ine mabara yezvinhu zvekufunga nezvazvo paunenge uchitenga imba","answer":"\\"Izvi zvinotevera zvinhu zvekufunga nezvazvo kana uchitenga imba:1. Nzvimbo2. Mutengo wekutenga uye mari yekubhadhara3. Floor Plan / Layout4. Dhizaini / Kupedzisa5. Nzvimbo yegaraji6. Nzvimbo yekuchengetera7. Munhu anoronga kugarako kwenguva yakareba sei8. Mitero yepfuma9. Mari yeinishuwarenzi10. Mari yekuchengetedza\\""},{"question":"Qual animal produz o som mais alto?a) Bugiob) Leãoc) Baleia azuld) Hienae) Elefante africano","answer":"Resposta correta: c) Baleia azul.O som produzido pela baleia azul alcança 188 decibéis e pode ser ouvido a uma distância de cerca de 800 km. O segundo animal mais barulhento é o primata bugio, com 130 decibéis"},{"question":"請回答這個問題：地球上最古老的醫學體系是哪一個？","answer":"答案：中國的中醫體系"},{"question":"ශ්‍රී ලංකාව වෙනුවෙන් පළමු 6 පහර එල්ල කළ ක්‍රීඩකයා  කවුරුන්ද?","answer":"ටෙස්ට් තරගයකදී ශ්‍රී ලංකාව වෙනුවෙන් පළමු හයේ පහර එල්ල කළ ක්‍රීඩකයා ලෙස රන්ජන් මඩුගල්ල පිළිගැනේ. ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සහ එංගලන්තය අතර කොළඹ පී සරවනමුත්තු ක්‍රීඩාංගණයේ පැවැති මංගල ටෙස්ට් තරගයේදී මෙය සිදුවිය. මෙම තරගයේදී මඩුගල්ල ශ්‍රී ලංකා පළමු ඉනිමේ ලකුණු 65ක ඉහළම ලකුණු සංඛ්‍යාවට දායක වූවා පමණක් නොව ශ්‍රී ලංකා ටෙස්ට් ක්‍රිකට් ඉතිහාසයේ පළමු හයේ පහරේ ගෞරවයද  ලබා ගත්තේය."},{"question":"Question: If the fish were birds, what would be the sea be?a. Forestb. Skyc. Nestd. IslandAnswer: ","answer":"Answer: (b)Fish lives in the sea. Birds live in the sky. Therefore, if ‘fish’ were ‘birds’ then, ‘sea’ would be ‘sky’."},{"question":"హో లో థురాయిడియా ప్రధాన లక్షణాలను వివరించండి.","answer":"హోలోథురాయిడియా :ఈ విభాగంలో సముద్ర దోసకాయలను చేర్చారు. దేహం ముఖ -ప్రతిముఖ అక్షం వెంబడి పొడవుగా సాగి ఉంటుంది. చర్మం తోలులాగా ఉంటుంది. అంతశ్చర్మంలో వదులైన కంటకాలు ఉంటాయి. బాహువులు, ముళ్ళు, పెడిసిల్లేరియాలు ఉండవు. నోటి చుట్టూ ముకుళించుకోగల స్పర్శకాలు ఉంటాయి. (రూపాంతరం చెందిన నాళికాపాదాలు ఆహార సేకరణకు ఉపయోగపడతాయి). అంబులేక్రల్ గాడులు మూసుకొని ఉంటాయి. నాళికాపాదాలకు చూషకాలు ఉంటాయి. రంధ్ర ఫలకం అంతర్గతంగా (శరీర కుహరంలో) ఉంటుంది. శ్వాసాంగాలు ఒక జత అవస్కర శ్వాస వృక్షాలు. పిండాభివృద్ధి పరోక్షంగా జరిగి ఆరిక్యులేరియా డింభకం ఏర్పడుతుంది.ఉదా : హోలోతూరియా, సినాప్టా, థయోన్."},{"question":"Про яку подію розповідає текст: Опівночі 8 листопада 1942 року кораблі Центральної десантної групи союзників встали на якір на відстані 8 миль від Федали. О 6:00 ранку десантно-висадочні засоби з американським десантом на борту вирушили в напрямку берега для висадки на узбережжя Французької Північної Африки, зайняте французькими військами уряду Віші.","answer":"Про висадку союзників на узбережжя Французької Північної Африки."},{"question":"Биринчи жолу кайсы жылы iPhone сатылып алынган?","answer":"Биринчи жолу iPhone 2007-жылы сатылып алынган."},{"question":"සිංහල අක්ෂර වින්‍යාසයේ ෂ භාවිතය ගැන කියන්න.","answer":"සිංහල අක්ෂර වින්‍යාසයේ ෂ භාවිතය ගැන පහත දැක්වේ.(1) මුර්ධජ අක්‍ෂරයකට පුර්වයෙන් මුර්ධජ ෂ යෙදේ. විෂ්ණු, නෂ්ඨ, දෘෂ්ටි, අෂ්ටලෝක, කෘෂ්ණා(2) ක සමග සංයෝග වන්නේ මුර්ධජ ෂ වේ. අක්‍ෂර, දුෂ්කර, පරීක්‍ෂණ, තීක්‍ෂණ (3) ඇතැම් විට ප බලපෑම නිසා ෂ යෙදේ. නිෂ්පාදන, නිෂ්ප්‍රභා, නිෂ්පත්ති"},{"question":"तांब्याच्या जाड पत्र्यावर कोरुन तयार केलेल्या मजकूराला काय म्हणतात ?","answer":"तांब्याच्या जाड पत्र्यावर कोरुन तयार केलेल्या मजकूराला ताम्रपट म्हणतात. "},{"question":"Paragrafı devam ettir: - 2008 yılında Alonso'nun yerine McLaren koltuğuna oturan Heikki Kovalainen ile takım arkadaşı olan Hamilton, bir sonraki sezonda da başarılı performansını sürdürdü. İkinci sezonunda beş yarış zaferi elde eden Hamilton, on kez de podyuma çıktı. Interlagos'taki sezonun son yarışına","answer":"7 puan farkla lider çıkan Hamilton, şampiyonluk şansını ikinci sıradaki Ferrari pilotu Felipe Massa'nın kendi ülkesindeki son yarışa bıraktı. Son turlarında yağmurun bastırdığı yarışı kazanan Massa damalı bayrağı gördüğünde Hamilton Sebastian Vettel'in arkasında 6. sırada olduğundan Massa ile puanları eşitleniyor, Hamilton'a kıyasla daha fazla yarışı 2. olarak tamamlayan Massa şampiyon oluyordu. Massa ve Ferrari ekibi yarış zaferini ve Massa'nın neredeyse kesinleşmiş ilk şampiyonluğunu kutlarken Hamilton, yarışın son turunun son virajında kuru zemin lastikleriyle devam ettiği için yavaşlamak durumunda kalan Timo Glock'u geçerek yarışı 5. bitirdi ve sezonu Massa'nın 1 puan önünde şampiyon kapattı. Hamilton'ın yavaşlayan Timo Glock'u kolay bir şekilde geçerek şampiyonluğunu ilan etmesi şike ve usulsüzlük iddialarını peşinde getirse de Glock, yağmurlu havada kuru zemin lastikleriyle yol tutuşunu çok zor bir şekilde ayarlayabildiği için yavaşladığını belirterek usulsüzlük iddialarını reddetti. 2008 yılında ilk şampiyonluğunu kazanan Hamilton, ayrıca 1996 yılında şampiyon olan Damon Hill'den beri dünya şampiyonu olan ilk Britanyalı pilot oldu. Ertesi sezon Hamilton, şampiyon olduğu 2008'e kıyasla başarısız bir sezon geçirerek 2 yarış zaferiyle sezonu 5. tamamladı."},{"question":"Ала көөдөн","answer":"Маактанчаак, курулай күүлөнгөн, жеңил мүнөз.Ал жигит дагы баягы ала көөдөндүгүн карматып, эл алдында уят болду."},{"question":"\\"Ny fandrafetana voninkazo dia ny famoronana voninkazo ho an'ny fotoana manokana na fialamboly fotsiny. Ny \\"fleuriste\\" dia manam-pahaizana manokana amin'ny fanangonana fehezam-boninkazo sy fandrafetana voninkazo. Ikebana, zavakanto voninkazo japoney, dia malaza amin'ny fahatsorany sy ny hakantony.\\". Inona ny lohahevitr'io lahatsoratra eo ambony io?","answer":"Ny lohahevitr'io lahatsoratra eo ambony io dia ny voninkazo."},{"question":"ਇਹ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਕਿਸਦੇ ਹਨ, “ਵਿਆਹ ਇੱਕ ਸਮਝੌਤਾ ਹੈ ਜਿਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਬੱਚੇ ਦਾ ਪਾਲਣ-ਪੋਸ਼ਣ ਅਤੇ ਦੇਖ-ਭਾਲ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ ?”","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਮੈਲਿਨੋਵਸਕੀ ਦੇ ਹਨ ।"},{"question":"Ijọba Eko gbẹsẹ le ọkada bii aadoje, wọn ni wọn ṣẹ sofin irinna","answer":"Nitori pe wọn n rin lawọn ibi ti ijọba ti fofin de pe wọn ko gbọdọ de, awọn ọkada bii aadoje ni ijọba ipinlẹ Eko ti gbẹsẹ le nipinlẹ Eko lọjọ Aje, Mọnde, ọse yii. Ileeṣẹ to n ri si titẹle ofin imọtoto nipinlẹ Eko (Lagos State Sanitation Enforcement Agency), lo ko awọn ọkada ọhun. Bakan naa ni wọn mu awọn awakọ marun-un to wakọ lodi si ofin irinna.Aarọ kutu ọjọ Aje, Mọnde,  ni awọn ikọ bii ọgọrin ọhun, eyi ti ọga wọn, Shola Jẹjẹloye to jẹ ọga ọlọpaa dari, ya bo awọn ọlọkada to n gbero lawọn ibi ti ijọba sọ pe wọn ko gbọdọ ti maa ṣiṣẹ n’Iyana Ipaja.Abule-Ẹgba ni wọn mori le nigba ti wọn kuro ni Iyana Ipaja, nibi ti awọn ọkọ ti n gba ọna ti ko yẹ ki wọn gba, ti awọn ọlọkada atawọn onimọto mi-in si n kọju si awọn ọkọ to n bọ, leyii ti wọn fi da sun-kẹrẹ fa-kẹrẹ silẹ ni gbogbo agbegbe naa. Bi wọn ṣe n ri wọn ni wọn n fọwọ ofin mu wọn.Jẹjẹloye ni lati ọjọ Aje, Mọnde, ọsẹ yii, lawọn ti bẹrẹ eto ọhun, gbogbo asiko ọdun lawọn yoo maa jade lati mojuto bi awọn ọlọkada ṣe n ṣiṣẹ wọn lati ri i pe awọn ti wọn maa n fi ọkada jale lasiko ọdun ko raaye ṣịṣẹ buruku naa.Bẹẹ lo sọ pe ki awọn ọlọkada ti ko ba ti ṣẹ sofin tabi ti wọn ko lọ si awọn ibi ti ijọba ba ni ki wọn ma lọ ma ṣe foya, nitori awọn ko ni i de ọdọ wọn. O fi kun un pe awọn ko wa lati da wahala silẹ tabi lati gba ounjẹ lẹnu ẹnikẹni, bi ko ṣe lati ri i pe ohun gbogbo lọ bo ṣe yẹ, ati pe awọn onimọto ati ọlọkada bọwọ fun ofin irinna."},{"question":"Ya ya sunan babban birnin jihar Naija (Niger)?","answer":"Minna"},{"question":"Ngwala go tšwela pele ga serapa se - Go ya ka Caine, \\"khamphani e ile ya swarelela filimi ka nywaga ye mentši pele e lokollwa. Ka morago ga ngwaga wa go latela nako ye e swanetšego, ka bohlale bja kgonthe bja difilimi ba ile ba lokolla filimi bošegong bjoo re ilego ra hlasela Suez","answer":".. le Filimi yeo e ile ya theogela fase, gomme mošomo wa-ka wa difilimi le wona wa theogela fase. Ke be ke llela gore ga go na motho yo a kilego a bona filimi yeo, go ba go fihla ge nna ka noši ke e bone. Ke be ke le yo mobe! Lentšu la-ka e be e le le le šiišago...Matswele a-ka a mmala o mosehla le di-eyebrows tša-ka, tšeo di nago le mafelelo a go bolela ka go batamela ga selo seo se se nago sefahlego, gomme ga se tše kaone kudu ka go thuntšha ga magareng..Go tšwelela ga-ka e be e le mo go sego kae ka kgaugelo, morulaganyi o ile a dira phetho ya gore lefelo la phapoši ya go sega e be e le lefelo le le swanetšego bakeng sa maiteko a-ka a pele a go ba naledi ya lefase ka bophara\\"."},{"question":"Куш тилиндей","answer":"Кичинекей, тырмактай, аз гана.Ал келгенде табакта куш тилиндей гана эт калган."},{"question":"Firy ny isan'ny kandida filoham-pirenena tamin'ny 2013 teto Madagasikara?","answer":"Kandida miisa 33 no nakataoavin'ny fitsarana manokana misahana ny fifidianana tamin'ny 2013 teto Madagasikara."},{"question":"ጥያቄ፦ ፎርድ ሙስታንግ የተባለው ስም ምን ወይም ማን ነው? መልስ፦ ","answer":"የሁለተኛው የዓለም ጦርነት የተዋጊ አውሮፕላን ስም "},{"question":"டிடி கோசாம்பியின் மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தந்து விளக்குக .","answer":"மார்க்சியத்தை ஒரு தானியங்கி இயந்திரத்தின் உபயோகிப்புக் குறிப்புகளாகவோ அல்லது ஒரு பொன்மொழிகளின் கஜானாவாகவோ மாற்றிவிடக் கூடாது."},{"question":"Kadın kocasından razı olmazsa ne olur?","answer":"Namazı boşa gider demek değildir. Hadis-i şerifte buyuruluyor ki: Bir kadından kocası razı olmazsa, kadın, günahının cezasını çektikten sonra, Cennete girer. Cennete sadece kâfirler girmez."},{"question":"Fan moy péeyum réwum Afghanistan","answer":"Péeyum réwum Afghanistan mu ngi tudu Kaboul"},{"question":"રંગોળીનું મૂળ અને ઈતિહાસ જણાવો","answer":"રંગોળીનું મૂળ અસ્પષ્ટ છે, પરંતુ એવું માનવામાં આવે છે કે તે ભારતમાં 5,000 વર્ષ પહેલાં ઉદ્ભવ્યું હતું. કેટલાક માને છે કે તે મહેમાનોને આવકારવા અને ઘરમાં સારા નસીબ લાવવાના માર્ગ તરીકે ઉદ્દભવ્યું છે. અન્ય લોકો માને છે કે તેનો ઉદ્દભવ સંપત્તિ અને સમૃદ્ધિની હિન્દુ દેવી લક્ષ્મીની પૂજા કરવાના માર્ગ તરીકે થયો હતો."},{"question":"18 Mart Çanakkale Savaşının komutanı kimdir?","answer":"Çanakkale Deniz Savaşlarında görev alan Cevat (Çobanlı) Paşa'nın tarihe 18 Mart kahramanı olarak yazılması O'nun askeri ve stratejik başarısıdır. Bu çalışmada Çanakkale cephesinde özellikle deniz savaşlarında görev alan Cevat Paşa'nın faaliyetlerine yer verilmiştir."},{"question":"रोगको घटनालाई मापन गर्ने अध्ययन के हो?","answer":"एपिडेमियोलोजी भनेको मानिसका विभिन्न समूहहरूमा कति पटक रोगहरू हुन्छन् र किन हुन्छन् भन्ने अध्ययन हो।"},{"question":"பகத் சிங் மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":"கேளாத செவிகளைக் கேட்கச் செய்வதற்கு உரத்த குரல் தேவைப்படுகிறது. ஏப்ரல் 8, 1929 அன்று டெல்லி மத்திய சட்டமன்றத்தில் குண்டுவெடிப்பு வழக்கு விசாரணையில் பகத் சிங் மற்றும் பதுகேஷ்வர் தத் கூறினார்கள். இது இந்திய சுதந்திரப் போராட்டத்தின் முழக்கங்களில் ஒன்றாக மாறியது."},{"question":"¿Cuál es el animal más grande del mundo? ","answer":"La ballena azul antártica es el animal más grande del planeta. Llega a pesar hasta 400,000 libras (180 ton) o el equivalente a unos 33 elefantes y medir unos 98 pies (29 m) de largo."},{"question":"கிருத்திகாஇயற்றிய நூல்கள் யாவை ?  ","answer":"புதினங்கள்1.புகை நடுவினில்2.சத்யமேவ3.பொன்கூண்டு4.வாஸவேஸ்வரம்5.தர்ம ஷேத்ரே6.புதிய கோணங்கி7.நேற்றிருந்தோம்குறும் புதினங்கள்1.யோகமும் போகமும்2.தீராத பிரச்சனை3.நாடகங்கள்4.மனதிலே ஒரு மறு5.மா ஜானகி"},{"question":" Sheeg Sanadkii La-Oofsaday Rasuulka (NNKH)","answer":" Waxa La-Oofsaday 11-Kii Hijriyada."},{"question":"Sheeg Kumuu Ahaa Qofkii Ugu Horeeyey Ee Qora Bismillaahi Raxmaanil Raxiim?","answer":"Wuxu Ahaa Nabi Suleymaan CS."},{"question":"హార్మోన్స్ అనగానేమి?","answer":"వినాళ గ్రంథులచే స్రవించబడే రసాయన పదార్థాలను “హార్మోన్స్” అంటారు. ఇవి నేరుగా రక్తంలోనికి విడుదలై నిర్దిష్ట అవయవాలను ప్రభావితం చేస్తాయి. 1905 వ సంవత్సరంలో ఆంగ్ల శరీరధర్మ శాస్త్రవేత్త వీటికి హార్మోన్స్ అని పేరుపెట్టాడు."},{"question":"Zadzisa pakashama _\\"_ ndiyo foni yepamusoro pamusika\\"","answer":"Iphone ndiyo foni yepamusoro pamusika"},{"question":"Adele Ajosun","answer":"Oba Adele tàbí Adele Ajosun (ó fi ayé sílẹ̀ ní ọdún 1837) jọba ní Èkó fún ṣáà méjì; àkọ́kọ́ , láti ọdún c1811 sí 1821, àti ẹlẹ́kejì láti ọdún 1835 sí 1837. Bàbá rẹ̀ ni Oba Ologun Kutere, àwọn ẹbí rẹ̀ sì ni Oba Osinlokun àti Ọba Akitoye, ìran Ologun Kutere ti gun orí oyè ọba Èkó fún ọ̀pọ̀ ìgbà láti ìgbà náà.Adele gun orí ìtẹ́ ọba Èkó lẹ́yìn ọdún márùn-ún tí bàbá rẹ̀, Ologun Kutere, fi ayé sílẹ̀. Àwọn ìtàn àti àkọọ́lẹ̀ kòkan fihàn pé ète Ologun Kutere ni pé kí Adele di Oba Èkó nítorí iṣẹ́ ribiribi tí ó ti ṣe fún Ologun Kutere. Onítàn John. B. Losi kọ́ pé Adele tọ́ju àwọn ohun ìní Ologun Kutere.Nígbà ìjọba Adele, ẹ̀sìn Mùsùlùmí gba ilẹ̀ ní Èkó."},{"question":"Scrivi una possibile continuazione a questo paragrafo: \\"Se necessario, una gara può iniziare o anche terminare in regime di \\"safety car\\". La partenza in regime di safety car avviene se ci sono condizioni meteo sfavorevoli, come durante un forte acquazzone prima della partenza. Ciò è accaduto undici volte in Formula 1: nel 1997 e nel 2000 in Belgio, nel 2003 in Brasile, nel 2007 al Gran Premio del Giappone sul Circuito del Fuji, nel 2008 al Gran Premio d'Italia a Monza, nel 2009, in Cina, ...\\"","answer":"\\"... nel 2010 in Corea, nel 2011 in Canada, nel 2014 in Giappone e infine nel 2016 a Monaco, in Gran Bretagna e in Brasile. Dal 2017 la procedura di partenza dietro la \\"safety car\\" in caso di condizioni della pista proibitive è stata modificata: le monoposto effettueranno dei giri dietro la vettura di sicurezza finché le condizioni della pista non permettono una partenza; tale partenza può essere da fermo oppure lanciata: nel caso di partenza da fermo il numero di giri della gara viene ridotto del totale dei giri percorsi dietro la safety car meno uno (quello di formazione originariamente previsto), mentre nel caso di partenza lanciata tutti i giri percorsi dietro la safety car sono detratti dal totale. Nel caso le condizioni della pista non permettano una partenza (da fermo o lanciata) l'intera procedura viene sospesa e si procede con una ripartenza da effettuarsi con la stessa procedura prevista nel caso di una sospensione della gara. Nei casi descritti la durata massima della gara (4 ore) comincia ad essere calcolata dall'orario di partenza programmato della gara. La procedura di partenza secondo le nuove norme è stata applicata una volta nel 2019 in Germania.\\""},{"question":"Berikan tiga peribahasa yang bermaksud sama dengan peribahasa \\"arang itu, jika dibasuh dengan air mawar sekalipun, tiada akan putih\\".","answer":"Peribahasa-peribahasa yang mempunyai maksud yang sama dengan peribahasa \\"arang itu, jika dibasuh dengan air mawar sekalipun, tiada akan putih\\" ialah:a. anjing itu, meskipun dirantai dengan rantai emas, nescaya berulang-ulang juga ia ke tempat najis, b. burung gagak itu jika dimandikan dengan air mawar sekalipun, tiada akan menjadi putih bulunya, c. gagak dimandikan tujuh kali sehari pun, takkan putih bulunya"},{"question":"సమాఖ్య ప్రభుత్వ లక్షణాలను చర్చించండి.","answer":"‘ఫెడరేషన్’ అనే ఆంగ్ల పదం ఫోడస్ అనే లాటిన్ పదం నుంచి ఉద్భవించింది. ‘ఫోడస్’ అనగా ఒడంబడిక లేదా అంగీకారం అని అర్థం. ఆధునిక రాజకీయ వ్యవస్థలో ‘సమాఖ్య విధానం’ ఒక రాజకీయ ఆలోచనా ప్రక్రియగా మారింది. ఈ విధానం అత్యంత బహుళ ప్రాచుర్యం పొందింది. అమెరికా (1789), స్విట్జర్లాండ్ (1848), ఆస్ట్రేలియా (1901), కెనడా (1931) వంటి దేశాలు సమాఖ్య ప్రభుత్వ వ్యవస్థకు మంచి ఉదాహరణలు.నిర్వచనాలు:ఎ.వి. డైసీ: “జాతీయ సమైక్యత, ప్రాంతీయ విభాగాల హక్కులను సమన్వయపరిచే రాజకీయ సాధనమే సమాఖ్య ప్రభుత్వం.”జె.డబ్ల్యు. గార్నర్: “సమాఖ్య ప్రభుత్వ వ్యవస్థ అనేది ప్రభుత్వానికి గల మొత్తం అధికారాలను కేంద్రం- రాష్ట్రాల మధ్య జాతీయ రాజ్యాంగం ద్వారా పంపిణీ చేసేది.”సమాఖ్య ప్రభుత్వ లక్షణాలు: సమాఖ్య ప్రభుత్వం అనేక లక్షణాలను కలిగి ఉంది. వాటిని ఈ క్రింది విధంగా తెలుసుకోవచ్చు.1. లిఖిత రాజ్యాంగం: సాధారణంగా సమాఖ్య వ్యవస్థ ఉనికిలో ఉన్న దేశాల్లో. లిఖిత రాజ్యాంగం ఉంటుంది. ఆ రాజ్యాంగం దేశం మొత్తానికి అత్యున్నత శాసనంగా పరిగణించబడుతుంది. ఆ రాజ్యాంగమే అధికారాలను నిర్వచించి, నిర్ణయించి కేంద్రం, రాష్ట్రాల మధ్య పంపిణీ చేస్తుంది. ఆ విధంగా సమాఖ్య వ్యవస్థ అవసరమైన, ఆచరణయోగ్యమైన ప్రభుత్వ విధానంగా ఉంటుంది.2. ద్వంద్వ పౌరసత్వం: సమాఖ్య రాజ్య వ్యవస్థలో పౌరులకు ద్వంద్వ (రెండు) పౌరసత్వం ఉంటుంది. (ఒకటి జాతీయస్థాయి, రెండు సంబంధిత రాష్ట్రస్థాయి) అందువల్ల పౌరులు కేంద్రం, రాష్ట్రాల పౌరసత్వాన్ని పొందుతారు. తత్ఫలితంగా, పౌరులు జాతీయ, ప్రాంతీయ ప్రభుత్వాల ఎన్నిక ప్రక్రియలో ప్రాతినిధ్యం వహిస్తారు.3. అధికార విభజన: సమాఖ్య విధానంలో ప్రభుత్వ అధికారాలు కేంద్ర, రాష్ట్ర ప్రభుత్వాల మధ్య విభజింపబడతాయి. కేంద్ర ప్రభుత్వం జాతీయ ప్రయోజనాలను కాపాడే అంశాలపై నియంత్రణ కలిగి ఉంటుంది. ఉదాహరణకు రక్షణ, విదేశీ వ్యవహారాలు, సుంకాలు, ఎగుమతులు-దిగుమతులు వంటి జాతీయ ప్రాముఖ్యత గల అంశాలను నియంత్రిస్తుంది. అదేవిధంగా, వ్యవసాయం, విద్య, వైద్యం, నీటి పారుదల విషయాలను ప్రాంతీయ ప్రభుత్వాలకు అప్పగించటం జరుగుతుంది.4. ద్విసభా విధానం: ద్విసభా విధానమనేది సమాఖ్య వ్యవస్థకు మరో ముఖ్య లక్షణం. సమాఖ్య రాజ్యంలో రెండు సభలు ఉంటాయి. ఎగువ సభ రాష్ట్రాలకు ప్రాతినిధ్యం వహిస్తూ రాష్ట్రాల ప్రయోజనాలను పరిరక్షిస్తుంది. ఎగువ సభలో రాష్ట్రాల జనాభాననుసరించి ప్రాతినిధ్యం కల్పించటం జరుగుతుంది. దిగువసభ ప్రజలకు ప్రత్యక్ష ప్రాతినిధ్యం వహిస్తుంది.5. దృఢ రాజ్యాంగం: సాధారణంగా, సమాఖ్య వ్యవస్థలో రాజ్యాంగం దృఢ లక్షణాన్ని కలిగి ఉంటుంది. అందువల్ల రాజ్యాంగ సవరణ అంత సులభం కాదు. కొన్ని ముఖ్యమైన అంశాలకు సంబంధించి రాజ్యాంగ సవరణ చేయటానికి కేంద్ర, రాష్ట్ర ప్రభుత్వాల అనుమతి తప్పనిసరి. ఈ కారణం వల్ల, అటు కేంద్ర ప్రభుత్వం గానీ ఇటు రాష్ట్ర ప్రభుత్వాలు గానీ రాజ్యాంగ సూత్రాలను ఏకపక్షంగా సవరించలేవు.6. స్వతంత్ర న్యాయశాఖ: సమాఖ్యప్రభుత్వ విధానంలో అతి ముఖ్యమైన లక్షణమేమిటంటే స్వయం ప్రతిపత్తి కలిగిన న్యాయశాఖ. ఎందుకంటే, కేంద్రం, రాష్ట్రాల మధ్యగల వివాదాలను ఒక్క న్యాయశాఖ మాత్రమే తీర్చగలదు. అందువల్ల న్యాయమూర్తులు రాజ్యాంగపరంగా సంక్రమించిన స్వతంత్ర హోదానుసంతృప్తిగా అనుభవిస్తారు. సాధారణంగా న్యాయమూర్తుల నియామకం ఒకసారి జరిగిన తరువాత వారిని తొలగించడం అంత సులభం కాదు. వారు పౌరుల ప్రాథమిక హక్కులను పరిరక్షిస్తారు. అంతేకాదు శాసననిర్మాణ, కార్యనిర్వాహక శాఖలు అమలుపరిచే అధికారాలు దుర్వినియోగం జరుగుతున్నట్లు భావించినట్లయితే, ఆ అధికారాలను నియంత్రించేది న్యాయశాఖ మాత్రమే."},{"question":"Tohizo izao ohabolana izao : \\"  Aza mba matin-kenamaso ohatry ny sola mandrafozana,  ............... \\" ","answer":"\\"  Aza mba matin-kenamaso ohatry ny sola mandrafozana, na marary aza ny loha ny vilany tsy maintsy lolohavina \\""},{"question":"Quando foi a primeira publicação da Vogue?","answer":"A primeira publicação da Vogue foi em dezembro de 1892. Vogue é uma revista americana mensal de moda e estilo de vida que cobre muitos tópicos, incluindo moda, beleza, cultura, estilo de vida e passarela."},{"question":"Thành phố nào được ví là tiểu Paris của Việt Nam?","answer":"Thành phố Đà Lạt, Lâm Đồng, nằm trên cao nguyên Lâm Viên ở độ cao 1.500 m so với mặt nước biển. Đà Lạt rộng hơn 393 km2, được công nhận là đô thị loại 1 năm 2009.Thời Pháp thuộc, thành phố có tên Dat Aliis Laetitiam Aliis Temperiem, nghĩa là cho những người này niềm vui, cho những người khác sự mát mẻ. Thời đó, Đà Lạt có hơn 1.300 biệt thự với kiến trúc đa dạng, nhiều nhất là kiến trúc phía bắc nước Pháp nên được ví là \\"tiểu Paris\\". "},{"question":"ஈ. வெ. இராமசாமி மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":"தந்தை பெரியார், பெரியார் எனப் பரவலாக அறியப்படும் ஈ. வெ. இராமசாமி (செப்டம்பர் 17, 1879 - டிசம்பர் 24, 1973) சமூக சீர்திருத்ததிற்காகவும், சாதி வேற்றுமையினை அகற்றுவதற்காகவும், மூடநம்பிக்கைகளை மக்களிடமிருந்து களைவதற்காகவும், பெண் விடுதலைக்காகவும் போராடியவர்.1.நான் சொல்கிறேன் என்பதற்காக எதையும் நீங்கள் ஒப்புக்கொள்ளாதீர்கள். பிறகு, மதவாதிகள் புராணத்தை முன்வைத்து பேசுவதை நீங்கள் ஒப்புக் கொள்வதற்கும், இதற்கும் வித்தியாசம் இல்லாமல் போய்விடும். நான் பேசியதை வைத்து உங்களுக்குள் நிறைய கேள்விகளை எழுப்புங்கள், அதன் பின்னர் நான் சொன்னது சரியென்கும் பட்சம் ஒப்புக் கொள்ளுங்கள்.2.இன்றைய நிலைக்கு நான் பேசும் கொள்கைகள் சரி ; என் திட்டங்கள் சரி என்றால் எனக்குப் பிறகும், இன்னும் 100, 200, 1000 வருடங்களுக்குப் பிறகும் என் கொள்கைகள் - நான் வகுத்த திட்டங்கள் கொஞ்சம் கூட மாற்றப்படாமல் அப்படியே இருக்க வேண்டும் என்பது என்ன நியாயம்"},{"question":"\\"Tao anatin'ny fotoana vitsivitsy izay, ny foto-kevitra momba ny minimalism dia nahazo laza ho toy ny safidin'ny fomba fiaina. Ny fifantohana amin'ny fihenan'ny mpanjifa, ny fanatsorana ary ny finiavana dia mifanohitra amin'ny mpanjifa. Ny Minimalism dia misy fiantraikany amin'ny fahasalamana ara-tsaina, ny faharetan'ny tontolo iainana ary ny famerenana indray ny fikatsahana fahasambarana.\\"","answer":"Ny lohahevitra tamin'ny andalana teo aloha dia ny \\"Minimalism\\" sy ny fomba fiaina."},{"question":"අභ්‍යවකාශ ගමන් සේවා සපයන space x ආයතනය ආරම්භ කරන ලද්දේ","answer":"ඊලෝන් මසන්"},{"question":" इन्कलाब जिंदाबाद ही घोषणा कोणी केली होती?उत्तर :","answer":"भगतसिंग"},{"question":"కింద ఇచ్చిన పదాలని విడదీసి సంధి పేరు మరియు సంధి సూత్రం రాయండి:1. పేదరికమిట్లు2 జీవితాశ3. పదాఙ్ఞాతంబు4. దారిద్ర్యాంధకార5. వాలుఁగన్నులు","answer":"1. పేదరికమిట్లు : పేదరికము + ఇట్లు = ఉకార సంధిసూత్రం : ఉత్తునకచ్చు పరంబగునపుడు సంధియగు2 జీవితాశ : జీవిత + ఆశ = సవర్ణదీర్ఘ సంధిసూత్రం : అకార, ఇకార, ఉకార, ఋకారములకు సవర్ణములు పరమైనచో వాని దీర్ఘమేకాదేశమగును.3. పదాఙ్ఞాతంబు : పద + అఙ్ఞాతంబు = సవర్ణదీర్ఘ సంధిసూత్రం : అకార, ఇకార, ఉకార, ఋకారములకు సవర్ణములు పరమైనచో వాని దీర్ఘమేకాదేశమగును.4. దారిద్ర్యాంధకార : దారిద్య్ర + అంధకార = సవర్ణదీర్ఘ సంధిసూత్రం. : అకార, ఇకార, ఉకార, ఋకారములకు సవర్ణములు పరమైనచో వాని దీర్ఘమేకాదేశమగును.5. వాలుఁగన్నులు : వాలున్ + కన్నులు = సరళాదేశ సంధిసూత్రం : ద్రుత ప్రకృతికము మీది పరుషములకు సరళములుగు."},{"question":"¿Cómo funciona el algoritmo de backpropagation?","answer":"Cualquier función se puede representar a través de un grafo computacional donde cada vértice representa una operación. Por ejemplo, la función f(a, b, x) = sqrt(a*x + b) se puede representar con el siguiente grafo:Un nodo v1 representa al valor a, otro nodo v2 presenta al valor x, y otro nodo v3 representa el valor b.Luego, un nuevo nodo v4 representa a*x, otro nodo v5 representa a*x + b, y un último nodo v6 representa sqrt(a*x+b).En otras palabra v1 := a, v2 := x, v3 := b. Lueg v4 := v1 * v2, v5 := v4 + v3, v6 := sqrt(v5). Lo que estamos haciendo es representar la función f como una composición de otras funciones más simples.Luego, cuando necesitamos computar la derivada de la función f con respecto a a,b,x, utilizamos la regla de la cadena de Leibnitz, que dice que si df/dx = df/dg * dg/dx.Entonces, podemos computar la derivada dv6/dv5, dv5/dv4 y dv5/dv3, y dv4/dv1, dv4/dv2, y de esta manera podemos computar la derivada de f con respecto a las tres variables a,b,x en un punto en particular. Para hacerlo, primeramente hacemos un pase hacia adelante, para computar f(a,b,x) en los valores dado, y luego hacemos un pase hacia detrás de acuerdo a la regla de la cadena."},{"question":"Zombie-ing là gì?","answer":"Zombie-ing /ˈzɒm.bi-ɪŋ/ chỉ một người từng ngó lơ bạn nhưng sau một thời gian thì quay lại chủ động nhắn tin, gọi điện hỏi thăm như thể không có chuyện gì xảy ra.Zombie-ing là phiên bản “sinh sau đẻ muộn” của ghosting. Nếu đã từng bị ghost, bạn hẳn hiểu được cảm giác bối rối, khó chịu và tức giận khi một người thân thiết bỗng dưng “bơ” mình. Và khi bạn tưởng rằng bản thân đã vượt qua nỗi đau bị “bơ đẹp” ấy, thì người kia bỗng dưng “hồi sinh.”"},{"question":"Àwọn wo ni à ń pè ní Krìsìtẹ́nì?","answer":"Àwọn tí wọ́n gbàgbọ́ nínú ikú àti àjíǹde Jésù ni."},{"question":"Wat is een agononida normani?","answer":"Een agononida normani is een tienpotigensoort uit de familie van de Munididae. De wetenschappelijke naam van de soort is voor het eerst geldig gepubliceerd in 1885 door Henderson. "},{"question":"Amin'ny sehatra inona no azo ampisiaina ny ompa sy ny ozona ?","answer":"Anisan’ny mampiavaka ny ompa amin’ny teny rehetra ny sehatra ampiasana azy. Ny teny rehetra dia azo ampiasaina amin’ny fotoana rehetra sy toerana rehetra araka izay itiavana azy sy ilana azy. Tsy toy izany kosa ny ompa satria voafetra ny sehatra azo ampiasana azy ary misy ny toerana sy fotoana azo ampiasana azy ary misy koa ny tsy azo anaovana izany. Tsy tenitenenina foana amin’ny tsy misy dikany izy ireny satria tafiditra ao anaty teny fady."},{"question":"Ano ang Bluetooth?","answer":"Ang Bluetooth ay isang short-range wireless connection medium standard na ginagamit para sa pagpapalitan ng data sa pagitan ng mga fixed at mobile device sa mga malalayong distansya at pagbubuo ng mga personal na area network. Sa pinakakaraniwang ginagamit na mode, ang transmission power ay limitado sa 2.5 milliwatts, na nagbibigay dito ng napakaikling hanay na hanggang 10 metro. Kadalasang ginagamit ang Bluetooth para magpalitan ng mga files sa pagitan ng dalawang device, o para kumonekta sa mga wireless headphones."},{"question":"ഈ വാചകം ഏത് പ്രധാന സംഭവത്തെക്കുറിച്ചാണ്: കാലിഫോർണിയ ഗോൾഡ് റഷിന്റെ സമയം നിധി അന്വേഷകരായ കുടിയേറ്റക്കാർ അനേകശതം ഒഴുകിയെത്തി. ഖനന സാദ്ധ്യത തിരഞ്ഞുവന്നവർ പ്രദേശത്തു തമ്പടിച്ചു. ജനസംഖ്യ 1848 ലെ 1000 പേരിൽ നിന്ന് 1849 ഡിസംബറിൽ 25,000 ലേയ്ക്ക് എത്തിച്ചേർന്നു. നിധിയെക്കുറിച്ചുള്ള അതിശയ കഥകൾ വളരെ ശക്തമായിരുന്നു അക്കാലത്ത്. യൂറോപ്പിൽ നിന്നു പരശതം കപ്പലുകൾ ഈ പ്രദേശത്തേയ്ക്ക് ഒഴുകിയെത്തി. വന്നവരെല്ലാം കപ്പലുകൾ തുറമുഖത്തുപേക്ഷിച്ച് സ്വർണ്ണപ്പാടം ലക്ഷ്യമാക്കി പാഞ്ഞു. സാൻഫ്രാൻസിസ്കോ തുറമുഖം ഉപേക്ഷിക്കപ്പെട്ട കപ്പലുകളുടെ പ്രേതഭൂമിയായി മാറി. ഏകദേശം 500 നു മകളിൽ ഉപേക്ഷിക്കപ്പെട്ട കപ്പലുകൾ പിന്നീട് ഹോട്ടലുകളായും കടകളായും സ്റ്റോറുകളായും മറ്റും ഉപയോഗിക്കപ്പെട്ടു. കപ്പലുകളില് പലതും കാലപ്പഴക്കത്തിൽ തകരുകയും കുറേയെണ്ണം വെള്ളത്തിൽ താഴ്ന്നു പോകുകയും ചെയ്തു. 1851 ൽ തുറമുഖം വികസിപ്പിച്ചു. അനേകം കെട്ടിടങ്ങൾ നിർമ്മിക്കപ്പെട്ടു. 1870 ല് തുറമുഖം വികസിപ്പിക്കുന്നതിന് കൂടുതല് പ്രദേശങ്ങൾ മണ്ണിട്ടു നികത്തി. പുതിയ കെട്ടിടങ്ങള് നിർമ്മിക്കുന്നതിന് അടിത്തറ കുഴിക്കുമ്പോള് പഴയകാലത്തു മണ്ണിനടിയില്പെട്ട കപ്പലുകളുടെ ഭാഗങ്ങൾ പൊന്തി വരാറുണ്ട്[40]","answer":"ഖണ്ഡിക \\"കാലിഫോർണിയ ഗോൾഡ് റഷിനെ\\" കുറിച്ച് സംസാരിക്കുന്നു. "},{"question":"السؤال: ما هي الحقوق الخاصة؟","answer":"الإجابة: الحقوق الخاصة حقوق تتسم بالطابع الفردي، فهي تخص شخص أو مجموعة أشخاص محددين."},{"question":"O digba ta a ba ṣe ohun to yẹ ka ṣe ki iṣoro aabo yii too dopin – Babangida","answer":"Olori orileede yii laye ologun, Ajagun-fẹyinti Ibrahim Babangida, ti sọ ero rẹ lori iṣoro aabo to mẹhẹ to n koju orileede yii lọwọlọwọ, o ni o digba ti ijọba ba ṣe ohun to yẹ ki wọn ṣe ki iṣoro naa too re odo lọọ mu’mi.Ninu ifọrọwanilẹnuwo wo kan to ṣe lede Hausa, lọjọ Aiku, Sannde yii, Babangida ni wahala awọn janduku agbebọn, ajinigbe ati ti Boko Haram ki i ṣe iṣoro ti a ko le bori bi ijọba ba pinnu lati bori ẹ, ti wọn si gbe igbesẹ to yẹ ki wọn gbe.Lara igbesẹ ti Babangida lo pọn dandan funjọba lati gbe ni ki wọn ra awọn nnkan ija igbalode fawọn jagunjagun wa, ki wọn si fun wọn ni idalẹkọọ lori bi wọn ṣe maa lo o. O lawọn ologun wa ko le bori iṣoro aabo pẹlu nnkan ija to wa lọwọ wọn bayii, tori awọn nnkan eelo wọn ko bode mu mọ, ko si kunju oṣuwọn to.Babangida ni: “Bẹẹ ni, awọn ologun wa nilo nnkan ija tuntun, to bode mu. Ṣugbọn wọn tun nilo idalẹkọọ lori bi wọn ṣe maa lo o, ki i ṣe ka kan ko nnkan ija tuntun fun wọn lai mọ lilo ẹ, a gbọdọ kọ wọn ni.A tun gbọdọ fọwọ sowọ pọ pẹlu awọn ologun wa, a gbọdọ wa niṣọkan, ka si ṣatilẹyin fawọn adari wa, ki gbogbo wa ni afojusun kan naa. Laarin awọn adari ati araalu, iṣọkan ati alaafia gbọdọ wa, ti ko ba si, a o le bori awọn ipenija wọnyi. Mo ranti pe ọdun mẹta la fi jagun abẹle, awọn araalu ṣugbaa ijọba lasiko yẹn, ijọba naa si ṣe gbogbo nnkan ti wọn le ṣe, wọn pese nnkan eelo to yẹ, awọn ti wọn jagun yẹn gbagbọ pe iṣọkan orileede yii lo ṣe pataki ju lọ, a si ṣaṣeyọri.”Babangida tun sọ pe loorekoore loun maa n gba ijọba to wa lode yii lamọran, oun ki i pariwo ẹ sita ni. O ni ko sigba toun ki i fun wọn ni iṣiti ati amọran to yẹ, ṣugbọn ọtọ ni ka gbaayan lamọran ọtọ ni konitọhun ṣiṣẹ lori ẹ bo ṣe yẹ.Ṣugbọn ẹgbẹ ajijangbara ilẹ Yoruba nni, Afẹnifẹre ti sọrọ lori amọran ti Badamọsi Babangida loun n gba ijọba apapọ yii, wọn ni fifi akoko ṣofo lo jẹ lati gba Buhari lamọran, tori Aarẹ wa ki i gbamọran, ko si ni i tẹle e.Adari ẹgbẹ naa, Oloye Ayọ Adebanjọ, sọ nirọlẹ ọjọ Aiku pe “Ki lo de ti Babangida n dibọn, ṣe o maa loun o mọ Buhari ni? Afi ti Babangida ba fẹẹ purọ lo ku, ko le sọ pe oun ko mọ pe Aarẹ Babangida ki i tẹle amọran ti wọn ba gba a, tinu ẹ lo maa n ṣe, tori naa, bii ẹni to n pọnmi sinu apẹrẹ lo jẹ lati sọ peeyan n gba ijọba yii lamọran, ifakoko ṣofo lasan ni.”"},{"question":"Misy famelabelarana manan-danja hataonao any am-piasana. Ahoana no tokony hiomananao?Manana safidy roa ianao.Safidy 1: Mamorona slide PowerPoint amin'ny antsipiriany ho an'ny teboka tsirairay.Safidy 2: Mifantoka amin'ny fanomanana votoaty ary mampiasa sary mihetsika tsotra mba hampisehoana ireo hevi-dehibe.","answer":"Safidy tsara indrindra: Safidy 2 no tsara indrindra. Mifantoka amin'ny fanomanana votoaty ary mampiasa sary mihetsika tsotra mba hampisehoana ireo hevi-dehibe."},{"question":"Арчанын дарылык касиеттери?","answer":"Арча жыттуу, пайдалуу дарак же бадал түрүндөгү өсүмдүк. Ал дайыма көк-жашыл болуп, жаратылыштын көркүнө көрк кошот. Арча жаратылыш шартына жараша бирде коюу, бирде суюк өсөт. Адамдар аны абаны тазартуу жана дары-дармек жасоо үчүн да колдонушат. Тоолордо нымды жакшы сактайт. Токойлордон 800-1000 жаштагы арча дарактарын кезиктирүүгө болот. Кыргыздар байыркы убактан эле арчадан түрдүү турмуш-тиричилик буюмдарын (бешик, айырмач, идиш-аяк ж. б.) жасашкан."},{"question":"Àjọ̀dún ọdún Badagry","answer":"Ọdún ìbílẹ̀ Àgbádá-rìgì jẹ́ ayẹyẹ tí wọ́́n ma ń ṣe ní ẹ̀ẹ̀kan ṣoṣo lọ́dun tí ó ma ń wáyé ní ìlú Àgbádá-r̀ig̀i  (Badagry), tí ó jẹ́ ìlú ńlá kan ní ìpínlẹ̀ Èkó, ní orílẹ̀ èdè Nàìjíríà. Àjọ African Renaissance Foundation (AREFO) ló ma ń ṣ̀agbátẹr̀u ayẹyẹ náà. Àwọn èt̀o inú ayẹyẹ náà má ń fi ip̀o ìlú náà hàn ní àsìk̀o ìkóni lẹ́rú àwón Èèbó (slave trade era). Ayẹyẹ náà má ń jẹ́ ìdàpọ̀ àṣà àjogúnbá ilẹ̀ Adúláwọ̀. Àwọn  elétò má ń mú àṣà ìbílẹ̀ tí àwọn olùfẹ́ràn àṣà jákè jádò àgbáyé ma ń wá láti bá wọn yọ̀ lásìkò ayẹyẹ náà. Èyí tí ó jẹ́ ọ̀kan pàt̀akì nínú àwọn àṣà àti ìṣẹ̀ṣe ilẹ̀ adúláwò tí wọ́n ma ń gbéga níbẹ̀ ni Egúngún, Ijó ìbílẹ̀, iná gbígbé-jẹ àti bẹ̣́̀e bẹ́ẹ̀ lọ. Bákan náà ló tún ma ṣ̀agbékalẹ̀ ìdíje eré bọ́ọ̀lù aláfẹsẹ̀-gbá, àti lílù ilù  Sato, àti ìsàmì ọjọ́ ìjàjà-ǹ-gbaraWọ́n dá ayẹyẹ ọdún yìí kalẹ̀ ní ọdún 1999 láti fi ṣe ìrántí ìparí òwò ẹrú tó ti fìgbà kan wáyé rí nínú ìlú náà nígb̀a láé láé.Ayẹyẹ àjọ̀dún ti ọdún  2015  ni wọ́n pè ní: (\\"Toussaint L'Ouverture: The Catalyst for the struggle for liberation of the black\\"). tó túmọ̀ sí \\"Akitiyan ìjàjà-ǹ-gbara aláwọ̀ dúdú\\". Ayẹyẹ náà bẹ̀rẹ̀ ní 20 August tí ó sì wá sópin ní 30 August 2015. Àjọ̀dún ná̀a fi àyè sílẹ̀ fún àwọn ọmọ bíbí ilẹ̀ Àgbádá-rìgì tó wà káà kiri ilẹ̀ adúláwò tó kù láti kópa nínú ayẹyẹ náà àti láti tún rántí ilé bàbá won. Àjọ̀dún tí wọ́n ṣe kẹ́yìn wáyé nínú ọgb̀a ilé ìwẹ́ girama ìlú náà ìyẹn (Badagry Grammar School), Badagry, ipinle Eko, Nàìjíríà.ÌTÀN ÒWÒ ẸRÚ NÍLU ÀGBÁDÁ-RÌGÌOrúkọ tí ìlú náà ń jẹ́ lónìí (Badagry)  ni wọ́n fà yọ láti inú iṣẹ́ àwọn ènìyàn ìlú náà.  Lára iṣẹ́ náà ni: iyọ̀ ṣíṣe, ẹja pípa, iṣẹ́ àgbẹ̀. Bákan náà, àwọn mìíràn gbà wípé ìlú náà ni wọ́n fi sọrí ẹnìkan tí ó ń jẹ́ Agbedeh,  ẹni tị ó jẹ́ gbajú-gbajà àgbẹ̀ nílu náà tí orúkọ oko rẹ̀ ń jẹ́ Àgbádá-rìgì, tí àwọn Èèbó amúnisìn padà yí sí (Badagry).Ní àsìkò 18th century Badagry jẹ́ ọnà àrẹ́sẹ̀pa fún àwọn Èèbó tí wọ́n fi ń kó àwọn ẹrú tí wọ́n bá ti rà ránṣẹ́ sí ibi tí wọ́n bá fẹ́ kó wọn lọ. Ibẹ̀ ni ilé tí wọ́n ń pè ní; \\"Àlọ lámi-lámi\\" (Point of No Return) tí wọ́n gbẹ́ kànga kan sí tí ó jẹ́ pé ẹrú tí ó bá ti mu nínú omi kànga náà kò tún ní rántí ibi tí ó ti wá mọ́ láé láé. Ní ìparí 18th century, Badagry di ọ̀nà tí wọ́n tún ń kó ẹrú gb̀a láti Portnovo àti Dahomey. Badagry náà tún ni ó jẹ́ àyè kan tí wọ́n ti ma ń dúnàá dúràá lórí iye tí wọ́n fẹ́ ta ẹrú tí wọ́n fi tipá mú nínú ogun abúlé sí abúlé tí ó bá wáyé. Ni ọdún 1983, Olóyè Mobee jẹ́ ọ̀kan lára àwọn olóyè ilẹ̀ Adúláwọ̀ tó kópa nínú òwò ẹrú lásìkò náà.Àgbádá-rìgì ní Ilé alájà méjì àkọ́kọ́ (first two-storey building) irú rẹ̀ ní orílẹ̀ èd̀e Nàìjíríà tí wọ́n kọ́ sórí omi Màrínà, wà ní ọdún 1845. Lọ́wọ́ lọ́wọ́́ báyìí, ilé náà kò fi bẹ́ẹ̀ fẹsẹ̀ múlẹ̀ mọ́ látàtàrí wípé ìjọba kùnà láti tọ́jú ilé náà. Àmọ́ ìjọba gómìnà Bábátúnde Fashola ḷ́onà àti dá ògo ilé náà padà ni ó bẹ̀rẹ̀ iṣẹ́ àkànṣe ọ̀nà márosè tí ó lọ sí ìlú Àgbádá-rìgì "},{"question":"Explain to me what reading skills are made of. Give me a few tips on how to improve reading skills. ","answer":"Reading skills are the abilities that allow us to read and understand written text. They include a variety of sub-skills, such as:Decoding: The ability to identify and pronounce words.Fluency: The ability to read smoothly and accurately at a pace that allows us to understand the text.Vocabulary: The knowledge of the meaning of words.Comprehension: The ability to understand the meaning of text, including the main ideas, supporting details, and inferences.Critical thinking: The ability to think about and evaluate the text, including its purpose, author's point of view, and evidence.Text structure: The ability to identify the different parts of a text and how they are organized.Inference: The ability to make logical deductions from the text.Summarization: The ability to condense the text into a brief, accurate statement of the main points.Visualization: The ability to create mental images of the events or scenes described in the text.These skills are all interrelated and work together to allow us to read and understand written text. The more developed our reading skills are, the better we will be able to read and understand a variety of texts, from simple stories to complex textbooks. There are many things we can do to improve our reading skills. Here are a few tips:Read often: The more we read, the better our reading skills will become.Read a variety of texts: This will help us to develop a broad range of reading skills.Read challenging texts: This will help us to push ourselves and improve our skills.Take breaks: Don't try to read for too long at a time without taking a break.Ask questions: If we don't understand something, don't be afraid to ask questions.Talk about what we read: This will help us to solidify our understanding of the text.Reading skills are an essential part of learning and communication. By developing our reading skills, we can open up a world of knowledge and opportunity."},{"question":"Awọn ọmọọta dana sun agọ ọlọpaa Apapa-Iganmu","answer":"Ni nnkan bii aago mẹsan-an aarọ yii ni awọn ọmọọta kọ lu agọ ọlọpaa to wa ni Orile Iganmu, ti wọn si dana sun un.Awọn ọmọọta to ṣiṣẹ ibi naa ko fu awọn ọlọpaa to wa ni teṣan ọhun lara rara ti wọn fi sọna si i, ti ina naa si n jo ni koṣẹ koṣẹ. Wọn ti ranṣẹ pe awọn panapana lati waa dẹkun ina naa."},{"question":"Sana'ar Sassaƙa a ƙasar Hausa. ","answer":"A cikin sauƙaƙƙiyar Hausa, muna iya kiran sassaƙa da kafintanci. Sassaƙa sana’a ce da ake fiƙe itace ko a kankare shi don a mayar da shi abin amfani. Masu yin wannan sana’a su ake kira masassaƙa."},{"question":"Regl döneminde ameliyata girilir mi?","answer":"Regl dönemi ortopedik veya beyin cerrahi ameliyatınız için engel teşkil etmemektedir. Ancak kullanılan ilaçlar mutlaka gözden geçirilmektedir. Hastanemizde yapılan ameliyatlar açısından adet döneminde olmanız tıbbi olarak engel oluşturmamaktadır."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਗਉੜੀ ਮਹਲਾ ੩ ॥ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਸੇਵਾ ਪ੍ਰਾਨ ਅਧਾਰਾ ॥ਹਰਿ ਜੀਉ ਰਾਖਹੁ ਹਿਰਦੈ ਉਰ ਧਾਰਾ ॥ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਸੋਭਾ ਸਾਚ ਦੁਆਰਾ ॥੧॥ਪੰਡਿਤ ਹਰਿ ਪੜੁ ਤਜਹੁ ਵਿਕਾਰਾ ॥ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਭਉਜਲੁ ਉਤਰਹੁ ਪਾਰਾ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਵਿਚਹੁ ਹਉਮੈ ਜਾਇ ॥ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਮੈਲੁ ਨ ਲਾਗੈ ਆਇ ॥ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਨਾਮੁ ਵਸੈ ਮਨਿ ਆਇ ॥੨॥ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਕਰਮ ਧਰਮ ਸਚਿ ਹੋਈ ॥ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਅਹੰਕਾਰੁ ਜਲਾਏ ਦੋਈ ॥ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਨਾਮਿ ਰਤੇ ਸੁਖੁ ਹੋਈ ॥੩॥ਆਪਣਾ ਮਨੁ ਪਰਬੋਧਹੁ ਬੂਝਹੁ ਸੋਈ ॥ਲੋਕ ਸਮਝਾਵਹੁ ਸੁਣੇ ਨ ਕੋਈ ॥ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਸਮਝਹੁ ਸਦਾ ਸੁਖੁ ਹੋਈ ॥੪॥ਮਨਮੁਖਿ ਡੰਫੁ ਬਹੁਤੁ ਚਤੁਰਾਈ ॥ਜੋ ਕਿਛੁ ਕਮਾਵੈ ਸੁ ਥਾਇ ਨ ਪਾਈ ॥ਆਵੈ ਜਾਵੈ ਠਉਰ ਨ ਕਾਈ ॥੫॥ਮਨਮੁਖ ਕਰਮ ਕਰੇ ਬਹੁਤੁ ਅਭਿਮਾਨਾ ॥ਬਗ ਜਿਉ ਲਾਇ ਬਹੈ ਨਿਤ ਧਿਆਨਾ ॥ਜਮਿ ਪਕੜਿਆ ਤਬ ਹੀ ਪਛੁਤਾਨਾ ॥੬॥ਬਿਨੁ ਸਤਿਗੁਰ ਸੇਵੇ ਮੁਕਤਿ ਨ ਹੋਈ ॥ਗੁਰ ਪਰਸਾਦੀ ਮਿਲੈ ਹਰਿ ਸੋਈ ॥ਗੁਰੁ ਦਾਤਾ ਜੁਗ ਚਾਰੇ ਹੋਈ ॥੭॥ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਜਾਤਿ ਪਤਿ ਨਾਮੇ ਵਡਿਆਈ ॥ਸਾਇਰ ਕੀ ਪੁਤ੍ਰੀ ਬਿਦਾਰਿ ਗਵਾਈ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਬਿਨੁ ਨਾਵੈ ਝੂਠੀ ਚਤੁਰਾਈ ॥੮॥੨॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 229 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਮਰਦਾਸ ਜੀ ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਵਾਰਾਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਸਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"(ਹੇ ਪੰਡਿਤ!) ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸਨਮੁਖ ਹੋ ਕੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਸੇਵਾ-ਭਗਤੀ ਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੇ ਜੀਵਨ ਦਾ ਆਸਰਾ ਬਣਾ, ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੇ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਟਿਕਾ ਕੇ ਰੱਖ, (ਹੇ ਪੰਡਿਤ!) ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪੈ ਕੇ ਤੂੰ ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਦਰ ਤੇ ਵਡਿਆਈ ਹਾਸਲ ਕਰੇਂਗਾ ।੧।ਹੇ ਪੰਡਿਤ! ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਪੜ੍ਹ (ਅਤੇ ਇਸ ਦੀ ਬਰਕਤਿ ਨਾਲ ਆਪਣੇ ਅੰਦਰੋਂ) ਵਿਕਾਰ ਛੱਡ । (ਹੇ ਪੰਡਿਤ!) ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪੈ ਕੇ ਤੂੰ ਸੰਸਾਰ-ਸਮੁੰਦਰ ਤੋਂ ਪਾਰ ਲੰਘ ਜਾਏਂਗਾ ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ।(ਹੇ ਪੰਡਿਤ!) ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪਿਆਂ ਮਨ ਵਿਚੋਂ ਹਉਮੈ ਦੂਰ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ, ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪਿਆਂ (ਮਨ ਨੂੰ ਹਉਮੈ ਦੀ) ਮੈਲ ਆ ਕੇ ਨਹੀਂ ਚੰਬੜਦੀ (ਕਿਉਂਕਿ) ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪਿਆਂ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਆ ਵੱਸਦਾ ਹੈ ।੨।(ਹੇ ਪੰਡਿਤ!) ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸਨਮੁਖ ਰਿਹਾਂ ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਵਿਚ ਲੀਨਤਾ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ (ਤੇ ਇਹੀ ਹੈ ਅਸਲੀ) ਕਰਮ ਧਰਮ । ਜੇਹੜਾ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਉਹ (ਆਪਣੇ ਅੰਦਰੋਂ) ਅਹੰਕਾਰ ਤੇ ਮੇਰ-ਤੇਰ ਸਾੜ ਦੇਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਵਿਚ ਰੰਗੇ ਜਾ ਕੇ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸਨਮੁਖ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੂੰ ਆਤਮਕ ਆਨੰਦ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ।੩। (ਹੇ ਪੰਡਿਤ! ਪਹਿਲਾਂ) ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਨੂੰ ਜਗਾਓ ਤੇ ਉਸ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਹਸਤੀ ਨੂੰ ਸਮਝੋ । (ਹੇ ਪੰਡਿਤ! ਤੁਹਾਡਾ ਆਪਣਾ ਮਨ ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਮੋਹ ਵਿਚ ਸੁੱਤਾ ਪਿਆ ਹੈ, ਪਰ) ਤੁਸੀ ਲੋਕਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਸਿੱਖਿਆ ਦੇਂਦੇ ਹੋ (ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਕਦੇ) ਕੋਈ ਮਨੁੱਖ (ਸਿੱਖਿਆ) ਨਹੀਂ ਸੁਣਦਾ । ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪੈ ਕੇ ਤੁਸੀ ਆਪ (ਸਹੀ ਜੀਵਨ-ਰਸਤਾ) ਸਮਝੋ, ਤੁਹਾਨੂੰ ਸਦਾ ਆਤਮਕ ਆਨੰਦ ਮਿਲੇਗਾ ।੪। (ਹੇ ਪੰਡਿਤ!) ਆਪਣੇ ਹੀ ਮਨ ਦੇ ਪਿੱਛੇ ਤੁਰਨ ਵਾਲਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ (ਧਾਰਮਿਕ) ਵਿਖਾਵਾ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਬੜੀ ਚਤੁਰਾਈ ਵਿਖਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ (ਪਰ ਜੋ ਕੁਝ ਉਹ) ਆਪ (ਅਮਲੀ ਜੀਵਨ) ਕਮਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਉਹ (ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀਆਂ ਨਜ਼ਰਾਂ ਵਿਚ) ਪਰਵਾਨ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੁੰਦਾ,ਉਹ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਜਨਮ ਮਰਨ ਦੇ ਗੇੜ ਵਿਚ ਪਿਆ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਆਤਮਕ ਸ਼ਾਂਤੀ ਦੀ ਕੋਈ ਥਾਂ ਨਹੀਂ ਮਿਲਦੀ ।੫।ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਦੇ ਪਿੱਛੇ ਤੁਰਨ ਵਾਲਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ (ਆਪਣੇ ਵਲੋਂ ਧਾਰਮਿਕ) ਕਰਮ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ (ਪਰ ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਅੰਦਰ ਬਹੁਤ ਮਾਣ ਪੈਦਾ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਸਦਾ ਬਗਲੇ ਵਾਂਗ ਹੀ ਸਮਾਧੀ ਲਾ ਕੇ ਬੈਠਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਉਹ ਤਦੋਂ ਹੀ ਪਛੁਤਾਵੇਗਾ ਜਦੋਂ ਮੌਤ ਨੇ (ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਸਿਰੋਂ ਆ) ਫੜਿਆ ।੬।(ਹੇ ਪੰਡਿਤ!) ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪੈਣ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ (ਦੰਭ ਆਦਿਕ ਤੋਂ) ਖ਼ਲਾਸੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੁੰਦੀ । ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਨਾਲ ਹੀ ਉਹ (ਘਟ ਘਟ ਦੀ ਜਾਣਨ ਵਾਲਾ) ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਮਿਲਦਾ ਹੈ । (ਹੇ ਪੰਡਿਤ! ਸਤਜੁਗ ਕਲਜੁਗ ਆਖ ਆਖ ਕੇ ਕਿਸੇ ਜੁਗ ਦੇ ਜ਼ਿੰਮੇ ਬੁਰਾਈ ਲਾ ਕੇ ਗ਼ਲਤੀ ਨਾਹ ਖਾਹ) ਚੌਹਾਂ ਜੁਗਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਗੁਰੂ ਹੀ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਦੀ ਦਾਤਿ ਦੇਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਹੈ ।੭।(ਹੇ ਪੰਡਿਤ!) ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪੈਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਮਨੱੁਖ ਵਾਸਤੇ ਹਰਿ-ਨਾਮ ਹੀ ਉੱਚੀ ਜਾਤਿ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਉੱਚੀ ਕੁਲ ਹੈ, ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਵਿਚ ਉਹ ਆਪਣੀ ਇੱਜ਼ਤ ਮੰਨਦਾ ਹੈ । ਨਾਮਿ ਦੀ ਬਰਕਤਿ ਨਾਲ ਹੀ ਉਸ ਨੇ ਮਾਇਆ ਦਾ ਪ੍ਰਭਾਵ (ਆਪਣੇ ਅੰਦਰੋਂ) ਕੱਟ ਕੇ ਪਰੇ ਰੱਖ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਹੈ ।ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ! (ਆਖ—ਹੇ ਪੰਡਿਤ!) ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਤੋਂ ਵਾਂਜੇ ਰਹਿ ਕੇ ਹੋਰ ਹੋਰ ਚਤੁਰਾਈ ਵਿਖਾਣੀ ਵਿਅਰਥ ਹੈ ।੮।੨।\\""},{"question":"N.P.P.P.P Waxa uu ka mid ahaa xisbiyadii jirey xornimada ka hor. Sheeg erayada Luuqadda Ingiriiska ee laga soo gaabiyey?","answer":"Waxaa laga soo gaabiyey “Northern  Province People’s Progressive Party”"},{"question":"Skriv en fortsättning på den här paragrafen - Serien utspelar sig i huset \\"165 Eaton Place\\" i London, där parlamentsledamoten Richard Bellamy bor med sin hustru Lady Marjorie och deras barn. I huset finns en rad av tjänstefolk, från den mycket korrekte Mr Hudson och den bistra Mrs Bridges via den rättrådiga kammarjungfrun Rose, till","answer":"den hunsade kökspigan Ruby. I seriens början är året 1903 och i sista avsnittet har man hunnit fram till 1930. Serien har med viktiga historiska händelser under 1900-talet, som bland annat förlisningen av Titanic (1912), första världskriget (1914–1918) och börskraschen på Wall Street 1929."},{"question":"வினா : சிறுகதையின் தோற்றமும் வளர்ச்சியும் குறித்து கட்டுரை வரைக.","answer":"விடை : சிறுகதையின் தோற்றமும் வளர்ச்சியும்முன்னுரைஉலகத்தில் தோன்றிய அனைத்து சமூகங்களிலும் கதை சொல்லுதல், கேட்டல் என்ற வாய்மொழி மரபு காணப்பட்டே வந்துள்ளது. இந்த மரபின் மூலமாகவே சிறுகதைகளின் எழுத்துருவும் தோற்றம் கண்டுள்ளது. அந்த வகையில் நாம் இக்கட்டுரையில் தமிழ் சிறுகதைகளைப் பற்றி முதன்மையாக நோக்கலாம்.தமிழ் சிறுகதைகளின் தோற்றம்மேலைத்தேய தொடர்புகளின் காரணமாக தமிழ் மொழியிலும் புதிய இலக்கிய வகைகள் உட்புகுந்தன. அவ்வாறே சிறுகதை எழுத்துருவாக்கமும் இடம்பெற்றுள்ளது.அதாவது 19ஆம் நூற்றாண்டில் ஆங்கில மொழியின் வருகையோடு, அச்சு இயந்திர பாவனையும் அதிகரித்தமையினால் இந்த வாய்மொழியில் இருந்த சிறுகதைகள் எழுத்துருவுக்கு கொண்டுவரப்பட்டன.அதன் அடிப்படையில் வா.வே.சு.ஐயரினால் எழுதப்பட்ட “குளத்தங்கரை ஆலமரம்” என்பது தமிழின் முதல் சிறுகதையாக காணப்படுகின்றது.சிறுகதைக்கான இலக்கணம்“செட்ஜ்விக்” என்பவர் குறிப்பிடுகையில் ஒரு சிறுகதையின் தொடக்கமும் முடிவும் குதிரை பந்தயம் போல் அமைய வேண்டும் என்கிறார்.இன்னும் கூறுவோமே ஆனால் 3000 சொற்களுக்கு மேற்படாததாகவும், அரை மணி நேரத்துக்குள் வாசித்து முடிக்க கூடியதாகவும் இந்த சிறுகதைகள் அமைய வேண்டும். மேலும் சுருங்கச் சொல்லுதலும், சொல்ல வந்த விடயத்தை தெளிவாக சொல்லுதலும் இச்சிறுகதைகளுக்கான உத்திகள் ஆகும்.சிறுகதைகளின் வளர்ச்சிக்கான காரணங்கள்சிறுகதை வளர்ச்சி பெறுவதற்கு மிகவும் முக்கியமான காரணம் எழுத்தாளர்கள் ஆகும். அந்த வகையில் கல்கி, பிச்சமூர்த்தி, ராஜகோபாலன் போன்றோர் தமிழ் சிறுகதையின் வளர்ச்சிக்கு பங்காற்றியவர்களாவர்.மேலும் பல்வேறு இதழ்கள் சிறுகதை போட்டிகளை உருவாக்கி அதற்கான பரிசீல்களை வழங்குவதன் மூலமும், இன்று தொழில்நுட்பத்தின் வளர்ச்சியின் காரணமாக இணையதளம், அலைபேசிகளின் மூலமாகவும் சிறுகதைகள் வளர்ச்சி கண்டு வருவதனை காணலாம்.உலகளாவிய ரீதியில் சிறுகதைகளின் வளர்ச்சிஉலக நாடுகளைப் பொறுத்த வரையில் அமெரிக்காவிலேயே சிறுகதைகள் மிகவும் விருப்பமான இலக்கிய வடிவமாக காணப்படுகின்றது.நத்தானியன்ஸ் ஹாதான், வாஷிங்டன் இர்விங் மற்றும் ஒஹென்றி போன்றோர்கள் அமெரிக்காவில் சிறுகதை வளர்ச்சிக்கு பங்காற்றியுள்ளார்.மெரிமீ, பால்ஸாக்,மாப்பசான் போன்றோர் பிரான்சிய சிறுகதை வளர்ச்சிக்கு பங்காற்றி உள்ளனர்.ஜோசப் கான்ராட், ஹென்றி ஜேம்ஸ், ஜேம்ஸ் ஜாய்ஸ் போன்ற எழுத்தாளர்களும், ஸ்டான்ட், ஆர்கஸி, பியர்சன்ஸ் மெகசின் போன்ற இதழ்களும் இங்கிலாந்தின் சிறுகதை வளர்ச்சிக்கு பங்காற்றி உள்ளன. இவ்வாறு ஆசிய நாடுகளிலும் ஆப்பிரிக்க நாடுகளிலும் சிறுகதை வளர்ச்சி அடைந்தே வருகின்றது.முடிவுரைகாலத்துக்கு ஏற்ப வளர்ச்சி கண்டு வருகின்ற இந்த சிறுகதைகள் இன்றைய அவசர காலங்களுக்கு ஏற்ப ஒரு பக்க அல்லது அரை பக்க அளவிலான மைக்ரோ சிறுகதைகளாகவும் வரத் தொடங்கியுள்ளன. உலகளாவிய ரீதியில் சிறுகதைகளுக்கான தனித்துவமான ஓர் இடம் உண்டு.அதன் காரணமாகவே இன்று சிறுகதைகள் இணையதளங்களிலும் வளம் வருவதனை காண முடிகின்றது. எனவே சிறுகதைகளின் வளர்ச்சி காலத்துக்கு ஏற்ப வளர்ந்து கொண்டே செல்லும் என குறிப்பிடலாம்."},{"question":"Эндоплазмалык тордун клеткалардагы ролу кандай жана ал белок синтезине кандай салым кошот?","answer":"Эндоплазмалык ретикулум (ЭР) клеткалардын ичиндеги белоктун синтезине жана липиддердин алмашуусуна катышат. Ал белоктордун бүктөлүшүнө, өзгөрүшүнө жана ташууларына жардам берет."},{"question":"ನನಗೆ ಕೆಲವು ಆರ್ಥಿಕ ಸಲಹೆಗಳನ್ನು ಒದಗಿಸಿ","answer":"ಖಂಡಿತ, ನಾನು ನಿಮಗೆ ನೀಡಬಹುದಾದ ಕೆಲವು ಆರ್ಥಿಕ ಸಲಹೆಗಳು ಇಲ್ಲಿವೆ:1. ಬಜೆಟ್ ರಚಿಸಿ ಮತ್ತು ಅದಕ್ಕೆ ಅಂಟಿಕೊಳ್ಳಿ. ಇದು ನಿಮಗೆ ಯಾರಾದರೂ ನೀಡಬಹುದಾದ ಪ್ರಮುಖ ಆರ್ಥಿಕ ಸಲಹೆಯಾಗಿದೆ. ನಿಮ್ಮ ಹಣಕಾಸಿನ ಗುರಿಗಳನ್ನು ತಲುಪಲು ನೀವು ಟ್ರ್ಯಾಕ್‌ನಲ್ಲಿರುವಿರಿ ಎಂದು ಖಚಿತಪಡಿಸಿಕೊಳ್ಳಲು ನಿಮ್ಮ ಹಣ ಎಲ್ಲಿಗೆ ಹೋಗುತ್ತಿದೆ ಎಂಬುದನ್ನು ತಿಳಿದುಕೊಳ್ಳುವುದು ಅತ್ಯಗತ್ಯ.2. ಸಾಲವನ್ನು ಆದಷ್ಟು ಬೇಗ ತೀರಿಸಿ. ಕ್ರೆಡಿಟ್ ಕಾರ್ಡ್ ಸಾಲದಂತಹ ಹೆಚ್ಚಿನ-ಬಡ್ಡಿ ಸಾಲವು ನಿಮ್ಮ ಹಣಕಾಸಿನ ಮೇಲೆ ಪ್ರಮುಖ ಡ್ರೈನ್ ಆಗಿರಬಹುದು. ಈ ಸಾಲವನ್ನು ಸಾಧ್ಯವಾದಷ್ಟು ಬೇಗ ಪಾವತಿಸಲು ಆದ್ಯತೆ ನೀಡಿ, ಇದರಿಂದ ನೀವು ಬಡ್ಡಿಯ ಮೇಲೆ ಹಣವನ್ನು ಉಳಿಸಬಹುದು ಮತ್ತು ಇತರ ಗುರಿಗಳಿಗಾಗಿ ಹೂಡಿಕೆ ಮಾಡಲು ಅಥವಾ ಉಳಿಸಲು ಹೆಚ್ಚಿನ ಹಣವನ್ನು ಹೊಂದಿರಬಹುದು.3. ಮುಂಚಿತವಾಗಿ ನಿವೃತ್ತಿಗಾಗಿ ಉಳಿಸಿ. ನೀವು ಎಷ್ಟು ಮುಂಚಿತವಾಗಿ ನಿವೃತ್ತಿಗಾಗಿ ಉಳಿತಾಯವನ್ನು ಪ್ರಾರಂಭಿಸುತ್ತೀರೋ, ನಿಮ್ಮ ಹಣವು ಹೆಚ್ಚು ಸಮಯ ಬೆಳೆಯಬೇಕಾಗುತ್ತದೆ. ನೀವು ಪ್ರತಿ ತಿಂಗಳು ಒಂದು ಸಣ್ಣ ಮೊತ್ತವನ್ನು ಮಾತ್ರ ಉಳಿಸಬಹುದಾದರೂ, ಅದು ಕಾಲಾನಂತರದಲ್ಲಿ ಸೇರಿಸಲ್ಪಡುತ್ತದೆ.4. ದೀರ್ಘಾವಧಿಗೆ ಹೂಡಿಕೆ ಮಾಡಿ. ನೀವು ದೀರ್ಘಾವಧಿಗೆ ಹೂಡಿಕೆ ಮಾಡಿದಾಗ, ನಿಮ್ಮ ಹಣವನ್ನು ಬೆಳೆಯಲು ಮತ್ತು ಸಂಯೋಜಿಸಲು ಸಮಯವನ್ನು ನೀಡುತ್ತೀರಿ. ಇದರರ್ಥ ನಿಮ್ಮ ಹಣವು ಬಡ್ಡಿಯ ಮೇಲೆ ಬಡ್ಡಿಯನ್ನು ಗಳಿಸುತ್ತದೆ, ಇದು ನಿಮ್ಮ ಹಣಕಾಸಿನ ಗುರಿಗಳನ್ನು ವೇಗವಾಗಿ ತಲುಪಲು ಸಹಾಯ ಮಾಡುತ್ತದೆ. 5. ನಿಮ್ಮ ಹೂಡಿಕೆಗಳನ್ನು ವೈವಿಧ್ಯಗೊಳಿಸಿ. ನಿಮ್ಮ ಎಲ್ಲಾ ಮೊಟ್ಟೆಗಳನ್ನು ಒಂದೇ ಬುಟ್ಟಿಯಲ್ಲಿ ಹಾಕಬೇಡಿ. ನಿಮ್ಮ ಹೂಡಿಕೆಗಳನ್ನು ವೈವಿಧ್ಯಗೊಳಿಸುವ ಮೂಲಕ, ಒಂದು ಹೂಡಿಕೆಯು ಮೌಲ್ಯವನ್ನು ಕಳೆದುಕೊಂಡರೆ ನಿಮ್ಮ ಅಪಾಯವನ್ನು ನೀವು ಕಡಿಮೆಗೊಳಿಸುತ್ತೀರಿ. 6. ವೃತ್ತಿಪರ ಆರ್ಥಿಕ ಸಲಹೆ ಪಡೆಯಿರಿ. ನಿಮ್ಮ ಹಣಕಾಸು ನಿರ್ವಹಿಸಲು ಅಥವಾ ನಿಮ್ಮ ಹಣಕಾಸಿನ ಗುರಿಗಳನ್ನು ತಲುಪಲು ನೀವು ಹೆಣಗಾಡುತ್ತಿದ್ದರೆ, ವೃತ್ತಿಪರ ಆರ್ಥಿಕ ಸಲಹೆಯನ್ನು ಪಡೆದುಕೊಳ್ಳಿ. ಹಣಕಾಸು ಸಲಹೆಗಾರರು ನಿಮಗೆ ಬಜೆಟ್ ರಚಿಸಲು, ಸಾಲವನ್ನು ಪಾವತಿಸಲು, ನಿವೃತ್ತಿಗಾಗಿ ಉಳಿಸಲು ಮತ್ತು ಭವಿಷ್ಯಕ್ಕಾಗಿ ಹೂಡಿಕೆ ಮಾಡಲು ಸಹಾಯ ಮಾಡಬಹುದು.ಇವುಗಳು ನಾನು ನಿಮಗೆ ನೀಡಬಹುದಾದ ಕೆಲವು ಆರ್ಥಿಕ ಸಲಹೆಗಳಾಗಿವೆ. ನಿಮ್ಮ ಆರ್ಥಿಕ ಆರೋಗ್ಯವನ್ನು ಸುಧಾರಿಸಲು ನೀವು ಮಾಡಬಹುದಾದ ಇತರ ಹಲವು ವಿಷಯಗಳಿವೆ. ಕ್ರಿಯೆಯನ್ನು ಪ್ರಾರಂಭಿಸುವುದು ಮತ್ತು ನಿಮ್ಮ ಆರ್ಥಿಕ ಭವಿಷ್ಯಕ್ಕಾಗಿ ಯೋಜನೆಯನ್ನು ಮಾಡುವುದು ಅತ್ಯಂತ ಮುಖ್ಯವಾದ ವಿಷಯವಾಗಿದೆ."},{"question":"පරිමේය සංඛ්‍යා යනු මොනවාද?","answer":"භාග සංඛ්‍යාවක හරයේ සහ ලවයේ නිඛිල ඇති විට (තවද හරයේ 0 නොමැති විය යුතු වේ) ඒවා පරිමේය සංඛ්‍යා ලෙස හැඳින්වේ."},{"question":"Ci gan kembaar la réewum Jordanie nékk?","answer":"Réewum Jordanie mu ngi nékk ci kembaar bi ñuy wax Asie."},{"question":"ගොයම් කවියක්  සඳහා   උදහරණයක් දෙන්න ","answer":"බු දු න් තිලෝකෙට උත්තම ව න්නේයොදුන් ගණන් බුදු රැස් විහි දෙ න්නේස ඳු න් සුවඳ මුල්පුදකර ව න්නේබු දු න් සරණ සිහි කර කිය මි න්නේ"},{"question":"इस विस्तृत प्रश्न का उत्तर तैयार कीजिए: तारकीय न्यूक्लियोसिंथेसिस के सिद्धांत को तैयार करने वाले खगोलविद ने किस ऐतिहासिक पेपर का सह-लेखन किया?","answer":"उन्होंने 'सिंथेसिस ऑफ़ द एलिमेंट्स इन स्टार्स' पेपर का सह-लेखन किया था, जिसे 'बी-२.एफ़.एच' के नाम से भी जाना जाता है।  "},{"question":"قال تعالى(قولوا أمنا بالله ومآ أنزل إلى إبراهيم وإسماعيل وإسحاق ويعقوب والأسباط) سورة البقرة(136) المقصود بـ(الأسباط)…؟","answer":"الحفدة ديال يعقوب عليه السلام"},{"question":"电风扇的工作原理是什么？","answer":"答：电风扇的工作原理主要是通过电动机的旋转，驱动风扇叶片产生风力。当电流通过电动机时，会产生磁场，驱动电动机的转子旋转，然后通过齿轮或直接连接，使风扇叶片旋转，从而产生风力。"},{"question":"වර්තමානයේදී \\" ඊස්වාතීනි රාජ්‍යය \\" ලෙස නම භාවිතාකරන අප්‍රිකානු රට , අතීතයේදී හැඳින්වූ නම කුමක්ද ?","answer":"ස්වාසීලන්තය"},{"question":"فين كايعيش أصغر انواع التماسيح؟","answer":"فنهر الكونغو بأفريقيا و الطول ديالو 120 سم."},{"question":"野球は９人、サッカーは１１人、バスケットボールは５人。ではラグビーは１チーム何人？","answer":"１５人です。"},{"question":"Mikä on dengue?","answer":"Dengue on dengueviruksen aiheuttama kuumetauti, jota esiintyy laajasti maapallon trooppisilla sekä subtrooppisilla alueilla. Denguevirusta on olemassa neljää eri serotyyppiä. Virus kuuluu flavivirusten sukuun, johon kuuluvat myös muun muassa TBE-virus, zikavirus sekä Länsi-Niilin virus. Flavivirusten isäntinä toimivat ihmiset ja muut nisäkkäät, mutta ne leviävät isännästä toiseen pääasiassa hyttysten välityksellä. Denguevirus onkin siirtynyt muun muassa zikaviruksen tapaan apinoista ihmiseen."},{"question":"Waxaad Sheegtaa garoonka Kubada Cagta Ee Stadium Moqdisho Dalkii Dhisay?","answer":"Garoonka Kubada Cagta Ee Stadium Moqdisho Waxa Dhisay Dalka Shiinaha (China)."},{"question":"ශ්‍රී ලංකා‍වේ බුදු පිළිම ගැන විස්තර කරන්න.","answer":"ථෙරවාද බෞද්ධ සම්ප්‍රදායට අයත් විශිෂ්ට ගණයේ බුද්ධ ප්‍රතිමා ලැබෙන්නේ ශ්‍රි ලංකාවෙනි. ලංකා බුදු පිළිමය ආන්ද්‍ර ශෛලියේ ආභාසය ලබා ප්‍රභවය වූවක් බව සාමාන්‍ය පිළිගැනීමයි.එසේ වුවද බුදු පිළිමය මුලින්ම පහල වූයේ භාරතයේ නොව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ යැයිද එහෙයින් එය ස්වාධීන කෘතියක් යැයි සිතන්නෝද වෙති. සිංහල බුද්ධ ප්‍රතිමා ශිල්පීහු සිය නිර්මාණයන්ට දේශීයත්වය සමාරෝපණය කළහ. මුල් යුගයේ සිට දහ වැනි සියවස දක්වා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ නෙළන ලද බුදු පිළිම වලින් අධිකතර සංඛ්‍යාවක් සිංහල නිර්මාණ ශිල්පීන්ගේ යැයි වෙසෙසා හැඳින්වීමට ප්‍රමාණවත් දේශීය ලක්ෂණ වලින් පරිපෝෂිතය. මුල් අවධියේ ලක්දිව බුදු පිළිම වලට මහායාන ආභාසය ලැබී ඇත්තේ අල්ප වශයෙනි.මෙයට ප්‍රබල හේතුව එකල අනුරාධපුර මහා විහාර සම්ප්‍රදාය අතිශයින් ප්‍රබලව පැවතීමය. මහා විහාර සම්ප්‍රදාය මහායානය දැඩිව ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කළේය. පොළොන්නරු අවධියේ සිට මහායාන බලපෑම වැඩි වශයෙන් සිදු වීම නිසා බුදු පිළිමය විෂයෙහිද ඒ ආභාසය දක්නට ලැබේ. එහි ප්‍රතිඵලයක් වශයෙන් ඒ ප්‍රතිමා වල විදේශීය ලක්ෂණද දක්නට ලැබේ.පිළිම වර්ගශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ නිමැවුණු බුදු පිළිම ඒවායේ ඉරියව් අනුව ප්‍රධාන කොටස් තුනකට වෙන් කළ හැකිය.1.හිඳි පිළිම2.හිටි පිළිම3.සැතපෙන පිළිමයනුවෙනි.බුදු පිළිම මුද්‍රාසෑම බුදු පිළිමයක්ම කිසියම් මුද්‍රාවකට අනුව සිදු කර ඇත.කලාතුරකින් ප්‍රතිමාවක මුද්‍රා ලක්ෂණ දෙකක් දැක ගැනීමට පුලුවන.සාම්ප්‍රදායික වශයෙන් පොදු සම්මුතියට පත් මුද්‍රා හයකි.සමාධි මුද්‍රාවමුද්‍රා වර්ගවීරාසන ‍හෝ පද්මාසන ශෛලියෙන් හිඳ උඩ අතට හැර වූ වම් අත්ල මත දකුණු අත්ල පිහිටුවා වැඩ සිටී.උඩු කය කෙලින් තබාගෙන සිටී.කමටහනට සිත යොමු කරගෙන සිටී. මහා කරැණාවේත් මහා ප්‍ර‍ඥාවේත් උත්තරීතර අවස්ථාවයි.ධර්ම චක්‍ර මුද්‍රාවබුදු හිමියනගේ ධර්ම දේශනා විලාසය සංකේතවත් කරනු ලබන මුද්‍රාවයි.දකුණු අත්ල පිටතට හරවා පපුවේ මට්ටමට තබාගෙන,එහි දබර ඇඟිල්ලෙන් හා මහපට ඇඟිල්ලේ තුඩු දෙක කවයක් සෑදෙන සේ එකට තබා ඇතුළට හැරැණු වම් අතේ ඇඟිල්ලක් ස්පර්ශ කරන අයුරින් පැවතීම ධර්ම චක්‍ර මුද්‍රාවේ ලක්ෂණයයි.අභය මුද්‍රාවදකුණු අත උඩට නවා ඇඟිලි සම්පූර්ණයෙන්ම දිග හැර,අත්ල ඉදිරිපසට සිටින සේ විවෘතව තැබීම අභය මුද්‍රාවේ සාමාන්‍ය ලක්ෂණයයි.එහි සංකේතාර්ථය නිර්භයත්වය හෝ අභය දීමයි.විතර්ක මුද්‍රාවඅත්ල පපු පෙදෙසට ප්‍රමාණ වන පරිදි දකුණු අත උඩට නවා,දබර ඇඟිල්ල මාපට ඇඟිල්ල උඩට කවයක් ඇති වන ආකාරයෙන් තබා සිටීම මෙහි ලක්ෂණයයි.බුදු හිමි විවිධ පුද්ගලයන් සමඟ වාද විවාද පැවැත්වූ අවස්ථාව මෙයින් සංකේතවත් වේ.භූමි ස්පර්ශ මුද්‍රාවඑනම් පොළොව ස්පර්ශ කිරීම යන්නය.දකුණු අත දකුණු දණ හිස උඩින් අත්ල ඇතුළතට සිටින අයුරින් සියලු ඇඟිලි දිගහැර පහතට යොමුව තිබීම මෙහි ලක්ෂණයයි.බුදු සිරිත හා බැඳුණු මාර පරාජයේදී බුදුන් වහන්සේ මිහිකත වෙත අත දිගු කොට සාක්ෂ්‍ය එළ වූ අයුරු මෙයින් ප්‍රකාශිත වේ.වරද මුද්‍රාවදකුණත පහත් කොට,ඉදිරියට දිග හැර,අත්ල ඉදිරියට හරවා ඇඟිලි දිග හැර තිබීම මෙම මුද්‍රාවේ ලක්ෂණයයි.බෙහෙවින්ම මෙම ලක්ෂණය හිටි පිළිම වල දක්නට ලැ‍බේ."},{"question":"次の文章を読んで、その内容に適したタイトルを付けてください： 福島県福島市の飯野町は、UFOを見たという情報が多くて、UFOに関係がある建物などをつくってPRしています。このようなPRを始めてから去年30年になりました。福島市は、飯野町にある山の上に、空に向かって強い光を出すライトを置きました。宇宙にメッセージを送っているような光です。ライトは縦と横が30cmぐらいの四角形で3つあります。必要な電気は太陽の光からつくります。夕方暗くなってから1時間ぐらいライトがつくと、UFOを呼んでいるような不思議な空になります。福島市によると、UFOに興味がある人たちなどがSNSでライトのことを伝えています。飯野UFOふれあい館の人は「この光を見てUFOが来てくれたらうれしいです。暗い道に気をつけて光を見に来てください」と話しています。","answer":"福島市　UFOに光でメッセージを送るようなライト"},{"question":"Nyatakan subjek dan predikat bagi ayat tersebut: Bangunan itu bangunan Kementerian Pendidikan.","answer":"Subjek: Bangunan ituPredikat: bangunan Kementerian Pendidikan"},{"question":"كمل الحكي:\\"صح عيد ميلادك قرب طيب، إمك وأبوك بيوافقوا؟\\"","answer":"\\"أنا مش ولد صغير. صار عمري ٣٠ سنة، وبعدين إنت معي.\\""},{"question":"🇰🇬 Манас эпосу 📚Чоң казатта чалгынга Манас минген ат 🐎 кайсы?а) Тайкүрөң б) Мааникерв) Аймаңбоз г) Аккула","answer":"🇰🇬 Манас эпосу 📚в) Аймаңбоз "},{"question":"மணியம்மையின் மேற்கோள் ஒன்றினைத்தரவும்.","answer":"எப்படியும் நம்மை ஒழித்துக் கட்டிவிட எதிரிகள் நம்மீது ஒரு கண் வைத்துக் கொண்டுதான் இருக்கிறார்கள். தோழர்களே, நீங்கள் தற்காத்துக் கொள்ள உடற்பயிற்சிகளை மேற்கொள்வீர்களாக!"},{"question":"*كم مرة وردت (فبأي آلاء ربكما تكذبان ) في سورة الرحمن ؟","answer":"31 مرة"},{"question":"Fenoy ny banga_\\"Ataovy fihavanam-bava sy tanana: raha marary ny tanana _ ny vava, ary raha marary ny vava _ ny tanana.\\"","answer":"Ataovy fihavanam-bava sy tanana: raha marary ny tanana mitsoka ny vava, ary raha marary ny vava manafosafo ny tanana."},{"question":"செயற்கை உரம் என்றால் என்ன?  செயற்கை உரங்களைப் பயன்படுத்துவதால் ஏற்படும் விளைவுகளை குறிப்பிடுக.","answer":"  செயற்கை உரம் என்றால் என்ன?       செயற்கை உரம் என்பது தாவர உணவாகும், இது மேக்ரோநியூட்ரியண்ட்களை வழங்குகிறது - தாவரங்கள் செழிக்க அதிக அளவில் தேவைப்படும் இரசாயன கலவைகள் - இதன் விளைவாக பார்வைக்கு ஈர்க்கும் தாவரங்கள் விரைவாக வளரும் ஆனால் அவசியமில்லை.செயற்கை உரங்களைப் பயன்படுத்துவதால் ஏற்படும் விளைவுகள்:         90 ஆண்டுகளுக்கு முன்பு தொடங்கி, பசுமைப் புரட்சி உலகம் முழுவதும் செயற்கை உரங்கள் அறிமுகப்படுத்தப்பட்டதன் காரணமாக அதிக பயிர் விளைச்சலை அனுமதித்தது. எவ்வாறாயினும், சமீபத்தில்தான் ஆராய்ச்சியாளர்களும் அக்கறையுள்ள குடிமக்களும் மண்ணில் இத்தகைய இரசாயனங்களைப் பயன்படுத்துவதால் தாவரங்கள் மற்றும் விலங்குகள் - மனிதர்கள் உட்பட துரதிர்ஷ்டவசமான விளைவுகளைக் கண்டறியத் தொடங்கியுள்ளனர்.        ஷில் கிரவுண்ட்ஸ் மேனேஜ்மென்ட்டில், நாங்கள் நிலத்துடன் மிக நெருக்கமாக வேலை செய்வதால், சுற்றுச்சூழலின் பொறுப்பாளர்களாக நாங்கள் கருதுகிறோம். தவறாகப் பயன்படுத்தினால், நாம் பயன்படுத்தும் தயாரிப்புகள் பலர் வசிக்கும், வேலை செய்யும் மற்றும் விளையாடும் இடங்களுக்கு பெரும் தீங்கு விளைவிக்கும் என்பதை நாங்கள் அறிவோம்.சுற்றுச்சூழலைப் பற்றி நாங்கள் அதிகம் அக்கறை காட்டுவதால், சொத்து மேலாளர்கள் செயற்கை உரங்களைப் பயன்படுத்துவதைக் குறைத்து, கரிமத்திற்கு மாறுவதற்கான நான்கு காரணங்களை நாங்கள் விவாதிக்கிறோம்.      செயற்கை உரங்கள் சுற்றுச்சூழலுக்கு தீங்கு விளைவிக்கும், ஏனெனில் அவற்றின் நைட்ரஜன் மற்றும் பாஸ்பரஸ் அளவுகள் பெரும்பாலும் அதிகமாக இருக்கும். உரங்களைப் பயன்படுத்தும் பண்ணைகள் மற்றும் நிலப்பரப்புகளில் இருந்து வெளியேறும் பாஸ்பரஸ் ஏரி ஏரியில் பாசிகள் பூப்பதற்கு பங்களித்தது , இது இப்பகுதியில் உள்ள நீர்வாழ் உயிரினங்களுக்கு பேரழிவை ஏற்படுத்தியது.          செயற்கை உரங்கள் மண்ணில் உள்ள நன்மை பயக்கும் பாக்டீரியாக்களை அழிப்பதாக சில ஆதாரங்கள் கூறுகின்றன. இது அவசியம் இல்லை என்றாலும், உண்மை சிறப்பாக இல்லை. மாறாக, மண்ணில் உள்ள பாக்டீரியா மற்றும் நுண்ணுயிரிகள் செயற்கை உரத்தில் உள்ள ரசாயனங்களால் தூண்டப்படுகின்றன, இது தாவரங்கள் மண்ணில் மீண்டும் வைக்கக்கூடியதை விட அதிக கரிமப் பொருட்களை உட்கொள்ள வழிவகுக்கிறது.          இது இறுதியில் தாவரங்களுக்குத் தேவையான முக்கிய ஊட்டச்சத்துக்களை அகற்றும் மண்ணில் விளைகிறது, இது தொந்தரவாக இருக்கிறது, ஏனெனில் வளமான மண் நமது கிரகத்தின் மிகவும் குறைவாக மதிப்பிடப்பட்ட இயற்கை வளமாக இருக்கலாம்.          மண் சோர்வு காரணமாக கடந்த காலத்தில் சரிந்த முழு நாகரிகங்களின் கதைகளால் வரலாறு சிக்கலாக உள்ளது , மேலும் தாவர வளர்ச்சி மற்றும் விளைச்சலை மேம்படுத்துவதற்கான சிறந்த வழிகளை சமூகம் தேடும் நேரம் இது.        உங்களிடம் செல்லப்பிராணி இருந்தால், அவர்கள் வாயில் பொருட்களை வைக்க விரும்புகிறார்கள் என்பது உங்களுக்குத் தெரியும், மேலும் தாவரங்களும் இதற்கு விதிவிலக்கல்ல. சமீபத்தில் செயற்கை உரத்துடன் சிகிச்சையளிக்கப்பட்ட புல் அல்லது பிற தாவரங்களை உண்ணும் பூனைகள் மற்றும் நாய்கள் வாந்தியிலிருந்து வலிப்புத்தாக்கங்கள் வரை அறிகுறிகளை அனுபவிக்கலாம் , மேலும் இரசாயன உரங்கள் நேரடியாக ஜீரணிக்கும் விலங்குகளுக்கு கூட ஆபத்தானவை.           ஏனென்றால், செயற்கை உரங்கள் தாவரங்களுக்குத் தேவையான நைட்ரஜன் மற்றும் பொட்டாசியம் போன்ற அடிப்படை ஊட்டச்சத்துக்களைக் கொண்டிருப்பது மட்டுமல்லாமல், பூச்சிக்கொல்லிகள், யூரியா மற்றும் சில சமயங்களில் ஆர்சனிக் போன்ற தீங்கு விளைவிக்கும் பொருட்களின் காக்டெய்லையும் கொண்டிருக்கின்றன.            சில கரிம உரங்கள் விலங்குகளின் எலும்பு உணவில் இருந்து தயாரிக்கப்படுகின்றன , அவை அவற்றின் செரிமான அமைப்பில் உறைந்தால் விலங்குகளுக்கு தீங்கு விளைவிக்கும், ஷில் பயன்படுத்தும் உரமானது திரவமானது மற்றும் மிகவும் பாதுகாப்பானது.            இந்த தயாரிப்புகளால் உரோமம் கொண்ட நண்பர்கள் மட்டும் ஆபத்தில் இருப்பதில்லை. செயற்கை உரங்கள் குழந்தைகளுக்கு எவ்வளவு தீங்கு விளைவிக்கின்றன என்பது குறித்து நடுவர் குழு முடிவு செய்துள்ளது, ஆனால் அவற்றின் பயன்பாடு கருவின் எடை குறைவது முதல் நரம்பியல் விளைவுகள் வரை புற்றுநோய்கள் வரை அனைத்திற்கும் தொடர்பு இருப்பதாக ஆய்வுகள் கண்டறிந்துள்ளன."},{"question":"What was considered one of the Seven Ancient Wonders?","answer":"The Seven Wonders of the Ancient World were a list of remarkable constructions of classical antiquity. One of these wonders was the Great Pyramid of Giza. The Great Pyramid, located near Cairo, Egypt, is the oldest and the only surviving wonder of the ancient list. It was built as a tomb for Pharaoh Khufu (also known as Cheops) and is part of a complex that includes two other pyramids and the Sphinx. The Great Pyramid is renowned for its architectural and engineering excellence, and it stood as the tallest man-made structure in the world for over 3,800 years."},{"question":"கேள்வி : இடி இடிக்கும், மின்னல் மின்னும், மழை பெய்யாது- அது என்ன?","answer":"பதில் :  பட்டாசு"},{"question":"Fan la Saamóori Ture dëkkoon ?","answer":"Gine leu dioudo wanté gabon leu fato"},{"question":"Iga gaarsiiya wiilasheena fariintaan?","answer":"💌 Iga gaarsiiya wiilasheena fariintaan 💌Waxaan goobjoog usoo ahayn ayado soomaliya ay fagaaraha ciyaaraha afrika ka joogto  meesha ugu hooseyso safar walbo ay qaranku aadaana daraasiin goolal ah dhabarka kuso qaata taaso ku kaliftay bahda ciyaaraha inay xata ka niyad jabaan dhagaysida wararka ku saabsan ciyaaraha xulkeena, nasiib wanaag waxaa meel dheer nooga baxay iftiin yar oo rajo ku abuuray bahda xiisaysa guud ahaan ciyaaraha gaar ahaan qarankeen kuwaaso muujiyay inay wali Somaliya leedahay ciyaartoy calanka wadankeena meel sare geeyn kara kuwaaso ah rajada kaliya ee noo hartay xiligan la joogo. Hadaad tihiin ciyaartoyda xulka qaranka dalkeena, dhamaantiin waxaad matalaysaan magaca iyo calanka soomaliyeed waxadna qabateen waxa ugu wanagsan ee wadankeenu u baahnaay in loo qabto,   Hawlkarnimadina, dadaalkiina, iyo go'aan qaadashadiina heerka sare waxay noo tahay dhamaanten  dhiirigelin, waxaana aad ugu faanayna inaad wakiil ka tihiin qarankeena masraxayada caalamiga ah ee ciyaaraha gaar ahaan afrikan. Waan ognahay in ciyaartooy ahaan aad  dareemeysan cadaadis aad u weyn oo ah in sharafka qarankeena uu ku jiro hadba sidaad masuuliyad iskaga saartaan intaad ku jirtaan garoonka dhaxdiisa, laakiin sidoo kale waxaan ognahay cadaadis walbo aad dareemysan inaad haysatan fursad aysan helin ciyaartoy adinko kale ah si ay u sooo bandhigaan waxa ugu fiican oo ay u qaban lahayeen dalkeena. Xusuusnaada inaadan keligiin ahayn oo aan garabkiina taaganahay ayna idinla jirto ducadeena, taageradeena iyo dhiirigalinteena si aad magaca Soomalieeyd meel sare u gaysaan waxaana ku kalsoonahay inaad meel sare gayn doontaan magaca wadankena. Waxaan ku qanacsanahay natiijo walboo aad inoo keentaan, hadaad guulaysataan iyo hadaad guuldaraysatan inataba waxaan rabna inad noso noqotaan adinko sharfan, madixiinu sareeyo, muujiyayna inay soomaaliya wali leedahay dhalinyaro adinkoo kale ah oo  meel sare gayn kara magaca wadankeena. Waad guulaysanaysaan insha allah. Aan u duceeyno wiilasheena"},{"question":"වහන්තරාව කියන්නේ කුමක්ද?","answer":"වහන්තරාව , වසන්තරාව ද වේ.වසන දෙය හෙවත් වැසීමට උපකාර වන දෙයආතුරයකු හට සෙත් ශාන්තියක් කිරීමට පෙර අන්‍යයන්ට නොපෙනෙන සේ ආවරණය කර තබන සුදු රෙද්ද.එම රෙදි කඩ ආතුරයා නොපෙනෙන සේ දෙදෙනෙකු විසින් අල්ලාගෙන සිටින අතර ඇදුරා විසින් මන්ත්‍රයක් ජපකර දුම්මල කීලක් එම රෙදි කඩට ගසනවාත් සමගම රෙදි කඩ ඉවත් කරන අතර ආතුරයා  සෙස්සනට දැක බලා ගැනීමට හැකි කම ලැබේ. එතැන් පටන් ආතුරයා  වෙනුවෙන් ඉදිරි මන්ත්‍ර කටයුතු කෙරේ. මෙම රෙදි කඩ වහන්තරාව ලෙස හැඳින්වේ."},{"question":" Sheeg Shinida Imisa Indhood Ayey Leedahay?","answer":"Shinida Waxay Leedahay Shan (5) Indhood"},{"question":"Que nome se dá a plantas pequenas, geralmente com alguns poucos centímetros de altura, que vivem preferencialmente em locais úmidos?a) Briófitasb) Tundrac) Suculentas","answer":"letra A - A resposta correta é Briófitas"},{"question":"ICT යන අකුරු පෙනී සිටින්නේ කුමක් සඳහාද?","answer":"ICT යන අකුරු පෙනී සිටින්නේ \\"Information and communication Technologies\\", \\"තොරතුරු සහ සන්නිවේදන තාක්ෂණ\\" යන ස්ථාවරය සඳහාය. එය සන්නිවේදනය සහ තොරතුරු සැකසීමට පහසුකම් සපයන පුළුල් පරාසයක ඩිජිටල් සහ ඇනලොග් තාක්ෂණයන් ඇතුළත් වේ. මෙයට ගුවන්විදුලිය, රූපවාහිනිය සහ දුරකථන වැනි සාම්ප්‍රදායික තාක්‍ෂණයන් මෙන්ම පරිගණක, අන්තර්ජාලය, ජංගම උපාංග සහ මෘදුකාංග යෙදුම් වැනි නවීන තාක්‍ෂණ ඇතුළත් වේ. අධ්‍යාපනය, සෞඛ්‍ය සේවා, ව්‍යාපාර සහ රජය වැනි විවිධ අංශවල තොරතුරු හා සන්නිවේදන තාක්‍ෂණය සේවා වැඩිදියුණු කිරීමට, ඵලදායිතාව ඉහළ නැංවීමට සහ සන්නිවේදනය පෝෂණය කිරීමට යොදා ගනී."},{"question":"Unsay English sa, Maayong Buntag?","answer":"Good morning."},{"question":"नेपालको शिक्षा प्रणालीको संरचना कस्तो छ ?","answer":"नेपालको शिक्षा प्रणालीलाई तीन तहमा विभाजन गरिएको छ: प्राथमिक शिक्षा, माध्यमिक शिक्षा र उच्च शिक्षा।"},{"question":"তাজিংডং পাহাড়ের সংক্ষিপ্ত বর্ণনা দাও।","answer":"সরকারিভাবে বাংলাদেশের সর্বোচ্চ পর্বতশৃঙ্গ তাজিংডং। জাতীয় শিক্ষাক্রম ও টেক্সটবুক বোর্ডের মাধ্যমিক ভূগোল বই-এ এর উচ্চতা দেখানো হয়েছে ১২৩১ মিটার বা ৪১৩৮.৭১ ফুট। অন্যদিকে জেলা প্রশাসক ওয়েবসাইটে এর উচ্চতা ১০০৩ মিটার বা ৩২৯০.৬৮ ফুট। ১৯৯৬ সালে একদল পর্বতারোহী দেশের দ্বিতীয় সর্বোচ্চ পর্বতশৃঙ্গ কেওক্রাডং থেকে প্রায় ৪০ কিলোমিটার দূরের এ পর্বত শিখর আবিষ্কার করেন। এটি বান্দরবান জেলার রুমা উপজেলার রেমাক্রীপাংশা ইউনিয়নের সাইচল পর্বতসারিতে অবস্থিত। এ পর্বতের পাশে রয়েছে ক্ষুদ্র নৃগোষ্ঠীদের পল্লী। স্থানীয় মারমা ভাষায় 'তাজিং' শব্দের অর্থ 'বড়' আর 'ডং' শব্দের অর্থ 'পাহাড়'। এ দুটি শব্দ থেকে এর নামকরণ করা হয় 'তাজিংডং'। সরকারিভাবে তাজিংডংকে 'বিজয়' নামে সম্বোধন করা হয়। বছরের যে কোনো সময় তাজিংডং ঘুরে আসতে পারেন। বর্ষায় এর আকর্ষণ সবচেয়ে সুন্দর। বান্দরবান সদর হতে প্রায় ৭০ কিলোমিটার এবং রুমা উপজেলা সদর থেকে ২৫ কিলোমিটার দূরে এ পর্বতের অবস্থান।"},{"question":"Дүйнөдөгү эң шарты начар түрмөлөр жөнүндө жазып бере аласыңбы?","answer":"Гитарама. (Руанд)  Гитарама ааламдагы эң катаал түрмөлөрдөн. Мындагы жашоонун начардыгын ушундан билиңиз, тирүү калуу максатында кылмышкерлер каннибализмге(адамдын этин жегендик) барууга да мажбур. Көпчүлүк жаза өтөөчүлөр бул жайды \\"тирүүлүктөгү тозок\\" деп комментарий беришкен. 400 кишиге болжолдоонгон камакта учурда 7 миң кылмышкер бар. "},{"question":"السؤال: ماذا كانت لعبة حفلات الأطفال الشهيرة التي لا تتضمن الكرات في الأولمبياد من 1900 إلى 1920؟","answer":"الإجابة: شد الحبل"},{"question":"සැන් ෆ්රැන්සිස්කෝ හි හොඳම croissant සොයා ගන්නේ කොහෙන්ද?","answer":"සැන් ෆ්රැන්සිස්කෝ හි හොඳම croissant හි පිළිතුර බොහෝ දුරට ඔබගේ මනාපය මත රඳා පවතින බැවින් මෙය පැවසීම අපහසුය. Arsicault සාමාන්‍යයෙන් croissants සඳහා ඉතා ජනප්‍රිය බේකරියකි. මෙහි ඇති ක්‍රොයිසන්ට් ඉතා පියලි සහ ඉතා බටර් සහිතයි. එය ඔබගේ මංසන්ධිය නිවැරදි නම්, අනිවාර්යයෙන්ම ඔවුන්ට පැමිණෙන්න! Arsicault හැරුණු විට, SF හි නිර්මාණාත්මක පෙරළියක් සහිත croissant පිරිනමන බොහෝ බේකරි තිබේ. ප්‍රෙට්සල් ක්‍රොයිසන්ට් සඳහා හහ්ඩෝ සහ ඇඹුල් ක්‍රොයිසන්ට් සඳහා ඇරිස්මෙන්ඩි උදාහරණ කිහිපයක් වේ. පුද්ගලිකව, මම මගේ croissants ඉතා බටර් නොවන නමුත් මැද තෙත් සහ පිටත හැපෙනසුළු වීමට කැමතියි. මගේ පුද්ගලික ප්‍රියතම එක තමයි Inner Richmond හි Schubert's Bakery. මිල ලක්ෂ්‍යය සහ රසය මා සොයන දේ සමඟ හොඳින් ගැලපේ!"},{"question":"வினா: சூரியனை நேருக்கு நேர் பார்க்கக்கூடிய பிராணி எது?","answer":"விடை: கழுகு "},{"question":"உரைநடையின் அணிநலன்களை சுருக்கி எழுதுக.","answer":"முன்னுரை:சங்க இலக்கியம் நம் பாட்டனார் தோப்பு. இடைக்கால இலக்கியம் நம் தந்தையார் தோட்டம். இக்கால இலக்கியம் நம் பூங்கா. இவை அனைத்தின் நயங்களையும் ஒன்று சேர்த்து உரைநடையின் அணிநலன்களாகக் காண்போம்.உரைநடையில் உருவகம் இணை ஒப்பு:தற்பொழுது முகநிலவில் வியர்வை முத்துகள் துளிர்த்தன என்று உருவகமாக எழுதுகிறார்கள். களம்புகத் துடித்து நின்ற உனக்கு வெற்றிச்சாறு கிடைத்துவிட்டது, உண்டு மகிழ்ந்தாய், உன் புன்னகைதான் அதற்குச் சான்று இது அறிஞர் அண்ணாவின் உரைநடை.எடுத்துக்காட்டு உவமை அணியை உரைநடையில் பயன்படுத்துகையில் இணை நட்பு என்கிறோம். ஊர் கூடிச் செக்குத் தள்ள முடியுமா? எனக் கேட்கிறார்கள் ஊர் கூடின பிறகுதான் செக்குத் தள்ள வேண்டும் என்று காத்திருப்பவர்களின் காரியம் கைகூடாது. புரோகிதருக்காக அமாவாசை காத்திருப்பதில்லை என்று எழுத்தாளர் வ. ராமசாமி மழையும் புயலும் என்ற நூலில் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.உரைநடையில் இலக்கணை:“சோலையில் புகுவேன்; மரங்கள் கூப்பிடும்; விருந்து வைக்கும், ஆலமர நிழலில் அமர்வேன்; ஆல், ‘என் விழுதைப் பார். அந்த அரசுக்கு இஃது உண்டா ?’ என்னும். அரசு கண்ணிற்படும். ‘யான் விழுதின்றி வானுற ஓங்கி நிற்கிறேன், என்னை மக்கள் சுற்றிச் செல்கிறார்கள், காண்’ என்னும், வேம்பு, என்நிழல் நலஞ்செய்யும். என் பூவின் குணங்களைச் சொல்கிறேன் வா’ என்னும், அத்தி, நாகை, விளா, மா, வில்வம் முதலிய மரங்கள் விளியாமலிருக்குமோ? சிந்தனையில் அவைகளின் நுட்பங்கள் விளங்கும். மலை என்னை அடிக்கடி அழைக்கும். மலைமீது இவர்வேன், ஓரிடத்தில் அமர்வேன்; மேலும் கீழும் பார்ப்பேன்; சுற்றுமுற்றும் பார்ப்பேன். மனம் அமைதி எய்தும் “. எங்கள் காலத் தமிழ்த்தென்றல் திரு. வி. கலியாணசுந்தரனார் இப்படி எழுதியிருக்கிறார்.உரைநடையில் எதுகை மோனை:“தென்றல் அசைந்துவரும் தென்தமிழ் நாட்டில் அமைந்த திருக்குற்றாலம், மலைவளம் படைத்த பழம்பதியாகும். அம்மலையிலே, கோங்கும் வேங்கையும் ஓங்கி வளரும்; குரவமும் முல்லையும் இத்தகைய மலையினின்று விரைந்து வழிந்திறங்கும் வெள்ளருவி வட்டச் சுனையிலே வீழ்ந்து பொங்கும்பொழுது சிதறும் நீர்த் திவலைகள் பாலாவிபோற் பரந்தெழுந்து மஞ்சினோடு சேர்ந்து கொஞ்சிக் குலாவும் ” என்று சொல்லின் செல்வர் இரா. பி. சே. தமிழின்பம் என்னும் நூலில் எழுதியுள்ளார்.உரைநடையில் எதிரிணை:அமைத்து எழுதுவோம்…. இதனை எதிரிணை இசைவு என்கிறோம். குடிசைகள் ஒரு பக்கம்; கோபுரங்கள் மறுபக்கம்; பசித்த வயிறுகள் ஒருபக்கம். புளிச்சேப்பக்காரர்கள் மறுபக்கம்; மெலிந்த எலும்புக்கூடுகள். ஒருபக்கம் பருத்த தொந்திகள் மறுபக்கம்; கேடுகெட்ட இந்தச் சமுதாயத்திற்கு என்றைக்கு விமோசனம்? தோழர்களே, சிந்தியுங்கள்!’ என்று தோழர் ப. ஜீவானந்தம் எழுதியிருப்பது இதற்கு நல்ல எடுத்துக்காட்டு!’ முடிவுரை:பேசினால் உரையாடல், எழுதினால் உரைநடை, இன்றைய உரைநடையின் வளர்ச்சியோ அளவற்றது. கட்டுரை, சிறுகதை, புதினம் இவையெல்லாம் இன்றைய உரைநடையின் இலக்கிய வடிவங்களாகத் திகழ்கின்றன. இவற்றைப் படித்து நம் அறிவை வளப்படுத்திக் கொள்வோம்."},{"question":"පහත වචනයට අදාළ විරුද්ධ පද කුමක්ද?කැඩීම ","answer":"තැනීම"},{"question":"Hãy tiếp tục đoạn văn sau: \\"Năm 1991, trong một bài viết trên tạp chí Xã hội học Mỹ, Scott Feld đưa ra một khái niệm gọi là Nghịch lý tình bạn (Friendship paradox), cho thấy rằng phần lớn mọi người sẽ có ít bạn bè hơn so với những người bạn của họ. Chúng ta nhìn vào những người bạn của mình và thấy rằng họ đều có rất nhiều mối quan hệ xã hội, khiến chúng ta tự ti hơn về bản thân mà không biết rằng đó là ảnh hưởng của nghịch lý tình bạn. Scott Feld phân tích dữ liệu dựa trên một nghiên cứu của Coleman năm 1961 mang tên Xã hội của thanh thiếu niên (The Adolescent Society) về tình bạn của học sinh thuộc 12 trường trung học. Khi nhìn vào các học sinh nữ thuộc trường Marketville, phân bố số lượng bạn bè của họ được mô tả như trên hình 8.3. Phần lớn các học sinh sẽ có 1-3 người bạn, chỉ có một số ít có nhiều hơn 5 người bạn. Mặt khác, nếu nhìn vào phân bố số lượng bạn bè của những người bạn, phân bố sẽ tập trung vào những giá trị lớn hơn, như có thể thấy trên hình 8.4. Những người bạn của họ hầu hết sẽ có từ 2-5 bạn bè. Điều này dẫn đến một kết luận là, những người bạn của chúng ta thường nổi bật hơn so với chúng ta! Trung bình một học sinh nữ trường Marketville có 2,7 người bạn, trong khi đó, những người bạn của họ có trung bình 4,0 người bạn. Hiện tượng này không chỉ được bắt gặp trong các mối quan hệ thường nhật, mà còn có thể được thấy trên các nền tảng trực tuyến và mạng xã hội. Nếu bạn chọn ngẫu nhiên một người bạn của mình trên Facebook, một khả năng cao là người bạn đó sẽ có nhiều bạn bè hơn bạn. Tờ Washington Post dẫn lời một nghiên cứu của Pew Research Center cho thấy, một người dùng Facebook trung bình có 245 bạn bè, nhưng một người bạn của họ có trung bình là 359 bạn bè.\\"","answer":"Lý do của hiện tượng này là gì? Nghịch lý tình bạn là một dạng của nghịch lý điều tra. Bạn có thể sẽ nghĩ rằng khả năng để bạn của mình có nhiều bạn bè hơn hay có ít bạn bè hơn mình là như nhau, nhưng thực tế thì không phải như vậy. Bạn có nhiều khả năng sẽ quen với một người nổi bật và nhiều bạn bè hơn mình! Để minh họa rõ hơn, hãy chia tất cả người dùng Facebook mà bạn có thể kết bạn thành 3 nhóm: những người nổi bật hơn và có nhiều bạn bè hơn bạn; những người nổi bật tương đương với bạn; những người ít nổi bật hơn bạn. Để đơn giản, giả sử ba nhóm người này có tỉ lệ tương đương nhau, đều chiếm 1/3 số lượng người dùng. Ba nhóm này được minh họa trên hình sau: Mặc dù ba nhóm người có tỉ lệ phân bố bằng nhau, khả năng để bạn làm quen được với từng nhóm người là khác nhau. Hãy nghĩ về một người rất nổi bật, có nhiều mối quan hệ xã hội và cũng cởi mở hơn trong giao tiếp. Đó là những người mà rất sẵn lòng kết bạn với bạn và bạn cũng có thể thấy anh ta/cô ta hoạt động tích cực trên Facebook hơn. Anh ta/cô ta có thể gửi yêu cầu kết bạn với rất nhiều người, đồng thời cũng dễ dàng chấp nhận một yêu cầu từ người khác. Điều này khiến người đó xuất hiện trong danh sách bạn bè của rất nhiều người và bạn có nhiều khả năng sẽ kết bạn với một người như thế hơn. Ngược lại, với những người không nổi bật và ít mối quan hệ trên Facebook, họ sẽ chỉ giao tiếp với một nhóm người nhỏ. Điều này khiến cho khả năng để anh ta/cô ta xuất hiện trong danh sách bạn bè của bạn sẽ là thấp hơn. Kết quả là, phân bố thực tế của ba nhóm người trong danh sách bạn bè của bạn sẽ có nhiều người nổi bật hơn bạn, như được minh họa với phân bố phía bên phải của hình trên. Một cách khác để hình dung là, nếu bạn đi vào một quán bar và làm quen với một người bạn mới, người bạn đó sẽ thuộc nhóm người nào? Một khả năng cao hơn là anh ta hoặc cô ta là những người có nhiều mối quan hệ bạn bè và thích làm quen với những người mới. Những người ít quan hệ sẽ ít tham gia vào những hoạt động như vậy hơn và bạn sẽ có khả năng gặp được họ thấp hơn. Điều tương tự cũng có thể thấy được nếu nhìn vào các mối quan hệ yêu đương. Một anh chàng sẽ rất thất vọng khi làm quen được với một cô bạn gái mới và biết rằng cô ta đã trải qua nhiều mối tình hơn anh ta. Nếu anh chàng này hiểu về nghịch lý điều tra, anh ta có thể sẽ thông cảm và bỏ qua điều đó."},{"question":"Түндүк Африканын көп бөлүгүн ээлеген чөлдүн аты кандай?","answer":"Сахара чөлү Түндүк Африканын көп бөлүгүн камтыйт"},{"question":"Awọn ọlọpaa ti mu tẹgbọn-taburo to ji baba wọn gbe, ti wọn n beere owo itusilẹ","answer":"Iya ati baba kan naa lo bi awọn ọkunrin meji yii, ni Yola, nipinlẹ Adamawa. Ṣugbọn niṣe lawọn mejeeji ti wọn jẹ tẹgbọn-taburo yii gbimọ-pọ, ti wọn ji baba to bi wọn gbe, wọn si ti n beere owo itusilẹ paapaa, ko too di pe ọwọ palaba wọn segi.Ohun to ṣẹlẹ gẹgẹ ba a ṣe gbọ ni pe lẹyin ti awọn gende meji yii ji baba wọn gbe tan, wọn tọju rẹ sibi ti ẹnikẹni ko ti ni i fura. Lẹyin igba naa ni wọn si waa n beere owo rẹpẹtẹ lọwọ awọn ẹgbọn ati aburo baba naa, wọn ni bi wọn ko ba mu owo wa, ki wọn gbagbe pe wọn yoo tun foju kan eeyan wọn naa mọ o.Ṣugbọn awọn ẹbi baba wọn ko ri owo tawọn ajinigbe naa n beere san, ko si jọ pe kinni kan wa ti wọn le ṣe si i rara.Nigba tawọn mejeeji yii ko ri owo gba, ti wọn ko si fẹ ki aṣiri tu pe awọn lawọn ji baba awọn gbe, wọn pinnu lati kuku pa a danu, ki ohun to n run nilẹ tan kia.Afi ti pe awodi oke wọn ko mọ pe ara ilẹ n wo oun, awọn ọmọ to ji baba gbe yii ko mọ pe ẹni kan ri awọn lasiko ti wọn n gídì baba naa mọlẹ, ti wọn fipa wọ ọ sinu ọkọ ti wọn fi gbe e lọ.Ẹni naa lo ṣalaye ohun to ṣẹlẹ fawọn ẹbi baba naa to n daamu lati san owo itusilẹ rẹ, bi wọn ṣe lọọ fọlọpaa gbe awọn ọmọ yii niyẹn.Awọn mejeeji ti wa latimọle bayii, ko le pẹ ti wọn yoo fi de kootu, lati dahun ẹsun ijinigbe."},{"question":"Pateikite man trivialumo pavyzdį šioje kategorijoje: politika","answer":"Kuris metais Bašaras al-Asadas tapo prezidentu? 2000 m.  tapo Sirijos prezidentu. 1988 m. baigė Damasko universitetą, įgijo oftalmologo specialybę. Studijavo Vokietijoje ir Didžiojoje Britanijoje. 1999–2000 m. Liaudies gvardijos vadas."},{"question":"Inona avy ireo toro-hevitra sasantsasany amin'ny fanomanana fialan-tsasatra mahomby ho an' ny fianakaviana?","answer":"Manomàna mialoha, ampidiro ny olon-drehetra amin'ny fandraisana fanapahan-kevitra, mandinika ny toerana aleha tsy ny hetsika izay mety atao any amin'ilay toerana, ary mahaiza mandanjalanja amin'ny fandaharam-potoana."},{"question":"Fiisito (examination) u same.","answer":"U samee baaritaan calaamadaha qofka nafaqadarada heyso sida timahiisa oo khafiif noqda,afka nabro yar yar ku yeesha iyo qofka oo dhamaada."},{"question":"هل توجد فلسطين في قارة أوروبا؟","answer":"لا، توجد فلسطين في قارة آسيا."},{"question":"Según la biblia, cuál es el.mandamiento más importante?","answer":"El.mandamiento mas importante es: \\"ama a Dios con todo tu corazón\\" "},{"question":"问：如何保护大脑健康？","answer":"答：以下是一些保护大脑健康的方法：保持健康的饮食，多吃新鲜水果和蔬菜。适量运动，保持身体健康。充足的睡眠，让大脑得到休息。避免吸烟和酗酒，减少对大脑的伤害。保持积极乐观的心态，减少压力。"},{"question":"Fenoy ny banga :\\"Boka nangala-pary, _\\"","answer":"Ity no fenon' ilay banga: \\"ka ny fary tsy azo, ary ny tanana feno lay.\\""},{"question":"次のパラグラフを続ける： オーストラリアとニュージーランドでサッカー 女子","answer":"ワールドカップを行っています。日本は決勝トーナメントの最初の試合でノルウェーに3-1で勝って、ベスト8になりました。しかし、次の試合でスウェーデンに1-2で負けました。 日本の宮澤ひなた選手は、この大会で5点取りました。1つの大会で5点取ったのは、2011年の澤穂希さんと同じで、日本の選手でいちばん多くなりました。そして、この大会でいちばん点を取った選手になる可能性が残っています。 東京で17日、宮澤選手は「チームの雰囲気がよくて、みんなが一つになっていると感じていました。もっと勝ちたかったです」と話しました。これからについては、「もっと成長したいです。外国でいろいろな国の選手の中でやりたい気持ちもあります」と話しました。"},{"question":"Apakah peribahasa yang bermaksud \\"Melaga-lagakan seseorang atau kumpulan dengan seseorang atau kumpulan yang lain.\\"","answer":"adu domba"},{"question":"පොදු රාජ්‍ය මණ්ඩලීය රාජ්‍ය නායක සමුඵව පැවැත්වෙන්නේ වසර කීයකට වරක්‌ද?","answer":"පොදු රාජ්‍ය මණ්ඩලීය රාජ්‍ය නායක සමුඵව පැවැත්වෙන්නේ වසර 2 වරක්‌ය. මෙම රැස්වීමට නිල වශයෙන් සහභාගිවන ආණ්ඩු ප්‍රධානයකු එකම තැනැත්තා වන්නේ පොදු රාජ්‍ය මණ්ඩලීය නායක දෙවන එලිසබෙත් රැජින (හෝ ඇයගේ නියෝජිත රාජකීයයා) වේ."},{"question":"Tunjukkan resipi untuk udang goreng celup dengan langkah-langkah yang terperinci. ","answer":"Udang goreng celup ialah sejenis makanan yang popular di gerai makanan laut Malaysia dan gerai pasar malam. Proses \\"celup\\" merujuk kepada teknik mencelup udang dalam adunan tepung yang mengandungi bahan-bahan yang sesuai untuk memberikan rasa dan tekstur sebelum digoreng.Bahan:  ½ kg udang segar, ½ cawan tepung beras, 1 sudu besar tepung jagung, ¼ sudu kecil serbuk kunyit, ¼ sudu kecil kapur makan – cairkan dengan sedikit air, ¼ sudu kecil garam secukup rasa, air secukupnyaCara memasak:1. Bersihkan udang dan toskan. Kemudian lap kering menggunakan tuala kertas.2. Bancuhkan adunan untuk menggoreng dengan mencampurkan tepung beras, tepung jagung, air kapur dan serbuk kunyit. Kemudian masukkan air sedikit demi sedikit sambil mengacau untuk menghasilkan adunan tidak terlalu pekat atau terlalu cair.3. Untuk menggoreng, panaskan minyak banyak dalam kuali. Celupkan udang dalam bancuhan tepung dan goreng secara \\"deep fry\\" sehingga garing.4. Angkat dan toskan.5. Hidangkan panas-panas ketika tepung masih rangup bersama sos pencicah."},{"question":"Grecja znajduje się w Azji. Prawda czy fałsz?","answer":"Fałsz. Grecja to państwo w Europie południowo-wschodniej."},{"question":"एक पुरानी मंदिर की कहानी लिखें, जो एक रहस्यमय समाधि छिपाता है।","answer":"मंदिर में गहरे रहस्य छिपे थे, जो सिर्फ वो लोग समझ सकते थे जो प्रेम और सच्चाई के साथ आत्म-साक्षात्कार करने के लिए तैयार थे। जिन्होंने इसे महसूस किया, उनकी ज़िंदगी में बड़ा बदलाव आया।"},{"question":" Cite um Pintor Açoriano notável.","answer":"Entre os Pintores Notáveis dos Açores, destaca-se César Augusto Pires, conhecido por sua representação vívida da paisagem açoriana. As suas telas capturam a exuberância das ilhas, com cores vibrantes e detalhes cativantes."},{"question":"日本の元号のうち、「平（たいら）」という漢字で始まるのは、平成と何でしょう？","answer":"平治（へいじ）です。"},{"question":"Tuliskan sebuah karangan yang bertajuk ‘Laporan Lawatan Sambil Belajar ke Kilang Coklat Cadbury’.","answer":"Persatuan Geografi Sekolah Menengah Kebangsaan Saint George telah mengadakan lawatan sambil belajar ke Kilang Coklat Cadbury yang terletak di Shah Alam pada 15 Jun 2022. Rombongan ini terdiri daripada empat puluh orang ahli Persatuan Geografi dan tiga orang guru pengiring, yakni Puan Saloma, Puan Zubaidah, dan Puan Siti Muqalmah. Seawal lapan pagi lagi, para pelajar dan guru yang terlibat sudah menaiki bas yang disewa khas oleh ahli jawatankuasa lawatan ini. Perjalanan mengambil masa tiga puluh minit sahaja kerana antara jarak sekolah dengan kilang tersebut hanya 20 kilometer.Sebaik-baik sahaja tiba di kilang tersebut, rombongan kami disambut dengan tangan terbuka oleh pengurus pemasaran dan promosi, Encik Soo Ming Lei. Encik Soo telah membawa kami ke bilik mesyuarat yang terletak di tingkat tiga Wisma Cadbury. Di dalam bilik mesyuarat itu, kami diberi penerangan sejarah penubuhan kilang coklat secara ringkas tapi jelas. Selepas mendengar taklimat, ahli rombongan pun bersemangat tinggi dan menanyakan pelbagai soalan yang berkaitan dengan kilang coklat tersebut. Hal ini demikian kerana mereka perlu menyediakan laporan lawatan ini.Program pascataklimat ialah memulakan lawatan ke bahagian memproses coklat. Kami dibawa ke bahagian paling penting, yakni zon penyediaan. Di kawasan itu, kami diberi pakaian berupa tudung kepala, penutup mulut, dan sarung tangan. Langkah penyediaan yang bersih dan selamat adalah penting kata Encik Soo kerana pihak kilang amat mementingkan soal kualiti coklat. Hal ini demikian kerana kebersihan menjamin mutu makanan yang disediakan. Kami melihat sendiri biji koko panggang dikisar dengan sebuah mesin. Selepas itu, koko yang lumat dimasak bersama gula dan susu yang diimport khas.Selepas proses penyediaan selesai, coklat dalam bentuk cecair pekat yang mencapai kepanasan seratus lima puluh darjah itu disalurkan ke paip besar yang menuju ke bahagian pemprosesan coklat prapembungkusan. Di bahagian itu, kami dapat melihat pelbagai jenis coklat berjaya diproses dengan mesin yang canggih. Mesin itu seterusnya menghantar jongkong-jongkong coklat yang sudah siap diproses menuju ke peringkat pembungkusan mengikut saiz dan perisa. Di bahagian ini, bilangan pekerja yang banyak diperlukan untuk menyudahkan proses pembungkusan sehingga proses akhir, penyimpanan.Sepanjang lawatan di bahagian penyediaan, kami telah mengemukakan soalan tentang kepentingan penyediaan makanan yang selamat. Sepanjang dua jam lawatan, kami berasa teruja dan berpuas hati dengan penerangan yang disampaikan. Walau bagaimanapun, kami berasa penat kerana kawasan pemprosesan kilang ini amat besar. Di bilik mesyuarat, kami diberi taklimat multimedia berkaitan perancangan masa depan kilang coklat ini. Daripada taklimat multimedia ini, kami berasa kagum akan semangat pengurusan syarikat ini yang memegang para prinsip “genggam bara api biar jadi abu”.Sebelum mengakhiri lawatan, Pengarah Urusan Kilang Cadbury telah meluangkan masa untuk berjumpa dengan ahli rombongan sekali gus menyampaikan cenderahati kepada kami. Selain itu, kami juga diberi baucar istimewa untuk membeli coklat dengan potongan harga sebanyak dua puluh hingga empat puluh peratus. Selepas bersalam dengan tuan pengarah, kami pun menuju ke kedai coklat yang terletak di sebelah pintu besar kilang itu. Ahli rombongan yang selesai membeli coklat bersiap sedia menaiki bas untuk pulang ke sekolah.Rombongan ini tiba di sekolah pada pukul dua belas tengah hari. Cikgu Saloma yang bertugas menjaga disiplin pelajar berpuas hati dengan kelakuan ahli rombongan walaupun ada segelintir daripada mereka yang mulut murai. Akhirnya, murid-murid pun pulang ke rumah masing-masing. Lawatan sambil belajar seperti ini amat bermanfaat kepada pelajar. Selain mendapat ilmu dan pengalaman, kami juga berjaya menimba pengetahuan tentang pengurusan kilang. Hal ini ibarat sambil menyelam minum air. Kami berharap lawatan umpama ini akan dijadikan agenda tahunan Persatuan Geografi Sekolah Menengah Kebangsaan Saint George.Laporan disediakan oleh,  Ali(Muhammad Ali bin Abdul Razak)Setiausaha Persatuan Geografi Sekolah Menengah Kebangsaan Saint George"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"adat pusaka\\"?","answer":"Adat lama yang dilakukan turun-temurun."},{"question":"Đoạn văn sau đang nói về vấn đề gì? Trưa 31-7, nguồn tin của Tuổi Trẻ Online xác nhận lực lượng Trạm cảnh sát giao thông (CSGT) Đa Phước thuộc Phòng CSGT đường bộ - đường sắt Công an TP.HCM đang phối hợp cùng Công an huyện Bình Chánh điều tra nguyên nhân vụ tai nạn giữa ôtô biển xanh và xe container xảy ra trên đường Nguyễn Văn Linh. Khoảng 2h30 sáng cùng ngày, ôtô biển xanh do nam tài xế cầm lái (chưa rõ danh tính), chạy trên đường Nguyễn Văn Linh, hướng từ huyện Bình Chánh về quận 7. Khi vừa qua khu dân cư Dương Hồng khoảng 100m thuộc xã Bình Hưng, huyện Bình Chánh thì bất ngờ tông vào đuôi xe container, kéo theo rơmooc đang đậu sửa chữa bên đường. Sau va chạm, phần đầu ôtô biển xanh hư hỏng nặng, móp méo, nát bươm. Vụ tai nạn làm người đàn ông đang vá vỏ phía sau container bị thương, nhập viện cấp cứu. Còn những người trên xe biển xanh an toàn. Lực lượng chức năng sau đó có mặt khám nghiệm hiện trường, điều tra nguyên nhân vụ tai nạn.","answer":"Xe biển xanh tông đuôi xe container lúc rạng sáng, nát bươm phần đầu - Tuổi Trẻ Online"},{"question":"Η κίνηση μιας μάζας αέρα πάνω από την επιφάνεια της Γης προκαλεί: σεισμική δραστηριότητα, τοπικές καιρικές αλλαγές, παγκόσμια θέρμανση ή οικολογική διαδοχή; Η σωστή απάντηση είναι:","answer":"τοπικές καιρικές αλλαγές"},{"question":"张辽的后代如何？","answer":"答：张辽的儿子张遵、张钧都在曹魏政权中担任过要职，他们都继承了父亲的勇猛和智慧。"},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'juling air'? Berilah satu contoh ayat untuknya.","answer":"Ia bermaksud juling sedikit. Contoh ayat: Walaupun dia juling air, wajahnya sentiasa berseri-seri."},{"question":"Vilnius moy péeyu ban réw?","answer":"Vilnius moy péeyu réwum Lituanie"},{"question":"🇰🇬 Манас эпосу 📚Кенжекара манасчы ―Семетейдин кайсы бөлүмүн мыкты айткан? а) Семетейдин төрөлүшүнб) Семетейдин балалык чагынв) Семетейдин Айчүрөккө үйлөнүшүнг) Семетейдин Ала-Тоого кайтып келишин.","answer":"🇰🇬 Манас эпосу 📚в) Семетейдин Айчүрөккө үйлөнүшүн."},{"question":"Qual destes países é transcontinental?a) Rússiab) Filipinasc) Marrocosd) Groenlândiae) Tanzânia","answer":"Alternativa a: Rússia.A Rússia, cujo nome oficial é Federação Russa, é o maior país em extensão territorial do mundo. Essa nação é transcontinental, pois pertence a mais de um continente: Europa e Ásia."},{"question":"قلب: أذين(أ) سما: أرض(ب) لسان: أسنان(ج) انف: شم(د) أسرة: أبن","answer":"الإجابة (د) علاقة الكل بالجزء"},{"question":"Dựa trên tiêu đề sau, hãy viết một đoạn văn tối đa 500 chữ: \\"Nga tố Ukraine tấn công Hạm đội Biển Đen, Kiev bác bỏ.\\"","answer":"\\"Một vật thể không xác định đã bay vào khu vực trụ sở hạm đội. Theo thông tin sơ bộ, nó là một chiếc máy bay không người lái\\", Mikhail Razvozhayev, thị trưởng Sevastopol ở bán đảo Crimea, nơi đóng quân Hạm đội Biển Đen của Nga, viết trên Telegram hôm nay. Cuộc tấn công diễn ra trước thềm các lễ kỷ niệm nhân Ngày Hải quân Nga 31/7, khiến 5 người bị thương và phải hủy bỏ các hoạt động, ông Razvozhayev cho biết, thêm rằng Cơ quan An ninh Liên bang (FSB) đang điều tra sự việc. \\"Tất cả lễ kỷ niệm đã bị hủy bỏ vì lý do an ninh. Hãy bình tĩnh và ở nhà nếu có thể\\", ông Razvozhayev nói, đồng thời chỉ trích Ukraine \\"đã quyết định phá hỏng Ngày Hải quân của chúng ta\\". Cáo buộc của Thị trưởng Sevastopol được đưa ra vài giờ trước khi Tổng thống Nga Vladimir Putin tới giám sát lễ kỷ niệm Ngày Hải quân Nga ở quê nhà St Petersburg. Trong khi đó, Sergiy Bratchuk, phát ngôn viên quân khu Odessa của Ukraine, bác bỏ Kiev đứng sau vụ tấn công. \\"Việc giải phóng Crimea khỏi quân chiếm đóng sẽ được thực hiện theo cách khác và hiệu quả hơn nhiều\\", ông viết trên Telegram. Ngày Hải quân là dịp lễ hàng năm của Nga, trong đó các hạm đội sẽ tổ chức các cuộc diễu hành hải quân và tôn vinh các thủy thủ. Nga sáp nhập Crimea từ tháng 3/2014 sau một cuộc trưng cầu dân ý và các buổi lễ nhân Ngày Hải quân cũng diễn ra tại đây. Trong khi đó, phương Tây và Ukraine không công nhận việc sáp nhập, gọi Crimea là \\"lãnh thổ bị chiếm đóng tạm thời\\". Nga mở chiến dịch quân sự ở Ukraine từ ngày 24/2 và xung đột hai bên tới nay chưa có dấu hiệu hạ nhiệt dù đã bước sang tháng thứ sáu. Moskva từng tuyên bố mục tiêu chiến dịch là \\"giải phóng Donbass\\", song sau đó cho biết sẽ mở rộng ra các khu vực khác ở Ukraine. Thứ trưởng Quốc phòng Ukraine Volodymyr Havrylov hôm 19/7 nói rằng Kiev đang chuẩn bị cuộc tấn công nhằm vào Hạm đội Biển Đen của Nga. Ông Havrylov cũng cho biết Ukraine lên kế hoạch giành lại Crimea thông qua biện pháp ngoại giao hoặc quân sự."},{"question":"Mistä aineista tiesuola, jolla tiet suolataan talvisin, koostuu?","answer":"Natriumkloridia (NaCl) on oltava vähintään 97 %. Analyysi tehdään kuivasta suolasta. Paakkuuntumisen estoainetta (kalium tai natriumferrosyanidi) saa olla enintään 150 ppm (0,015 %). Suolan rakeisuudelle ei ole asetettu vaatimuksia. Perinteisesti talvisuolan maksimiraekoko on asetettu arvoon 5 mm ja hienoainesta (seula 0,125 mm) on ollut enintään 5 %. Kalsiumkloridia (CaCl2) sallitaan käytettäväksi vain liuoksena pieninä annoksina ja rakeisen natriumkloridin kostutukseen. Kalsiumkloridi hankitaan yleensä valmiina 32-prosenttisena liuoksena.Pohjavesialueilla on myös kokeiltu vaihtoehtona suolaamiselle kalium- tai natriumformiaattia, jotka ovat ympäristöystävällisempiä vaihtoehtoja. Ne ovat kuitenkin selvästi suolaa kalliimpia, mikä rajoittaa niiden käyttöä. Ne eivät myöskään ole aivan yhtä tehokkaita menetelmiä liukkauden torjunnassa kuin suola."},{"question":"Апыртма деген сөздүн синонимдери кайсы сөздөр?Апыртмадан биз эмнени үйрөнөбүз?","answer":"Апыртма жалган калп бул сөздөрдүн айтылышы ар башка бирок мааниси бирдей синоним сөздөргө кирет.Апыртма максаты калптан чындыкты жалгандын туурасын айырмалай билүү тарбиялык жагы.Мен эки жашымда коён 🐇 аттым,Күл үстүнө казан 🍲 астым,Жейин десем коён 🐇жок,Жебей туруп курсак ток,Үйгө 🏠 кайттым көөнүм ток 🤗."},{"question":"મિસ યુનિવર્સ લારા દત્તા વિષે જણાવો.","answer":"લારા દત્તા ભારતીય અભિનેત્રી છે. જેમણે સને ૨૦૦૦ માં મિસ યુનિવર્સ નો ખિતાબ મેળવેલો.લારા દત્તાનો જન્મ ગાઝીયાબાદ,ઉત્તર પ્રદેશમાં એપ્રિલ ૧૬, ૧૯૭૮નાં રોજ થયેલો. તેમનાં પિતા વિંગ કમાન્ડર  એલ.કે. દત્તા અને માતા જેનિફર દત્તા છે. તેમને બે મોટી બહેનો છે, જેમાની એક ભારતીય વાયુ દળમાં સેવા આપે છે. એક નાની બહેન પણ છે. દત્તા કુટુંબ ૧૯૮૧માં બેંગલોર આવ્યું જ્યાં તેણીએ 'સેન્ટ ફ્રાન્સિસ ઝેવિયર ગર્લસ હાઇસ્કુલ'માં પોતાનું ઉચ્ચતર માધ્યમિક શિક્ષણ લીધું. તેણીએ મુંબઇ વિશ્વવિદ્યાલયમાંથી અર્થશાસ્ત્રમાં સ્નાતકની ઉપાધી મેળવી."},{"question":"Dựa trên tiêu đề sau, hãy viết một đoạn văn tối đa 500 chữ: Ten Hag ca ngợi Lisandro Martinez, gây áp lực lên Maguire","answer":"Lisandro Martinez đã có trận ra mắt Man United khi Quỷ đỏ hòa 1-1 với Rayo Vallecano. Sự xuất hiện của cầu thủ người Argentina và màn trình diễn không sai sót của anh có thể gây rắc rối cho đội trưởng Harry Maguire, người có phong độ kém cỏi ở mùa giải trước. Sự sa sút của Maguire nghiêm trọng đến mức HLV tạm quyền Ralf Rangnick đã phải loại bỏ anh trong vài trận đấu để cầu thủ này có thời gian nghỉ ngơi và lấy lại tinh thần. Với việc tân binh Lisandro kết hợp khá ổn với Raphael Varane ở trận gặp Vallecano, Maguire hẳn đang phải lo lắng có thể mất suất đá chính tại Man United trong mùa giải tới. Lần đầu tiên ra sân cho MU, Lisandro cho thấy khả năng phòng ngự và kỹ thuật khá ấn tượng. Cựu cầu thủ của Ajax đã có tỷ lệ tắc bóng thành công lên tới 100%. Anh cũng có tỷ lệ chuyền thành công vào phần ba cuối sân lên tới 100%. Sau trận đấu, HLV Ten Hag đã dành những lời khen cho cậu học trò của mình: \\"Tôi nghĩ cậu ấy là sự kết hợp thực sự tốt với Varane. Họ đã chơi thực sự chắc chắn và thật tuyệt\\". Lisandro không lạ gì cách chơi của Ten Hag khi đã có nhiều năm làm việc với ông tại Ajax. Trước đó, tân HLV của Quỷ đỏ cũng công khai đánh giá cao Maguire và đảm bảo băng đội trưởng của cầu thủ này. \\"Harry Maguire vẫn sẽ là đội trưởng. Tôi phải làm quen với tất cả các cầu thủ và cần có thời gian, nhưng cậu ấy là một đội trưởng đã thành danh trong một vài năm và đạt được rất nhiều thành công. Vì vậy tôi không nghi ngờ gì về vấn đề này\\", Ten Hag nói. Tuy nhiên, bất chấp những phát biểu này của Ten Hag, nếu Lisandro tiếp tục hòa nhập, anh sẽ dần chiếm lấy suất đá chính của Maguire trong đội hình của Man United."},{"question":"Observe a seguir os níveis de organização de um ser vivo e selecione a alternativa que contém os termos que substituem adequadamente os números 1, 2 e 3.Célula → (1) → (2) → Sistema → (3)a) 1- tecido, 2- organismo, 3- corpo.b) 1- órgão, 2- tecido, 3- organismo.c) 1- tecido, 2- órgão, 3- organismo.d) 1- organela, 2- tecido, 3- corpo.e) 1- organela, 2- órgão, 3- tecido.","answer":"A resposta mais adequado é a opção \\"c\\": Célula → Tecido → Órgão → Sistema → Organismo. Esta organização reflete o processo de constituição de seres vivos, partindo da unidade da vida, a célula. O processo ocorre da seguinte forma:1. Inicialmente, diversas células juntam-se e, realizando uma determinada função, formam os tecidos. 2. Os tecidos, por sua vez, reúnem-se e formam órgãos.3. Os órgãos formam sistemas que trabalham em prol de um mesmo objetivo.4. Por fim, os sistemas trabalham juntos para formar o organismo."},{"question":"In International Trade, what function does the World Trade Organization (WTO) play?","answer":"An international organization that oversees and promotes international commerce is the World commerce Organization (WTO). Promoting free trade, settling trade disputes, and giving member nations a platform to negotiate trade agreements are among its main goals. In order to guarantee that its member nations follow just and open trade practices, the WTO creates the norms and guidelines that regulate global commerce. The World Trade Organization (WTO) seeks to lower trade barriers and provide a more stable and predictable international economic environment by promoting a multilateral trading system. The organization is essential in spreading the values of reciprocity and non-discrimination among its member countries as well as in enabling talks and settling conflicts."},{"question":"Tóm tắt sơ lược cuộc đời nhà văn Vương Hồng Sển.","answer":"Vương Hồng Sển nguyên quán thôn Lâm Mễ, làng Quan Khảo huyện Đổng Ấn, phủ Tuyền Châu, tỉnh Phước Kiến (Trung Quốc), đến đời tổ phụ sang cư ngụ tại làng Khánh Hưng, tổng Nhiêu Khánh, tỉnh Nguyệt Giang (sau đổi là Sóc Trăng). Nhà văn mang ba dòng máu Việt, Hoa, Miên ở Sóc Trăng (cha Hoa, mẹ Việt - Khmer).Năm 8 tuổi, ông vào học trường sơ học làng Khánh Hưng, năm 18 tuổi đậu bằng Tiểu học Pháp Việt. Năm 1919, ông lên Sài Gòn theo học trường Chasseloup Laubat (nay là trường THPT Lê Quý Đôn), đến năm 1923 thi đỗ Brevet Elementaire và bằng Thành chung.Năm 1923, ông ra trường, được bổ chức thư ký tại Trường máy Đỗ Hữu Vị, nay là Cao đẳng Kỹ thuật Cao Thắng, sau đó làm việc tại Tòa bố Sa Đéc, Sở Địa bộ tỉnh Sóc Trăng.Năm 1938, ông về Sài Gòn làm việc ở Phòng dân sự Dinh Thống đốc Nam Kỳ. Cuối năm 1941, ông được biệt phái lên Đà Lạt tùng sự tại Dinh Toàn quyền Decoux với chức danh \\"Thơ ký hạng nhất\\"; năm 1943 đổi về quê nhà làm việc ở tòa bố Sóc Trăng cho đến ngày hưu trí ngạch công chức Nam Kỳ.Sau 1945, ông được tổ chức Thanh niên Tiền phong địa phương tiến cử làm Phó tỉnh trưởng hành chánh tỉnh Sóc Trăng, cho đến ngày Pháp tái chiếm Nam Bộ. Năm 1947, ông bị bệnh, lên Sài Gòn điều trị. Hai năm sau đó, ông làm việc với tư cách hợp đồng ở Viện Bảo tàng Sài Gòn, về sau giữ chức Giám đốc Viện này.Năm 1963, nhà văn về sống tại Gia Định. Sau ngày về hưu, ông được mời giảng một số chuyên đề văn học miền Nam và cổ ngoạn tại Đại học Văn khoa Sài Gòn và Huế."},{"question":"هل يمكنك مساعدتي في التعرف على منظمة الأمم المتحدة؟","answer":"بالتأكيد. منظمة الأمم المتحدة، وتعرف اختصارًا بالأمم المتحدة، هي مُنظمة حُكومية دَولية وواحدة من أكبر وأشهر المنظمات الدولية في القرن العشرين، تأسَّست عام 1945 بعد الحرب العالمية الثانية، وقد حدَّد ميثاق الأمم المتحدة الغاية من تأسيسها بالمحافظة على السلم والأمن الدوليين عن طريق اتخاذ تدابير جماعية فعَّالة لمنع وإزالة الأخطار التي تهدد السلام، وإلى تنمية العلاقات الودية بين الدول على أساس احترام مبدأ المساواة في الحقوق وتقرير المصير للشعوب وتعزيز وتشجيع احترام حقوق الإنسان والحريات الأساسية للجميع دون تمييز بسبب العرق أو الجنس أو اللغة أو الدين، بالإضافة لأن تكون مركزًا لتنسيق أعمال الدول في تحقيق هذه الغايات المشتركة. يقع المقر الرئيسي للأمم المتحدة على أرض دولية (حصانة محلية) في مدينة نيويورك، ولها مكاتب رئيسية أخرى في جنيف ونيروبي وفيينا ولاهاي.تأسست الأمم المتحدة (خلفًا لعصبة الأمم) بهدف منع الحروب مستقبلًا، ففي 25 أبريل 1945 اجتمعت 50 دولة في سان فرانسيسكو وعقدت مؤتمرًا لصياغة ميثاق الأمم المتحدة، والذي اعتُمد في 26 يونيو 1945 ودخل حيِّز التنفيذ في 24 أكتوبر 1945 وهو نفس التاريخ الذي باشرت فيه الأمم المتحدة عملها. تشمل أهداف المنظمة وفقًا للميثاق الحفاظ على السلم والأمن الدوليين، وحفظ حقوق الإنسان، وتقديم المساعدات الإنسانية، وتعزيز التنمية المستدامة، ودعم القانون الدولي. بلغ عدد الدول الأعضاء عند تأسيس المنظمة 51 دولة، ومع انضمام جنوب السودان عام 2011 أصبح عدد الدول الأعضاء في المنظمة 193 دولة يمثلون تقريبًا جميع الدول ذات السيادة في العالم.كانت مهمة المنظمة في الحفاظ على السلام العالمي معقَّدة في سنواتها الأولى بسبب الحرب الباردة بين الولايات المتحدة والاتحاد السوفيتي وحلفائهما. تألَّفت بعثاتها في المقام الأول من مراقبين عسكريين غير مسلحين وقوات مسلحة بأسلحة خفيفة، وتولَّت المتابعة والإبلاغ وبناء الثقة بالدرجة الأولى."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'biar lambat asalkan selamat'? Berilah satu contoh ayat untuknya.","answer":"Ia bermaksud jangan terburu-buru melakukan sesuatu pekerjaan sebaliknya lakukannya dengan penuh kesabaran demi kebaikan bersama-sama. Contoh ayat: Encik Roslan memandu dengan cermat untuk pulang ke kampung bersama-sama keluarganya kerana dia memegang prinsip biar lambat asalkan selamat."},{"question":"أعطني مثالاً على المعلومات العامة في هذه الفئة: السياسة","answer":"مَن الذي كان عضوًا لمجلس الشيوخ لماساتشوستس وتزوج أيضًا بجيم ارين في الماضي؟ اليزابيث وارن - Elizabeth Warren."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai aur atas bukit\\"? Berikan satu contoh ayat yang menggunakannya. ","answer":"Maksud peribahasa ini adalah menyerahkan diri kepada nasib. Contoh ayat: Setelah gagal mencari anaknya yang hilang, wanita itu kini berserah sahaja kepada nasib bagai aur atas bukit."},{"question":"Dame un ejemplo de trivia en esta categoría: Historia.","answer":"¿Cuál civilización antigua creó acueductos para mover el agua hacia la ciudad? La civilización Inca y Romana.Dos civilizaciones antiguas crearon acueductos para mover el agua hacia sus ciudades, fueron la civilización romana y la civilización inca. La civilización romana construyó acueductos elevados con arcos, mientras que la civilización inca desarrolló sistemas subterráneos o canales abiertos, como los \\"qanats\\" o \\"puquios\\", para asegurar el suministro de agua desde manantiales naturales y corrientes. Ambas civilizaciones demostraron una notable habilidad en ingeniería hidráulica para satisfacer las necesidades de agua de sus asentamientos y campos agrícolas."},{"question":"2018年の流行語大賞に選ばれた、そだねー。はあるスポーツの女子団体の掛け声でした。そのスポーツとは何だったでしょう?","answer":"カーリングです。"},{"question":"Mắt của tôi cận 2.75 và loạn 0.75. Bác sĩ cho hỏi gần 40 tuổi có nên đi mổ mắt chữa cận loạn không? Vì mọi người bảo mắt ở tình trạng sắp lão hóa thì không nên đi mổ nữa.","answer":"Vì bạn 40 tuổi nên có hiện tượng lão thị. Độ cận thị không cao có khả năng trung hòa với độ lão thị. Việc mổ chỉ theo nhu cầu thực tế của bạn, ví dụ như bạn có mong muốn nhìn xa tối đa khi lái xe, hay chơi thể thao thì bạn nên mổ"},{"question":"Inona no anarana iantsoana ny fampiakarana isan-taona ny karaman’ny mpiasa iray mba hijerena ny fidangan’ny vidim-piainana?1-Fiakaran’ny vidim-piainana2-Fahombiazana tombony3-Fety Bonus","answer":"Valiny: 1. Fiakaran’ny vidim-piainana"},{"question":"යුක්‍රේනයේ අගනුවර වන්නේ ?","answer":"යුක්රේනයේ අගනුවර කියු (Kyiv) වේ."},{"question":"Эпос Манасчы серияларын жараткан, СССР мамлекеттик сыйлыгынын лауреаты (1971) сүрөтчү айыма) З. П. Петрова б) Л. А. Ильинав) К. Т. Смирнова г) М. А. Боярская","answer":"б) Л. А. Ильина"},{"question":"குட்டி ரேவதி அவர்களின்  வாழ்க்கை வரலாறு  பற்றி விவரிக்க?              ","answer":"குட்டி ரேவதி (Kutti Revathi) இந்தியாவின் தமிழ்நாட்டைச் சேர்ந்த சென்னையை வசிப்பிடமாகக் கொண்ட ஒரு பெண் கவிஞர் ஆவார்.[1] சித்த மருத்துவரான இவர் பாடலாசிரியர், பெண்ணிய ஆர்வலர், திரைப்பட இயக்குநர் மற்றும் மருத்துவர் என பன்முகங்களுடனும் சமகாலத்தில் எழுதிவரும் பெண் படைப்பாளிகளுள் கவனிக்கத்தக்க ஒருவராகவும் இயங்கிவருகிறார். கவித்துவமும் சிந்தனைத் தெளிவும் நிறைந்தவர். இவர் மூன்று கவிதை நுால்களை வெளியிட்டுள்ளார்.பெண்களுக்கான இலக்கிய காலாண்டு இதழான பணிக்குடம் என்ற முதல் தமிழ் பெண்ணிய இதழின் ஆசிரியராகவும் உள்ளார். இவ்விதழில் பெண்ணிலக்கியவாதிகளின் படைப்புகளே அதிகம் வெளியிடப்படுவது குறிப்பிடத்தக்கது. பல இலக்கிய சந்திப்புகள் மற்றும் சக மாணவர்களின் கவிதைத் தொகுப்புகளை மதிப்பாய்வு செய்தபின்னரே தனது சொந்த படைப்புகளில் சிலவற்றை குட்டி ரேவதி உருவாக்கத் தொடங்கினார்.தலித் பெண்ணியம் என்பதை சித்தாந்த வடிவில் கட்டமைப்பதும் களப்பணிக்குச் செயல்படுத்துவதும் தான் இந்தியாவில் பெண்களின் உரிமைகளை முழுமையான வடிவில் பெற்றுத் தரும் என்று நம்புபவர். சாதிய மறுப்பும் ஒழிப்பும் தான் பெண்ணுடலை அடிமைத் தளையிலிருந்து விடுவிக்கும் என்ற உணர்வுடன் தலித் பெண்ணியத்தைத் தனக்கேயான மொழியில் சித்தாந்தப்படுத்தி வருபவர். இதற்கு தமிழகத்தில் உருவெடுத்த பெண் கவிஞர்களின் ’உடல் அரசியல்’ மொழியும் எழுச்சியும் முக்கியமான பங்களிப்பு என்கிறார். சிற்றிதழ் இயக்கம் மற்றும் நவீனத் தமிழ் இலக்கியம் வழி உருவெடுத்தவர். இந்நூற்றாண்டின் முக்கியமான பெண்ணியச் செயல்பாடு என்பது தனித்த பெண்ணியச் சிந்தனைகளைக் கட்புல படிமங்களாக பரிணமிக்கச்செய்தலே[தெளிவுபடுத்துக] என்ற தன் தீவிர நம்பிக்கையின் படி முழுமூச்சாக ஆவணப்படத்துறையிலும் திரைப்படத்துறையிலும் இயங்கிவருபவர். சிறகு என்ற ஒரு திரைப்படத்தையும் குட்டி ரேவதி இயக்கியுள்ளார்.இவர் தனது சக மாணவர்களின் கவிதைத் தொகுப்புகள் தொடர்பான திறனாய்வு இலக்கியக் கூட்டங்களை நடத்தியுள்ளார். இவர் தனது சுய படைப்புகள் குறித்தும் பணிகளைத் தொடங்கினார். பள்ளிப்படிப்பிற்குப் பிறகு உலகின் மிகப் பழமையான மருத்துவ முறையாகவும், தமிழ்நாட்டைத் தாயகமாகவும் கொண்ட சித்த மருத்துவத்தைப் பயின்று இளங்கலைப் பட்டமும் பெற்றார். அவர் சென்னையில் உள்ள மெட்ராசு வளர்ச்சிசார் கல்வி நிறுவனத்தில் (Madras Institute of Development Studies) மருத்துவம் சார்ந்த மானிடவியலில் தனது முனைவர் பட்டத்திற்கான ஆய்வுப் படிப்பை மேற்கொண்டார். இந்தியா டுடே என்ற பத்திரிக்கையால் வழங்கப்பட்ட எதிர்கால இலக்கியத்தின் முகங்கள் (சிகரம் 15) என்ற விருதினைப் பெற்றார். சாகித்ய அகாதெமி அமைப்பினரால் 2005 ஆம் ஆண்டில் இந்தியாவில் உள்ள இலக்கியவாதிகளை சந்திப்பதற்கான உதவித்தொகையைப் பெற்றார். இவர் சமகாலத்திய தமிழ் கவிஞராக இருந்து கருத்து முரண்பாடுகளைக் கொண்ட, வாதத்துக்கிடமான பல கவிதைத் தொகுப்புகளை வெளியிட்டுள்ளார்"},{"question":"Vilket av dessa hockeylag är från Värmland?","answer":"Värmlands stolthet är Färjestad BK när det kommer till hockey. Det är ett av Sveriges mest framgångsrika hockeylag genom tiderna med 10 SM-guld. Dessutom har Färjestad spelat i Sveriges högsta hockeyliga i över 55 säsonger."},{"question":"එක් වසරක් තුළ වැඩිම ටෙස්ට් කඩුලු සංඛ්‍යාවක් දවාගත් ක්‍රීඩකයා වන්නේ කවුද?","answer":"ශේන් වෝන් (ඕස්ට්‍රේලියානු)"},{"question":"\\"कर्णाली नदी\\" को सांस्कृतिक महत्व र पश्चिम नेपालका समुदायको जीवनमा यसको भूमिका व्याख्या गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"कर्णाली नदी सांस्कृतिक रूपमा महत्त्वपूर्ण छ र यसले पश्चिम नेपालका समुदायहरूको जीविकोपार्जनमा महत्त्वपूर्ण भूमिका खेल्छ।"},{"question":"Aṅụ","answer":"Olundi - anwụ"},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'kaki bodek'? Berilah satu contoh ayat untuknya.","answer":"Ia bermaksud memuji dengan tidak ikhlas / puji dengan harapan dapat balasan. Contoh ayat: Orang kaki bodek sering ponteng kerja kerana dia pandai mengampu pegawai atasan."},{"question":"Izihlabathi ziyaqibana ngempela uma ubheka ngasohlangothinilezimfashini. Phambilini uma ukhuluma ngemfashini ubusukeubhekise ezingutsheni zokugqoka kuphela. Nokho-ke isikhathisesiguqukile ngoba sekukuningi kakhulu okubizwa ngemfashiningaphandle kwezingubo zokugqoka. Indlela yokulungisa izinwele,uhlobo lwezimoto olungajwayelekile, omakhalekhukhwini konkelokhu kuyaba imfashini. Uma imfashini ethile isangenisile baningiabantu ababa nesiqiniseko sokuthi ayibedluli. Abanye bancamelaukutsheleka imadlana okukanye bayintshontshe ukuze bazibusisengemfashini.Akuve kudabukisa nokho-ke ukufica umuntuesezimpintshe kabuhlungu ngesiketi noma ngebhulukwe egamenilokuthi imfashini. Imfashini phela nayo iyabhekelelwa. Kwesinyeisikhathi kuhle nje ukuthi uyiyeke imfashini yedlule ungazangeuzihluphe ngayo. Abantu abaningi bazithola sebengonomafashiningenxa yokuthi bafuna ukwamukeleka kubangani babo. Basukebefuna ukusika ukhasi emiphakathini abahlala kuyo. Imisakazonamaphephandaba iyazama ukunqanda lesi sihlava ngokuthi kubenezinhlelo ezithize ezikhuluma ngobubi nobuhle bezimfashini. 1. Nikeza umsebenzi wamagama adwetshelwe asemgqeni","answer":"kabuhlungu- lisebenze ukukhanyisa isenzo (esezimpintshe).noma-lisebenze ukuhlanganisa. "},{"question":"Apakah jawapan untuk teka-teki berikut: Boleh dijumpai pada hari jadi, atau semasa gelap.","answer":"Jawapannya ialah lilin. "},{"question":"Inona ary izany: ny reniny miteny hoe andao hitsangana, ny zanany manao hoe andao hitsivalana?","answer":"Ny valiny dia tohatra."},{"question":"Declan encontra Eve e Nikki a correr num edifício. A Nikki encontra a Eve e o Declan a correr para um edifício. Pergunta: A frase 1 e a frase 2 expressam o mesmo significado? Sim ou não?","answer":"Não."},{"question":"Какве особине и карактеристике најчешће имају особе које у свом животу имају број девет, и како се то одражава на њихов живот?","answer":"Број девет у нумерологији симболизује крај и завршетак. Он је као виша октава броја шест и уметност коју шестица представља, деветка елевира на ниво више уметности и најузвишеније форме љубави. Онима који су рођени под овим бројем често се приписују више ступње интуиције и снажне емоције. Међутим, ова интуиција и емоционална дубина могу бити и мач с две оштрице. Деветке често идеализују своје емоционалне односе и подлежу разочарању јер их стварност не може испунити. Иако воле своју самоћу и тишину, оне се често отварају само када то желе, што може бити изазовно за људе окo њих. На тему вере и духовности, многе деветке су склоне верској пракси и институцијама. У сфери здравља и благостања, оне су склоне алтернативној медицини, али и негативно аспектована деветка може бити подложна пороцима и избегавању проблема. Занимљиво је да деветка влада планетом Нептун и знаком Рибе, који су везани за снагу интуиције и емоционалну дубину."},{"question":"வினா:பாரதிதாசன் குறிப்பு வரைக.","answer":"விடை:பாரதிதாசன் (29 ஏப்ரல் 1891 – 21 ஏப்ரல் 1964) பாண்டிச்சேரியில் (புதுச்சேரியில்) பிறந்து, பெரும் புகழ் படைத்த பாவலர் ஆவார். இவருடைய இயற்பெயர் கனகசுப்புரத்தினம் ஆகும். தமிழாசிரியராகப் பணியாற்றிய இவர், சுப்பிரமணிய பாரதியார் மீது கொண்ட பற்றுதலால், 'பாரதிதாசன்' என்று தம் பெயரை மாற்றிக் கொண்டார். பாரதிதாசன், தம் எழுச்சி மிக்க எழுத்துகளால், \\"புரட்சிக் கவிஞர்\\" என்றும் \\"பாவேந்தர்\\" என்றும் பரவலாக அழைக்கப்படுபவர். இவர் குயில் என்னும் (கவிதை வடிவில்) ஒரு திங்களிதழை நடத்தி வந்தார்.வாழ்க்கைக் குறிப்பு:புரட்சிக்கவி பாரதிதாசன், ஏப்ரல் 29, 1891 ஆம் ஆண்டு புதுவையில் செங்குந்தர் கைக்கோள முதலியார் மரபில், பெரிய வணிகராயிருந்த, கனகசபை முதலியார், இலக்குமி அம்மாள் ஆகியோருக்குப் பிறந்தார். கவிஞரின் இயற்பெயர் கனகசுப்புரத்தினம். 1920-ஆம் ஆண்டில் பழநி அம்மையார் என்பவரை மணந்து கொண்டார்.இவர் சிறு வயதிலேயே பிரெஞ்சு மொழிப் பள்ளியில் பயின்றார். ஆயினும், தமிழ்ப் பள்ளியிலேயே பயின்ற காலமே கூடியது. தமது பதினாறாம் வயதிலேயே, கல்வே கல்லூரியில் தமிழ்ப் புலமைத் தேர்வு கருதிப் புகுந்தார். தமிழ் மொழிப் பற்றும், முயற்சியால் தமிழறிவும் நிறைந்தவராதலின், இரண்டாண்டில், கல்லூரியிலேயே முதலாவதாகத் தேர்வுற்றார். பதினெட்டு வயதிலேயே அவரின் சிறப்புணர்ந்த அரசியலார் அவர் அரசினர் கல்லூரித் தமிழாசிரியரானார்.இசையுணர்வும், நல்லெண்ணமும் அவருடைய உள்ளத்தில் கவிதையுருவில் காட்சி அளிக்கத் தலைப்பட்டன. சிறு வயதிலேயே சிறுசிறு பாடல்களை, அழகாகச் சுவையுடன் எழுதித் தமது தோழர்களுக்குப் பாடிக் காட்டுவார்.நண்பர் ஒருவரின் திருமணத்தில், விருந்துக்குப் பின், சி. சுப்பிரமணிய பாரதியாரின் நாட்டுப் பாடலைப் பாடினார். பாரதியாரும் அவ்விருந்துக்கு வந்திருந்தார். ஆனால் கவிஞருக்கு அது தெரியாது. அப்பாடலே, அவரைப் பாரதியாருக்கு அறிமுகம் செய்து வைத்தது. ஆயினும் அதற்கு முன்பே அவர் பாரதியாரைச் சந்தித்திருப்பது பாரதியார் தாமே எழுதின தராசு என்ற தொடரில் பாரதிதாசனைப் பெயர் சுட்டாமே ஒரு கைக்கோளச் சாதித் தமிழ்க் கவிராயர் தம்மிடம் வந்து எங்கெங்குக் காணினும் சக்தியடா- தம்பி ஏழு கடல் அவள் மேனியடா!\\" என்று ஒரு பாடலைப் பாடிக் காட்டியதாகக் கூறியிருப்பது இவரே அந்தக் கவிராயர் என்று உறுதிப்படுத்துகிறது.\\"தன் நண்பர்கள் முன்னால் பாடலைப் பாடு\\" என்று பாரதி கூறப் பாரதிதாசன் \\"எங்கெங்கு காணினும் சக்தியடா\\" என்று ஆரம்பித்து, இரண்டு பாடல்களைப் பாடினார். இவரின் முதற் பாடல், பாரதியாராலேயே 'சிறீ சுப்பிரமணிய கவிதா மண்டலத்தைச் சார்ந்த கனக சுப்புரத்தினம் எழுதியது' என்றெழுதப்பட்டுச் 'சுதேசமித்திரன்' இதழுக்கு அனுப்பப்பட்டது.புதுவையிலிருந்து வெளியான தமிழ் ஏடுகளில், \\"கண்டழுதுவோன்\\", \\"கிறுக்கன்\\", \\"கிண்டல்காரன்\\", \\"பாரதிதாசன்\\" எனப் பல புனைப் பெயர்களில் எழுதி வந்தார்.தந்தை பெரியாரின் தீவிரத் தொண்டராகவும் விளங்கினார் . மேலும் அவர் திராவிடர் இயக்கத்தில் மிகுந்த ஈடுபாடு கொண்டார். அதன் காரணமாகக் கடவுள் மறுப்பு, சாதி மறுப்பு, மத எதிர்ப்பு போன்றவற்றினை தனது பாடல்கள் மூலம் பதிவு செய்தார்.பிரபல எழுத்தாளரும், திரைப்படக் கதாசிரியரும், பெரும் கவிஞருமான பாரதிதாசன், அரசியலிலும் தன்னை ஈடுபடுத்திக் கொண்டார். புதுச்சேரி சட்டமன்ற உறுப்பினராக, 1954-ஆம் ஆண்டு தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்டார்.1946, சூலை 29-இல் அறிஞர் அண்ணாவால், கவிஞர் \\"புரட்சிக்கவி\\" என்று பாராட்டப்பட்டு, ரூ.25,000 வழங்கப்பட்டுக் கௌரவிக்கப்பட்டார்.பாரதிதாசன் அவர்கள், நகைச்சுவை உணர்வு நிரம்பியவர். கவிஞருடைய படைப்பான \\"பிசிராந்தையார்\\" என்ற நாடக நூலுக்கு, 1969-இல் சாகித்ய அகாடமியின் விருது கிடைத்தது. இவருடைய படைப்புகள் தமிழ்நாடு அரசினரால் 1990-இல் பொது உடைமையாக்கப்பட்டன."},{"question":"Quais estados dos EUA produzem fosfatos?","answer":"Os EUA são o 3º maior produtor mundial de fosfato. Sendo os principais estados produtores os estados da Flórida, Carolina do Norte, Idaho e Tennessee. "},{"question":"肚子餓了為什麼會咕咕叫？","answer":"人體在飢餓的時候通常會有一些不同的反應，比如最簡單的是“感覺”到了飢餓，或者是“肚子餓得咕咕叫”了，甚至於到“餓得頭昏眼花”了。　　來自波茨坦營養學研究所的科學家約爾格·哈斯勒認為，這其中的“咕咕叫”無疑是最明確的信號，表明你需要進食了。　　據德通社報導說，哈斯勒研究發現，其實當人們說自己的肚子空了感到飢餓的時候，在胃部也並非是空無一物，而是存有空氣與水。在這種情況下，胃部肌肉的相互“拉扯”運動，會使得胃部形成諸如一根“軟管”一般的狀態。“而空氣和水就在這根軟管里受到擠壓，自然就會咕咕作響”，哈斯勒解釋說。　　科學家認為，整個過程其實只是人體內一個很自然的反應。此外，這種反應還會在某些條件下受到人體其它反應的刺激而得到激發或者加強，比如當某些美味食品落入你的視線，導致嘴裡開始分泌唾液、胃部開始分泌胃酸等幫助消化的物質的時候，你就會覺得產生了飢餓的感覺，而往往肚子也會適時地開始了“咕咕叫”。"},{"question":"ਅੱਜ-ਕੱਲ੍ਹ ਮਲਿਕਾ ਸ਼ੇਰਾਵਤ ਅਜੈ ਦੇਵਗਨ ਦੀਆਂ ਤਰੀਫ਼ਾਂ ਕਰਦੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਥੱਕਦੀ। ਹੁਣੇ ਹੁਣੇ ਉਸ ਨੇ ਅਜੈ ਦੇਵਗਨ ਨਾਲ ਨਵੀਂ ਆ ਰਹੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਤੇਜ਼’ ਵਿੱਚ ਲੈਲਾ ਆਈਟਮ ਨੰਬਰ ਕੀਤਾ ਹੈ। ਸੂਤਰਾਂ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਉਹ ਸੈੱਟ ’ਤੇ ਅਜੈ ਦੇਵਗਨ ਨਾਲ ਹੀ ਗੱਪਾਂ ਮਾਰਦੀ ਰਹੀ।ਹਾਲੀਵੁੱਡ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਪਾਲੀਟਿਕਸ ਆਫ ਲਵ’ ’ਚ ਆਪਣੀ ਅਦਾਕਾਰੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਦਰਸ਼ਕਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਪ੍ਰਭਾਵਤ ਕਰਨ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਮਲਿਕਾ ਇੱਕ ਵਾਰ ਫਿਰ ਬਾਲੀਵੁੱਡ ’ਚ ਵਾਪਸ ਆ ਗਈ ਹੈ। ਇਨ੍ਹੀਂ ਦਿਨੀਂ ਉਹ ਵਿਵੇਕ ਓਬਰਾਏ ਦੇ ਨਾਲ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਕਿਸਮਤ’, ‘ਲਵ’, ‘ਪੈਸਾ’ ‘ਦਿੱਲੀ’ ਸਮੇਤ ਕੁਝ ਹੋਰ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ਕਰ ਰਹੀ ਹੈ। ਮਲਿਕਾ ਸ਼ੇਰਾਵਤ ਨੇ ਜਦੋਂ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਲੀਵੁੱਡ ’ਚ ਕਦਮ ਰੱਖਿਆ, ਉਦੋਂ ਤੋਂ ਹੀ ਉਹ ਲਗਾਤਾਰ ਕਿਸੇ ਨਾ ਕਿਸੇ ਕਾਰਨ ਕਰਕੇ ਵਿਵਾਦਾਂ ’ਚ ਘਿਰੀ ਰਹੀ ਹੈ। ਉਹ ਖ਼ੁਦ ਕਹਿੰਦੀ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਵਿਵਾਦਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਤਾਂ ਮੇਰਾ ਨਜ਼ਦੀਕੀ ਰਿਸ਼ਤਾ ਹੈ ਪਰ ਮੇਰੇ ’ਤੇ ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦਾ ਕੋਈ ਅਸਰ ਨਹੀਂ ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਮੈਂ ਬਹੁਤ ਸਪਸ਼ਟ ਰੂਪ ’ਚ ਗੱਲ ਕਰਦੀ ਹਾਂ। ਹੁਣ ਤਕ ਮੇਰੀ ਸਮਝ ’ਚ ਇਹ ਨਹੀਂ ਆਇਆ ਕਿ ਲੋਕ ਆਪਣੀ ਪੀੜ੍ਹੀ ਹੇਠ ਸੋਟਾ ਮਾਰਨ ਦੀ ਥਾਂ ਹੋਰਾਂ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਵਾਦ ਕਿਉਂ ਖੜ੍ਹੇ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ? ਮੈਂ ਕਦੇ ਕਿਸੇ ਵਿਵਾਦ ਨੂੰ ਜਨਮ ਨਹੀਂ ਦਿੱਤਾ। ਇਸ ਦੇ ਬਾਵਜੂਦ ਵਿਵਾਦ ਉੱਠਦੇ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ ਅਤੇ ਮੈਂ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦਾ ਲੁਤਫ਼ ਉਠਾਉਂਦੀ ਹਾਂ।ਸਵਾਲ: ਤੁਹਾਡੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਹਿਸ’ ਨੂੰ ਦਰਸ਼ਕਾਂ ਨੇ ਪੂਰੀ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਨਕਾਰ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਤੇ ‘ਡਬਲ ਧਮਾਲ’ ਨੂੰ ਵੀ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਸਫ਼ਲਤਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਮਿਲੀ ਜਦੋਂਕਿ ਇਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਦਾ ਗੀਤ ‘ਜਲੇਬੀ ਬਾਈ’ ਕਾਫ਼ੀ ਚਰਚਿਤ ਰਿਹਾ ਸੀ?ਜਵਾਬ: ਸਫ਼ਲਤਾ ਤੇ ਅਸਫ਼ਲਤਾ ਜ਼ਿੰਦਗੀ ਦੇ ਇੱਕੋ ਸਿੱਕੇ ਦੇ ਦੋ ਪਹਿਲੂ ਹਨ। ਮੈਂ ਕਦੇ ਇਸ ਦੀ ਪਰਵਾਹ ਨਹੀਂ ਕੀਤੀ। ਮੈਂ ਤਾਂ ਸਿਰਫ਼ ਆਪਣੇ ਕੰਮ ਨੂੰ ਈਮਾਨਦਾਰੀ ਨਾਲ ਕਰਨ ਵੱਲ ਧਿਆਨ ਦਿੰਦੀ ਹਾਂ। ਜਦੋਂ ਤਕ ਮੇਰੇ ਕੋਲ ਕੰਮ ਹੈ, ਉਦੋਂ ਤਕ ਆਪਣੇ ਆਪ ਨੂੰ ਸਫ਼ਲ ਮੰਨਦੀ ਹਾਂ। ਅੱਜ ਦੀ ਤਰੀਕ ’ਚ ਮੇਰੇ ਕੋਲ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ਦੀ ਘਾਟ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੈ। ਮੈਂ ਜਿੱਥੇ ਵਿਵੇਕ ਓਬਰਾਏ ਨਾਲ ਸੰਜੇ ਖੰਡੂਰੀ ਦੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਕਿਸਮਤ’, ‘ਲਵ’, ‘ਪੈਸਾ’, ‘ਦਿੱਲੀ’ ਕਰ ਰਹੀ ਹਾਂ, ਉੱਥੇ ਅਭਿਨੇਤਾ-ਨਿਰਮਾਤਾ ਸੋਨੂੰ ਸੂਦ ਨਾਲ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਲੱਕੀ-ਅਣਲੱਕੀ’ ਕਰ ਰਹੀ ਹਾਂ। ਮੇਰੀ ਸਮਝ ’ਚ ਤਾਂ ਇਹੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਆਉਂਦਾ ਜਦੋਂ ਮੇਰੀ ਕੋਈ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਸਫ਼ਲ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ ਤਾਂ ਮੀਡੀਆ ਚੁੱਪੀ ਧਾਰ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਜਦੋਂ ਕੋਈ ਅਸਫ਼ਲ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ ਤਾਂ ਵਧਾ ਚੜ੍ਹਾ ਕੇ ਗੱਲ ਕੀਤੀ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ। ਮੇਰੀ ਹਾਲੀਵੁੱਡ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਪਾਲੀਟਿਕਸ ਆਫ ਲਵ’ ਨੂੰ ਵਿਦੇਸ਼ਾਂ ’ਚ ਕਾਫ਼ੀ ਪਸੰਦ ਕੀਤਾ ਗਿਆ ਪਰ ਹਿੰਦੁਸਤਾਨੀ ਮੀਡੀਆ ਨੇ ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਕੋਈ ਤਵੱਜੋ ਨਹੀਂ ਦਿੱਤੀ।ਸਵਾਲ: ਤੁਹਾਡੀ ਹਾਲੀਵੁੱਡ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਪਾਲੀਟਿਕਸ ਆਫ ਲਵ’ ਭਾਰਤ ’ਚ ਰਿਲੀਜ਼ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੋਈ ਤੇ ਨਾ ਹੀ ਤੁਸੀਂ ਜਾਂ ਨਿਰਮਾਤਾ ਨੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਕੁਝ ਦੱਸਿਆ?ਜਵਾਬ: ਉਹੋ ! ਇਹ ਤਾਂ ਗੜਬੜ ਹੋ ਗਈ ਪਰ ਤੁਸੀਂ ਚਿੰਤਾ ਨਾ ਕਰੋ। ਬਹੁਤ ਜਲਦੀ ਅਸੀਂ ਇਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਨੂੰ ਭਾਰਤੀ ਸਿਨੇਮਾ ਘਰਾਂ ’ਚ ਦਿਖਾਵਾਂਗੇ।ਸਵਾਲ: ਕੀ ਤੁਸੀਂ ਕਿਸੇ ਹਾਲੀਵੁੱਡ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਦੇ ਸਬੰਧ ਵਿੱਚ ਅਮਰੀਕਾ ਦੇ ਰਾਸ਼ਟਰਪਤੀ ਬਰਾਕ ਓਬਾਮਾ ਨੂੰ ਮਿਲੇ ਸੀ?ਜਵਾਬ: ਜੀ ਹਾਂ, ਇਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਦੇ ਸਿਲਸਿਲੇ ’ਚ ਹੀ ਬਰਾਕ ਓਬਾਮਾ ਨਾਲ ਮੇਰੀ ਦੋ ਵਾਰੀ ਮੁਲਾਕਾਤ ਹੋਈ। ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਮੁਲਾਕਾਤ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਪਤਾ ਲੱਗਿਆ ਕਿ ਮੈਂ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਪਸੰਦੀਦਾ ਕਲਾਕਾਰ ਹਾਂ। ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਕਿਹਾ ਕਿ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਖੁਸ਼ੀ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਇੱਕ ਭਾਰਤੀ ਹੁੰਦੇ ਹੋਏ ਤੁਸੀਂ ਪੂਰੇ ਸੰਸਾਰ ’ਚ ਛਾ ਗਏ। ਤੇਰੇ ਅੰਦਰ ਹਰ ਹਾਲਾਤ ਨਾਲ ਲੜਨ ਦੀ ਸ਼ਕਤੀ ਹੈ। ਮੈਨੂੰ ਉਮੀਦ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਕੌਮਾਂਤਰੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਜਗਤ ’ਚ ਤੇਰਾ ਨਾਂ ਰੌਸ਼ਨ ਹੋਵੇਗਾ। ਅਮਰੀਕਾ ਵਰਗੇ ਦੇਸ਼ ਦੇ ਰਾਸ਼ਟਰਪਤੀ ਦੇ ਮੂੰਹੋਂ ਅਜਿਹੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਸੁਣਨ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਹੋਰ ਕੀ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ?ਸਵਾਲ: ਤਾਂ ਫਿਰ ਕੀ ਤੁਸੀਂ ਹਾਲੀਵੁੱਡ ਤਕ ਹੀ ਸੀਮਤ ਰਹਿਣਾ ਚਾਹੁੰਦੇ ਹੋ?ਜਵਾਬ: ਕੀਹਨੇ ਕਿਹਾ ! ਜੇ ਅਜਿਹਾ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਤਾਂ ‘ਪਾਲੀਟਿਕਸ ਆਫ ਲਵ’ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਮੈਂ ਬਾਲੀਵੁੱਡ ਦੀਆਂ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ’ਚ ਕਦੇ ਰੁੱਝੀ ਨਾ ਹੁੰਦੀ। ਮੈਂ ਅੱਜ ਜੋ ਕੁਝ ਵੀ ਹਾਂ ਬਾਲੀਵੁੱਡ ਕਰਕੇ। ਮੈਂ ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਕਦੇ ਅਲਵਿਦਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਕਹਾਂਗੀ। ਹਰ ਸਾਲ ਹਾਲੀਵੁੱਡ ਦੀ ਇੱਕ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਜ਼ਰੂਰ ਕਰਨਾ ਚਾਹੁੰਦੀ ਹਾਂ।ਸਵਾਲ: ਜੇ ਇਹੋ ਗੱਲ ਹੈ ਤਾਂ ਤੁਸੀਂ ਨਿਰਮਾਤਾ ਵਿਨੋਦ ਬਚਨ ਤੇ ਨਿਰਦੇਸ਼ਕ ਆਨੰਦ ਕੁਮਾਰ ਦੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਜ਼ਿਲ੍ਹਾ ਗਾਜ਼ੀਆਬਾਦ’ ਕਰਨ ਤੋਂ ਸਾਫ਼ ਮਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਕਿਉਂ ਕੀਤਾ?ਜਵਾਬ: ਮੇਰੀ ਸਮਝ ’ਚ ਨਹੀਂ ਆ ਰਿਹਾ ਕਿ ਇਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਨੂੰ ਲੈ ਕੇ ਇਹ ਗੱਲਾਂ ਕਿਉਂ ਹੋ ਰਹੀਆਂ ਹਨ ਜਦੋਂਕਿ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਇਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਦੀ ਕੋਈ ਪੇਸ਼ਕਸ਼ ਹੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੋਈ। ਫਿਰ ਇਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ’ਚ ਕੰਮ ਕਰਨ ਤੋਂ ਮਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਕਰਨ ਦਾ ਤਾਂ ਸਵਾਲ ਹੀ ਪੈਦਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੁੰਦਾ। ਹਾਂ ਐਨਾ ਪਤਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਇਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਦੇ ਨਿਰਮਾਤਾ ਤੇ ਨਿਰਦੇਸ਼ਕ ਨੇ ਇਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਨੂੰ ਲੈ ਕੇ ਬਿਪਾਸ਼ਾ ਬਾਸੂ ਨਾਲ ਗੱਲ ਕੀਤੀ ਸੀ। ਫਿਰ ਕੀ ਹੋਇਆ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਨਹੀਂ ਪਤਾ।ਸਵਾਲ: ਤੁਹਾਡੇ ਬਾਰੇ ਕਿਹਾ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਤੁਸੀਂ ਭੱਟ ਕੈਂਪ ਨਾਲੋਂ ਨਾਤਾ ਤੋੜ ਲਿਆ ਹੈ ਜਦੋਂਕਿ ਤੁਹਾਨੂੰ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਬਰੇਕ ਦਿੱਤੀ ਸੀ। ਮਹੇਸ਼ ਭੱਟ ਨੇ ਮਰਡਰ ਦੇ ਸੀਕੁਅਲ ਲਈ ਤੁਹਾਡੇ ਨਾਲ ਗੱਲ ਕੀਤੀ ਸੀ ਪਰ ਤੁਸੀਂ ਐਨੀ ਵੱਡੀ ਰਕਮ ਮੰਗੀ ਕਿ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਦੂਰੀ ਬਣਾ ਲਈ?ਜਵਾਬ: ਬਕਵਾਸ ! ਮੈਂ ਮਹੇਸ਼ ਭੱਟ ਨੂੰ ਕਦੇ ਮਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨਹੀਂ ਕਰ ਸਕਦੀ ਤੇ ਨਾ ਹੀ ਪੈਸੇ ਨੂੰ ਲੈ ਕੇ ਇਹੋ ਜਿਹੀ ਗੱਲ ਕਰ ਸਕਦੀ ਹਾਂ। ਮੈਂ ਮਹੇਸ਼ ਭੱਟ ਨਾਲ ਕੰਮ ਕਰਨਾ ਚਾਹੁੰਦੀ ਹਾਂ। ਉਸ ਤੋਂ ਵੀ ਵੱਡੀ ਗੱਲ ਇਹ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਮਰਡਰ ਦੇ ਸੀਕੁਅਲ ਲਈ ਮੇਰੇ ਨਾਲ ਕਦੇ ਸੰਪਰਕ ਕੀਤਾ ਹੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਗਿਆ।ਸਵਾਲ: ਕੋਈ ਅਗਾਊਂ ਯੋਜਨਾ?ਜਵਾਬ: ਮੈਂ ਬਹੁਤ ਸਾਰਾ ਕੰਮ ਕਰਨਾ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਭਰਾ ਬਿਕਰਮ ਨੂੰ ਪੈਰਾਂ ’ਤੇ ਖੜ੍ਹੇ ਕਰਨਾ ਹੈ। ਉਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਬਾਲੀਵੁੱਡ ਦਾ ਹੀਰੋ ਬਣਨ ਦੇ ਸਾਰੇ ਗੁਣ ਹਨ ਪਰ ਕਿਸੇ ਨਿਰਮਾਤਾ ਦੀ ਉਸ ’ਤੇ ਨਜ਼ਰ ਨਹੀਂ ਪਈ।ਸਵਾਲ: ਤੁਸੀਂ ਆਪਣੀ ਨਿੱਜੀ ਜ਼ਿੰਦਗੀ ’ਚ ਕਿਸੇ ਇਨਸਾਨ ਬਾਰੇ ਕੋਈ ਚਰਚਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਕਰਦੇ?ਜਵਾਬ: ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਮੇਰੀ ਜ਼ਿੰਦਗੀ ’ਚ ਮੇਰੇ ਭਰਾ ਬਿਕਰਮ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾਂ ਹੋਰ ਕੋਈ ਮਰਦ ਨਹੀਂ। ਫਿਰ ਮੈਂ ਚਰਚਾ ਕੀ ਕਰਾਂ।ਸਵਾਲ: ਆਪਣੇ ਹੁਣ ਤਕ ਦੇ ਸਫ਼ਰ ਬਾਰੇ ਕੋਈ ਪਛਤਾਵਾ ਹੈ?ਜਵਾਬ: ਰਾਤ ਗਈ ਬਾਤ ਗਈ। ਮੈਂ ਕਦੇ ਬੀਤੇ ਬਾਰੇ ਨਹੀਂ ਸੋਚਦੀ।ਸਵਾਲ: ਹਾਲੀਵੁੱਡ ਦੇ ਸਟਾਰ ਅਦਾਕਾਰ ਜੈਕੀ ਚੈਨ ਨਾਲ ਤੁਹਾਡੇ ਸਬੰਧਾਂ ਦੀ ਅਕਸਰ ਚਰਚਾ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਰਹਿੰਦੀ ਹੈ?ਜਵਾਬ: ਉਹ ਮੇਰੇ ਦੋਸਤ ਹਨ। ਇੱਕ ਅਦਾਕਾਰ ਦੇ ਤੌਰ ’ਤੇ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਮੇਰੀ ਕਾਫ਼ੀ ਮਦਦ ਕੀਤੀ। ਅੱਜ ਹਾਲੀਵੁੱਡ ’ਚ ਮੈਂ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਬਦੌਲਤ ਕੰਮ ਕਰ ਪਾ ਰਹੀ ਹਾਂ। ਅਸੀਂ ਸੰਪਰਕ ’ਚ ਹਾਂ ਪਰ ਸਾਡੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੋਸਤੀ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾਂ ਹੋਰ ਕੋਈ ਸਬੰਧ ਨਹੀਂ।ਸਵਾਲ: ਕਿਹਾ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਪਿਆਰ ਬਿਨਾਂ ਕੋਈ ਜ਼ਿੰਦਗੀ ਨਹੀਂ?ਜਵਾਬ: ਇਹੀ ਵਿਡੰਬਨਾ ਕਿ ਅੱਜ ਤਕ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਕੋਈ ਪਸੰਦੀਦਾ ਇਨਸਾਨ ਨਹੀਂ ਮਿਲਿਆ। ਹਰ ਵਾਰ ਆਸਕਰ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਇੱਧਰ ਧਿਆਨ ਦੇਣ ਦੀ ਕੋਸ਼ਿਸ਼ ਕਰਦੀ ਹਾਂ ਪਰ ਕੋਈ ਅਜਿਹਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਮਿਲਿਆ। ਕਾਸ਼! ਕੋਈ ਅਜਿਹੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਹੋਵੇ, ਜਿਸ ’ਚ ਮੈਂ ਆਪਣੇ ਹੁਨਰ ਦਾ ਲੋਹਾ ਮੰਨਵਾ ਸਕਾਂ। ਫਿਲਹਾਲ ਮੈਂ ਪਿਆਰ ਨੂੰ ਭੁਲਾ ਕੇ ਆਸਕਰ ਵੱਲ ਧਿਆਨ ਦੇਣਾ ਚਾਹੁੰਦੀ ਹਾਂ।   ਇਹ ਸਮਝ ਲਵੋ ਕਿ ਹਾਲ ਦੀ ਘੜੀ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਆਸਕਰ ਨਾਲ ਪਿਆਰ ਹੈ।ਸਵਾਲ: ਕੋਈ ਕਿਰਦਾਰ ਜੋ ਤੁਸੀਂ ਨਿਭਾਉਣਾ ਚਾਹੁੰਦੇ ਹੋ?ਜਵਾਬ: ਮੈਂ ਹਰ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਦਾ ਕਿਰਦਾਰ ਨਿਭਾਉਣਾ ਚਾਹੁੰਦੀ ਹਾਂ। ਮੈਂ ਆਪਣੇ ਆਪ ਨੂੰ ਕਿਸੇ ਹੱਦ ਤਕ ਮਹਿਦੂਦ ਨਹੀਂ ਕੀਤਾ। ਮੈਨੂੰ ਉਮੀਦ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਇੱਕ ਦਿਨ ਮੇਰੀ ਕਲਾ ਦਾ ਮੁੱਲ ਪਵੇਗਾ ਤੇ ਮੇਰੀ ਇਸ ਕਲਾ ਨੂੰ ਉਭਾਰ ਕੇ ਸਾਹਮਣੇ ਆਵੇਗਾ।ਪ੍ਰਸ਼ਨਃ ਮਲਿਕਾ ਸ਼ੇਰਾਵਤ ਨੇ ਅਭਿਨੇਤਾ-ਨਿਰਮਾਤਾ ਸੋਨੂੰ ਸੂਦ ਨਾਲ ਕਿਹੜੀ  ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਕੀਤੀ?","answer":"ਉੱਤਰਃ ਮਲਿਕਾ ਸ਼ੇਰਾਵਤ ਨੇ ਅਭਿਨੇਤਾ-ਨਿਰਮਾਤਾ ਸੋਨੂੰ ਸੂਦ ਨਾਲ ‘ਲੱਕੀ-ਅਣਲੱਕੀ’  ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਕੀਤੀ।"},{"question":"Hãy viết một đoạn văn ít nhất 200 chữ dựa trên nội dung được nói tới trong câu sau: Quảng Ninh: Tai nạn giao thông khiến một phụ nữ tử vong | VTV.VN","answer":"Theo thông tin ban đầu, vào khoảng 23h15, ngày 30/7, tại ngã tư đường Lý Công Uẩn giao với đường Nguyễn Văn Cừ thuộc khu Hồng Hà, phường Ninh Dương, thành phố Móng Cái, xảy ra vụ tai nạn giao thông đường bộ, giữa xe ô tô biển kiểm soát 14A-5xx.96 do anh N. Q. D (sinh năm 1988, có hộ khẩu thường trú tại khu I, phường Hoà Lạc, thành phố Móng Cái; chỗ ở tại khu 7, phường Hải Yên, thành phố Móng Cái), điều khiển xe trên đường Lý Công Uẩn theo hướng đường Hùng Vương về hướng đường biên giới sông Ka Long, đã va chạm với chị Ng. T. Ng (sinh năm 1971, trú tại khu Hồng Hà, phường Ninh Dương, thành phố Móng Cái), đang đẩy xe 4 bánh tự chế, chở máy ép nước mía đi cùng chiều phía trước. Hậu quả sau cú va chạm, cả hai phương tiện bị hư hỏng. Chị Ng. T. Ng được anh N. Q. D và người dân đưa đến Trung tâm Y tế thành phố Móng Cái cấp cứu nhưng đã tử vong. Sau khi gây tai nạn và đưa nạn nhân đi cấp cứu, lái xe đã đến Cơ quan điều tra trình diện, khai nhận nội dung, diễn biến vụ tai nạn. Hiện vụ việc đang được các lực lượng chức năng thành phố Móng Cái điều tra để xử lý theo qui định của pháp luật. Như vậy, trong tháng 7/2022, trên địa bàn thành phố Móng Cái đã xảy ra 2 vụ tai nạn giao thông khiến 3 người tử vong, 2 người bị thương. * Mời quý độc giả theo dõi các chương trình đã phát sóng của Đài Truyền hình Việt Nam trên TV Online và VTVGo! Từ khóa:"},{"question":"வினா: ஆங்கிலேயர் ஆட்சியில் இருந்து இந்தியா சுதந்திரம் பெற்ற ஆண்டு எது?","answer":"விடை: 1947"},{"question":"Ahoana no hanaovana kafe? Manana vahaolana roa azo atao ianao:Vahaolana 1: Manaova vovon-kafe amin'ny rano mafana ary araraka ao anaty kaopy.Vahaolana 2: Araraka ao anaty kaopy ny ronono mangatsiaka ary atao hoe vovon-kafe.","answer":"Ny vahaolana 1 dia mitombina kokoa. Tafiditra ao anatin'izany ny fomba fanaovana kafe mahazatra, raha diso kosa ny fandrarahana ronono anaty kaopy voalohany."},{"question":"Mene ne Ma'anar Sababben Lokaci?","answer":"Shi ne lokacin da yake nuni ga aikin da aka saba yi. Kalmar kan ce ka bayyana shi. Misali:1. Na kan ci ɗanwake da rana.2. Ta kan share gidanta da safe.3. Na san ka kan faɗi gaskiya."},{"question":"મને શરદ પૂર્ણિમા વિષે જણાવો","answer":"વિક્રમ સંવત નાં આસો સુદ પૂનમને શરદ પૂર્ણિમા અથવા શરદ પૂનમ તરીકે ઓળખવામાં આવે છે. આ દિવસે ચંદ્ર પુર્ણકળાએ ખીલેલ હોય છે. જે એક માણવાલાયક ક્ષણ હોય છે. આ દિવસે અનેક જગ્યાઓએ શરદોત્સવ મનાવવામાં આવે છે. જેમાં ચોખાના પૌવા, સાકરને દૂધ સાથે આરોગવાનો રીવાજ છે. તેમ જ ચંદ્રના અજવાળામાં મોડી રાત સુધી રાસ લેવામાં આવે છે."},{"question":"Ijọba ṣekilọ: Ẹnikẹni ko gbọdọ tọju tabi sin oku sinu ile mọ l’Ekoo o","answer":"Ijọba ipinlẹ Eko ti fofin de aṣa ṣiṣẹ oku lọjọ sinu ile adani tawọn eleebo n pe ni ẹnbaamu (embalment) ati titọju oku pamọ sile bayii, wọn lẹnikẹni ko gbọdọ tun ṣe iru nnkan bẹẹ mọ jake-jado ipinlẹ naa.Atẹjade kan ti Akọwe agba lẹka to n ri si atunṣe ofin (Lagos State Law Reform Commission), Abilekọ Ade Adeyẹmọ, buwọ lu, sọ pe tori ewu ajakalẹ arun nijọba ṣe ṣofin yii.O ni latilẹ wa, ko bofin mu lati sọ yara adani ninu ile tawọn eeyan n gbe di ibi igbokuu-pamọ-si, tabi ki wọn maa da kẹmika si oku lara nibẹ lati ṣe e lọjọ, ko si yẹ ki wọn sọ ile gbigbe di itẹkuu. Awọn ọsibitu ijọba ati aladaani to ni aaye fun iru nnkan bẹẹ ti wa kaakiri to yẹ kawọn eeyan maa lo gẹgẹ bo ṣe sọ.O fi kun un pe bijọba ko ṣe sọrọ lori ọrọ yii tẹlẹ ko tumọ si pe aṣa naa bofin mu, ati pe loorekoore lawọn maa n yiri awọn ofin ipinlẹ Eko wo lati mu un ba igba mu, lara ẹ si ni ofin ti wọn kede  yii.Ni ipari ọrọ rẹ, Adeyẹmọ ni ta a ba fẹẹ bọ lọwọ ewu akoran ati ajakalẹ arun bii Ẹbola, iba Lassa atawọn mi-in, o pọn dandan ka pa ofin yii mọ, tori ẹnikẹni to ba tapa si i lati asiko yii lọ yoo geka abamọ jẹ niwaju adajọ."},{"question":"कृपया नीचे दिए गए प्रश्न का उत्तर दें: प्रश्न: कोरोना वायरस 2019 के पहले मामले की पहचान कहां हुई थी?","answer":"कोरोना वायरस 2019 का पहला मामला चीन के वुहान शहर में सामने आया था।"},{"question":"Indro misy toe-javatra: \\" Feno zava-maniry, biby ary bibikely isan-karazany ny ala maitso, ka miteraka tontolo iainana sarotra sy mahavariana.\\" Inona no fanontaniana mety napetraka raha ohatra ka \\"Ny Ala\\" no valiny?","answer":"Inona no toeram-ponenana voajanahary, manankarena zavamaniry, biby ary bibikely, mamorona tontolo iainana sarotra sy mahavariana?"},{"question":"గోల్కొండ పట్టణంలోని అందచందాలను ‘వచన కవిత’ రూపంలో వ్రాయండి. ","answer":"గోల్కొండ నిర్మాణం – కోర్కెలకు నిలయంగోల్కొండ వైభవం – నిజాం కీర్తికి నిదర్శనంవిశాల నగరవీధులు – వేర్వేరుగ మొహల్లాలుసరదార్ల మేడలు – సరదాలకు నిలయాలునగీనాబాగ్ తోట – అందాలకు రాశులచటరాజ హార్మ్యం సొగసుచూడ – షాహిమహలు తెరచి చూడుదిల్ కుషా భవనం – సౌందర్య నిలయంగోల్కొండ సొగసుపెంచే – ఉద్యానములచట మించె\`మిద్దెమీది తోటలు – శిల్పుల నేర్పుకు గీటురాళ్ళుబాల్బోవా వృక్షం – నేత్రపర్వ దృశ్యంఅందాల గోల్కొండ – చేయును కనులవిందు."},{"question":"මූදේවි යන වචනයට අදහසක් ගෙන දෙන වචනය ලියා  දක්වන්න.","answer":"මූදේවි යන්නට විරුද්ධ අර්ථයක් ඇති පදය සීදේවි වේ. "},{"question":"Kumuu ahaa ninkii dakhray Nebigaﷺ, dagaalkii Uxud","answer":"Wuxuu ahaa Ibnu Qimah"},{"question":"3x + 2y = 15 రేఖీయ సమీకరణానికి క్రింది వానిలో ఏది సాధన కాదు ?A) x = 3, y = -3B) x = 3, y = 3C) x = 5, y = 0D) x = 7, y = -3","answer":"A) x = 3, y = -3"},{"question":"“Obinrin Ti Kò Ni Orogún, Kò Ti Mọ Àrùn Ara Rẹ̀”.","answer":"Òwe yi fi ara han ni itan iyàwó Aṣojú-ọba, ti a ò pè ni Tinumi pẹ̀lú ọmọ rẹ̀ kan ṣoṣo, ọkùnrin ti a mọ̀ si Mofẹ́.  Mofẹ́ dàgbà lati fẹ obinrin.  Ó̀ yan obinrin ti à ńpè ni Àyànfẹ́ ni iyàwó àfẹ́sọ́nà.  Nigbati ó mú Àyànfẹ́ lọ han àwọn òbi rẹ, Bàbá Mofẹ́ gba Àyànfẹ́ tọwọ́-tẹsẹ̀, ṣùgbọ́n iyá Mofẹ́ fi àáké kọ́ri pé ọmọ ohun kò ni fẹ́ Àyànfẹ́.  Wọn bẹ̀rẹ̀ idi ti kò ṣe fẹ́ ki ọmọ ohun fẹ ẹni ti ó múwá, Tinumi kò ri àlàyé ṣe ju pé ohun kò fẹ́ ki ọmọ ohun fẹ́ “Àtọ̀hún rin wa – ọmọ ti kò ni iran”.  Ọmọ rẹ naa fi àáké kòri pé ẹni ti ohun ma fẹ ni Àyànfẹ́.Tinumi sọ àfẹ́sọ́nà ọmọ rẹ di orogún, gbogbo ibi ti ó bá ti pàdé Àyànfẹ ni ibi àjoṣe ẹbi ni ó ti ḿbajà pé ki ó dẹ̀hin lẹhin ọmọ ohun.  Àyànfẹ́ lé ọmọ rẹ titi ṣùgbọ́n ó kọ̀ lati dẹhin.Lẹhin ọdún marun ti Mofẹ́ àti Àyànfẹ́ ti ńṣe ọ̀rẹ́, iwé jade pé wọn gbé Bàbá Mofẹ́.  Gẹgẹ bi Aṣojú-Ọba lọ si Òkè-òkun.  Bàbá ṣètò bi ọmọ àti iyàwó ti ma tẹ̀lé ohun.  Ọmọ kọ̀ pé ohun kò lọ pẹ̀lú òbi ohun ti àfẹ́sọ́nà ohun kò bá ni tẹ̀lé àwọn lọ.  Bàbá gbà pé ọmọ ohun ti tó fẹ́ iyàwó, wọn ṣe ètò igbéyàwó fún Mofẹ́ àti àfẹ́sọ́nà̀ rẹ.  Lẹhin ti Mofẹ́ àti Àyànfẹ́ ṣe iyàwó tán, wọn tẹ̀lé Bàbá àti Ìyá wọn lọ si Òkè-okun lati má jọ gbé.Àrùn ara Tinumi, aya Aṣojú-ọba bẹ̀rẹ̀ si han nitori ó sọ iyàwó ọmọ rẹ di orogún.  Nigbati ọkọ rẹ ri àlébù yi, ó pinu lati wa orogún fun Tinumi nitori ai ni orogún ni ó ṣe sọ aya ọmọ rẹ di orogún.  Gẹgẹ bi a ti mọ, igbéyàwó ibilẹ̀ kò ni ki ọkùnrin ma fẹ iyàwó keji.  Nigbati Bàbá Mofẹ́ fẹ́ iyàwó kékeré, ọmọ àti iyàwó kó kúrò lọ si ilé tiwọn, inú rẹ bàjẹ́ nigbati o kũ pẹ̀lú orogún rẹ.  Ó jẹ èrè iwà burúkú àti ìgbéraga."},{"question":"ਕੀ ਤੁਸੀਂ ਯੋਗੀ ਆਦਿਤਿਆਨਾਥ ਨੂੰ ਜਾਣਦੇ ਹੋ?","answer":"ਯੋਗੀ ਆਦਿਤਿਆਨਾਥ (ਜਨਮ ਅਜੇ ਸਿੰਘ ਬਿਸ਼ਤ; 5 ਜੂਨ 1972), ਇੱਕ ਭਾਰਤੀ ਹਿੰਦੂ ਸੰਨਿਆਸੀ ਅਤੇ ਸਿਆਸਤਦਾਨ ਹੈ ਜੋ 19 ਮਾਰਚ 2017 ਤੋਂ, ਉੱਤਰ ਪ੍ਰਦੇਸ਼ ਦੇ 21ਵੇਂ ਅਤੇ ਮੌਜੂਦਾ ਮੁੱਖ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਵਜੋਂ ਸੇਵਾ ਨਿਭਾ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ। ਭਾਰਤੀ ਜਨਤਾ ਪਾਰਟੀ ਅਤੇ ਆਰਐਸਐਸ ਦੇ ਇੱਕ ਮੈਂਬਰ, ਆਦਿਤਿਆਨਾਥ ਨੂੰ ਭਾਰਤੀ ਰਾਜਨੀਤੀ ਦੇ ਬਿਲਕੁਲ ਸੱਜੇ ਪਾਸੇ ਹੋਣ ਲਈ ਜਾਣਿਆ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ।ਭਾਰਤੀ ਜਨਤਾ ਪਾਰਟੀ (ਭਾਜਪਾ) ਨੇ 2017 ਦੀਆਂ ਰਾਜ ਵਿਧਾਨ ਸਭਾ ਚੋਣਾਂ ਜਿੱਤਣ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਉਸਨੂੰ 26 ਮਾਰਚ 2017 ਨੂੰ ਉੱਤਰ ਪ੍ਰਦੇਸ਼ ਦਾ ਮੁੱਖ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਨਿਯੁਕਤ ਕੀਤਾ ਗਿਆ ਸੀ ਜਿਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਉਹ ਇੱਕ ਪ੍ਰਮੁੱਖ ਪ੍ਰਚਾਰਕ ਸੀ। ਭਾਜਪਾ ਨੇ 2022 ਦੀਆਂ ਰਾਜ ਵਿਧਾਨ ਸਭਾ ਚੋਣਾਂ ਵੀ ਜਿੱਤੀਆਂ: ਅਦਿੱਤਿਆਨਾਥ ਮੁੱਖ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਵਜੋਂ ਜਾਰੀ ਰਿਹਾ, ਦਫਤਰ ਵਿੱਚ 5 ਸਾਲ ਦਾ ਕਾਰਜਕਾਲ ਪੂਰਾ ਕਰਨ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਸੱਤਾ ਵਿੱਚ ਵਾਪਸੀ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲੇ ਉੱਤਰ ਪ੍ਰਦੇਸ਼ ਦੇ ਪਹਿਲੇ ਮੁੱਖ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਬਣੇ।ਵਰਤਮਾਨ ਵਿੱਚ, ਉਹ ਮੁੱਖ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਵਜੋਂ ਦੂਜੀ ਵਾਰ (2022 ਤੋਂ) ਗੋਰਖਪੁਰ ਸ਼ਹਿਰੀ ਤੋਂ ਵਿਧਾਨ ਸਭਾ ਦੇ ਮੈਂਬਰ ਹਨ। ਉਸਨੇ 2022 ਦੀ ਰਾਜ ਵਿਧਾਨ ਸਭਾ ਚੋਣ ਗੋਰਖਪੁਰ ਸ਼ਹਿਰੀ ਤੋਂ ਲੜੀ ਅਤੇ ਵੋਟਾਂ ਦੇ ਵੱਡੇ ਫਰਕ ਨਾਲ ਜਿੱਤੀ। ਆਦਿਤਿਆਨਾਥ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਮੁੱਖ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਵਜੋਂ ਆਪਣੇ ਪਹਿਲੇ ਕਾਰਜਕਾਲ (2017-2022) ਦੌਰਾਨ ਵਿਧਾਨ ਪ੍ਰੀਸ਼ਦ ਦੇ ਮੈਂਬਰ ਸਨ। ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਵਿਧਾਨ ਸਭਾ ਲਈ ਚੁਣੇ ਜਾਣ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਵਿਧਾਨ ਪ੍ਰੀਸ਼ਦ ਤੋਂ ਅਸਤੀਫਾ ਦੇ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਸੀ।ਉਹ ਮੁੱਖ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਬਣਨ ਤੋਂ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ 1998 ਤੋਂ 2017 ਤੱਕ ਲਗਾਤਾਰ ਪੰਜ ਵਾਰ ਗੋਰਖਪੁਰ ਹਲਕੇ, ਉੱਤਰ ਪ੍ਰਦੇਸ਼ ਤੋਂ ਲੋਕ ਸਭਾ ਦੇ ਸਾਬਕਾ ਮੈਂਬਰ ਹਨ।ਆਦਿਤਿਆਨਾਥ ਗੋਰਖਪੁਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਇੱਕ ਹਿੰਦੂ ਮੱਠ, ਗੋਰਖਨਾਥ ਮੱਠ ਦੇ ਮਹੰਤ (ਮੁਖੀ ਪੁਜਾਰੀ) ਵੀ ਹਨ, ਇੱਕ ਅਹੁਦਾ ਉਹ ਸਤੰਬਰ 2014 ਤੋਂ ਮਹੰਤ ਅਵੈਦਿਆਨਾਥ, ਉਸਦੇ ਅਧਿਆਤਮਕ \\"ਪਿਤਾ\\" ਦੀ ਮੌਤ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਸੰਭਾਲ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ। ਉਹ ਹਿੰਦੂ ਯੁਵਾ ਵਾਹਿਨੀ, ਇੱਕ ਹਿੰਦੂ ਰਾਸ਼ਟਰਵਾਦੀ ਸੰਗਠਨ ਦਾ ਸੰਸਥਾਪਕ ਵੀ ਹੈ। ਉਹ ਇੱਕ ਹਿੰਦੂਤਵੀ ਰਾਸ਼ਟਰਵਾਦੀ ਅਤੇ ਇੱਕ ਸਮਾਜਿਕ ਰੂੜੀਵਾਦੀ ਦਾ ਅਕਸ ਰੱਖਦਾ ਹੈ।== ਹਵਾਲੇ =="},{"question":"«Ny literatiora dia zava-kanto vita amin’ny teny ka ny teny no akora nentina nandrafitra azy. Noho izany, izy dia teny voalamina sy voarindra mba hanehoana ny kanto ara-tsaina, ara-kevitra, ara-pihetsehampo, ny zava-misy sy ny tontolo iainana, dia ny hita maso sy ny nofinofy. Ambara ihany koa izy fa fitambaran’ny lahabolana, lahateny na lahatsoratra sy ny poezia. » Inona ny lohahevitr’io lahatsoratra ambony io ?","answer":"Ny lohahevitr’io lahatsoratra io dia ny literatiora."},{"question":"Complete the following phrase:  Gilbert gjorde sin internationella debut i OS 1988 i längdhopp. Vid Samväldesspelen 1990 blev Gilbert åttonde man i längdhoppstävlingen men vid OS 1992 deltog han endast som stafettlöpare. Vid VM 1993 löpte Gilbert andrasträckan i det kanadensiska bronslaget som noterade nationsrekordet 37,83 bakom Förenta Staterna (37,48) och Storbritannien (37,77). Året efter deltog Gilbert i guldlaget på 4x100 meter i","answer":"Samväldesspelen i Victoria samt noterade en fin femteplats i den individuella finalen."},{"question":"వినాశకర కీటకాల జీవ నియంత్రణ పద్ధతి వెనుక ఉన్న జీవ సూత్రం ఏమిటి?","answer":"ఆకులు, ముళ్ళు లేని నిర్మాణం కలిగిన పియర్ కాక్టస్ మొక్కలను 1920లో ఆస్ట్రేలియాలో ప్రవేశపెట్టారు. ఫలితంగా అది అతివేగంగా అభివృద్ధి చెంది మిలియన్ల హెక్టార్ల భూమి (సహజ గడ్డిభూములు)లో వ్యాపించి అస్థవ్యస్థ పరిస్థితి కలిగించింది. చివరకు అపాయకరంగా వ్యాపిస్తున్న కాక్టస్ను నియంత్రించడానికి కాక్టస్ను ఆహారంగా తీసుకొనే పరభక్షి (మిడత)ను ఆ దేశంలో ప్రవేశపెట్టారు. తరువాత పరిస్థితి చక్కబడింది.ఆహార జీవి జనాభాను నియంత్రించే భక్షక జీవుల సామర్థ్యాన్ని ఆధారంగా చేసుకొని వ్యవసాయ చీడల నియంత్రణలో జీవ నియంత్రణ పద్ధతులను వినియోగిస్తున్నారు."},{"question":"\\"വൈക്കം മുഹമ്മദ് ബഷീർ ജനിച്ചത് തലയോലപ്പറമ്പിലാണ്\\" എന്നതിന് സമാനമായ അർത്ഥമുള്ള ഒരു വാചകം സൃഷ്ടിക്കുക?","answer":"\\"വൈക്കം മുഹമ്മദ് ബഷീറിന്റെ ജന്മസ്ഥലമാണ് തലയോലപ്പറമ്പ്.\\""},{"question":"Tập hợp các kết quả có thể xảy ra của phép thử nghiệm tung một đồng xu làA.X = {N, S}B.X = {N}C.X = {S}D.X = {NN, S}","answer":"Trả lời:Phép thử nghiệm tung đồng xu có kết quả có thể là sấp (S) hoặc ngửa (N).Vậy tập hợp các kết quả có thể xảy ra làX = {N, S}Đáp án cần chọn là: A"},{"question":"पृथ्वीको भूवैज्ञानिक इतिहासमा मानवीय प्रभावहरू बुझ्नको लागि \\"एन्थ्रोपोसेन युग\\" र यसको प्रभावहरू छलफल गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"एन्थ्रोपोसेन युग एक प्रस्तावित भूवैज्ञानिक युग हो जुन मानव गतिविधिहरूले पृथ्वीको भूविज्ञान र पारिस्थितिकी तंत्रहरूमा महत्त्वपूर्ण प्रभाव पार्छ। यसले दिगो अभ्यास र संरक्षण प्रयासहरूको आवश्यकतालाई हाइलाइट गर्दछ।"},{"question":"Кыргыздын улуттук оюну 'ак чөлмөк' жөнүндө.","answer":"Ак чөлмөк кыргыз элинин эң байыркы оюндарынын бири. Оюн каалаган жерде ойнолот. Кыз-улан аралаш ойнойт. Оюнчулар жашына жараша жаатка бөлүнүшүп, оюнга калыс шайлашат. Ар бир жаатка ат коюлат. Мара белгиленет. «Ак чөлмөк» узундугу соомчо келген ак сөөк (бодонун шыйбылчагы), жонулган же ак менен сырдалган жыгач болот.Калыс оюнчулардын бардыгына ак чөлмөктү көрсөтүп, андан кийин оюнчуларды тескери каратып тургузуп, алар ак чөлмөк кайсыл тарапка ыргытылганын билбей калсын үчүн бир тарапка таш, экинчи тарапка ак чөлмөктү ыргытат. Ыргытылган ак чөлмөктүн кайсы жерге түшкөнүн баамдоого эки жак тең даяр турушат. Түшөөр замат жапырт чуркашып ак чөлмөктү издей башташат. Биринчи тапкан оюнчу өз жаатынын атын үнүн бийик чыгарып атайт да, мараны көздөй чуркап жөнөйт. Атаандаштары ак чөлмөктү андан тартып алууга аракеттенишет. Ал тарттырып жибербей буйтай качып, жазгырып же өнөктөрүнүн бирине бере салууга аракеттенет. Эгер атаандаштары ак чөлмөктү тартып алса, алар да өз тобунун атын кыйкырып атап качууга тийиш. Ак чөлмөктү марага алып келген жак кайра ыргытат. Ак чөлмөктү марага бир жолу таштаган жаатка 1 упай эсептелинет.Калыс упайларды эсептейт, оюндун жыйынтыгын чыгарат. Оюн эрежесинин туура сакталышына көз салат. Эрежени оюнчулар бузган убакта «ышкырып» белги берип оюнду токтотот. Калыстын буйругун аткарбаган оюнчу оюндан чыгарылат. Оюндун жыйынтыгында кайсы жаат көп упай топтосо ошол жаат утат. Упайлар барабар болуп калса кайсы жаат оюнду аз бузса, ошол жаат жеңет. Ак чөлмөктү талашууда кийимден, колдон, буттан тартпастан, түртпөстөн, оюнчунун колундагы ак чөлмөктү гана алууга аракеттенүү керек. Оюн күч сынашмай оюндарынын катарына да кирет. Оюн көбүнчө айлуу түндө ойнолот. Бул оюн «ака чөөл» (?) деп да аталат."},{"question":"පහත යෙදුමේ තේරුම කුමක්ද?(කිතුල් කර්මාන්තය හා  සම්බන්ධවේ) මල් කපනා පිහිය","answer":"කිතුල් මලෙන් ඉතා කුඩා කොටසක් දිනපතා කපා දැමීමට භාවිත කල මුවහත් පිහියකි. දැලිපිහියක් තරමටම මෙහි මුවාත සියුම් ය."},{"question":"ماذا يسمى الفيروس المسبب لمرض الإيدز ؟","answer":"فيروس نقص المناعة البشرية أو اتش أي في (hiv)"},{"question":"Hvad er spørgsmålet til: \\"Identifikation af stationer plejede at ske regelmæssigt af en annoncør i midten af et tv-program eller mellem programmerne\\"? Emnet er stationsidentifikation.","answer":"\\"Hvor ofte skal amatør-stationen identificer sig?\\""},{"question":"Kor u qaadista jir difaaca caruuta?","answer":"QAABAB AAD DIFAACA CARUURTA KOR UGU QAADI KARTO Ogow hooyo ama aabo in kor uqaadista difaca ilmaha uu bilawdo kahor inta aney dhalan.✅ Taloyin u muhima waalidiinta Kor uqadida difaaca cunuga waxey bilwta inta uu uurka kujiro waxa muhim ah hooyada uurka leh iney caafimaad keeda kor uqado Qaababka aad kor ugu qaadi krto difaaca cunigada waxa kamida:-1= Daryeelida cafimadka hoyda uurka leh Hooyo hadad uurey thy sidaan sameey 🚩  Uurey cun cunto caafimaad leh  sida qudaarta, miraha, si eey u xojiyan difacda iyo difaca ilmahada. 🚩 Saneey jimicsiga fudud ee lagu oglyhy intaad uurka sido 🚩 Iska yareey walwalka sido kale seexo hurdo kugu filan 2= Naas nuujin dabiici ah ( naaska kalya) Caanaha ugu horeya ee naaska hooyada markey dhasho ee dambarta waa muhim dhalanka yar waxey siiyan difac waxey xojiyan difacisa aygo jirkisa kailaliya ineey soweraran infection nada bisha kowaad Intaas waxsii dheer faidoyinka badan ee ilmahu kahelo naaska kligiis inlodayo.....3= Waqti badan kuhay guriga nuunaha 6 bilood ee ugu horeysa nuunaha wainad kuhysi guriga bananka ha ubixin wuxuu halis ugu jiraa ilma aragtada iyo cudurada nuunaha yar wali difacisa maxogeysan marka bananka kadaa 4= Kangaroo care Waxaa jira qaab daryeeleed looyaqaan Kangaroo care kaas oo micnihiisa yahay inu maqaarka ilmaha yar taabto maqarka hoyada ama aabaha walba malmaha hore ee uu dhasho wxu kahelayaa unaso gudbinyn noola yaal nacfi uleh dhalaanka yar xojiyana difaacisa. Waliba cunuga markuy horay kadhasho wain hoyada laabteda lagu jifyo.5= Nadafada caruurta 80% taabasho ayey kugudban infection nada mrka caruurtada bar ineey sabuun iyo biyo kudhaqan gacmahoda 6= Seexi hurdo kufilan caruurtada Hurdada caafimad ka leh waxay kor uqda difaca ilmaha walba sixogan Ilmaha anan helin hurdo kufilan jirkooda somadayo ( cytokines) kaas oo ladagala ilma aragtda yareyana."},{"question":"Euskal literaturan, hainbat idazle ezagun daude. Zein da hauek ezagunena?A) Miguel de Cervantes, \\"Don Quijote\\" idazlea.B) Koldo Izagirre, euskal poeta eta idazlea.C) Paulo Coelho, \\"Alkimista\\" idazlea.","answer":"B) Koldo Izagirre, euskal poeta eta idazlea."},{"question":"С. Каралаевдин вариантында Жакыптын түшүн ким жоруйт?а) Ошпур б) Бакдөөлөтв) Байжигит г) Акбалта","answer":"Туура жообу:в) Байжигит "},{"question":"Төмөнкү берилген сөздөрдун арасынан,  бир маанилүү сөздөр кайсы катарда жазылган? Туура жообун таап берчи.(А) акыл, тоо, китеп (Б) көз, кыш, баш (В) машина, жаз, борбор (Г) күн, ак, суу","answer":"Берилген суроого жооп бере турган болсок, катарда жазылган сөздөрдүн арасынан бир  маанилүү сөздөр (А) вариантында туура  берилген. "},{"question":"Slutför den här frasen: Han draftades i tredje rundan i 2004 års","answer":"draft av Montreal Canadiens som 84:e spelare totalt."},{"question":"Dalam pelajaran komponen sastera Melayu, Sinopsis bermaksud…..","answer":"ringkasan cerita"},{"question":"Inona ny fanalavana ny FTM?","answer":"Ny fanalavana ny FTM dia: Foibe Taotsaritanin'i Madagasikara."},{"question":"എക്കാലത്തെയും മികച്ച ക്രിക്കറ്റ് താരം ആരാണ്?","answer":"എക്കാലത്തെയും മികച്ച ക്രിക്കറ്റ് കളിക്കാരൻ ആരെന്ന ചോദ്യം ആത്മനിഷ്ഠമാണ്, വ്യക്തിപരമായ അഭിപ്രായങ്ങളും മാനദണ്ഡങ്ങളും അനുസരിച്ച് വ്യത്യാസപ്പെടാം. പല ഇതിഹാസ ക്രിക്കറ്റ് താരങ്ങളും തങ്ങളുടെ അസാധാരണമായ കഴിവുകളും നേട്ടങ്ങളും കൊണ്ട് കായികരംഗത്ത് മായാത്ത മുദ്ര പതിപ്പിച്ചിട്ടുണ്ട്. \\"മികച്ച\\" ക്രിക്കറ്റ് കളിക്കാരനെ കൃത്യമായി നിർണ്ണയിക്കുന്നത് വെല്ലുവിളിയാണെങ്കിലും, ചർച്ചകളിലും സംവാദങ്ങളിലും പലപ്പോഴും പരാമർശിക്കപ്പെടുന്ന ചില പേരുകൾ ഉണ്ട്:സർ ഡോൺ ബ്രാഡ്മാൻ (ഓസ്ട്രേലിയ): ക്രിക്കറ്റ് ചരിത്രത്തിലെ ഏറ്റവും മികച്ച ബാറ്റ്സ്മാൻമാരിൽ ഒരാളായി പരക്കെ കണക്കാക്കപ്പെടുന്ന ബ്രാഡ്മാന്റെ ടെസ്റ്റ് മത്സരങ്ങളിൽ 99.94 എന്ന അതിശയിപ്പിക്കുന്ന ബാറ്റിംഗ് ശരാശരി ഇപ്പോഴും സമാനതകളില്ലാത്തതാണ്.സച്ചിൻ ടെണ്ടുൽക്കർ (ഇന്ത്യ): എക്കാലത്തെയും മികച്ച ബാറ്റ്‌സ്മാൻമാരിൽ ഒരാളായി സച്ചിൻ കണക്കാക്കപ്പെടുന്നു. ടെസ്റ്റിലും ഏകദിനത്തിലും (ODI) ഏറ്റവും കൂടുതൽ റൺസ് ഉൾപ്പെടെ നിരവധി റെക്കോർഡുകൾ അദ്ദേഹത്തിന്റെ പേരിലാണ്.സർ വിവിയൻ റിച്ചാർഡ്സ് (വെസ്റ്റ് ഇൻഡീസ്): ആക്രമണാത്മക ശൈലിക്ക് പേരുകേട്ട ഒരു തകർപ്പൻ ബാറ്റ്സ്മാനാണ് റിച്ചാർഡ്സ്. 1970 കളിലെയും 1980 കളിലെയും പ്രബലമായ വെസ്റ്റ് ഇൻഡീസ് ടീമുകളുടെ വിജയത്തിൽ അദ്ദേഹം ഒരു പ്രധാന പങ്ക് വഹിച്ചു.സർ ഗാർഫീൽഡ് സോബേഴ്‌സ് (വെസ്റ്റ് ഇൻഡീസ്): ബാറ്റിംഗിലും ബൗളിംഗിലും ഒരുപോലെ മികവ് പുലർത്തിയിരുന്ന ഒരു ഓൾറൗണ്ടറായിരുന്നു സോബേഴ്‌സ്. എക്കാലത്തെയും ബഹുമുഖ ക്രിക്കറ്റ് കളിക്കാരിൽ ഒരാളായി അദ്ദേഹം പലപ്പോഴും കണക്കാക്കപ്പെടുന്നു.ഷെയ്ൻ വോൺ (ഓസ്‌ട്രേലിയ): ക്രിക്കറ്റ് ചരിത്രത്തിലെ ഏറ്റവും മികച്ച സ്പിൻ ബൗളർമാരിൽ ഒരാളായി കണക്കാക്കപ്പെടുന്ന വോണിന്റെ വൈദഗ്ധ്യവും കൗശലവും ലെഗ് സ്‌പിന്നിലൂടെ ബാറ്റ്‌സ്മാനെ ബാംബൂസിൽ ആക്കാനുള്ള കഴിവും അദ്ദേഹത്തെ കായികരംഗത്തെ ഇതിഹാസതാരമാക്കി.ഈ ലിസ്റ്റ് സമഗ്രമല്ല എന്നത് ശ്രദ്ധിക്കേണ്ടതാണ്, കൂടാതെ കായികരംഗത്ത് കാര്യമായ സംഭാവനകൾ നൽകിയ മറ്റ് നിരവധി ക്രിക്കറ്റ് താരങ്ങളുണ്ട്. വ്യക്തിഗത മുൻഗണനകൾ, സ്ഥിതിവിവരക്കണക്ക് നേട്ടങ്ങൾ, കളിയിലെ സ്വാധീനം, അവർ കളിച്ച കാലഘട്ടം തുടങ്ങിയ ഘടകങ്ങളെ ആശ്രയിച്ച് \\"മികച്ച\\" ക്രിക്കറ്റ് കളിക്കാരന് വ്യത്യാസപ്പെടാം."},{"question":"سوال: چه کسي اين کار خوب رو انجام داد که به همه روستاهاي هريانا  برق رسانی کرد؟ جواب:","answer":"بانسی لال"},{"question":"અવિનાશ વ્યાસ ની \\"જોવા વાળો જોશે\\" કવિતા લખો.","answer":"એક જીભને બે કાન દઈ,ભગવાન બેઠો આભલે,એથી જ કહીએે એક ત્યારે દુનિયા બે સાંભળે.જોવા વાળો જોશે, દેવા વાળો દેશે,તું તારું કામ કરે જા..સૌએ સૌની સંભાળશે, તું તારું ભાથું ભરે જા.રે ભાઈ તારું કામ કરે જા..કંટક આવે, કંકર આવે, તડકો આવે, છાંયો આવે,આ લખે લખ્યો લખ ચોરાશીનો ફેરો ભૂંડા ફરે જા.રે ભાઈ તારું કામ કરે જા..મીંઠળ બાંધ્યા માંડવડા પર, એ ચંદરમા ઉગતો,એજ ચાંદલો મસાણ માથે ઉગવા ટાણે પૂગતો,સ્થળને પળથી પર રહી પ્યારા, તારી ચાલ ચલે જા.રે ભાઈ તારું કામ કરે જા.."},{"question":"Alagidi niyawo mi, ki i bọwọ fawọn ẹbi mi, mi o fẹ ẹ mọ-Taiwo","answer":"Ile-ẹjọ kọkọ-kọkọ kan niluu Ikọle-Ekiti,  ti tu igbeyawo ogun ọdun ka laarin, Taiwo Olominu ati iyawo ẹ, Ajibikẹ. Ohun to si fa a ni pe ọrọ awọn tọkọ-tiyawo ọhun ko ye ara wọn mọ. Eyi ni adajọ fi ni ki kaluku maa ṣe tiẹ lọtọọtọ.Ẹni ọdun mẹtalelaaadọta ni Olominu, alaye to si ṣe nile-ẹjọ ni pe ọmọ mẹrin ni obinrin naa bi foun, ṣugbọn ki i ṣe pe oun fẹ ẹ niṣu lọka gẹgẹ bii aṣa agbegbe awọn.Ninu ọrọ ẹ naa lo ti sọ pe oun ati obinrin ti oun kọ silẹ yii lawọn jọ n tọ awọn ọmọ naa, ṣugbọn oun gan-an loun maa n san owo ileewe wọn.O ni Ajibikẹ ki i bọwọ foun, o lagidi, bẹẹ lawọn ẹbi oun paapaa ko jọ ọ loju rara. Baale ile yii ni ni nnkan bii ọdun mejila sẹyin loun ti kọkọ wọ ohinrin naa lọ sile-ẹjọ pe oun ko fẹ ẹ mọ, ṣugbọn nigba ti ẹbẹ pọ lọdọ awọn ẹbi lo jẹ ki oun foriji i nigba naa, ti awọn si n ṣe lọkọ-laya pada. Ṣugbọn ni bayii, ki ile-ẹjọ tu ajọṣepọ awọn ka, ki kaluku maa ba tiẹ lọ.Ọkunrin yii ti sọ pe oun ṣetan lati fi ile ti oun ati obinrin yii jọ kọ silẹ fun oun atawọn ọmọ to bi foun, lati gba alaafia laaye.Bo tilẹ jẹ pe Ajibikẹ ko si nile-ẹjọ lọjọ naa, sibẹ, Aarẹ ile-ẹjọ ọhun, Arabinrin Yemisi Ojo, tu igbeyawo ọhun ka lori ẹsun agidi, ọrọ buruku ti ọkọ ẹ lo maa n sọ soun ati bi wọn ṣe maa n lu ara wọn lọpọ igba.O ni niwọn igba tawọn mejeeji paapaa ko ti ṣeto igbeyawo kankan tẹlẹ, to jẹ pe niṣe ni wọn kan n bimọ funra wọn, ti wọn ko tun gbọ ara wọn ye, ki kaluku maa ba tiẹ lọ. Bẹẹ naa lo pa ọkunrin yii laṣẹ ko fi ile ti wọn jọ kọ silẹ, ko si maa sanwo ileewe awọn ọmọ ti obinrin naa bi fun un."},{"question":"Que língua é falada na Hungria?","answer":"Sua língua oficial é o húngaro, falado por cerca de 13 milhões de pessoas no mundo atualmente. O húngaro, diga-se, é considerada uma das dez línguas mais difíceis de se aprender no mundo, ao lado do russo, japonês, chinês, árabe e finlandês."},{"question":"Jawab soalan teka-teki ini:  Anak raja yang suka menumpang rakyat di bawah tanah?","answer":"Jawapannya ialah Putra LRT"},{"question":"नेपालमा खेती गरिने \\"परम्परागत धानका प्रजातिहरू\\" र स्थानीय आहारहरूमा तिनीहरूको महत्त्व वर्णन गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"नेपालले स्थानीय आहारको अभिन्न अंग भएका सुगन्धित र स्वदेशी लगायतका विविध धानका प्रजातिहरू खेती गर्छ।"},{"question":" ما هي المدينة التي تسمّى مدينة الضباب؟","answer":"مدينة لندن."},{"question":"இயற்கையைப் போற்றுதல் தமிழர் ……………… –அ) மரபுஆ) பொழுதுஇ) வரவுஈ) தகவு","answer":"அ) மரபுமரபு அல்லது பாரம்பரியம் (Heredity) எனப்படுவது பெற்றோர்கள் அல்லது முன்னோர்களிலிருந்து, சந்ததிகளுக்கு இயல்புகள் கடத்தப்படும் செயல்முறையாகும். சந்ததியின் உயிரணு அல்லது உயிரினம் உருவாகும்போதே, பெற்றோர் உயிரணு அல்லது உயிரினத்தில் இருந்து இயல்புகளைப் பெற்றுக் கொள்வது இந்த செயல் முறையினாலேயே ஆகும்.இந்த பாரம்பரிய செயல்முறையின்போது, இயற்கையாகவும், சூழல் தாக்கத்தினாலும் உயிரினங்களில் வேறுபாடுகளும் தோன்றுவதனால், அவற்றில் புதிய இயல்புகள் உருவாகி புதிய இனங்களும் தோன்றும்."},{"question":"Inona avy ireo zavatra nitranga tamin'ny taona 1896?","answer":"Io taona io dia nanamarika zavatra betsaka teo amin'ny tantaran'ny Malagasy satria lasa zana-tany frantsay izy ireo tamin'io fotona io. Tamin'io taona io ihany koa no nandefasana sesi-tany ny Mpanjaka Vavy RANAVALONA FAHA3 tany Algeria.\\t"},{"question":"Tohizo izao ohabolana izao : \\"  Raha razana tsy hitahy .......................................   \\" ","answer":"\\"  Raha razana tsy hitahy mifohaza iady vomanga  \\" "},{"question":"Rispondi alla domanda: La mia vita può durare qualche ora, quello che produco mi divora. Sottile sono veloce, grossa sono lenta e il vento molto mi spaventa. Chi sono?","answer":"La risposta: la candela."},{"question":"Tarjamahkeun kalimah ieu tina basa Sunda kana basa Indonésia:Batagor jeung peuyeum nyaéta kadaharan khas kota Bandung.","answer":"Batagor dan peuyeum merupakan makanan khas Kota Bandung."},{"question":"لاندې برخې ته مراجعه وکړئ او بیا وروسته پوښتنې ته په ورته ژبه ځواب ورکړئ لکه څنګه چې د برخې سره:  پاساژ: د ډاونچي کوډ د ډین براون لخوا د 2003 راز افسانوي ناول دی. دا د براون دوهم ناول دی چې د رابرټ لینګډن کرکټر پکې شاملوي: لومړی یې د هغه 2000 ناول فرښتې او شیطانان و. د ډاونچي کوډ د \\"سمبولوجیسټ\\" رابرټ لینګډن او کریپټولوژیست صوفي نیوو تعقیبوي وروسته له هغه چې په پاریس کې د لوور میوزیم کې وژنه دوی د سیون او اوپوس ډای ترمینځ په جګړه کې دخیل شي د دې امکان په اړه چې عیسی مسیح د مریم مګډالین ملګری و.  پوښتنه: د ډاونچي کوډ کله خپور شو؟","answer":"په ۲۰۰۳ کال کې"},{"question":"Bagaimanakah rakyat Malaysia menghargai nilai kemerdekaan yang dikecapi sekarang?","answer":"Patriotisme dan Pengibaran Bendera: Rakyat Malaysia menunjukkan patriotisme dengan mengibarkan bendera Malaysia dan menghiasi rumah dan tempat awam dengan dekorasi yang menggambarkan semangat kemerdekaan. Pengibaran bendera adalah tanda kesatuan dan semangat patriotik.Penglibatan dalam Aktiviti Sosial dan Sukan: Rakyat Malaysia sering terlibat dalam aktiviti-aktiviti sosial dan sukan yang memupuk semangat kemerdekaan dan persatuan. Ini boleh merangkumi kempen amal, pertandingan sukan, atau projek-projek komuniti.Pendidikan tentang Sejarah Kemerdekaan: Pendidikan tentang sejarah kemerdekaan Malaysia dimainkan peranan penting dalam menghargai nilai ini. Rakyat Malaysia belajar mengenai perjuangan dan pengorbanan yang dilakukan oleh pemimpin dan rakyat jelama penjajahan, yang membantu mereka menghargai lebih mendalam makna kemerdekaan.Menghormati Lambang Kemerdekaan: Lambang-lambang kemerdekaan seperti lagu kebangsaan, bendera, dan lambang negara diberi penghormatan. Rakyat Malaysia menghargai nilai-nilai yang diwakili oleh lambang-lambang ini dan menggunakannya dengan rasa hormat.Penghargaan terhadap Pelbagai Kebudayaan: Rakyat Malaysia menghargai kepelbagaian budaya, etnik, dan agama yang ada dalam negara ini. Ini adalah cara untuk menghormati nilai kemerdekaan yang menyokong prinsip inklusiviti dan harmoni antara pelbagai kelompok.Pertahankan Demokrasi dan Keadilan: Rakyat Malaysia melibatkan diri dalam proses demokrasi dengan mengundi dan mengambil bahagian dalam urusan awam. Mereka juga menghargai nilai keadilan dan kesaksamaan dalam sistem perundangan negara.Usaha Membina Negara yang Maju: Rakyat Malaysia berusaha untuk membina negara yang maju, sejahtera, dan berdaya saing. Usaha-usaha ini melibatkan pembangunan ekonomi, pendidikan, kesihatan, dan inovasi.Melibatkan Diri dalam Usaha Sosial dan Kemanusiaan: Rakyat Malaysia menghargai nilai kemerdekaan dengan terlibat dalam usaha sosial dan kemanusiaan, membantu mereka yang memerlukan bantuan dan memberikan sumbangan kepada masyarakat."},{"question":"atao inona ny ovy alohan'ny hitetehana azy?","answer":"voasana dia sasana ny ovy alohan'ny hitetehana azy"},{"question":"在加拿大，左轉時，你的車輛已經在交叉路口中等待， 當交通號誌由黃燈變紅燈時，你應該？","answer":"確認安全後轉彎"},{"question":"புத்தரின் மேற்கோள் ஒன்றினை தரவும்.","answer":"புல்லறிவுள்ள மூடர்கள் தாமே தமக்குப் பகைவர் அவர்கள்; பாவ கருமங்களைச் செய்துகொண்டு திரிகின்றனர்; அவை கசப்பான துன்பக்கனிகளையே அளிக்கின்றன."},{"question":"1° frase: Durante la Guerra de Independencia de Venezuela en 1821, García de Luna luchó contra Simón Bolívar y las Legiones Británicas en el lado español en la batalla de Carabobo.2° frase: Durante la Guerra de Independencia de Venezuela en 1821, García de Luna luchó contra Simón Bolívar y las legiones españolas en el lado británico en la batalla de Carabobo.Pregunta: ¿La frase 1 y la 2 expresan el mismo significado? ¿Sí o No?","answer":"No."},{"question":"Мага кызыктуу факты жазып берчи ?","answer":"Албетте , мына сизге кызыктуу факты :Дүйнөдөгү эң узун көпүрө Гонконг менен Макао шаарын байланыштырат.  Анын узундугу 55 км, ал эми курулуш 9 жылга созулган."},{"question":"ਧਰਮ ਖੰਡ ਕਾ ਏਹੋ ਧਰਮੁ ॥ ਗਿਆਨ ਖੰਡ ਕਾ ਆਖਹੁ ਕਰਮੁ ॥ਕੇਤੇ ਪਵਣ ਪਾਣੀ ਵੈਸੰਤਰ ਕੇਤੇ ਕਾਨ ਮਹੇਸ ॥ ਕੇਤੇ ਬਰਮੇ ਘਾੜਤਿ ਘੜੀਅਹਿ ਰੂਪ ਰੰਗ ਕੇ ਵੇਸ ॥ਕੇਤੀਆ ਕਰਮ ਭੂਮੀ ਮੇਰ ਕੇਤੇ ਕੇਤੇ ਧੂ ਉਪਦੇਸ ॥ ਕੇਤੇ ਇੰਦ ਚੰਦ ਸੂਰ ਕੇਤੇ ਕੇਤੇ ਮੰਡਲ ਦੇਸ ॥ ਕੇਤੇ ਸਿਧ ਬੁਧ ਨਾਥ ਕੇਤੇ ਕੇਤੇ ਦੇਵੀ ਵੇਸ ॥ਕੇਤੇ ਦੇਵ ਦਾਨਵ ਮੁਨਿ ਕੇਤੇ ਕੇਤੇ ਰਤਨ ਸਮੁੰਦ ॥ ਕੇਤੀਆ ਖਾਣੀ ਕੇਤੀਆ ਬਾਣੀ ਕੇਤੇ ਪਾਤ ਨਰਿੰਦ ॥ ਕੇਤੀਆ ਸੁਰਤੀ ਸੇਵਕ ਕੇਤੇ ਨਾਨਕ ਅੰਤੁ ਨ ਅੰਤੁ ॥੩੫॥","answer":"ਧਰਮ ਖੰਡ ਦਾ ਨਿਰਾ ਇਹੀ ਕਰਤੱਬ ਹੈ, (ਜੋ ਉੱਪਰ ਦੱਸਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ) । ਹੁਣ ਗਿਆਨ ਖੰਡ ਦਾ ਕਰਤੱਬ (ਭੀ) ਸਮਝ ਲਵੋ (ਜੋ ਅਗਲੀਆਂ ਤੁਕਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਹੈ) ।(ਅਕਾਲ ਪੁਰਖ ਦੀ ਰਚਨਾ ਵਿਚ) ਕਈ ਪ੍ਰਕਾਰ ਦੇ ਪਉਣ, ਪਾਣੀ ਤੇ ਅਗਨੀਆਂ ਹਨ, ਕਈ ਕ੍ਰਿਸ਼ਨ ਹਨ ਤੇ ਕਈ ਸ਼ਿਵ ਹਨ। ਕਈ ਬ੍ਰਹਮੇ ਪੈਦਾ ਕੀਤੇ ਜਾ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ, ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਕਈ ਰੂਪ, ਕਈ ਰੰਗ ਤੇ ਕਈ ਵੇਸ ਹਨ।(ਅਕਾਲ ਪੁਰਖ ਦੀ ਕੁਦਰਤਿ ਵਿਚ) ਬੇਅੰਤ ਧਰਤੀਆਂ ਹਨ, ਬੇਅੰਤ ਮੇਰੂ ਪਰਬਤ, ਬੇਅੰਤ ਧੂ੍ਰ ਭਗਤ ਤੇ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਉਪਦੇਸ਼ ਹਨ। ਬੇਅੰਤ ਇੰਦਰ ਦੇਵਤੇ, ਚੰਦ੍ਰਮਾ, ਬੇਅੰਤ ਸੂਰਜ ਅਤੇ ਬੇਅੰਤ ਭਵਨ-ਚੱਕਰ ਹਨ। ਬੇਅੰਤ ਸਿੱਧ ਹਨ, ਬੇਅੰਤ ਬੁਧ ਅਵਤਾਰ ਹਨ, ਬੇਅੰਤ ਨਾਥ ਹਨ ਅਤੇ ਬੇਅੰਤ ਦੇਵੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਪਹਿਰਾਵੇ ਹਨ। (ਅਕਾਲ ਪੁਰਖ ਦੀ ਰਚਨਾ ਵਿਚ) ਬੇਅੰਤ ਦੇਵਤੇ ਅਤੇ ਦੈਂਤ ਹਨ, ਬੇਅੰਤ ਮੁਨੀ ਹਨ, ਬੇਅੰਤ ਪਰਕਾਰ ਦੇ ਰਤਨ ਤੇ (ਰਤਨਾਂ ਦੇ) ਸਮੁੰਦਰ ਹਨ। (ਜੀਵ-ਰਚਨਾ ਦੀਆਂ) ਬੇਅੰਤ ਖਾਣੀਆਂ ਹਨ, (ਜੀਵਾਂ ਦੀਆਂ ਬੋਲੀਆਂ ਭੀ ਚਾਰ ਨਹੀਂ) ਬੇਅੰਤ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਹਨ, ਬੇਅੰਤ ਪਾਤਸ਼ਾਹ ਤੇ ਰਾਜੇ ਹਨ, ਬੇਅੰਤ ਪਰਕਾਰ ਦੇ ਧਿਆਨ ਹਨ (ਜੋ ਜੀਵ ਮਨ ਦੁਆਰਾ ਲਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ) , ਬੇਅੰਤ ਸੇਵਕ ਹਨ। ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ! ਕੋਈ ਅੰਤ ਨਹੀਂ ਪੈ ਸਕਦਾ। 35।"},{"question":"A cidade de Campo Grande pertence a qual estado?","answer":"Campo Grande pertence ao estado do Mato Grosso do Sul."},{"question":"Hãy hoàn thiện đoạn văn sau: Uống nhiều nước ngọt Nước ngọt và đồ uống có ga không tốt cho quá trình hydrat hóa. Hơn nữa, nước ngọt có hàm lượng đường cao và các chất phụ gia có khả năng gây hại cho cơ thể. Thay vì sử dụng các loại thức uống này, mỗi ngày nên bổ sung cho trẻ đủ 2 lít nước lọc. Đồng thời, bổ sung thêm các loại nước ép trái cây, rau củ và nước dừa. Lạm dụng thực phẩm chế biến sẵn Những loại dầu hóa học có trong thực phẩm chế biến sẵn dễ dẫn tới béo phì, tăng mức cholesterol xấu. Do đó, thường xuyên tiêu thụ thực phẩm chế biến sẵn có thể làm  chậm chậm quá trình phát về thể chất, tăng nguy cơ mắc các bệnh về tim mạch hay bệnh tiểu đường. Tốt hơn hết là hãy chuẩn bị bữa ăn cho trẻ với các món yêu thích và đảm bảo khẩu phần dinh dưỡng. ","answer":"Ăn ít cá Trẻ em và thanh thiếu niên thường không thích ăn cá, chủ yếu là vì nhiều xương. Nhưng bạn phải quen với việc đưa thực phẩm này vào chế độ ăn uống của con mình. Cá mang lại nhiều lợi ích cho sức khỏe, chẳng hạn như cải cải thiện thị lực, tăng cường trao đổi chất và ngăn ngừa chứng béo phì. Một khác, hàm lượng protein và chất béo omega 3 có trong cá còn giúp kiểm soát viêm và tăng cường sức đề kháng. Nếu trẻ sợ xương, bạn có thể chế biến thành món món chả cá cho trẻ ăn. Ăn ít rau Thanh thiếu niên có xu hướng ăn ít rau. Tuy nhiên, bạn nên cho trẻ tiêu thụ từ 3 -5 ngày rau mỗi tuần để duy trì sức khỏe tốt. Bởi vì, rau xanh chứa nhiều chất chống oxy hóa giúp kiểm soát tình trạng viêm nhiễm, tăng cường khả năng miễn dịch vào bảo vệ cơ thể khỏi các tác nhân gây hại. Uống nước hoa quả vừa đỡ khát vừa có dinh dưỡng Có rất nhiều phụ huynh cho rằng, trong nước hoa quả giàu vitamin, nên uống nhiều có thể bổ sung vitamin cho trẻ, mà không nghĩ đến việc trong nước hoa quả có nhiều chất đường, uống nhiều khiến trẻ dễ bị béo phì."},{"question":"Хаббл телескобунун мааниси эмнеде?","answer":"Хаббл телескобу алыскы галактикалар жана аалам жөнүндө укмуштуудай сүрөттөрдү жана баалуу маалыматтарды берип, космосту түшүнүүбүздү олуттуу түрдө өркүндөттү үчүн мааниси чоң."},{"question":"கேள்வி: கீழ்கண்ட எந்த இரு கோள்களுக்கு நிலவு இல்லை?கீழ் காணப்படும் நான்கு பதிலில் இருந்து சரியான பதிலை தேர்ந்து எடுக்கவும்:அ)  புதன், வெள்ளிஆ) வியாழன், வெள்ளிஇ) புதன், சனிஈ)  வியாழன், செவ்வாய்","answer":"சரியான பதில்: அ)  புதன், வெள்ளிமுழு சூரிய குடும்பத்திலும் நிலவுகள் இல்லாத இரண்டு கிரகங்கள் புதன் மற்றும் வெள்ளி மட்டுமே. இது சூரியனுக்கு அருகில் இருப்பதால் இருக்கலாம்."},{"question":"Biển Chết đã từng có tuyết rơi hay chưa?","answer":"Đã từng cóVào cuối mùa hè, bề mặt Biển Chết được bao phủ bởi một lớp “tuyết” mỏng. Hiện tượng bí ẩn này được phát hiện lần đầu vào những năm 1980, gần đây nó đã được giải thích là kết tủa muối. “Tuyết” là kết quả của “sự đối lưu khuếch tán kép”, một hiện tượng xảy ra khi nước từ tầng trên rất mặn kết hợp với nước ít mặn hơn ở tầng sâu hơn."},{"question":"Rispondi alla seguente domanda: A cosa ci si riferisce quando si parla di Sacro Romano Impero?","answer":"Il Sacro Romano Impero, talvolta chiamato anche Primo Reich (facendo riferimento al Secondo e al Terzo Reich), fu una Confederazione di Stati dell'Europa centrale e occidentale nato nell'Alto Medioevo ed esistito per circa un millennio. Traeva il nome \\"Impero romano\\" dall'essere considerato una continuazione dell'Impero romano d'Occidente e perciò un potere universale, mentre l'aggettivo \\"sacro\\", che lo contrapponeva all'impero pagano dei primi tre secoli, sottolineava che la rinascita del potere imperiale era legata alla religione cristiana e doveva considerarsi voluta da Dio; per questo motivo il potere di incoronare l'imperatore era attribuito al papa, almeno fino alla Riforma.Il Sacro Romano Impero iniziò formalmente con l'incoronazione di Carlo Magno la notte di Natale dell'anno 800 e fu dissolto il 6 agosto 1806 con la pace di Presburgo."},{"question":"Ta đã biết 3 . 2 = 6. Phải chăng (– 3) . (– 2) = – 6?","answer":"Lời giải:Nhận thấy phép tính (– 3) . (– 2) là phép nhân hai số nguyên âm. Để làm được phép nhân này, ta phải học qua §5. Sau khi học bày này, ta thực hiện ngay phép nhân hai số nguyên:(– 3) . (– 2) = 3 . 2 = 6 Vì 6 và – 6 khác nhau. Do đó phát biểu trên đề bài là không chính xác. "},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe kintana fitifirana?","answer":"Ny kintana fitifirana, antsoina koa hoe meteor, dia singa cosmic izay miditra amin'ny atmosfera eto an-tany ary mirehitra ka mamela lalana mamirapiratra rehefa simba."},{"question":"What are the potential answers to the question: What experience do you have working with diverse communities?","answer":"There are many ways in which to answer this question depending on your personal experience of working with diverse communities and the job you're applying for."},{"question":"Ẹgbẹ Emere Onitẹsiwaju ṣajọdun wọn l’Oṣogbo","answer":"Fọọfọọ ni tẹmpili Ọgbẹyọnu to wa ninu ile Araba Awo tiluu Oṣogbo, Oloye Ifayẹmi Ẹlẹbuibọn, kun l’Ọjọbọ Tọsidee, ọsẹ yii, lasiko ti awọn ẹgbẹ emere onitẹsiwaju ṣayẹyẹ ajọdun ọdun keji idasilẹ ẹgbẹ wọn.Kaakiri ijọba ibilẹ to wa nipinlẹ Ọṣun ni awọn ti wọn jẹ ọmọ ẹgbẹ ti pe jọ sibi ọdun naa pẹlu aṣọ leesi funfun lọrun wọn.Araba Ifayẹmi Ẹlẹbuibọn ati Oloye Atanda Ifagbenuṣọla to jẹ Aṣiwaju Awo Agbaye naa ko gbẹyin nibẹ nitori awọn mejeeji ni babaasalẹ ẹgbẹ ọhun.Ninu ọrọ apilẹkọ rẹ, Aarẹ ẹgbẹ Emere onitẹsiwaju kaakiri agbaye, Iyaooṣa Oyelọla Ẹgbẹyẹmi Ẹlẹbuibọn dupẹ lọwọ Eledumare fun anfaani to fun wọn lati ṣe ayẹyẹ naa, o si tun dupẹ lọwọ gbogbo awọn ti wọn jẹ oniṣẹse atawọn adari wọn kaakiri.Iyaooṣa ṣalaye pe imugbooro aṣa ati ẹsin Yoruba lo ṣokunfa bi ọpọlọpọ wọn ṣe wa nibi ayẹyẹ ọhun. O ni awọn alalẹ (ancestors) ti fi ipilẹ iṣerere lelẹ fun aṣa Yoruba, o waa ku si iran yii lọwọ lati ma ṣe jẹ ko dohun igbagbe, ki laalaa awọn akọni Yoruba ma si ja sasan.O fi kun ọrọ rẹ pe awọn eeyan orileede Europe, Amẹrika ati Latin ti n kọ asa ati ẹsin Yoruba, bẹẹ ni wọn n gbin in si ọkan awọn ọmọ wọn, ti wọn si n sọ ọ lai tiju, o waa ku si awa oni nnkan lọwọ bi ko ṣe ni i jẹ pe awọn eeyan orileede yẹn ni wọn yoo pada maa kọ awọn ọmọ wa."},{"question":"O ṣoju mi koro (Apa Keji)","answer":"Ẹ jẹ ka ṣọra fun Koro oArun Korona ti wọn pariwo ẹ nibẹrẹ ọdun yii ti tun bẹrẹ lakọtun o. Kaakiri ipinlẹ ni ijọba ti n ṣe ofin oriṣiiriṣii, ohun ti wọn si n ṣe ni bi arun naa ko ṣe ni i maa gbilẹ si i. Ṣugbọn ọpọlọpọ eeyan ni ko gba pe arun kan wa to n jẹ Korona, wọn ni awọn ti wọn n ṣejọba n fi kinni naa ko owo jẹ laaye ara wọn ni. Awọn mi-in ni arun oyinbo ni, awọn mi-in ni ko sohun ti Koro fẹẹ fi awọn ṣe; awọn mi-in ni ibinu Ọlọrun lori awọn oloṣelu jẹgudujẹra ni, nigba ti awọn ko si ti n ṣe oloṣelu, tabi oṣiṣọ ijọba, ti awọn ko si ko owo jẹ, ko si Koro ninu ọrọ tawọn. Gbogbo ọrọ yii le jẹ ootọ, ṣugbọn ohun kan to daju ni pe arun kan wa nita, abilu buruku ni, boya Koro ni o boya Koro kọ o, iyẹn lawa naa ko le sọ. Arun yii n paayan, bẹẹ ni ki i sọ fawọn to ba fẹẹ mu tẹlẹ ko too mu wọn. Nigba ti ko si si arun mi-in nita lẹnu lọọlọ yii to tun n paayan bẹẹ, afi ki awa naa gba pe koro yii naa ni. Boya oloṣelu lo ko o wa ni o, boya awọn oyinbo ni, boya iya ẹṣẹ ni tabi nnkan mi-in, Koro wa nigboro o, ko si si alaye fun ẹni to ba kọ lu, tọhun yoo mọ pe nnkan ba oun. Boya koro muuyan ki i ṣe pe ọjọ iku ẹ pe, ṣugbọn bi wọn ko ba tete mura si i lo maa n ja siku. Ọpọ eeyan la ti tun gbọ iku wọn bayii ti wọn n sọ pe Koro lo pa wọn, bẹẹ ni awọn naa ko le sọ pe awọn mọ igba ti kinnni naa wọ wọn lara. Nitori ẹ lo ṣe jẹ ẹni ti ara rẹ ko ba ti ya, ko fi ile awọn ọlọsibitu wẹlọ, ko tete lọọ ṣe ohun to ba yẹ. bo ba si jẹ awọn oogun tiwa kan wa ti tọhun mọ pe o n gbọ akọ iba ati awọn arun ti ko nidii bayii, ki tọhun gbe e lura ko ṣe nnkan kan. Ṣugbọn pataki ju lọ ni ka sọra, ka ma jẹ ki Koro yii mu wa, nitori bo ba ti mu eeyan, a maa pẹ ko too lọ. Ka ṣọra nibi ti ero ba ti pọ ju, boya ni pati ni o, tabi ni awọn ibi ariya mi-in, bo ba si di dandan ka lọ, ki awa naa bo imu wa bi awọn to ku ti n ṣe. Ko si ohun to buru bi a ba ṣe eleyii niwọn igba ti Koro yii ba ṣi wa, nitori fun alaafia ara wa ni. Bi a ko ba fẹ ki Koro na wa lowo, ti a ko si fẹ ko da wa jokoo, ki awa naa tọju ara wa o. Ogun awitẹlẹ ki i pa arọ, arọ to ba gbọn nikan ni o.Ki Ṣeyi Makinde fura, ifura loogun agbaAriwo to wa niluu bayii ni pe aarin Gomina Ṣeyi Makinde ati igbakeji rẹ, Rafiu Ọlaniyan ko fi bẹẹ gun mọ, wọn ni ija gidi wa laarin wọn, bo tilẹ jẹ kinni naa ko ti i jade sita. Eleyii ki i ṣe akọkọ ti iru eyi yoo ṣẹlẹ, eyi to si ṣe wọn ninu APC ni Ondo buru debii pe niṣe ni wọn fi ẹgbẹ naa silẹ funra wọn. Ni ọpọ igba, awọn alaṣẹ pẹlu igbakeji wọn ki i ṣọrẹ pẹ titi, kinni kan yoo ṣaa ṣẹlẹ ni. Ohun to si maa n jade sita naa ni pe gomina ko faaye gba igbakeji ẹ, ki i fi nnkan han an, o ti sọ ọ di ẹru, tabi pe o n da nikan ṣe ijọba rẹ ni. Ọrọ to maa n jade lẹnu ọpọ igbakeji awọn gomina yii niyẹn. Ni tootọ, bi a ba fẹẹ da a silẹ ti a si fẹẹ tun un ṣa, ko si awo kan ninu awo ẹwa, ko si ohun to yẹ ki gomina maa ṣe ki igbakeji rẹ ma mọ, nibi ti nnkan ba ti dara, ti olori ijọba si n ṣejọba bo ti yẹ ko ṣe e. Idi ni pe igbakeji gomina yii naa, bii gomina funra ẹ ni, nitori yatọ si pe wọn jọ dibo yan wọn sipo naa, bi ko ba ti si gomina yii nile, igbakeji rẹ yii ni yoo maa ṣejọba titi ti yoo fi de, bi gomina ko ba waa fi ohun to n lọ han igbakeji rẹ, bawo ni yoo ṣe le ṣe iru iṣẹ bẹẹ. Ṣugbọn nitori bi ọrọ oṣelu ilẹ wa ṣe ri, adiẹ ko fi ibi akitan han ọmọ rẹ ni, awọn gomina ki i fẹ ki igbakeji awọn ri ibi ti awọn ti n jẹ. Eyi ko sọ pe awọn igbakeji mi-in naa ko buru o, awọn naa le, nitori ni gbara ti wọn ba ti debẹ ni wọn yoo ti maa ṣe ọna bi awọn yoo ṣe gbajọba lọwọ ọga wọn lasiko ti ibo mi-in tun n bọ. Nidii eyi, aidaa, ati aburu gomina naa ni wọn yoo maa ṣare, wọn yoo si maa rojọ rẹ fun gbogbo awọn olori ẹgbẹ oṣelu wọn laidaa. Eyi a maa jẹ ki gomina mi-in foju ọdalẹ wo igbakeji rẹ, wọn ko si ni i ṣejọba jinna ti wọn yoo fi di ọta ara wọn. Bẹẹ bi aarin gomina ati igbakeji rẹ ko ba dan mọran, ipalara ni yoo jẹ fun ipinlẹ, nitori ilọsiwaju to ba yẹ ko wa ko ni i wa rara. Ohun ti Makinde ko ṣe gbọdọ faaye gba awuyewuye to n lọ nigboro bayii niyi. Bi kinni kan ba wa laarin oun ati igbakeji rẹ, ko yanju rẹ kia, bo ba si jẹ awọn aṣaaju ẹgbẹ oṣelu rẹ lo n binu, ko mọ bi yoo ti ṣe e. Ibi ti eeyan ba ti ba gun igi ni yoo wo, eeyan kan ki i gbagbe ibi to ba doke. Loootọ awọn aṣaaju ẹgbẹ oṣelu mi-in, ole paraku ni wọn, bii ko ko gbogbo owo ile ijọba fun wọn ni yoo ri loju wọn, Makinde ni yoo mọ bi yoo ti ṣe e ti gbogbo aye yoo fi ri i pe alaṣeju niru awọn ẹni bẹẹ. Asiko ti Makinde gbọdọ fura ree, nitori ifura loogun agba, ti kinni naa ba kọja asiko yii, afaimo ki nnkan ma yi biri fun un.Fayemi ati APC l’EkitiNigba ti awọn ẹgbẹ oṣelu to n ṣẹjọba ni ipinlẹ kan ba ni awọn sọrọ, to ba ti jẹ ni Naijiria wa yii ni, keeyan ti mọ pe olori ijọba ibẹ lo sọrọ, nitori ko si ẹgbẹ oṣelu kan to n da duro ni ipinlẹ kan, gomina ibẹ ni yoo maa paṣẹ le gbogbo ẹni to ba wa nibẹ lori. Oun ni yoo yan alaga ati awọn ijoye ẹgbẹ, oun ni yoo si mọ bi ẹgbẹ yoo ṣe maa ṣe, nitori oun ni yoo maa fun wọn lowo lati fi ṣe akoso ẹgbẹ naa. Lọrọ kan, gomina ipinlẹ kan lolori ẹgbẹ oṣelu rẹ nibẹ, ko sẹni ti i ba a du u rara. Eyi lo ṣe jẹ ọrọ ti awọn APC ipinlẹ Ekiti sọ lọsẹ to kọja yii pe  dandan ni ki Kayọde Fayẹmi ti i ṣe gomina ibẹ du ipo aarẹ ni 2023 lorukọ ẹgbẹ wọn, ki i ṣe lati ẹnu ẹlomi-in lo ti wa, lati ẹnu Fayẹmi funra ẹ ni. Ko si ọrọ awo kan ninu ọrọ yii mọ, gbogbo ilu lo ti mọ pe Fayẹmi yoo du ipo aarẹ, eyi ti ko ni i tọna nibẹ ni ọgbọn alumọkọrọyi tabi etekete. Bi yoo ba dupo aarẹ, ko si ohun to buru nibẹ, bo ba ti mọ pe oun ni aya ẹ, oun si lọgbọn lati ṣe’lu, oun si ni eto rere fun ọmọ Naijiria gbogbo. Nibi ti nnkan ti daa, ko si ohun to buru rara pe ki Fayẹmi du ipo, nitori o ti kọ ẹkọ gẹgẹ bii gomina, ati gẹgẹ bii minisita, o ti mọ eto iṣejọba daadaa debii pe o yẹ ko le mu ayipada rere ba ilu. Ṣugbọn ọna to wa n gba yii kọ ni yoo gba, oun ati awọn aṣaaju rẹ gbọdọ jọ jokoo, ki wọn sọrọ naa ko gun rege. Fayẹmi ko le sare kuro lẹyin Tinubu ko lọọ sọ ara rẹ di ọrẹ awọn Fulani nitori yoo ṣejọba. Awọn Fulani ko le mọ ọn, bẹẹ ni wọn kiba ti ri i bi ko jẹ Tinubu wa lẹyin rẹ lati di gomina. Oun paapaa yoo ṣaa si maa ranti awọn ọjọ to jẹ ile Tinubu loun n gbe tọsan-toru, nigba ti ko jẹ kinni kan, ti ko si sẹni to ka a si gẹgẹ bii oloṣelu gidi. Bo ba waa di gomina loni-in yii, to ba di minisita, to si n lakaka lati dupo aarẹ, o gbọdọ maa fi oju ẹgbẹ kan wo Tinubu, ko si maa ranti atẹyinwa, wọn gbọdọ jọ jokoo sọrọ yii kunna laarin ara wọn ni. Ko ṣaa le sọ pe oun ko mọ pe Tinubu fẹẹ du ipo arẹ, ṣe o waa fẹẹ daju ọga rẹ ni gbangba bẹẹ ni. Ki Fayẹmi tete ṣe ohun to yẹ ko ṣe o, ko lọọ ba ọga rẹ sọrọ, ko ṣalaye fun awọn agbaagba APC ilẹ Yoruba, nigba naa ni yoo ṣẹṣẹ waa kede ohun ti oun fẹẹ ṣe. Ṣugbọn eyi ti oun ati awọn Fulani ọrẹ rẹ n ṣe yii, ṣakara lasan ma ni, bii ẹni to n fi akoko ṣofo ni!Ẹ jẹ ki Tinubu jade ko fi ẹnu ara ẹ sọrọDayọ Adeyẹye, ọkan ninu awọn aṣaaju PDP to pada wọ inu APC, ko ero lẹyin lọsẹ to kọja, o dile awọn ọba ilẹ Yoruba. Wọn gba ile Ọọni kọja, wọn ko ya ibẹ (Ọlọrun nikan lo mọ ohun to ṣẹlẹ), ọdọ Olubadan ati Alaafin ni wọn lọ taara. Nigba to n lọ, o mu Musiliu Ọbanikoro dani, aṣaaju PDP loun naa, o ti ṣe minisita nibẹ daadaa ko too waa pada wa si APC, bẹẹ lawọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ APC mi-in tun tẹle wọn. Njẹ kin ni wọn n wa kiri! Wọn ni awọn waa ri awọn ọba mejeeji, ki awọn le sọ fun wọn pe ni 2023, Tinubu ni yoo ṣe aarẹ ilẹ Naijiria, awọn si ti bẹrẹ iṣẹ fun un. Bi Tinubu ba dide, to loun yoo di aarẹ ilẹ wa, nigba to jẹ oloṣelu ni, ọga wọn ni paapaa, gbogbo aye lo si mọ iṣẹ to ti ṣe sẹyin ki ẹni to wa nibẹ yii too di aarẹ. Bakan naa ni ko si ohun to buru bi Tinubu ba ranṣẹ si awọn ọba ati ijoye ilu, ohun to buru ni ki awọn eeyan kan ko ara wọn jọ, ki wọn waa maa tan ara wọn jẹ, ki wọn ni ki i ṣe Tinubu lo ran awọn niṣẹ, awọn kan dide lati ọdọ awọn, awọn si n wa ẹni ti yoo ṣe aarẹ, awọn si ri i pe Tinubu lo yẹ lẹni naa. Ọrọ naa ko daa, bii igba ti awọn eeyan yii n pe araalu lọbọ ni. bẹẹ wọn ko pe ara ilu lọbọ o, ara wọn ni wọn n pe ni akinyẹyẹ, nitori oju oniranu lawọn eeyan yoo maa fi wo wọn. Bẹẹ bo ba jẹ nigba ti wọn de ile awọn ọba wọnyi ti wọn ba sọ fun awọn ọba naa pe Tinubu lo ran awọn wa o, Tinubu fẹẹ di aarẹ, oun naa n bọ o, ọmọ yin ni, a fẹ kẹ ẹ ṣe atilẹyin fun un. Ọrọ naa yoo daa leti awọn araalu, awọn yoo si le mọ ohun ti wọn yo ṣe. Ṣugbọn nigba to ti jẹ omi-irọ ni wọn fi da awọn oloṣelu Naijiria, aye wọn ki i daa bi wọn ko ba ti i purọ, irọ ti wọn yoo fi bẹrẹ ipolongo yii naa ree, irọ naa ni wọn yoo si fi pari rẹ. Ọpọ igba ni wọn ti beere lọwọ Tinubu funra ẹ to ni oun ko sọ fẹnikẹni pe oun fẹẹ du ipo aarẹ. Titi di bi a ti n wi yii, ko ti i jade nibi kan pe oun fẹẹ du ipo aarẹ, iru iṣẹ dindinrin wo waa lawọn yii n ko ara wọn lẹyin ti wọn n jẹ kiri. Wọn ni awọn n ṣiṣẹ fun Tinubu! Wọn si ni ki i ṣe Tinubu lo ran awọn! Ṣe ko le di lọla kan ki Tinubu ni awọn eeyan kan lo waa bẹ oun ni! Tabi ta lawọn eeyan yii n ṣiṣẹ fun. Dajudaju, wọn n ṣiṣẹ fun ara wọn ati fun apo ara wọn ni, nitori ko si araalu kan to gbe iru iṣẹ bayii le wọn lọwọ. Bi Tinubu ba fẹẹ du ipo aarẹ, ẹ jẹ ko jade, ko kọkọ sọ bẹẹ, eyi lawọn araalu yoo fi mọ eyi ti wọn yoo ṣe. Gbogbo eyi ti ẹ n ba kiri yii, iranu ni o; ẹ jẹ ki Tinubu jade ko fẹnu ara ẹ sọrọ.Ki awọn ọba wa paapaa ṣọra wọn gidigidiAwọn oloṣelu ti bẹrẹ si i pooyi kiri bayii, wọn dele  Alaafin, wọn si de ọdọ Olubadan, ariwo ti wọn n pa bayii ni pe ki ọmọ Yoruba waa di aarẹ. Ṣugbọn awọn ọba wa gbọdọ ṣọ ara wọn gidigidi, nitori bi wahala kan ba ṣẹlẹ nidii ọrọ oṣelu lasiko yii, awọn ọba ti wọn ba lọwọ si abosi, iru awọn ọba bẹẹ yoo fi ara gba ohun ti ko dara o, ko ma di pe wọn jo aafin, ti wọn yoo si le ọba funra ẹ jade, ti ọba yoo si fi arugbo ara maa sa kabakaba kaakiri. Bi ọba kan ba fi ara rẹ si ipo ọwọ to yẹ ki ọba wa, iru iyẹn ko ni i ṣẹlẹ si i. Awọn ti wọn n kiri yii, ọba kọọkan gbọdọ ba wọn sọ ootọ ọrọ, ki wọn si jẹ ki araalu mọ ohun ti awọn ba wọn sọ. Akọkọ ni pe kin ni awọn oloṣelu ti wọn kiri lọjọsi, ti wọn ni Buhari yoo mu ire ba ilẹ Yoruba nitori pe o mu Ọṣinbajo ni igbakeji, ri ṣe si gbogbo iṣoro to n koju awa Yoruba bayii, paapaa iṣoro aile-sun aile-wo tawọn Fulani wọnyi ko ba wa. Kin ni awọn oloṣelu ilẹ Yoruba ti wọn gbe Buhari wa ri ṣe si ọrọ pe wọn Fulani n gba ilẹ wa? Kin ni wọn ri ṣe si pe Buhari n yọ awọn Yoruba nidii iṣẹ gidi ni Naijiria, o si n fi awọn Fulani si i. Kin ni wọn ri ṣe si pe ko si ifọkanbalẹ, ati isinmi kan ni ọpọ ilẹ Yoruba laye ijọba to wa lode yii! Ọna wo gan-an ni awọn naa si fẹẹ gba ti ijọba tiwọn yoo fi yatọ. Ki lo de ti wọn ko si fun ijọba to wa lode yii ni iru amọran bẹẹ, lati le mọ ohun ti wọn yoo ṣe. Gbogbo ohun ti awọn ọba yii gbọdọ beere ree ki wọn too wa lẹyin oloṣelu kan. Ọba to ba n gbe oloṣelu kan gẹgẹ lasiko yii, to n fipa mu awọn eeyan rẹ pe oun ni ki wọn tẹle, toun naa n jade, to n ko agbada wọ kiri lori ohun ti ko mọ, tabi nitori owo buruku ti wọn ko wa fun un, ọba bẹẹ yoo jẹka gbẹyin, yoo kabaamọ, nitori bi wahala ba bẹrẹ, ile rẹ ni awọn ọdọ ati aralau yoo kọkọ rọ lọ, iru alejo bẹẹ ko si ni i jẹ alejo alaafia, alejo lile ni. Ọba to ba fẹẹ fi igbadun lo igbẹyin aye rẹ, afi ko ṣọra fun awọn oloṣelu lasiko yii, ọba to ba jẹ ki wọn ko ba oun, ko ti mọ pe ohun ti oju oun ba ri, oun loun fi ọwọ ara oun fa a o. Ẹyin ijoye ilu, ẹyin ayaba gbogbo, ẹ ba awọn kabiyesi sọrọ, nitori ọba to ba fọwọ ẹ fa jọgọdi, yoo fori ara rẹ ru u o. Ni asiko ta a wa yii, ẹ sọ fawọn ọba wa ki wọn sọra wọn gidigidi!Asiko ti awọn ọba wa gbọdọ sọ ara wọn gidigidi ree o."},{"question":"குறைந்த எலக்ட்ரான் கவர் தன்மையுடைய தனிமம் \\t1. ஹைட்ரஜன்2. சீசியம்3. குளோரின்4. ஃப்ளுரின்","answer":"2. சீசியம்"},{"question":"(Ngokumangala) Sanibonani Sonto, kwenzenjani? Wafika nabantuboMthetho?Ungethuki Nkosikazi. Mina ngingumseshi uNhleko. Kasizile ngobubi.Sidinga usizo lwakho nje, esethemba ukuthi sizoluthola.(Esathukile) Mina nginguMaNsibande. Kwenzenjani?Siyadabuka ukukwazisa ukuthi uMfundisi uZondo uhlaselwe,utholakale edutshuliwe, njengamanje ulimele kakhulu esibhedlela.(Ethwala izandla ekhanda) Hawu! Hawu! Ngomfundisi Nkosi yamiwoneni nje, kubani?(Ngezwi elinozwela) Nathi sizwe ubuhlungu nkosikazi. Impelasiyadabuka, sizwelana nani.(Esula izinyembezi emehlweni.) Kodwa ngoMfundisi pho!Nami ivele nje yangethusa le ndaba ntombi.Hawu! Kodwa ubangiswani uMfundisi? Kanti banjani abantuemhlabeni bakithi? Bambulala ebe enzeni nje uMfundisi?Kusolakala sengathi kumayelana nemali ngoba kukhona etholakeleendlini lapho edutshulelwe khona uMfundisi.Washo ngabona, kade befuna imali yomnikelo. Kodwa beyazelaphingoba indaba yemali ibiphakathi kwethu sobathathu?E, ngizodinga usizo lwakho-ke dadewethu. (Ekhipha ibhukwana.)Ngingakubuza imibuzo embalwa?Yebo, ayikho inkinga.Umgcine nini uMfundisi?Izolo ntambama.Bekungaba ngubani isikhathi?(Elokhu esula izinyembezi.) Bese ligamanxile ihora lesikhombisa.Ingabe ukhona yini umuntu enimgibelisile endleleni?Cha, impela akekho.Kuyiqiniso ukuthi ngenkathi nigcinana nobathathu benikade nibalaimali yomnikelo negcine ihambe noMfundisi?Yebo kuyiqiniso.1. Le ndawo okukhulunywa ngayo kulo mdlalo inomlando wobugebengu. Sekelalo mbono ngephuzu ELILODWA.","answer":"USonto wathenga izigebengu ukuthi zibulale uMaNtuli.√√/• USonto wadubula umfundisi wantshontsha imali yomnikelo. √√• Wathumela abantu ukuthi babulale uMbhele.√√/• Umakhelwane weba imali eyafihlwa uSonto"},{"question":"كم عدد الصحابة المبشرين بالجنة؟\\t","answer":"10 صحابة"},{"question":"🇰🇬 Манас эпосу 📚Манастын Париканага кала курдурганы деген 3 басма табак көлөмдөгү үзүндү жазылып алынган, атасы бул Сейит уулум деп атаган, эпостун бардык бөлүмүн айткан манасчы аял?а) Алыйман Муса кызы б) Сейде Дейди кызыв) Сейдене Молдоке кызы г) Молдокулова Эсенбүбү","answer":" 🇰🇬 Манас эпосу 📚б) Сейде Дейди кызы."},{"question":"Complete the following phrase:  Operasi PX adalah nama sandi untuk serangan teror biologis yang direncanakan Jepang untuk dilakukan di pantai barat Amerika Serikat dalam Perang Dunia II. Operasi terencana itu dibatalkan karena penolakan yang kuat dari Kepala Staf Umum Yoshijirō Umezu dan","answer":"kurangnya persediaan logistik untuk melaksanakan serangan tersebut. Selain itu, Jepang juga khawatir bahwa tindakan semacam itu akan memicu serangan  balasan yang lebih dahsyat dari Amerika Serikat. Sebagai gantinya, Jepang lebih berfokus pada strategi perang konvensional dan operasi militer lainnya dalam upaya untuk mencapai keunggulan di medan pertempuran."},{"question":"Viết một tập hợp A gồm các số tự nhiên lẻ nhỏ hơn 10.","answer":"Các số tự nhiên lẻ nhỏ hơn 10 là: 1; 3; 5; 7; 9.Do đó tập hợp A được viết như sau:A = {1; 3; 5; 7; 9}."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai menatang minyak yang penuh\\"? Nyatakan satu contoh ayat bagi peribahasa tersebut.","answer":"Ia bermaksud memelihara anak dengan penuh kasih sayang. Contoh ayat:  Zainab menjaga satu-satunya anak perempuannya dengan sepenuh hati dan kasih sayang bagai menatang minyak yang penuh."},{"question":"أريد إنشاء قصيدة هجاء من بحر الطويل. هل يمكنك مساعدتي؟","answer":"يَقولونَ ماشِ الدَهرَ مِن حَيثُ ما مَشىفَكَيفَ بِماشٍ يَستَقيمُ وَأَظلَعُوَما واثِقٌ بِالدَهرِ إِلاّ كَراقِدٍعَلى فَضلِ ثَوبِ الظِلِّ وَالظِلُّ يُسرِعُوَقالوا تَعَلَّل إِنَّما العَيشُ نَومَةٌيُقَضّى وَيَمضي طارِقُ الهَمِّ أَجمَعُوَلَو كانَ نَوماً ساكِناً لَحَمِدتُهُوَلَكِنَّهُ نَومٌ مَروعٌ مُفَزَّعُ"},{"question":"Inona ary izao : \\"Solabe minaonaona\\"","answer":"Valiny : aponga. Milaza ny endrika ivelan'ilay aponga izay eo amin'ilay sola no velesina mba hampisy feo azy."},{"question":"இதை தமிழில் மொழிபெயர்க்கவும்-carriage return","answer":"ஏந்தி மீளல்"},{"question":"Эгемендүүлүк майрамын качан майрамдашат?","answer":"Кыргыз Республикасынын Эгемендүүгүн 31-август күнү белгилейт."},{"question":"السؤال: من هو النبي الذي كان يصنع من الطين تماثيل على هيئة طير وينفخ فيها فتصبح طيوراً بإذن الله؟","answer":"الإجابة:  نبي الله عيسى عليه السلام."},{"question":"Tohizo izao ohabolana izao : \\" Mpamosavy milaza tia fahavalony, ____  \\"","answer":"\\"  Mpamosavy milaza tia fahavalony, hay mila tamby fahafatesana \\"."},{"question":"අන්නාසි වගාකරන ප්‍රබේද නම් කරන්න.","answer":"ප්‍රධාන ව‍ශයෙන් වගාකරන ප්‍රබේද දෙකක් ඇත.1. මුරුසි ප්‍රබේදය ඉදවා අළුත් පළතුරක් ලෙස වැඩිවශයෙන් පරිබෝජනය කරයි. හොඳින් ඉදුණු ගෙඩියෙන් සුවඳක් හමයි. මාංශලය තද කහ වර්ණයෙන් යුතු අතර ඉතා පැණිරසය. හොඳින් වැඩුණු ගෙඩියක් කිලෝ එකහමාරක් පමණ බරය. මේ ප්‍රබේදයේ පත්‍ර කටු සහිතය.මේ ගසකින් මොරෙයියන් වැඩිප්‍රමාණයක්ද ලබාගත හැක.2. කිව් ප්‍රබේදය ටින්වල ඇසිරීම සඳහා ගනුලබයි. කිව් ප්‍රබේදය මුරුසි ප්‍රබේදය තරම් පැණිරස නැත.තරමක් ඇඹුල් රසැතිය. මාංශලය සුදු පාටට හුරු ලාකහ පැහැතිය. ඉතා වැඩි යුෂ ප්‍රමාණයක් ඇත.ගෙඩියක් කිලෝ එකහමාරේ සිට කිලෝ තුන පමණ දක්වා වැඩේ.පත්‍රවල කටු අඩු අතර මොරෙයියන් හටගැනීමද අඩුය."},{"question":"రాము యొక్క హృదయ స్పందన రేటు 72/ని. అయిన అతని నాడీ స్పందన రేటు ………..","answer":" 72/ ని. కు సమానం"},{"question":"Ik zoek een goedkope open bank test koffer met de volgende vereisten:    Helemaal open, geen panelen    Het liefst plat, maar dubbelverdieping mag ook    Geschikt voor een mATX moederbord formaat    Plaats voor ATX voeding en bevestiging 2 slots GPU    Max € 80, ik ben krenterigNatuurlijk ben ik een bewonderaar van de Streacom BC1, maar met een prijskaart van € 175 ligt het helaas buiten mijn budget.Tot nu toe is deze AliExpress variant de beste match en sta ik op punt om het te bestellen, maar ik dacht even polshoogte nemen bij mijn mede-tweakers die misschien leuke suggesties zouden hebben. Ik zal voor de zilveren variant gaan, want de zwarte heeft GPU bevestiging die er erg fragiel uitziet.","answer":"Ik geloof er niets van dat een fabrikant zo iets zou doen. Ten eerste, zullen ze nooit iets wat afgekeurd is zomaar verkopen. Als iemand dat dan ziet, kunnen ze denken dat de fabrikant slechte standaarden heeft.Hele goede manier om in een klap je reputatie kapot te maken.Die onderdelen gebruiken ze gewoon voor andere kasten, of het word gewoon gerecycled.Daarbij kost dit ook veel meer moeite dan dat het ooit waard is. Streacom zou dan een afgekeurde kast bij de fabrikant moeten gaan halen, en die los moeten verkopen aan een klant? Verzenden vanaf de andere kant van de wereld?Dan kost dat afgekeurde ding waarschijnlijk minimaal het dubbele van een normale versie in de winkel.Vragen staat vrij, maar ik weet 99.9% zeker dat dat niets word. (bovendien zal je waarschijnlijk ook nooit iemand te spreken krijgen die hoog genoeg op de rangorde staat om dit voor elkaar te krijgen)"},{"question":"عدد الدول العربية الموجودة في قارة أفريقي؟","answer":"تسع دول عربية."},{"question":"கீழ்க்காணும் பாடலைப் படித்தறிந்து ஏதேனும் 5 நயங்களை மட்டும் எழுதுக:தாயென அன்பு செய்துதந்தைபோல் பரிந்து, சொந்தச்சேயென அணைத்துப் பேசிசெவ்விய அறிவு கூறிதூயநன் னடத்தை கற்கத்துணையென நடந்து காட்டும்ஆயநற் குணமுள் ளோனேஆசானென் றழைக்கத் தக்கோன். (- நாமக்கல் கவிஞர்)","answer":"ஆசிரியர் குறிப்பு:இயற்பெயர் : வெ. இராமலிங்கம்பிறப்பு : 29 அக்டோபர், 1888ஊர் : மோகனூர் – நாமக்கல் மாவட்டம்சிறப்பு பெயர் : காந்தியக் கவிஞர்படைப்பு : மலைக்கள்ளன், நாமக்கல் கவிஞர் பாடல்கள்இறப்பு : 24 ஆகஸ்டு 1972)திரண்ட கருத்து:ஒரு நல்ல ஆசிரியன் என்பவன் தாயைப் போல அன்பு செய்தும், தந்தையைப் போல பரிவுடனும், பெற்ற குழந்தையைப் போல அணைத்து பேசியும் நல்ல அறிவுரைகளை கூறுதல் வேண்டும். தூய நன்னடத்தைகளைக் கற்க துணையைப் போல நடந்துகாட்ட வேண்டும். இவ்வகையான தூய்மையான நல்ல குணங்கள் உள்ளவனே நல்ல ஆசான் ஆவார்.மையக் கருத்து:ஒரு நல்ல ஆசான் தாய், தந்தை, குழந்தை, துணையை போல இருக்க வேண்டும் என கூறுகிறார்.மோனை:மோனை – சீர்தோறும் முதல் எழுத்து ஒன்றி வருவதுஅன்பு – அறிவுஆயநற்குணம் – ஆசானெள்எதுகை:அடிதோறும் இரண்டாவது எழுத்து ஒன்றி வருவது அடி எதுகை.தாயென – சேசெயனதூயறள் – ஆயநள்அணி:உவமையணி"},{"question":"Qual é a diferença entre um meteoro, um meteorito, e um meteoroide?","answer":"Um meteoroide é um fragmento de rocha ou metal que orbita o Sol, e que tem um tamanho menor do que um asteróide. Um meteoro é o fenômeno luminoso que ocorre quando um meteoroide entra na atmosfera da Terra, e se aquece e se vaporiza devido ao atrito com o ar. Um meteorito é o fragmento de um meteoroide que sobrevive à passagem pela atmosfera, e atinge a superfície da Terra. Portanto, a diferença entre esses termos está relacionada ao local onde o fragmento se encontra: no espaço, na atmosfera, ou no solo."},{"question":"Вопрос: какие языки наиболее распространены на территории России?","answer":"193 народа, проживающих в России, используют приблизительно 277 языков (по другим данным – 295) и диалектов. Наиболее распространенные: : русский, татарский, тувинский, чеченский, и якутский языки."},{"question":"Cilmi baaris “saameynta ay hawada wasakhaysan kuleedahay caqliga aadamaha”.","answer":"Cilmibaadhis la sameeyey ayaa lagu sheegay in hawada wasakheysan ay sababto hoos u dhac weyn oo ku yimaada caqliga bani‟aadamka. Cilmibaadhayaasha oo ku sugnaa shiinaha ayaa waxa ay daraasadoooda ku sameeyeen saambalo laga soo qaadey imtixaano luqada iyo mid xisaaba, oo ay galeen ilaa 20,000 oo ardey oo da‟doodu kala duwan tahay, intaas oo la ururinayey mudo afar sano ah kadibna waxay khubaradii isbarbardhigeen natiijooyinka soo baxey iyo heerka wasakheynta hawada ee xilligaas, waxayna ogaadeen in haddii uu qofku ku noolaado mudo hawo wasakheysan ay badan tahay khatarta soo gaadheysa maskaxdiisa. Cilmibaadhayaasha ay waxay sheegeen sidoo kale in xogta ay heleen loo isticmaali karo dunida oo dhan."},{"question":"請回答這個問題：在物理學中，什麼是波粒二象性？","answer":"答案：波粒二象性是指粒子在某些實驗條件下表現出波動性質和粒子性質的現象。根據量子力學理論，微觀粒子如光子和電子具有波動-粒子二重性，既可以表現出波動特徵，也可以表現出粒子特徵。"},{"question":"Título: Hillary x Trump: a 'mensagem do povo alemão' aos americanos que se tornou viral Dado o título acima de um artigo imaginário, imagine o artigo.","answer":"Meme atribuído \\"ao povo alemão\\" viralizou e gerou muita controvérsia nas redesEsta mensagem, que compara a campanha do candidato republicano a presidente dos EUA Donald Trump com o Adolf Hitler da Alemanha da década de 1930, foi compartilhada por milhares de pessoas nas redes sociais nos últimos dias. O homem que criou a publicação disse estar satisfeito por ter começado uma das \\"discussões mais civilizadas\\" das eleições nos Estados Unidos, que acontecem nesta terça. O usuário do Twitter, que assegura se chamar Johan Franklin, publicou a mensagem aos americanos na última sexta-feira em nome do \\"povo alemão\\", perguntando aos americanos \\"o que poderia dar errado\\" caso votassem no candidato republicano. A carta compara Trump a Hitler - o que irritou muita genteA mensagem apareceu junto à hashtag #beentheredonethat (\\"já estive nessa situação e fiz isso\\", em tradução livre) e viralizou imediatamente em diversas redes sociais. Fim do Talvez também te interesseO caso levou alguns a criarem memes comparando Trump a Hitler. Mas também houve críticas à associação dos dois personagens.Franklin, que é alemão e trabalha em San Diego (Califórnia), defendeu sua publicação em entrevista à BBC.'Me assustei'\\"Não teve tanto a ver propriamente com Trump, mas com o fato dele continuar ganhando seguidores, independente do que dizia ou fazia.\\"\\"Me assustei quando tentei conversar com seguidores de Trump dentro do meu círculo de amigos e colegas e comecei a enxergar paralelos com o que meus avós e outras pessoas mais velhas me contaram sobre o que aconteceu na Alemanha durante os anos 1930\\", continuou.\\"A publicação se tornou popular quando foi compartilhada por um seguidor da democrata Hillary Clinton, rival de Trump.\\"Depois que o tuíte viralizou, Franklin explicou noutra mensagem por que havia feito a comparação: \\"Claro que não posso falar por toda a população alemã. Usei essa linguagem como forma de trazer drama e ênfase ao post\\".Ele continuou, frisando: \\"Não dá para comparar Trump (ou quem quer que..."},{"question":"Aiza ny firenena afrikanina misy ny piramida \\"Cheops\\"?a) Ejiptab) Sodanac) Alzeriad) Maroc","answer":"Ao Ejipta no ahitana ny piramida \\"Cheops\\"."},{"question":"Write a character-driven story about an individual who must confront their deepest fears to achieve personal growth.","answer":"एक पात्र-निर्देशित कहानी लिखें जिसमें एक व्यक्ति को अपने सबसे गहरे भयों का सामना करना होता है ताकि वह व्यक्तिगत विकास हासिल कर सके।"},{"question":"රාජ්‍ය මන්ත්‍රණ සභාවට තේරීපත්වූ පළමුවැනි දෙමළ ජාතිකයා කවුද?","answer":"රාජ්‍ය මන්ත්‍රණ සභාවට තේරීපත්වූ පළමුවැනි දෙමළ ජාතිකයා රත්නජෝති සරවනමුත්තු මහතාය ( උතුරු කොළඹ - 1931 )."},{"question":"Escribe el evento más importante del texto : Con el triunfo, el Club América obtuvo un lugar en la Copa Mundial de Clubes de la FIFA 2016 y logró imponer a la vez, el récord como el equipo con más títulos a nivel de clubes del máximo certamen del área con siete; Y de paso en el primer equipo de la zona en alcanzar los 10 títulos internacionales.","answer":"Que alcanzaron los 10 títulos internacionales. "},{"question":"तलको प्रश्नको उत्तर दिनुहोस् । १) ५४ / ९ ( भाग गर्नुहोस् ।)(क) ७(ख) ६(ग) ८(घ) ५","answer":"५४ / ९ को भाग गर्दा \\"(ख) ६\\" हुन्छ ।"},{"question":"வினா:தமிழ் சிறுவர் இலக்கியம் பற்றி எழுதுக. ","answer":"விடை :சிறுவர் இலக்கியம் என்பது பேசத்துவங்கும் குழந்தை முதல் சுமார் பதினான்கு வயது வரையிலான குழந்தைகளுக்கான இலக்கியம் என்று கூறலாம். ஏழு வயது வரையிலானோர்க்கான இலக்கியத்தைக் குழந்தை இலக்கியம் என்றும் அதற்கும் அதிகமான வயதினருக்கானதைச் சிறுவர் இலக்கியம் என்று வகைப்படுத்துகின்றனர். இரண்டு வகையினருக்குமான தேவை, வடிவம், களம், மொழி ஆகியவை நுட்பமாக மாறுபடும். ஆனாலும் பொதுவாக இவை இரண்டும் சிறுவர் இலக்கியம் என்றே பரவலாக வழங்கப்படுகின்றது. சிறுவர் இலக்கியத்தின் வடிவங்களாக எவை எல்லாம் சேர்த்துக்கொள்ளலாம்? கதைகள், பாடல்கள், கவிதைகள், கட்டுரைகள், நாவல்கள், அறிவியல் கட்டுரைகள், நாடகங்கள், சினிமா, சித்திரக்கதைகள், துணுக்குகள் இவை அனைத்தும் அடங்கும். அச்சு ஊடகம் பிரபலமான பின்னர் மேற்கில் இருந்து தான் சிறுவர் இலக்கியம் என்ற தனிப்பிரிவு வீரியம் கொண்டது எனலாம். அதற்கு முன்னர் சிறுவர்க்குப் பெரியவர்களுக்கு என்ற பிரிவு கிடையாது."},{"question":"لماذا سمي يوم الجمعة بهذا الاسم؟ .","answer":" الجواب حتى يجتمع فيها الناس"},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'mati tidak akan menyesal, luka tidak akan menyiuk'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud azam yang tekad, sudah bulat hati untuk melakukan sesuatu dan tidak akan mengumpat atau menyesal kemudiannya"},{"question":"Given the below title and summary of an article, generate a short article or the beginning of a long article to go along with them. Title: ‘చైనా ఏజెంట్లు ప్రపంచమంతా పాకేశారు.. అమ్మాయిలను ఎరవేసి బ్లాక్ మెయిలింగ్‌లు’nSummary: టెలికాం దిగ్గజం హువావే చుట్టూ తాజాగా అల్లుకున్న వివాదం, చైనా గూఢచర్యం విధానాలను మరోసారి బయటపెట్టింది.nArticle (Max 500 characters):","answer":"చైనా తన పనులు నెరవేర్చుకునేందుకు ప్రపంచవ్యాప్తంగా వ్యక్తులను, వ్యవస్థలను ఎలా ప్రభావితం చేస్తుందో ఇది తేటతెల్లం చేసింది. చైనా గూఢచర్యం ఏ స్థాయిలో ఉంది? అది ఎలా నడుస్తుంది? ఎవరు నడుపుతారు?మాజీ ఎం-16 గూఢచారి సహకారంతో ఇటీవల విడుదలైన ఓ రిపోర్ట్‌ అనేక అంశాలను బయటపెట్టింది.తమ టెలికాం కంపెనీ తిరిగి బ్రిటన్‌లో కార్యకలాపాలు కొనసాగించడానికి చైనా ప్రభుత్వం ఆ దేశ రాజకీయ నాయకులతో ఎలా వ్యవహారం నడిపిందో..  ప్రముఖ వ్యక్తులను ప్రభావితం చేయడానికి ఎలా ప్రయత్నించిందో అందులో వివరించారు."},{"question":"Ireto misy fanambarana ireto: \\"Mitondra fifaliana lehibe ho ahy ny fitendrena zava-maneno\\" sy  \\"Miaina fifaliana lehibe aho rehefa mitendry zava-maneno\\" mitovy ve ny resahan'ireo fanambarana ireo?","answer":"Eny, samy miresaka momba ny fitiavany mitendry zava-maneno ireo fanambarana roa ireo."},{"question":"Чоң тосмо рифи деген эмне?","answer":"Улуу Тосмо рифи - Австралиянын Квинсленд штатынын жээгинде жайгашкан дүйнөдөгү эң чоң коралл рифтери."},{"question":"问：江苏在中国的地理位置在哪里？","answer":"答：江苏位于中国的东部沿海地区，南邻浙江，北靠山东，西接安徽和河南，东临黄海。"},{"question":"የብርቱካን ዛፍ ቅጠሎች ምን ያህል ስፋት አላቸው?","answer":"ከ4 እስከ 10 ሳንቲሜትር"},{"question":"වෛද්‍ය විද්‍යාවේ පියා\\" ලෙස හඳුන්වන්නේ කවුද?","answer":"හිපොක්‍රටීස්"},{"question":"Vị vua nào đặt tên cho quần thể núi Ngũ Hành Sơn?A. Vua Minh MạngB. Vua Tự ĐứcC. Vua gia Long","answer":"A. Vua Minh MạngĐầu thế kỷ 19, tức năm 1825, Vua Minh Mạng vi hành đến đây, dựa vào cấu tạo năm ngọn núi theo phương vị Ngũ Hành: Kim, Mộc, Thủy, Hỏa, Thổ đã đặt tên quần thể là Ngũ Hành Sơn. Sách \\"Đại Nam dư địa chí ước biên\\" viết: \\"Năm Minh Mạng thứ 18 (1837) có sắc chỉ, ban cho ngọn núi phía đông bắc (núi Tam Thai) là Thủy Sơn. Ba ngọn núi phía tây nam là Mộc Sơn, Dương Hỏa, Âm Hỏa. Hai ngọn phía tây là Thổ Sơn, Kim Sơn và cho khắc tên núi đá\\"."},{"question":"السؤال:  اذكر فروع القانون الخاص ؟","answer":"الإجابة: القانون المدني ، القانون التجاري ، قانون المرافعات المدنية والتجارية ،  القانون الدولي الخاص ، القانون البحري، والقانون الجوي، والقانون الزراعي، وقانون العمل والضمان وقانون الاستثمار، وغيرها."},{"question":"Đoạn văn sau đang nói về vấn đề gì? Chữa lành vết thương Dầu mù u có chứa các polyphenol, calophyllolides và inophyllum giúp kích thích sản xuất collagen và tăng sinh tế bào da. Điều này có lợi cho việc chữa lành vết thương. Vì vậy, có thể thoa dầu mù u lên vết cắt, vết phồng rộp và vết xước để làm dịu và giúp vết thương mau lành hơn. Trị mụn trứng cá Dầu mù u có chứa các hợp chất hoạt tính sinh học như calophyllolide, axit calophyllic và lactone giúp loại bỏ vi khuẩn. Dầu mù u còn chống lại các chủng vi khuẩn gây mụn như Propionibacterium acnes  (P. acnes) và Propionibacterium granulosum (P. granulosum). Tác dụng chống viêm của dầu mù u còn hỗ trợ điều trị tình trạng viêm do mụn trứng cá gây ra. Ngoài ra, các chất chống oxy hóa trong dầu mù u còn làm mờ sẹo mụn. Giảm vết rạn, vết thâm trên da Dùng dầu mù u thoa trực tiếp lên da có thể làm giảm vết rạn da. Đồng thời, dầu mù u còn giúp làm sáng, hỗ trợ làm mờ vết thâm. Điều này là do dầu mù u có đặc tính tái tạo và thay đổi tế bào da mới. Giảm các dấu hiệu lão hóa sớm Các axit béo trong dầu mù u có thể ngăn ngừa các dấu hiệu lão hóa sớm. Các chất chống oxy hóa trong dầu sẽ trung hòa bất kỳ gốc tự do, từ đó làm chậm quá trình lão hóa da. Dầu mù u còn bảo vệ da khỏi tác hại của tia UV, nguyên nhân chính gây ra lão hóa da. Ngăn ngừa khô da Các axit oleic và linoleic trong dầu mù u nuôi dưỡng sâu, giúp dưỡng ẩm cho làn da. Có thể sử dụng dầu mù u đã pha loãng như một loại dầu dưỡng da mặt, ngăn ngừa khô da. Nên dùng dầu mù u thoa lên da trước khi đi ngủ. Điều trị bệnh chàm và bệnh vẩy nến Dầu mù u có các đặc tính kháng khuẩn và chống viêm, giúp giảm bớt các triệu chứng của bệnh chàm và bệnh vẩy nến. Thêm vào đó, dầu mù u còn giàu axit linoleic giúp giảm nguy cơ mắc bệnh vẩy nến. Chữa lành vết cháy nắng Kem chống nắng chứa 1% dầu mù u có thể giảm thiểu đáng kể 85% tác hại do tia UV gây ra. Vì vậy, thoa dầu mù u lên da sẽ bảo vệ làn da khỏi tia nắng mặt trời, giúp điều trị cháy nắng.","answer":"Lợi ích của dầu mù u đối với da"},{"question":"Su’aal: Sheeg Salaada Aan Aadaan Iyo Aqim Mid Lahayn?","answer":"Jawaab: Waa Salaada Ciida."},{"question":"पृथ्वीराज चौहाण माने संयोगिता हिला पळवून तिच्याशी विवाह केल्याची गोष्ट कोणत्या ग्रंथात आहे ?","answer":"पृथ्वीराज रासो"},{"question":"Sobre qual importante evento o texto a seguir faz referência? \\"A concessão do título condal em 1479 ao 5.º senhor de Cantanhede enquadra-se na onda de mercês, ainda mal estudada, decorrente da Batalha de Toro (1476) contra Fernando II de Aragão, no contexto da Guerra de Sucessão de Castela ou guerra da Beltraneja, em que D. Pedro de Meneses esteve presente ao lado de D. Afonso V e o futuro D. João II.\\"","answer":"Guerra de Sucessão de Castela"},{"question":"Inona no volana fahaefatra amin'ny teny gasy?","answer":"Ny volana fahaefatra amin'ny teny gasy dia Aprily."},{"question":"Maxay kala yihiin shuruudaha \\"Laa Ilaaha illa Laahu\\" ee toddobada ahi?","answer":"Waxay kala yihiin shuruudaha \\"Laa Ilaaha illa Laahu\\" sida tan:1. Garasho oo ah in aqoon loo yeesho macnaha iyo ujeedada \\"Laa Ilaaha illa Laahu\\".2. Yaqiinsasho aan shaki lahayn oo ah si hubaal ah oo loo aamino saxsanaanta Laa Ilaaha illa Laahu.3. Aqbalaad aan diidmo lahayn oo ah in la aqbalo Laa Ilaaha illa Laahu.4. Hogaansamid aan ka tegid lahayn oo ah in lagu dhaqmo Laa Ilaaha illa Laah.5. Ka runsheegid oo ah in ay is waafaqaan hadalkiisa iyo uurkiisu.6. Saafi yeelid aan shirki lahayn, oo ah in aan cid kale la caabudin.7. Jacayl aan necayb lahayn, oo ah haddii wax kale ka hor yimaado in aad waxa kale ka tagto."},{"question":"\\"Он колумда он шакек бар ал Чынарбай,Он койду карышкыр жеди кан чыгарбай,Аны тапкан адамга өзүм барам мал чыгарбай\\".-табышмактын жандырмагы кандай?","answer":"Табышмактын жандырмагы-\\"ТЫРМАК АЛУУ\\". "},{"question":"Đọc đoạn văn sau và đưa ra một tiêu đề phụ hợp với nội dung: Cựu người mẫu Ojani Noa vừa có buổi phỏng vấn độc quyền trên Daily Mail. Trong buổi trò chuyện, Ojani Noa chia sẻ về chuyện tình cảm trước đây với Jennifer Lopez cùng quá khứ đầy biến cố của anh. Ojani Noa nói: \\"Tôi cầu mong những điều tốt đẹp đến với Ben Affleck và cô ấy. Tuy nhiên, tôi không tin cuộc hôn nhân này kéo dài mãi mãi\\". \\"Jennifer Lopez thích cảm giác được yêu và đã đính hôn 6 lần. Ben là người thứ 4. Tôi là người đầu tiên. Cô ấy từng nói tôi là tình yêu của cuộc đời cô ấy và hứa ở bên nhau mãi mãi\\", cựu người mẫu nói thêm. Tuy nhiên, cả hai chia tay sau một năm kết hôn. Ojani Noa bày tỏ đây là lần đầu và lần cuối anh chia sẻ chuyện tình cảm trong quá khứ với nữ diễn viên. Bởi cựu người mẫu không muốn mọi người hiểu nhầm anh là kẻ ăn bám vào vợ cũ. \\"Chúng tôi gắn bó trong hai năm và giữ mối quan hệ bạn bè một thập kỷ sau đó. Cả hai yêu nhau khi cô ấy đã nổi tiếng. Trong quãng thời gian chúng tôi kết hôn, cô ấy vươn lên tầm siêu sao. Sau này, tôi vẫn đau lòng khi nhớ về chuyện tình cảm quá khứ. Tôi muốn yên tĩnh và sống cuộc đời của mình\\", anh chia sẻ. Ojani Noa kể thêm vào năm 2002, Jennifer Lopez khai trương nhà hàng mới ở Los Angeles. Lúc đó, anh vẫn được cô mời làm quản lý nhà hàng. \\"Lúc ấy, Jennifer Lopez xuất hiện cùng Ben. Anh ấy cầm một bó hồng lớn trên tay. Khi trò chuyện cùng tôi, Ben nói Jennifer là người phụ nữ tuyệt vời. Tôi đáp lại: 'Tôi biết điều đó'\\", chồng cũ của nữ diễn viên nhớ lại. \\"Giờ đây, khi hai người quay lại với nhau, tôi cảm giác mối quan hệ này không bền chặt. Tôi nghĩ cô ấy sẽ kết hôn đến 7-8 lần. Tôi không cảm thấy cô ấy muốn ở mãi bên một ai đó. Cô ấy luôn muốn phát triển công việc lên đỉnh cao trong hơn ba thập kỷ qua. Nhưng cô ấy cũng muốn thay đổi trong chuyện tình cảm\\", Ojani Noa nói. Sau lễ cưới bí mật, Jennifer Lopez và Ben Affleck đang hưởng tuần trăng mật tại Paris (Pháp). Ben Affleck và Jennifer Lopez hàn gắn mối quan hệ vào năm 2021, sau gần 2 thập niên chia tay. Trong cuộc phỏng vấn trên WSJ, sao phim Gone Girl nói anh thấy hạnh phúc khi được trao cơ hội thứ 2. Trong quá khứ, họ hẹn hò từ đầu năm 2002, đính hôn vào tháng 11/2002. Đến năm 2004, họ đường ai nấy đi. Lopez từng trải qua cuộc hôn nhân với Marc Anthony, có 2 con chung.","answer":"\\"Bức tranh tình cảm qua lời kể của cựu người mẫu Ojani Noa về Jennifer Lopez và Ben Affleck\\""},{"question":"Ada 3 sekawan pergi mandi-manda di kolam renang. Tapi lepas mandi, hanya 2 orang yang kepalanya basah. Kenapa yang lagi seorang ni tak basah?","answer":"Botak"},{"question":"Apakah maksud gajah dipandang seperti kuman?","answer":"Maksudnya adalah terlalu marah."},{"question":"請完成以下段落 - 一战中，纽芬兰军队在法国遭受了惨重损失，据估计，在战斗中该岛失去了四分之一的青壮年男子。这使得该岛的经济在战后瀕临崩溃。纽芬兰在1907年獲得自治地位，從英國的紐芬蘭殖民地成立紐芬蘭自治領（連同拉布拉多地區），但之後在第一次世界大戰期間，大量的紐芬蘭人在戰爭中犧牲，加之後來的大蕭條，導致紐芬蘭的經濟出現困難，於是英國在1934年暫停了該地的自治領地位，回退到了英國的殖民地。1948年，紐芬蘭舉行了公民投票","answer":"，通過了併入加拿大的決議。在1949年3月31日，紐芬蘭島連同拉布拉多地區正式加入加拿大聯邦，成為加拿大的第十個省紐芬蘭省（後改為紐芬蘭與拉布拉多省），亦是最後加入加拿大的省份。作为加拿大最年轻的省，以及英國最早的殖民地，纽芬兰在文化上显示出颇为不同的特色。"},{"question":"Đọc văn bản Nắng trưa bồi hồi và trả lời câu hỏi.NẮNG TRƯA BỒI HỒI - Thuỷ ơi! Má đi nha!Giá như mọi hôm, nghe má gọi thế, Thuỷ chỉ cần “dạ” rồi vẫn cắm cúi bên bàn học. Nhưng hôm nay thì không. Em vội vàng đứng lên. Ngoài kia trời nắng quá. Chiếc nón đã cũ chỉ che nổi một bên vai của má. Mấy cánh hoa đã nhạt trên nền vải áo – chiếc áo của chị Hạnh “cho” má – dấp mồ hôi như dán vào lưng má và thẫm hẳn lên.- Má để con dắt xe ra...Khoảng trời trước ngõ vút xanh thẳm. Nắng đổ chang chang. Con đường trải nhựa kẻ thẳng băng, sóng soài không bóng cây. Đã bao nhiêu năm tháng, mỗi ngày hai buổi má đạp xe đi về trên con đường ấy. Sao hôm nay em mới nhận ra?...- Thôi để má. Con vào học đi, không có nắng.Nói rồi, má lên xe. Nắng trưa đổ đầy lưng má. Má còn bảo em vào nhà đi kẻo nắng... Thuỷ thấy nghèn nghẹn ở cổ...Thế mà chiều hôm qua em đã “tức” má, đã cho là má “ghét” em nên cứ hơi một tí là mắng em. Lúc thì tại đưa cái này cho má chậm; lúc thì tìm thứ kia không thấy, cứ như khách ở đâu đến chơi.Chiều hôm qua, nhà có khách. Cô gì ấy, em không hỏi tên, nói là ở Hội Phụ nữ đến hỏi má. Cô ngồi chờ một lúc rồi về. Việc tưởng thế là xong. Em sẽ nói lại cho má biết. Không ngờ...Vừa bước vào nhà, má đã hỏi ngay:- Lúc cô Hoa đến, con làm gì?Em ngạc nhiên:- Cô Hoa nào ạ?- Là cô ở Hội Phụ nữ đến hỏi má ấy!- Má gặp cô rồi ạ?- Phải. Cô ấy chê con đấy. Con đang làm gì?- Con học bài.- Chứ không tiếp khách?- Dạ. Có. Con có mời cô uống nước.- Xong rồi, con lại học tiếp?- Vâng ạ.- Con cũng không hỏi cô đến có việc gì, có nhắn lại gì không?- Dạ không. Cô bảo cô đợi má.- Con cứ để cô ngồi một mình?- Dạ. Con học bài.- Vậy là có con ở nhà cũng như không có ai. Bị chê là phải.Thuỷ thấy má hôm nay “làm sao” ấy.- Thế con phải làm gì ạ?- Con có thể cùng ngồi tiếp chuyện, hỏi xem cô có việc gì nhắn hoặc là trả lời những câu cô hỏi. Ai lại khách đến nhà mà để khách ngồi trơ ra như thế bao giờ.Thuỷ tấm tức, chảy nước mắt:- Nhưng mà... có phải là khách của con đâu mà con biết nói chuyện ạ! Má cứ la con...- Lại còn cãi hả?Má cũng bực và để mặc cho em ngồi khóc, ngồi “tức” má. May quá, tối hôm ấy, ba đi công tác về, má không nói gì em nữa và hình như ba, má có nhắc đến sau bữa cơm. Chắc là... chuyện ấy.Đến tối, lúc chỉ có hai cha con, ba vui vẻ:- Ba con mình nói chuyện một lúc nào!Thuỷ hơi lạ. Ánh mắt của ba cười cười:- Chuyện người lớn. Không phải chuyện trẻ con đâu, con gái của ba ạ.Thuỷ dụi đầu vào vai ba:- Ba!Ba xoa tóc em:- Con có biết, bây giờ con là gì của má con không? Tất nhiên không phải là con trai rồi!- Con... thì con vẫn là con của má aiThuỷ ngỡ ba sắp chê việc tiếp khách mà má đã kể cho ba biết. Em cảm thấy tủi thân. Nhưng mà không, ba lại nói:- Không chỉ là con. Mà còn hơn thế nữa kialEm chưa hiểu và ngước mắt nhìn ba. Ba âu yếm nhìn em:- Bây giờ, nhất là những hôm ba đi vắng, con là chỗ dựa, là trợ lí cho má con rồi đó. Con đã là cô Thuỷ chứ không còn là cô bé Thuỷ, cái bé Thuỷ nữa đâu! Má con...Ánh mắt ba vừa dịu vừa đằm thắm:- Má con vất vả quá. Được hai chị em con, chị Hạnh đã về nhà chồng. Lại vẫn một tay má con chăm lo tất cả. Con đã lớn, má không dựa vào con, con không là chỗ dựa của má, thì còn ai vào đây nữa? Cả với ba nữa ấy. Khi vắng mẹ, con là chỗ dựa của ba đấy!Thật lạ lùng. Em không nghĩ ba lại nói với em những điều như thế. Ba vẫn nhỏ nhẹ gần như thầm thì với riêng em:- Đáng lẽ, ba phải cho con biết điều ấy sớm hơn để con không bị má mắng vì những chuyện lặt vặt. Mọi việc con làm đỡ má hôm nay, thực ra chỉ là sự chuẩn bị cho con mai đây mà thôi. Ở tuổi con như bây giờ, má con cũng bị ngoại con mắng như thế, và đó là việc ngoại dạy dỗ dần cho má con để má con là má của con hôm nay... Chẳng phải là ghét con mà má con mắng con đâu...Ôi, ba! Thuỷ không ngờ. Ba thật là... tình cảm. Ba đã nói “hộ” cho má những điều mà má chưa nói với em...Thì ra... Em không còn bé nữa. Đã có cô, bác là bạn của má nói vui là: “Trông hai má con cứ như hai chị em...”. Như thế là má chưa già. Như thế là em đã lớn.Sáng hôm nay, em nhìn má tất tưởi lo việc nhà, lo cả bữa ăn sáng cho em ăn rồi đi học. Má hình như có gầy yếu, có già hơn dạo em còn bé. Sao điều ấy em không hiểu nhỉ?Nắng trưa gay gắt.Má đang đạp xe trên con đường không bóng cây. Thế mà sao má cứ lo con dắt xe ra cho má bị nắng. Có đứa con nào lại không hiểu được sự chịu đựng đến vô cùng của người mẹ như thế vì cuộc sống, vì gia đình và vì những đứa con?...Thuỷ quay vào nhà. Em định chạy sang nhà Vi chơi một lúc. Em chợt nhìn và thấy vô khối công việc mà má chưa kịp làm...Thuỷ không đi nữa.Nắng trưa sao bồi hồi...Văn bản Nắng trưa bồi hồi viết về đề tài gì?","answer":"Văn bản Nắng trưa bồi hồi viết về đề tài Gia đình"},{"question":"હિંદુ પરંપરા મુજબ લગ્ન શું છે","answer":"વિશ્વભરના દરેક સમાજમાં પુરુષ અને સ્ત્રીના સહજીવનની શરુઆતની વિધિને લગ્ન (અંગ્રેજી: Marriage) ઓળખવામાં આવે છે. લગ્નપ્રથા આદિકાળથી ચાલતી આવી છે, જેમાં જ્ઞાતિમાં કે આંતરજ્ઞાતિય લગ્નો થાય છે. લગ્ન એ સમાજનું એક અંગ છે અને આધુનિક વિચારકો લગ્નને એક સંસ્થાન તરીકે ગણાવે છે.હિંદુ પરંપરા મુજબ લગ્નને વિવાહ સંસ્કાર કહેવામાં આવે છે, જે વ્યક્તિને એના જીવનમાં આપવામાં આવતા સોળ સંસ્કારો પૈકીનો એક સંસ્કાર છે. લગ્ન પછીના સહજીવનમાં સ્ત્રી જે પુરુષ સાથે વિવાહ સંસ્કારથી જોડાઈ હોય એની પત્ની અને પુરુષ જે સ્ત્રી સાથે વિવાહ સંસ્કારથી જોડાયો હોય એના પતિ તરીકે ઓળખાય છે."},{"question":"Мага кызыктуу факты жазып берчи ?","answer":"Албетте , мына сизге кызыктуу факты :705-жылдан бери  иштеп келе жаткан дүйнөдөгү эң эски мейманкана Япониянын Яманаши шаарындагы Nishiyama Onsen Keiunkan мейманканасы дүйнөдөгү эң эски мейманкананын Гиннес китебине кирет. Укмуштуудай Акайши тоолорунун этегинде жайгашкан бул ысык булак Фудзивара Махито негизделгенден бери 705-жылы иштеп келген.  Андан бери, ал 1300 жылдан ашуун убакыттан бери бир эле үй-бүлөнүн 52 муунунун колунда болгон."},{"question":"காட்டு விலங்குகள் என்ன","answer":"புலி, சிறுத்தை, யானை, சிறுத்தை,துருவ கரடி முதலியன..."},{"question":"fenoy ny banga :\\"Aleo mifanalavitra mifamono akoho toy izay _\\"","answer":"\\"mifanakaiky mifamono aliaka\\""},{"question":"Жарым арал деген эмне ?","answer":"Жарым арал-кургактыктын океанга, деңизге, көлгө же чоң дарыяларга кирип турган бөлүгү; үч тарабы суулар менен чулганып турат."},{"question":"Ọ bụ maka nfanyeaka n'ụkwụ ndị nkuzi  n'ihi ụgwọ ọnwa iri ha sị na gọọmentị ji ha nakwa ihe ndị ọzọ.Onyeisi otu jikọrọ ndị ọrụ n'Abia bụ Uchenna Obigwe kwuru na gọọmentị ekwela ndị nkuzi nkwa ịkwụ ụgwọ ọnwa abụọ.Mana nkwa a emeghị ka ndị nkuzi laghachị n'ụlọakwụkwọ dịka ụfọdụ ha ka na-ewe iwe banyere nke a.Onyeisi ndị nkuzi n'Aba-North bụ Njoku C.C gwara BBC Igbo na o nweela ndị nkụzi natarala ụgwọ ọnwa abụọ, ụfọdụ ọnwa atọ.Mana ndị nkuzi gbaa gburugburu anabataghị ụgwọ ọnwa atọ gọọmentị chọrọ ịkwụ n'ime ọnwa iri e ji ha n'ụgwọ.Ntụliakaelu Gọvanọ: Anyị akwụchala ndịọrụ ụgwọ ha - Ikpeazụ Njoku kwuru na ha na gọọmentị zutere mana ndị nkuzi Abia Steeti gbaa gburugburu ekweghi na mpụtara mkparịtaụka ahụ.Kedụ ihe bụ iwe ndị nkuzi a?Njoku C.C sị na ihe ndị nkuzi chọrọ ka gọọmentị Abia Steeti mee tupu ha amalite ọrụ gụnyere;1. Ịkwụcha ndị nkuzi ụgwọ ọnwa iri eji ha2. Ịkwụ ndị nkuzi ụgwọ ezumike ọrụ akpọrọ 'Leave Allowance'3. Ịkwụ ndị nkuzi ụgwọ mbuli n'ọkwa bụ 'Salary Upgrade'4. Ịkwụ ndị nkuzi Praịmarị ụgwọ 'Teachers Salary Subsidy'.Otu onye nkuzi Sekọndịrị bụ Anusionwu O. gwara BBC Igbo na akwụghị ụgwọ ọnwa metụtara ya n'ụzọ dị iche iche.Nke bụ na ego eji elekọta ezinaụlọ adịghị, na mgbe ụfọdụ, ọ na-abọrọ ndị mmadụ ahịhịa, buoro ndị mmadụ ibu iji hụ ihe a na-eri. Mbọ niile BBC Igbo gbara inweta gọọmentị Abia Steeti site n'aka onye enyemaka mgbasaozi gọvanọ bụ Onyebuchi Ememanka amịtaghị mkpụrụ.Dịka na ọ zaghị ekwentị ya n'oge a kpọrọ ya.Akụkọ ndị ga-amasị gị:Nye m ezigbo isiokwu maka ederede dị n'elu.","answer":"Nfanyeaka N'ụkwụ Ndị Nkụzi Abịa: Ụgwọ gọometị ji anyị karịrị akarị"},{"question":"Berikan jawapan kepada soalan yang rumit ini: Pasukan manakah yang saudara kembar Horace Grant ditukar kepada selepas musim 1992-1993 dalam Washington Bullets?","answer":"Portland Trail Blazers"},{"question":"శ్మశానంలోని అభేద భావాన్ని తెలపండి.","answer":"శ్మశానవాటి అంటే మన జీవితంలో ఉండే అంటరానితనం వంటి దురాచారాలకి తావులేని ప్రదేశం. ఇక్కడ విష్ణువు తన కపట లీలలతో ప్రాణాలు తీసి, మట్టిపాలు , చేస్తాడు. క్రూరమైన, మధించిన పెద్దపులిని, బలహీనమైన సాధుజీవియైన మేకను పక్కపక్కనే పెట్టి జోలపాట పాడతాడు. సామాజిక అసమానతలకు, హెచ్చుతగ్గులకు, వివక్షలకు, పీడనలకు, ఆధిక్య, అనాధిక్య భావనలకు తావులేని ప్రదేశం. అందరినీ అభేదంగా (సమానంగా) అక్కున చేర్చుకునే నిశ్చల స్థలం అని కవి పేర్కొన్నాడు."},{"question":"アラビア語では「イフタフ・ヤー・シムシム」、英語では「オープン・セサミ」というアラビアンナイトに出てくる呪文は何でしょう？","answer":"開けゴマです。"},{"question":"కింది ప్రశ్నకు సమాధానం ఇవ్వండినైట్రోజన్ ద్విపరమాణుక అణువుగాను, ఫాస్ఫరస్ P4గాను ఉంటాయి. ఎందువల్ల?","answer":"నైట్రోజన్ ద్విపరమాణుక అణువు :నైట్రోజన్ తక్కువ పరమాణు పరిమాణం మరియు అధిక ఋణ విద్యుదాత్మకత కలిగిన మూలకం. నైట్రోజన్ పరమాణువు Pπ – Pπ బహు బంధాలను ఏర్పరచును (త్రికబంధం). కావున అది ద్విపరమాణుక అణువుగా ఉంటుంది.ఫాస్పరస్ P4 అణువు :ఫాస్ఫరస్ ఎక్కువ పరమాణు పరిమాణం మరియు తక్కువ ఋణ విద్యుదాత్మకత కలిగి ఉండును. ఫాస్ఫరస్ P-P ఏకబంధాలను ఏర్పరచును. కావున P4 గా ఉంటుంది."},{"question":"V1 V2 V3 ne demek?","answer":"Örneğin geniş zamanda fiilin birinci hali (V1), -di'li geçmiş zamanda (past tense) ikinci hali (V2) ve present perfect tense'de fiilin üçüncü hali (V3) kullanılmalıdır. Bu açıdan düzenli ve düzensiz fiiler arasında bir fark yoktur."},{"question":"Tá mé ag méadú meáchain agus ba mhaith liom tosú ag cleachtadh.  Conas ba chóir dommo thuras meáchain caillteanas a thosú? ","answer":"Tá mé an-sásta go bhfuil tú ag déanamh céim sa treo ceart. D'fhéadfá tosú le cúpla míle a siúl gach lá. Chomh maith leis sin, tá damhsa agus siúlóid ina roinnt smaointe éadrom.Molaim duit rianóir cleachtaíochta a fháil agus do ghníomhaíochtaí a rianú. Nuair a fhaigheann tú bunlíne, is féidir liom cabhrú leat a fháil amach cé mhéad calraí a chaithfidh tú a dhó gach lá chun fanacht sláintiúil. Is féidir leat tosú ag rianú do chalarí a dhó agus do spriocanna sláinte. "},{"question":"USUMENYEZELWE-KE UMCEBO – MJ MngadiFundisisa lesi siqeshana senoveli bese uphendula imibuzo elandelayo.Ephephandabeni lwangoLwesine ekuseni waphuma umbiko uhambisana nezithombengoMbhishobhu oNgcwele uChule enweshulwa yizinja. Nakuba waba ngelikhuluigidigidi lehlaya kwabaningi, kepha abanye bebandla ayewumshumayeli kulo bawothaubomvu. Indaba yasha kakhulu ngeSonto ekuseni, khona emagcekeni esonto eMlazi.Ingakakhali insimbi bahlanganisa amakhanda abashumayeli bevutha bhe. Yebobabevutha abanye, kodwa hhayi njengoMasondo noLuthuli, uXaba noNdabanoMdunge. Babesigxeka isenzo sikaChule, beshoshozela ukuba ajeziswengokunqunywa ekushumayeleni.'Lo muntu uyingozi enkulu lapha ebandleni. Leli phekulazikhuni lihlezi nje lihloseukuqembula ibandla ukuze liyovula elalo. Uma siphetha inkonzo namuhla akuxoshweizingane, lithethwe yibandla lonke icala lakhe, achaze ngala manga aluhlaza okuthiuwumbhishobhi.''Yizwi lelo,' bevumelana.'Akuphakanyiswe kumfundisi ophethe ukuthi akehliswe esikhundleni, emukwe nalelijazi awakana ngalo,' kuvevezela amadevu kuMadlanduna.Insimbi yesonto yanqenqetha, wayibamba intshumayelo uMadlanduna owayekhulumakunyakama ubuso, ebila, elokhu ethi ngenhliziyo Chule uyangena, uyangena, do.Ekuphethweni kwenkonzo izingane zaxoshwa, udaba lwadingidwa. Bavumelanangokuba ngeSonto elilandelayo kucelwe umfundisi ukuba abekhona, noChuleazoziphendulela.Laqala-ke isonto nezakhe uChule owayeqedelwa nayisithombe sephephandabaejanduza phansi eshikashikwa yizinja. Isamudla indaba, ezivalele ehhovisi esitolo,wavakashelwa womunye wabazalwane owayethi akacele kuye ngeminyaka, uMnu.Sayimoni Gubhela. UGubhela wayekhona ngesikhathi ibandla libhoka likhahlelangendaba yaseThusini, nokho yena ewuhlabe inhlali. Wamkhinikela ukusuka nokuhlalangogobe ayeboshelwe lona, nokuthi obhongoza wobani nobani. Wadalula nokuthinjengoba uhlelo lwalukhomba ukuthi uyena uChule owayezoshumayela ngesontoelalilandela, umbimbi lwalubophe ukungahlabeleli lungenakuguqa nalapho esethimakuthandazwe. UGubhela owabongwa ngebhodlela lebhrendi wamshiya uChuleehlezi elusizana ebambelele esihlathini. Side isikhathi asihlala kanje edla amathamboekhanda. Ekugcineni walinikina, wasukuma ehleka yedwa. Kusukela ngaleso sikhathiimoto emnyama ayibange isaphunyuzwa. Yashaya phansi phezulu. UChule esehambanoSithole bezivivinyela ukuchitha imicibisholo yoMasondo.Akuvumelekile ukukopisha leli phepha Pheqa ikhasiNgamunye ngamunye ubhongoza uChule wamthinta kusihlwa ngocingo. WaqalangoMasondo, wazishaya izinombolo kwakhala kwakhe. 'Nqol' emasondosondo!'Babingelelana kuzwakala ukuthi uMasondo akazimisele ukukhuluma naye. 'Uxolokancane nje Masondo, ngithi ake sithi ukuhleba mzalwane ngokuhlwa nje.''Hhayi Chule,' Enikina ikhanda ngale, 'Awahlebi amakholwa. Ukhulumelani namingingedwa ibandla likhona?''Kanti kuyaye kube kuhle mzalwane uma amadoda engundaza ezawo zangasesengasese kungaze kuzwe omame. Ake sihlebe-ke Sondo elihle. Mhlawumbe lokhuengizokusho kuyihlazwana okungebe kuhle uma elizwa umama,' ekhulumela phansi.'Mina ngithanda izinto sizenze ngesizotha, sihlonipheke, sizihloniphe nathi. Akufanelesihlambalazane esidlangalaleni.'1. Ngabe ukusetshenziswa komlingiswa onguMahuzu kuyithuthukise kanjaniindikimba yomcebo kule noveli? Sekela impendulo yakho.2. Uyavumelana yini nombono wokuthi umculo womlingiswa onguGenyezawasiguqula isimo senhlalo sakwaChule? Sekela impendulo yakho. 3.  Xoxa ngempumelelo yombhali yokwethula isingeniso kule noveli.","answer":"1. Ukusetshenziswa kukaMahuzu kuyithuthukise kahle indikimba yomcebo.UMahuzu uvuma ukusetshenziswa ngunina uMaHadebe ukuze naye azotholaumcebo kaNomvula ngokuthi abuye eGoli aye eThekwini ayofuna uNomvulaukuze amdlise umuthi ukuze ahlomule naye kulo mcebo.2. Ngiyavumelana ngoba wathi uma esephumelela emculweni, umculo wakhewawulokhu uzwakala emsakazweni nakumabonakude. Lokhu kwashintshaisimo senhlalo kwaChule bahlala ngokuxabana kwaholela ekutheni uChuleabe nesikhwele agcine esola uNomvula ngokuthi usathanda uGenyezanjengoba ayelalela izingoma zakhe futhi embuka nakumabonakude3. Umbhali uphumelele kahle ukwethula isingeniso sale noveli ngobaumlingiswa omkhulu uMirriam uyethulwa. Uwina imali eningi, uphumanasemaphephandabeni aseThekwini eThusini lokhu okuba yisisusasodweshu."},{"question":"ما هي أكثر دول العالم انتاجا للفول السوداني ؟","answer":"الهند."},{"question":"Ndeipi yaive hit yakakurumbira yeTroggs?","answer":"The Troggs, boka reBritish rock kubva kuma1960, rinonyanya kuzivikanwa nenziyo yavo ye \\"Wild Thing.\\" Yakabudiswa muna 1966, \\"Wild Thing\\" yakava rwiyo rwedombo uye rwiyo runotsanangura rwenguva. Mumhanzi waro wakapfava uye unotapukira, pamwe chete nenziyo dzawo dzinokurudzira, zvakaikurudzira kuti ive imwe yenziyo dzeTroggs dzinozivikanwa uye dzinogara kwenguva refu.\\"Chinhu Chemusango\\" chakaratidza ruzha rweTroggs 'yakasvibirira uye ine simba, inoratidzirwa neanotungamira Reg Presley's distinctive vocals. Kufarirwa kwerwiyo kwakagara kwemakore, uye inoramba iri yemhando yepamusoro yedombo."},{"question":"ਰਾਜ ਕਪੂਰ ਕੌਣ ਹੈ?","answer":"ਰਾਜ ਕਪੂਰ (ਹਿੰਦੀ: राज कपूर), (راج کپور ਉਰਦੂ/ਸ਼ਾਹਮੁਖੀ), (14 ਦਸੰਬਰ 1924 – 2 ਜੂਨ 1988) ਪ੍ਰਸਿੱਧ ਅਭਿਨੇਤਾ, ਨਿਰਮਾਤਾ ਅਤੇ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਨਿਰਦੇਸ਼ਕ ਸਨ। ਨਹਿਰੂਵਾਦੀ ਸਮਾਜਵਾਦ ਤੋਂ ਪ੍ਰੇਰਿਤ ਆਪਣੀਆਂ ਸ਼ੁਰੁਆਤੀ ਫਿਲਮਾਂ ਤੋਂ ਲੈ ਕੇ ਪ੍ਰਭਾਵਸ਼ਾਲੀ ਪ੍ਰੇਮ ਕਹਾਣੀਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਪਰਦੇ ਉੱਤੇ ਪੇਸ਼ ਕਰਕੇ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਹਿੰਦੁਸਤਾਨੀ ਫਿਲਮ ਜਗਤ ਵਿੱਚ ਯਾਦਗਾਰੀ ਪੈੜਾਂ ਛੱਡੀਆਂ। ਭਾਰਤ ਵਿੱਚ ਉਹ ਆਪਣੇ ਸਮੇਂ ਦੇ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਵੱਡੇ ਸ਼ੋਮੈਨ ਸਨ।  ਸੋਵੀਅਤ ਯੂਨੀਅਨ ਅਤੇ ਮਧ-ਪੂਰਬ ਵਿੱਚ ਰਾਜ ਕਪੂਰ ਦੀ ਲੋਕਪ੍ਰਿਅਤਾ ਦੰਦਕਥਾ ਬਣ ਚੁੱਕੀ ਹੈ। ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਭਾਰਤ ਵਿੱਚ ਨੌਂ ਫਿਲਮ ਫੇਅਰ ਅਵਾਰਡ ਜਿੱਤੇ ਅਤੇ ਦੋ ਫਿਲਮਾਂ ਅਵਾਰਾ ਅਤੇ ਬੂਟ ਪਾਲਿਸ਼ ਕੈਨਜ ਫਿਲਮ ਫੈਸਟੀਵਲ ਲਈ ਨਾਮਜਦ ਹੋਈਆਂ।ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਫਿਲਮਾਂ (ਖਾਸਕਰ ਸ਼੍ਰੀ 420) ਵਿੱਚ ਬੰਬਈ ਦੀ ਜੋ ਮੂਲ ਤਸਵੀਰ ਪੇਸ਼ ਕੀਤੀ ਗਈ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਫਿਲਮ ਨਿਰਮਾਤਾਵਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਅਜੇ ਵੀ ਆਕਰਸ਼ਤ ਕਰਦੀ ਹੈ। ਰਾਜ ਕਪੂਰ ਦੀਆਂ ਫਿਲਮਾਂ ਦੀਆਂ ਕਹਾਣੀਆਂ ਆਮ ਤੌਰ ਤੇ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਜੀਵਨ ਨਾਲ ਜੁਡ਼ੀਆਂ ਹੁੰਦੀਆਂ ਸਨ ਅਤੇ ਆਪਣੀ ਜਿਆਦਾਤਰ ਫਿਲਮਾਂ ਦੇ ਮੁੱਖ ਅਦਾਕਾਰ ਵੀ ਉਹ ਖੁਦ ਆਪ ਹੀ ਹੁੰਦੇ ਸਨ।ਕਪੂਰ ਨੂੰ ਭਾਰਤੀ ਸਿਨੇਮਾ ਦੇ ਇਤਿਹਾਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਮਹਾਨ ਅਤੇ ਸਭਤੋਂ ਵੱਧ ਪ੍ਭਾਵਸ਼ਾਲੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਨਿਰਮਾਤਾਵਾਂ ਅਤੇ ਅਭਿਨੇਤਾਵਾਂ ਵਿੱਚੋ ਇੱਕ ਸਮਝਿਆ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ I ਉਹ ਭਾਰਤ ਵਿੱਚ ਕਈ ਅਵਾਰਡਾਂ ਦੇ ਜੇਤੂ ਸਨ, ਜਿਸ ਵਿੱਚ 3 ਨੈਸ਼ਨਲ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਅਵਾਰਡ ਅਤੇ 11 ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਫ਼ੇਅਰ ਅਵਾਰਡ ਸ਼ਾਮਲ ਸਨ I ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਫ਼ੇਅਰ ਲਾਈਫਟਾਇਮ ਐਚੀਵਮੈਂਟ ਅਵਾਰਡ ਰਾਜ ਕਪੂਰ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਤੇ ਹੀ ਰਖਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ I ਉਹ ਕਾਨਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਸਮਾਰੋਹ ਵਿੱਚ ਆਪਣੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਅਵਾਰਾ (1951) ਅਤੇ ਬੂਟ ਪਾਲਿਸ਼ (1954) ਲਈ ਦੋ ਬਾਰ ਪਾਮ ਡਿ’ਓਰ ਗ੍ਰੈੰਡ ਪੁਰਸਕਾਰ ਲਈ ਨਾਮਜ਼ਦ ਵੀ ਕੀਤੇ ਗਏ I ਅਵਾਰਾ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਵਿੱਚ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਕਾਰਗੁਜ਼ਾਰੀ ਨੂੰ ਦੇਖਦਿਆਂ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਟਾਇਮਸ ਮੈਗਜ਼ੀਨ ਦੁਆਰਾ ਚੋਟੀ ਦੇ ਦਸ ਮਹਾਨ ਪ੍ਰਦਰਸ਼ਨਾਂ ਵਿੱਚੋ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਸਥਾਨ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਗਿਆ Iਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ਨੇ ਦੁਨਿਆ ਭਰ ਦੇ ਦਰਸ਼ਕਾਂ ਦਾ ਧਿਆਨ ਆਪਣੇ ਵਲ ਖਿਚਿਆ, ਜਿਹਨਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਖਾਸ ਤੌਰ ਤੇ ਏਸ਼ੀਆ ਅਤੇ ਯੂਰਪ ਦੇ ਦਰਸ਼ਕਾਂ ਸ਼ਾਮਲ ਸਨ I   ਉਹਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਭਾਰਤੀਯ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਇੰਡਸਟਰੀ ਦਾ ਕਲਾਰਕ ਗੈਬਲ ਬੁਲਾਇਆ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਸੀ Iਸਾਲ 1971 ਵਿੱਚ ਕਲਾ ਦੇ ਖੇਤਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਯੋਗਦਾਨ ਲਈ, ਉਹਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਭਾਰਤ ਸਰਕਾਰ ਵੱਲੋਂ ਪਦਮ ਭੁਸ਼ਨ ਨਾਲ ਸਨਮਾਨਿਤ ਕੀਤਾ ਗਿਆ I ਭਾਰਤ ਸਰਕਾਰ ਨੇ ਸਾਲ 1987 ਵਿੱਚ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਭਾਰਤੀ ਸਿਨੇਮਾ ਦੇ ਸਭਤੋਂ ਵੱਡੇ ਅਵਾਰਡ ਦਾਦਾ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਫ਼ਾਲਕੇ ਅਵਾਰਡ ਪ੍ਦਾਨ ਕੀਤਾ I== ਸ਼ੁਰੂਆਤੀ ਜ਼ਿੰਦਗੀ ਅਤੇ ਪਿਠਭੂਮੀ ==ਰਾਜ ਕਪੂਰ ਦਾ ਜਨਮ ਪੇਸ਼ਾਵਰ ਦੇ ਕਿੱਸਾ ਖਾਨਵੀ ਬਜ਼ਾਰ ਦੇ ਨੇੜੇ ਢਾਕਿ ਮੁਨਾਵੱਵਰ ਸ਼ਾਹ (ਜੋ ਉਸ ਵੇਲੇ ਭਾਰਤ ਵਿੱਚ ਸੀ ਅਤੇ ਆਧੁਨਿਕ ਦਿਨਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਪਖਤੂਨਖਵਾ, ਪਾਕਿਸਤਾਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਹੈ) ਵਿੱਚ ਇੱਕ ਪੰਜਾਬੀ ਹਿੰਦੂ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਹੋਇਆ I ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਪਿਤਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਂ ਪਿ੍ਰਥਵੀਰਾਜ ਕਪੂਰ ਸੀ ਅਤੇ ਮਾਤਾ ਰਾਮਸਰਨੀ ਦੇਵੀ ਕਪੂਰ ਸਨ I ਉਹ ਆਪਣੇ 6 ਭੈਣ ਭਰਾਵਾਂ ਵਿੱਚੋ ਸਭਤੋਂ ਵੱਡੇ ਸਨ I[ ਉਹ ਦੀਵਾਨ ਭਾਸ਼ੇਸ਼ਵਰਨਾਥ ਕਪੂਰ ਦੇ ਪੋਤੇ ਅਤੇ ਦੀਵਾਨ ਕੇਸ਼ਾਵਮਲ ਕਪੂਰ ਦੇ ਪੜਪੋਤੇ ਸਨ, ਜੋਕਿ ਮਸ਼ਹੂਰ ਕਪੂਰ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਦੇ ਹਿੱਸੇ ਸਨ I ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਭਰਾ ਅਭਿਨੇਤਾ ਸ਼ਸ਼ੀ ਕਪੂਰ ਅਤੇ ਸਵਰਗਵਾਸੀ ਸ਼ਮੀ ਕਪੂਰ ਹਨ I ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਇੱਕ ਭੈਣ ਵੀ ਸੀ ਜਿਸਦਾ ਨਾਂ ਉਰਮਿਲਾ ਸਿਆਲ ਸੀ I ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਦੋ ਭੈਣ- ਭਰਾ ਬਚਪਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਹੀ ਚੱਲ ਵਸੇ I ਫਿਰ ਬਾਅਦ ਵਿੱਚ ਉਹ ਪੇਸ਼ਾਵਰ ਨੂੰ ਛੱਡਕੇ, ਨਿਵਾਸ ਅਤੇ ਸਿਖਿਆ ਲਈ ਮੌਜੂਦਾ ਭਾਰਤ ਵਿੱਚ ਆ ਗਏ Iਰਾਜ ਕਪੂਰ ਨੇ 1930 ਦੇ ਦਸ਼ਕ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੇਹਰਾਦੂਨ ਦੇ ਕੌਲੋਨਿਲ ਬਰਾਉਨ ਕੈਮਬ੍ਰਿਜ ਸਕੂਲ  ਤੋਂ ਅਤੇ ਸੇਂਟ ਜ਼ੈਵਿਅਰ ਕਾਲਜੀਏਟ ਸਕੂਲ  ਤੋਂ ਸਿਖਿਆ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਕੀਤੀ I== ਕਰੀਅਰ ==ਦਸ ਸਾਲ ਦੀ ਉਮਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਉਹ ਪਹਿਲੀ ਵਾਰ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਵਿੱਚ ਨਜ਼ਰ ਆਏ I ਉਹਨਾਂ ਨੇ ਸਾਲ 1935 ਵਿੱਚ ਆਈ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਇੰਕਲਾਬ ਕੰਮ ਕੀਤਾ I ਅਗਲੇ 12 ਸਾਲਾਂ ਤੱਕ ਕਈ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਕੰਮ ਕਰਨ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਰਾਜ ਕਪੂਰ ਨੂੰ  ਪਹਿਲੀ ਵਾਰ ਮੁੱਖ ਭੁਮਿਕਾ ਨਿਭਾਉਣ ਦਾ ਮੌਕਾ, ਸਾਲ 1947 ਵਿੱਚ ਆਈ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਨੀਲ ਕਮਲ ਵਿੱਚ ਮਧੁਬਾਲਾ ਨਾਲ (ਜੋਕਿ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਨਾਲ ਮੁੱਖ ਭੁਮਿਕਾ ਵਿੱਚ ਸੀ) ਮਿਲਿਆ I ਸਾਲ 1948 ਵਿੱਚ, 24 ਸਾਲ ਦੀ ਉਮਰ ਵਿੱਚ, ਉਹਨਾਂ ਨੇ ਆਰ. ਕੇ. ਫ਼ਿਲਮਸ ਨਾਂ ਦਾ ਆਪਣਾ ਸਟੁਡਿਓ ਸਥਾਪਿਤ ਕਰਕੇ ਉਹ ਆਪਣੇ ਸਮੇਂ ਦੇ ਸਭਤੋਂ ਘੱਟ ਉਮਰ ਵਾਲੇ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਨਿਰਦੇਸ਼ਕ ਬਣ ਗਏ ਜਿਸਨੇ ਸ਼ੁਰੂਆਤੀ ਨਿਰਦੇਸ਼ਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਅੱਗ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਵਿੱਚ ਨਰਗਿਸ, ਕਾਮੀਨੀ, ਕੌਸ਼ਲ ਅਤੇ ਪ੍ਰੇਮਨਾਥ ਦੇ ਨਾਲ ਨਾਲ ਆਪ ਵੀ ਅਭਿਨੇ ਕੀਤਾ I == ਇਹ ਵੀ ਵੇਖੋ ==ਅਵਾਰਾਬਰਸਾਤ== ਬਾਹਰਲੇ ਲਿੰਕ ==12 Indians who are famous in RussiaThe Raj Kapoor Fan Club Archived 2022-04-09 at the Wayback Machine.The Kapoor Family Site== ਹਵਾਲੇ =="},{"question":"Rehefa mampiasa ahy ianao dia manapaka ahy, ary raha mijery ahy ianao dia mitsiky amiko. Inona moa aho?","answer":"Valiny : Fitaratra - Rehefa mijery fitaratra dia mitsiky mahita ny tena eo aminy."},{"question":"Qual é a capital da Suécia?","answer":"Estocolmo."},{"question":"¿Dónde se encuentra el corazón en el cuerpo humano?","answer":"El corazón se encuentra en la cavidad torácica, ligeramente inclinado hacia la izquierda, detrás del esternón y entre los pulmones. Es un órgano musculoso que bombea sangre a través del sistema circulatorio, suministrando oxígeno y nutrientes a todas las células del cuerpo."},{"question":"Ano ang divide-and-conquer algorithm?","answer":"Ang divide-and-conquer algorithm sa larangan ng data structures ay isang uri ng algorithm na hinahati ang isang problem upang ito ay maging \\"sub-problems\\", hinahanap ang solusyon ng bawat subproblem, at pinagsasama-sama ang mga solusyo upang makuha ang final na solusyon sa kabuuang problem. Binubuo ito ng sumusunod na tatlong hakbang:1. Divide2. Solve3. Combine"},{"question":"எந்த வைட்டமின் குறைபாட்டால் இரவு குருட்டுத்தன்மை ஏற்படுகிறது?","answer":"வைட்டமின் ஏ குறைபாடு காரணமாக இரவு குருட்டுத்தன்மை ஏற்படுகிறது."},{"question":"Which Game of Thrones character is known as the Young Wolf?","answer":"Robb Stark"},{"question":"சிறுகதை : அறிவு உயிரைக் காப்பாற்றும்","answer":"வீமபுரி என்ற நாட்டை வீரகேசரி என்ற மன்னன் ஆண்டு வந்தான். அவன் நீதியும், நேர்மையும் தவறாமல் ஆட்சி செய்து வந்ததால் அவன் நாட்டு மக்கள் பயமும் கவலையும் இன்றி மகிழ்ச்சியாக வாழ்ந்து வந்தார்கள்.அந்த அரசன் தன்னாட்டு மக்களின் செயல்களை கண்காணிக்க மாறுவேடம் அணிந்து செல்வது வழக்கம். அவ்வாறு அவன் மாறுவேடம் அணிந்து செல்லும்போது வழியில் உழவன் ஒருவன் வயலில் உழுது கொண்டிருப்பதை பார்த்தான். அவனைக் கண்ட மாறு வேடத்தில் இருந்த அரசன், “எல்லாம் வல்ல இறைவன் உனக்கு நல்ல வலிமையையும், நீண்ட வாழ்நாளையும் வழங்குவானாக” என்று வாழ்த்தினான். அதற்கு அந்த உழவன் மாறுவேடத்தில் இருந்த அரசனைப் பார்த்து, “தாங்கள் என்மீது காட்டும் அன்பிர்க்கு மிக்க நன்றி” என்றான். “நிலத்தில் எவ்வளவு வருமானம் கிடைக்கிறது?” என்று மாறுவேடத்தில் இருந்த அரசன் அந்த உழவனிடம் கேட்டான். அதற்கு உழவன், “மாதத்திற்கு நூறு வெள்ளி காசுகள் கிடைக்கின்றன” என்று பதில் அளித்தான். “அவ்வளவு தொகையை என்ன செய்கிறாய்?” என்று அரசன் கேட்டான். “ஐந்தில் ஒரு பங்கை அரசனுக்கு வரியாக செலுத்துகிறேன். இன்னொரு பங்கை நான் பட்ட கடனுக்கு அடைகிறேன். மற்றொரு பங்கை கடனாக தருகிறேன். நான்காவது பங்கை வீசி ஏறிகிறேன். இறுதிப் பங்கை எனக்காக செலவு செய்கிறேன்” என்று புதிராக பேசினான்.இதை கேட்ட மாறுவேடத்தில் இருந்த அரசனுக்கு ஒன்றுமே புரியவில்லை. தன் மாறுவேடத்தை   கலைத்தான். இதுவரை தன்னிடம் பேசியவர் அரசர் தான் என்பதை அறிந்த உழவன் அவரை பணிவுடன் வணங்கினான்.“நீ சொன்ன பதிலில் வரியாக தருவதும், உனக்காக செலவு செய்வதும்தான், எனக்கு புரிந்தது. மற்றவற்றின் அர்த்தம் என்ன?” என்று கேட்டான் அரசன். அதற்கு உழவன் அரசே, “என் வருமானத்தில் ஒரு பங்கை என் தாய் தந்தையருக்கு செலவு செய்கிறேன். என்னை வளர்த்து ஆளாக்கிய அவர்களுக்கு செலவு செய்வதை கடனுக்கு அடைகிறேன் என்றேன்.இன்னொரு பங்கை என் மகனுக்கு செலவு செய்கிறேன். பிற்காலத்தில் என்னை காப்பாற்ற போகிறவன் அவன். அதனால், அதை கடனாக தருகிறேன் என்றேன். நான்காவது பங்கை என் மகளுக்கு செலவு செய்கிறேன். எப்படி இருந்தாலும் திருமணம் ஆகி இன்னொருவன் வீட்டில் வாழ வேண்டியவள். அதனால் அந்த செலவை வீணாகத் தெருவில் எறிகிறேன் என்றேன். அந்த  உழவனின் பதிலை கேட்டு மகிழ்ந்த அரசன். உன் அறிவு கூர்மை மிகவும் நன்றாக உள்ளது. “இந்த விளக்கத்தை நான் இல்லாமல் நீ யாரிடமும் கூறக்கூடாது. அப்படி கூறினால் உன் உடலில் உயிர் இருக்காது” என்று சொல்லிவிட்டு சென்றான். அரசவைக்கு வந்த அரசன் தான் கேட்ட புதிரை அனைவரிடமும் சொல்லி அதற்கு விளக்கம் கேட்டான். ஒருவராலும் அதற்கு விளக்கம் கூற முடியவில்லை. இந்த புதிருக்கு யார் விளக்கம் கூறினாலும் அவருக்கு ஆயிரம் பொற்காசுகள் பரிசாக வழங்கப்படும், என்று அறிவித்தான் அரசன். அரசனுக்கு இந்த புதிரை கூறியவர் யார் என்பதை அறிந்து கொண்டான் அமைச்சர்களுள் ஒருவன். அந்த அமைச்சர் நேராக இந்த உழவனிடம் சென்றான். “அரசு நாணய சாலையில் புத்தம் புதிதாக அச்சடித்த இந்த ஐநூறு பொற்காசுகளை பெற்றுக்கொண்டு அரசரிடம் சொன்ன புதிருக்கான விளக்கத்தை என்னிடம் கூறு” என்றான் அமைச்சர். கண்ணை பறிக்கும் ஒளியுடன் கூடிய பொற்காசுகளை கண்ட உழவன் அரசரை எப்படியும் சமாளித்துக் கொள்ளலாம் என்று எண்ணி அந்த புதருக்கான விளக்கத்தை கூறி பொற்காசுகளை பெற்றுக் கொண்டான்.அரண்மனை திரும்பிய அமைச்சர் நேரடியாக அரசிடம் சென்று புதிருக்கான விளக்கத்தை கூறினான். உழவன் தான் பதில் கூறி இருக்கிறான் என்பதை அரசன் அறிந்து கொண்டு, அவனை இழுத்து வருமாறு தன்னுடைய காவலர்களுக்கு ஆணையிட்டான்.அரசவைக்கு இழுத்து வரப்பட்ட உழவனை பார்த்து, “உனக்கு என்ன திமிரு? நான் இல்லாமல் யாரிடமும் அந்த புதிருக்கான விளக்கத்தை சொல்லக்கூடாது. சொன்னால் உன் உயிர் போய்விடும் என்று உனக்கு நான் கட்டளையிட்டிருந்தேன். என் கட்டளையை மீறி சொல்லி இருக்கிறாய், உன் உயிரை இப்பொழுது யார் காப்பாற்றப் போகிறார் என்று பார்ப்போம்” என்று கோபத்துடன் கேட்டான் அரசன். அதற்கு அந்த உழவன் அரசனைப் பார்த்து, “அரசே, நான் சொல்வதைக் கேளுங்கள். என் மீது எந்த தவறும் இல்லை என்று பணிவாக கூறினான்,” உழவன். அதற்கு அரசன், “நான் இல்லாமல் யாரிடமும் இந்த புதிருக்கான பதில் சொல்லக்கூடாது என்றேன் அல்லவா?” என்று கத்தினான். உடனே அமைச்சர் எடுத்து கொடுத்த பொற்காசுகளை அரசனிடம் காட்டிய உழவன், “இந்த பொற்காசுகளில் ஒரு பக்கத்தில் தங்கள் உருவம் பொறிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. இதை பார்த்து தான் அமைச்சரிடம் பதில் கூறினேன். எனவே தங்களை வைத்துக் கொண்டுதான் நான் விளக்கம் கூறினேன். தங்கள் கட்டளையை நான் எந்த வகையிலும் மீறவில்லை” என்று கூறினான். உழவனின் அறிவு கூர்மையை  அறிந்த அரசன் அவனுக்கு பரிசுகள் பல தந்து அனுப்பி வைத்தான். உழவனின் உயிரை தக்க சமயத்தில் காப்பாற்றியது அவருடைய அறிவு கூர்மையே ஆகும். நீதி : ஒருவரிடம் இருக்கும் அறிவு மிக சிறந்த செல்வமாகும். அது தக்க சமயத்தில் அவனுக்கு உதவும். எனவே அனைவரும் அறிவை மேன்மேலும் வளர்த்துக் கொள்ள வேண்டும்."},{"question":"Viết bài văn phân tích nhân vật Hộ trong tác phẩm Đời thừa","answer":"Với Truyện Kiều của Nguyễn Du, người đọc gặp bi kịch của kiếp “tài hoa bạc mệnh”, ở Chí Phèo của Nam Cao, là bi kịch của những khát khao lương thiện và cũng với Nam Cao ta gặp ở Đời thừa, tấn bi kịch tinh thần của người trí thức. Đời thừa bộc lộ rõ nét “tư tưởng nhân đạo mới mẻ độc đáo của nhà văn lớn Nam Cao”.Bi kịch tinh thần của nhân vật Hộ trong Đời thừa là bi kịch của một nhà văn – một trí thức giữa “cơn bể dâu” của cuộc đời, giữa một xã hội “chó đểu” (Vũ Trọng Phụng) – Nhà văn ấy giữ được phẩm giá của mình, ý thức được “thiên chức”, cao cả của mình vậy mà đành bó tay bất lực.Có thể nói bi kịch đầu tiên trong tấn bi kịch tinh thần của cuộc đời Hộ là bi kịch về những giấc mộng văn chương. Hộ đã đặt văn chương lên trên hết: Văn chương dường như là khát vọng lớn nhất của anh. Anh muôn trở thành nhà văn chân chính – nhà văn viết “mở hồn đón lấy những vang vọng của đời”. Anh mơ ước đến một ngày anh sẽ viết được một tác phẩm chung cho cả loài người. Nó đề cập đến những vấn đề bức xúc của cả xã hội của cả nhân loại. Nó nói được những cái “lớn lao, mạnh mẽ vừa đau đớn vừa phấn khởi. Nó ca tụng lòng thương, tình bác ái, sự công bình. Isĩó làm cho người gần người hơn”. Và nhất định anh sẽ giật giải Nôben! Đó là cuốn tiểu thuyết vĩ đại trong đời viết văn của anh. Nó sẽ làm rạng danh cho anh, cho nền văn học nước nhà. Đó quả là ước mơ chính đáng! Không phải người nghệ sĩ nào cũng khao khát như vậy khi bước vào con đường văn chương đầy khổ ải. Nhà văn phải biết xây ước mơ đẹp, và khát vọng của Hộ là khát vọng mạnh mẽ nhất và đẹp nhất. Hộ xác định đúng con đường cho mình – xác định đúng tư tưởng cho mình.Anh không sa vào những mơ mộng về nghệ thuật – nghệ thuật là “ánh trăng huyền ảo” (như Điền trong Trăng sáng). Anh thấy ánh tráng của nghệ thuật biết “làm đẹp cả những cảnh thật ra chỉ tầm thường xấu xa”. Quan điểm của anh đúng đắn lắm! Tư tưởng của anh tiến bộ lắm! Thế nhưng trong sáng tác của mình anh đã viết những gì? Anh đã cho ra đời những sáng tác như thế nào? Anh không hướng nghệ thuật vào “thứ văn chương của bọn nhàn rỗi”, anh không viết để cho những cô gái áo xanh, áo đỏ tha thướt đọc, nhưng anh viết những gì từ khi anh bắt tay vào sáng tác? Chao ôi! Thực tế có phải bao giờ cũng chiều theo khát vọng đâu! Anh đã viết những bài mà thậm chí khi đọc thấy tên của mình dưới bài viết phải “dỏ mặt” xâu hổ. Anh giận dữ với chính anh. Anh khinh ghét những tác phẩm chỉ biết “gợi những tình cảm rất nhẹ rất nông bằng một thứ văn chương quá ư bằng phẳng dễ dãi” của chính mình. Dường như anh hoảng hốt, anh ngạc nhiên trước những bài viết của mình mới ra đời. Anh dằn vặt ghê gớm. Anh muôn nhưng có phải bao giờ ý muốn cũng thành sự thật đâu! Và đó chính là cái bi kịch của anh – bi kịch của một đời viết văn – bi kịch của một người hiểu mình biết mình phải làm gì và đành lựa bút theo những điều mà mình chẳng hề muôn. Tôi cảm thấy cái đau đớn khủng khiếp tự chôn sâu thẳm của tâm hồn anh. Một cái gì đó bỗng chổc sụp đổ trong anh. Đấy chính là sự sụp đô của một khát vọng đẹp và chân chính.Anh phải viết ẩu như thế, bôi bác như thế cũng chính là vì những ràng buộc cua “áo cơm”. Chao ôi! Giá như anh được bay nhảy với những giấc mơ ấy!Nhưng “cơm áo không đùa với khách thơ” (Xuân Diệu). Anh còn vợ và một đàn con nhỏ. Kiếp người với bao toan tính bộn bề níu kéo anh, không cho anh bay lên cùng với những giấc mộng đời trai trẻ. Chính nỗi lo âu tiền bạc đã buộc anh viết những bài trái với lương tâm và trách nhiệm. Trong đầu anh luôn quay cuồng với những tính toán về giá cả sinh hoạt, về bữa ăn hàng ngày… thì đâu còn chỗ cho văn chương nữa. Anh phải viết thật nhanh, thật nhanh để người vợ, đàn con và chính anh khỏi chết đói! Giá như anh cứ bỏ vứt cái mộng văn chương thì chắc đời anh chắng khốn khổ đến thế! Nhưng anh cần nghĩ tới tác phẩm của anh – các tác phẩm cho toàn nhàn loại nên anh lại càng đau đớn! Nước mắt anh không chảy nhưng đớn đau thì chồng chất tập trung 'hơn. Chao ôi! “Đau đớn thay cho những kiếp sông muốn cất cánh bay cao nhưng lại bị áo cơm ghì sát đất” – (Sống mòn). Đó chính là bi kịch của cuộc đời viết văn của anh – bi kịch của những giấc mộng văn chương chính là ở chỗ đó! Và tưởng như giấc mộng văn chương ấy chính là điều day dứt trong anh mãi không thôi.Phải có những hiểu biết sâu sắc về tâm tư tình cảm con người thì Nam Cao mới viết những dòng đầy xúc cảm đến thế! Dường như những day dứt trong cuộc đời ông – cuộc đời văn sĩ khô’ ải – đã nhập vào những suy tư của Hộ, đả nhập vào tấn bi kịch tinh thần của Hộ. Có người nói Hộ chinh là hình ảnh của nhà vần Nam Cao thời kì trước Cách mạng. Tôi không hoàn toàn nghĩ thế. Nam Cao đả có thể bị cơm áo ghì chặt nhưng hơn hẳn Hộ; ông đã biết vượt lên trên những lo toan ấy đề biến giâc mơ thành sự thật. Ong đã viết những lời văn hay nhất, đẹp nhất về cuộc đời về những kiếp lầm than và chắc chắn Nam Cao không phải đỏ mặt khi thấy tên mình sau những tác phẩm như Chí Phèo, Đời thừa… Bởi đó chính là giấc mơ văn chương nảy nở. Có thể tự tin mà nói rằng với Đời thừa, Nam Cao đã bộc lộ được tư tưởng nhân đạo mới mẻ, độc đáo của mình khi viết những dòng bi kịch về Hộ. Kinh nghiệm và những vón sông đã cho ông viết những điều có sức rung động, lay chuyến lòng người đến thê! Đó chính là nhờ tư tưởng nhân đạo mới mẻ, độc đáo của nhà văn Nam Cao. Nhân đạo ở chỗ ca ngợi khát vọng đẹp đẽ của HỘ, nhân đạo ở chó cảm thông sâu sắc với người trí thức… Và có viết được những dòng như thế cũng là nhờ tư tưởng nhân đạo “mới mẻ” độc đáo của Nam Cao. Qua bi kịch tinh thần đầu tiên này của Hộ, Nam Cao đã bộc lộ được sự thông cảm, trân trọng bao kiếp người lao khổ trong cuộc đời này. Và phải chăng tư tưởng ấy đã kế thừa được cha ông lòng nhân đạo truyền thống. Nhà văn không “phản ánh để phản ánh” mà sau những câu chữ tưởng như lãnh dam, thờ ơ chính là một trái tim nhiệt thành, sôi nỗi – một trái tim tình nghĩa.Bi kịch đầu tiên của cuộc đời nhà văn Hộ và đó cũng là nguyên nhân cho bi kịch thứ hai — bi kịch của một con người. Giấc mộng văn chương qua những bài vàn viết ẩu. Thê nhưng Hộ vẫn còn một chút an ủi. Đó chính là cuộc sống, sự tồn tại của vợ con anh. Anh chưa thực hiện được khát vọng của mình — anh chưa viết được cuôn tiểu thuyết cùa đời anh, nhưng anh nuôi đủ vợ con. Anh đã kéo dài được sự tồn tại của gia đình anh. Và đó có thể coi là việc làm hữu ích. Đó cũng là an ủi cho cái Đời thừa của một nhà văn. Thế cũng đáng an ủi lắm chứ!Vì anh là người đặt “tình thương” lên hàng đầu, lẽ sông của anh là tình thương. Tình thương là trên hết. Chính trong lời khẳng định về tác phẩm “ca tụng lòng thương, lòng bác ái, sự công bình”. Trong văn chương, anh muôn ca ngợi tình thương và trong cuộc đời thực tình thương là tất cả. Chính vì lẽ sống tình thương của mình, anh đã đón Từ, giúp Từ thoát khỏi những tủi nhục khi một mình trơ trọi với đứa con không cha. Những giọt nước mắt của Từ và bà mẹ già của Từ đã khiến anh xúc động. Họ muôn khóc cho đến khi '‘bao nhiêu xương thịt cứ tan ra thành nước mắt” nhưng gặp anh, tình thương của anh đã tỏa rạng đến giúp họ thoát khỏi những đớn đau. Một người dám bỏ cuộc đời bay nhảy của tuổi xuân để nụôi nấng vợ con chẳng là người dũng cảm lắm sao! Chính tình thương – lẽ sống tình thương đã khiến anh làm việc ấy. Anh cao đẹp quá! Đời anh không phải là Đời thừa với gia đình nhỏ của anh. Anh đau khố vì tên anh cứ “lu mờ dần sau những cái tên khác mới xuất hiện rực rỡ” nhưng với Từ và đàn con – anh là biểu tượng sáng chói của tình thương. Tình thương ấy là rất đáng trân trọng. Trong một xã Hội rác rưởi “chó đểu” như thế, hành động của anh chẳng là một hành động tốt đẹp hiếm hoi hay sao? Thê nhưng anh cũng chẳng giữ được trọn vẹn các lẽ sông cao quý ấy của mình nữa. Quá là một sai lầm khi anh kết luận: nguyên nhân trực tiếp cho sự sụp đô các giấc mộng văn chương chính là vợ anh và đàn con nheo nhóc kia. Anh cạn nghĩ quá! Đó không phải hoàn toàn là lỗi vợ con anh. Thất vọng trong văn chương, buồn chán trong không khí gia đình đã khiến anh tìm niềm vui trong men rượu. Anh muôn quên, quên đi tất cả.Anh không say trong men tình ái, trong khúc nhạc đong đưa., mà say khủng khiếp trong men rượu. Chính anh cũng không hiểu tại sao anh vồ được đến nhà. Anh chỉ biết anh đã tỉnh dậy trên giường nhà mình khi chân tay rã rời. Men rượu “chết tiệt\\" ấy chính là cái trực tiếp làm cho bi kịch trong anh xuất hiện. Rượu đã khiến anh trỞ thành kẻ vô học, rượu đánh đồng loạt những cái xấu, người tốt, kẻ giàu, người nghèo trong những cơn say. Khi say, ai cũng như ai hết! Men rượu của anh không giúp anh có được cái tình của Chí Phèo giúp hắn hướng về cái thiên lương. Men rượu đã khiến anh trở thành một kẻ tiếu nhân vô học. Anh đã vi phạm lẽ sông tình thương của mình. Anh đã đánh vự con anh như một kẻ vũ phu. Vâng, chính lúc đó anh là kẻ vũ phu. Anh đã đánh đập người vợ tận tụy của mình không biết bao nhiêu lần nữa mà kể. Anh đã chí mặt Từ mà quát mắng:“Cả con mẹ mày nữa củng đáng vật chết”. Anh đã làm tất cả, tất cả trong say. Sao mà tai hại quá! Anh đã vi phạm lẽ sông của mình, vi phạm cái tốt đẹp – cái phần “người” vô cùng cao đẹp tưởng còn được an ủi bởi anh đã giữ trọn lẽ sông tình thương của mình. Ai ngờ, cuộc sống cũng không cho phép anh thực hiện được điều đó. Thế mà may, chính cái lẽ sống ấy anh cũng chà đạp nốt. Anh – cuộc sống đời anh quả là “đời thừa”. Bi kịch đầu tiên là bi kịch của những giấc mộng văn chương nên cái “thừa”không còn quá nhiều đau đớn như bi kịch này, bi kịch mà kế tục là cái “thừa” ấy của anh đã được thể hiện đầy đủ. Anh đã động đến phần cao quý nhất. Đó là bi kịch tinh thần của một con người mà đau đớn thay, đó lại là con người ý thức phẩm giá nhân cách của mình nhiều nhất! Ở bi kịch trước, cái mặc cảm tội lỗi trong anh rất lớn vì anh là một nhà văn. Nếu Chí Phèo chỉ gieo rắc tội lỗi của hắn cho dân làng Vũ Đại, anh giáo Thứ chỉ truyền thụ sự chán nản lên đầu học sinh thì anh – anh gieo những “tình cảm rất nhẹ, rất nong” những tình cảm quá ư tầm thường ấy và bao nhiêu độc giả. Sự nhiễm hại ấy lớn hơn. Dù thế bi kịch thứ hai này – bi kịch của một người mặc cảm tội lỗi còn lớn hơn nhiều. Với tư cách của một nhà văn đã gây ảnh hưởng đến người đọc từ những bài văn viết lấy lợi nhuận. Với tư cách của một con người, anh đã gây ra những điều ghê gớm hơn. Xã Hội này đã quá nhiều, quá thừa những cái xâu. Anh cô giữ tốt đẹp trong mình thế mà anh cũng phá hỏng nốt. Mặc cảm mà anh còn vi phạm thì chắng còn gì nữa cả. Bi kịch này của anh, lớn hơn gấp bội bi kịch kia bởi lẽ sống tình thương, chỗ dựa của bao giá trị phẩm giá khác đả sụp đổ.Bi kịch này khủng khiếp và hoàn toàn không có lối thoát và dường như nó bao trùm thành bi kịch của cả đời anh – một Đời thửa. Anh đố lỗi tất cả cho gia đình, nhưng tất cả là tại anh. Tuy vậy cũng cần nói thêm rằng, bi kịch ấy có nguyên nhân sâu xa chính từ xã Hội đương thời. Chính cái xã Hội ấy đã đẩy anh phải lo “cơm áo gạo tiền”. Nỗi lo sinh kế đã khiến anh phải từ bỏ giấc mộng văn chương. Và chính những thất vọng ấy đã khiến anh chà đạp lên lẽ sông tình thương của mình. Nguyên nhân ấy có lẽ anh không hiểu được – nguyên nhân của xã Hội thực dân nửa phong kiến – nguyên nhân mà ngày ấy, người ta đã nhận ra. Anh chưa tìm được lối thoát cho sự bô tắc. Đó là cái bê tắc của thời đại mà anh sống.Nhưng đó phải chăng là nét hạn chế trong tư tưởng nhân đạo của Nam Cao? Ong đã biết đề cao những khát vọng đẹp của người trí thức, đã biết thông cảm với những nỗi khô của họ nhưng chưa đề ra được lối thoát cho họ. Nhưng những “tư tưởng nhân đạo mới mẻ, độc đáo” ấy đã là đáng quý, đáng trân trọng biết bao! Độc đáo, mới mẻ chính là ở lòng thương người – tình người nồng đượm bao la đằng sau lôi viết văn tưởng như dứng dưng lãnh đạm.Ngày nay cuộc đời đã được đổi thay. Lớp văn sĩ thoát được dù là một phần của nỗi lo toan “cơm áo” không còn những bi kịch tinh thần như Hộ nữa. Nhà vàn ngày nay được ưu đãi hơn. Chúng ta không thể quên thời kì mà người trí thức văn nghẹ sĩ mang những bi kịch tinh thần.Tư tưởng nhân đạo mới mẻ, độc đáo của Nam Cao đã khiến cho nhân vật dù qua bao tháng trầm vẫn đứng vững với tư cách một con người chân chính."},{"question":"Kodi mchere umatanthauzanji m’Baibulo?","answer":"M’Baibulo muli mawu ambiri onena za mchere. M'malo osiyanasiyana, amagwiritsidwa ntchito mophiphiritsa kutanthauza kukhalitsa, kukhulupirika, phindu, mtengo, ndi kuyeretsedwa."},{"question":"Tỉnh thành nào có diện tích rộng nhất Việt Nam?","answer":"Nghệ An có diện tích lớn nhất Việt NamTỉnh Nghệ An có diện tích lớn nhất Việt Nam, gần 16.500 km2, thuộc vùng Bắc Trung Bộ. Trung tâm hành chính của tỉnh là thành phố Vinh, nằm cách thủ đô Hà Nội 291 km về phía nam."},{"question":" هوءَ پنهنجو ڪنڌ جهڪائيندي هئي. هن جي ٻي ماءُ روشن مسڪرائيندي هئي ۽ هن جي مٿي تي وار سمنڊ جي هيٺان ٻوٽن وانگر وهندا هئا. \`\` اسان صرف اهو چاهيون ٿا جيڪو توهان لاءِ بهترين آهي ،'هن چيو. هن ڪورالائن جي ڪلهي تي هٿ رکيو.","answer":"ڪورالائن"},{"question":"பெரியாரின் எழுத்துகளிலிருந்து  மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":"மாடுகளுக்குத் தினவெடுத்தால் உரசிக் கொள்ள தேய்ப்புக்கல் நட்டு வைக்கும் இந்து மக்கள், விதவைகளுக்கு என்ன செய்திருக்கிறார்கள்?."},{"question":"ચાર્ટર અધિનિયમ ૧૮૧૩ જણાવો","answer":"આ અધિનિયમ અન્વયે કંપનીનો વ્યાપારિક પરવાનો એકાધિકાર સમાપ્ત કરવામાં આવ્યો. તથા તમામ બ્રિટીશ નાગરિકો માટે ભારતીય બજારને ખુલ્લુ મૂકવામાં આવ્યું હતું. તેમજ ધર્મ પ્રચારકોને ભારતમાં પ્રચારની છૂટ આપવામાં આવી હતી. [૯] મદ્રાસ, મુંબઈ અને કલકત્તાની કાઉન્સિલોની સત્તા વધારવામાં આવી."},{"question":" Em que país está localizado o monumento pré-histórico feito de pedras conhecido como Stonehenge?","answer":"Em 1922."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'makan gaji'? Berilah satu contoh ayat untuknya.","answer":"Ia bermaksud bekerja untuk mendapatkan upah. Contoh ayat: Hasrom bekerja makan gaji dengan abangnya."},{"question":"Ngày thu phân là ngày bao nhiêu?","answer":"Ngày thu phân là ngày 23 và ngày 24 tháng 9."},{"question":"Vraag: Welke acteur speelt detective Benoit Blanc in de film Knives Out? A. Edward Norton B. Bryan Cranston C. Brad Pitt D. Daniel Craig","answer":"Antwoord: D. Daniel Craig"},{"question":"Tteokbokki কি তা ব্যাখ্যা কর","answer":"tteokbokki দক্ষিণ কোরিয়ার একটি ঐতিহ্যবাহী খাবার। এতে মশলা, কিমচি এবং সবজি দিয়ে তৈরি তরকারিতে ভাত এবং মাছের কেক থাকে।"},{"question":"தேனை உட்கொள்ளும்போது கவனிக்க வேண்டிய விஷயங்கள் என்னென்ன?","answer":"1. தேனை சூடான உணவு பொருட்களுடன் கலக்கக் கூடாது.2. தேனை சூடாக்குவதை தவிர்க்க வேண்டும்.3. வெப்ப நிலை அதிகமாக உள்ள இடங்களில் வேலை செய்பவர்கள் தேன் உட்கொள்வதை தவிர்க்க வேண்டும்.4. தேனை மழை நீர், கடுகு, நெய் மற்றும் காரமான உணவு வகைகளுடன் ஒருபோதும் கலக்கக் கூடாது.தேன் பல மலர்களின் மதுரம் கலந்த ஒரு கலவையே. அதில் நச்சு தன்மை வாய்ந்த மலர்களும் அடங்கும். நஞ்சு பொதுவாக கார மற்றும் உஷ்ண குணங்களையே கொண்டிருக்கும். ஆகவே தேனை கார மற்றும் சூடான உணவு பொருட்களுடன் கலக்கும் போது இந்த நச்சு தன்மைகள் மேலோங்கும் சாத்தியக்கூறு உள்ளது.தேனில் விட்டமின் பி1, பி2, பி3, பி5, பி6, சி, இ முதலிய வைட்டமின்களும் மற்றும் அயோடின், கால்சியம், கந்தகம், இரும்பு, சோடியம், மெக்னீசியம், தாமிரம், குளோரின், பொட்டாசியம், சுண்ணாம்புச்சத்து, பாஸ்பரஸ், உப்பு, குளுகோஸ், லெவுகோஸ், லாக்டிக் அமிலம், டார்டாரிக் ஆஸிட், சிட்ரிக் அமிலம், க்ளாரிக் அமிலம் போன்ற இதர வகையான சத்துப்பொருள்களும் உள்ளன. இவையாவும் நம் உடல் வளர்ச்சிக்குத் தேவை. தேன், பிறந்த குழந்தைகள், கர்ப்பிணிப் பெண்கள், பாலூட்டும் தாய்மார்கள், முதியவர்கள், விளையாட்டு வீரர்கள், நோயுற்றவர்கள் என அனைவருக்கும் ஏற்ற இயற்கை உணவுதான். இருப்பினும் பலர் தேனைப் பற்றி பல வதந்திகளைப் பரப்புவது முற்றிலும் அறியாமையே."},{"question":"Lẹyin ọdun mẹwaa to ti sa mọ wọn lọwọ, ọwọ tun ba ọkunrin yii nidii egboogi oloro l’Ekoo","answer":"Pampẹ ti ajọ to n gbogun ti lilo, gbigbe ati ṣiṣe okoowo egboogi oloro nilẹ wa, NDLEA, dẹ re, o si mu Chidi Olife. Ọdun kẹwaa ree ti wọn ni afurasi ọdaran naa ti sa mọ ajọ NDLEA lọwọ tori egboogi oloro, idi okoowo buruku naa ni wọn tun ti mu un lọjọ Abamẹta, Satide yii, niluu Eko.Atẹjade kan latọwọ ajọ ọhun nipa iṣẹlẹ yii sọ pe ọdun 2010 ni wọn ti kọkọ mu afurasi yii, ẹsun ti wọn fi kan an nigba naa ni pe o gbe egboogi oloro (Heroine), tijọba ti fofin de kan wọle lati orileede Pakistan. Inu awọn iwe kan lo dọgbọn tọju rẹ si, egboogi naa si tẹwọn ju kilogiraamu marun-un lọ (5.250kg).NDLEA ni bawọn ṣe bẹrẹ iṣẹ iwadii lori egboogi ti wọn ka mọ ọgbẹni naa lọwọ, ko sẹni to le sọ bo ṣe ṣẹlẹ, ṣadeede lo dawati, wọn o mọ bo ṣe sa lọ mọ awọn ọtẹlẹmuyẹ lọwọ.Wọn ni latigba naa ni wọn ti n wa a, ṣugbọn ko sẹni to pade ẹ, ajọ naa si yan igbimọ amuṣẹya kan lati maa dọdẹ ẹ. Ọgbẹni Adeniyi Olumuyiwa to jẹ igbakeji ọga to n ri si egboogi oloro lẹbulẹbu lalaga igbimọ naa.Igbimọ yii lo fura pe awọn kan ti n gbọna ẹyin lọọ ko awọn iwe ti afurasi naa fi ko egboogi oloro wọle ọhun ninu kọntena ti wọn tọju ẹ si. Lẹyin ti wọn fimu finlẹ, wọn lawọn ri i pe awọn kan ti wọn pera wọn ni ejẹnti to n ṣiṣẹ lawọn ẹnubode eti omi ni wọn, ọwọ ẹṣọ NDLEA si ba meji ninu wọn, Ọgbẹni Ọladimeji Ọladọtun ati Alaaji Idris Danjuma. Wọn lawọn mejeeji yii lo n to iwe bi wọn ṣe maa ri kọntena naa gbe kuro leti omi, aṣe afurasi ọdaran naa lo fori pamọ sibi kan, to bẹ wọn lọwẹ.Mimu ti wọn mu awọn ejẹnti meji yii lo ṣatọna bi wọn ṣe ri ẹni ti orukọ ẹ wa lakọọlẹ pe oun lo ni kọntena ti egboogi oloro naa wa atawọn iwe ti wọn fi ko o si, Ọgbẹni Ningo Oke mu,  lawọn agbofinro ba fi pampẹ ofin gbe oun naa.Asẹyinwa asẹyinbọ, akara tu sepo, Oke jẹwọ pe oun gan-an kọ loun ni ẹru ofin, o ni afurasi ọdaran ti wọn ti n wa yii lo ran awọn niṣẹ, o si mu wọn de ile Chidi Olife to wa lagbegbe  Ajao Estate, ni Isọlọ. Ibẹ ni wọn ti ri ọdaran to ti sa fọdun mẹwaa ọhun mu pada.NDLEA lawọn tun ti bẹrẹ iwadii lori afurasi yii atawọn tọrọ kan, ko si ni i pẹ rara tawọn maa taari wọn lọ sile-ẹjọ, ki wọn le fimu kata ofin."},{"question":"Kí ni a ń pè ní \\"shell of a snail\\" ní ède Yorùbá?","answer":"Ìkarahun ìgbín ni."},{"question":"ਹਰਦੀਪ ਸਿੰਘ ਨਿੱਝਰ : ਭਾਰਤ- ਕੈਨੇਡਾ ਦੇ ਕੂਟਨੀਤਿਕ ਸੰਕਟ ਤੋਂ ਪੱਛਮੀ ਮੁਲਕ ਕਿਉਂ ਘਬਰਾ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ ?","answer":"ਪੱਛਮੀ ਮੁਲਕਾਂ ਦੇ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਅਤੇ ਅਧਿਕਾਰੀ ਇਹ ਯਕੀਨੀ ਬਣਾਉਣ ਲਈ ਸਖ਼ਤ ਮਿਹਨਤ ਕਰਨਗੇ ਕਿ ਕੈਨੇਡਾ ਤੇ ਭਾਰਤ ਦਰਮਿਆਨ ਕੂਟਨੀਤਿਕ ਵਿਵਾਦ ਹੋਰ ਕੌਮਾਂਤਰੀ ਰਿਸ਼ਤਿਆਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਰੇੜਕਾ ਨਾ ਬਣੇ।ਅਮਰੀਕਾ ਅਤੇ ਹੋਰ ਪੱਛਮੀ ਮੁਲਕ ਹੁਣ ਆਖਰੀ ਚੀਜ਼ ਜੋ ਚਾਹੁੰਦੇ ਹਨ, ਉਹ ਇਹ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਇਹ ਵਿਵਾਦ ਹੋ ਵੰਡੀਆਂ ਨਾ ਪਾ ਦਵੇ।ਭਾਰਤ ਨਾ ਸਿਰਫ ਇੱਕ ਵੱਧ ਰਹੀ ਸ਼ਕਤੀ ਹੈ, ਸਗੋਂ ਦੁਨੀਆਂ ਦਾ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਵੱਧ ਆਬਾਦੀ ਵਾਲਾ ਅਤੇ ਪੰਜਵੀਂ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਵੱਡੀ ਆਰਥਿਕਤਾ ਵਾਲਾ ਮੁਲਕ ਹੈ।ਪਰ ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਪੱਛਮੀ ਮੁਲਕਾਂ ਵੱਲੋਂ ਚੀਨ ਵਿਰੁੱਧ ਇੱਕ ਸੰਭਾਵੀ ਧਿਰ ਵਜੋਂ ਵੀ ਦੇਖਿਆ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ।ਅਮਰੀਕਾ ਤੇ ਬ੍ਰਿਟੇਨ ਸਾਹਮਣੇ ਪਹੁੰਚਿਆ ਨਿੱਝਰ ਦਾ ਮਸਲਾ:ਕੈਨੇਡਾ ਦੀ ਵਿਦੇਸ਼ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਮੇਲੀਨਾ ਜੋਲੀ ਨੇ ਕਿਹਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਪ੍ਰਧਾਨ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਜਸਟਿਨ ਟਰੂਡੋ ਨੇ ਹਰਦੀਪ ਸਿੰਘ ਨਿੱਝਰ ਦੇ ਕਤਲ ਦਾ ਮਸਲਾ ਅਮਰੀਕੀ ਰਾਸ਼ਟਰਪਤੀ ਜੋਅ ਬਾਇਡਨ ਅਤੇ ਬ੍ਰਿਟੇਨ ਦੇ ਪ੍ਰਧਾਨ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਰਿਸ਼ੀ ਸੁਨਕ ਅੱਗੇ ਚੁੱਕਿਆ ਹੈ।ਬੀਬੀਸੀ ਪੰਜਾਬੀ "},{"question":"什么是神经网络？","answer":"答：神经网络是一种人工智能方法，用于模拟人脑神经元网络结构的数学模型，用于实现机器学习和深度学习算法。"},{"question":"Iru ki waa leleyii, olukọ fasiti ku sinu ọkọ rẹ l’Akungba Akoko","answer":"Olukọ agba kan ni Fasiti Adekunle Ajasin to wa niluu Akungba Akoko, Dokita Ọlatunde Adegbuyi, ni wọn deedee ba oku rẹ ninu ọkọ ayọkẹlẹ kan lọjọ Isẹgun, Tusidee, ọsẹ ta a wa yii.Akọroyin wa fidi rẹ mulẹ lati ẹnu ẹnikan to jẹ oṣiṣẹ fasiti ọhun pe awọn eeyan to wa lagbegbe ibi tiṣẹlẹ yii ti waye ni wọn kọkọ ṣakiyesi oloogbe naa nibi to sọ ori kọ si ninu ọkọ rẹ nitosi ọgba fasiti naa.Dokita Adegbuyi ni wọn lo jẹ olukọ lẹka tí wọn ti n kọ nipa imọ awọn ohun alumọọni ilẹ (Geology) ko too fẹyinti lọdun diẹ sẹyin, bo tilẹ jẹ pe awọn alasẹ fasiti ọhun tun pada fun un niṣẹ mi-in ṣe lẹyin to fẹyinti tan.Ko sẹni to le sọ ohun to pa ọkunrin naa."},{"question":"વોશિંગ્ટન રાજ્યમાં આવેલી રોડ ટ્રીપ જણાવો.","answer":"ઓલિમ્પિક નેશનલ પાર્ક, માઉન્ટ રેઇનિયર, માઉન્ટ બેકર, લેક ચેલાન, સ્નોક્વાલ્મી ફોલ્સ, મોસેસ લેક અને બેનબ્રિજ આઇલેન્ડની મુલાકાત લેવી એ બધી રોડ ટ્રિપ્સ છે જે ખૂબ જ મનોહર અને સુંદર છે."},{"question":"Анастомоз Гексли деген эмне ?","answer":"Анастомоз Гексли (анат.) — Гекслинин анастомозу; бурама жандыктардын кээ  бир түрүнүн сийдик түтүктөрүнүн туура түтүк менен кошулушу.  "},{"question":"Ẹẹmẹta ni reluwee dẹnu kọlẹ ninu igbo lọna Abuja, lawọn ero ba n binu sijọba","answer":"Pẹlu ibinu lawọn ero to wọ reluwee ijọba lati Kaduna si Abuja fi n sọko ọrọ sijọba apapọ lowurọ ọjọ Aje, Mọnde yii, nigba ti reluwee naa joye abiku soloogun di eke, ẹẹmẹta ọtọọtọ ni reluwee naa daku, bi wọn ṣe n tun un ṣe lo n taku.Lati ibudokọ reluwee to wa ni Rigassa, nipinlẹ Kaduna, ni ọkọ naa ti gbera ni aago meje owurọ ọjọ Aje, Mọnde, ọpọ awọn to si wọ ọ ni wọn fẹẹ lọọ wọṣẹ l’Abuja, pẹlu ireti pe irinajo naa ko ni i ju bii wakati kan lọ.Ba a ṣe gbọ, wọn ni ko ju bii iṣẹju mẹẹẹdogun tọkọ naa bẹrẹ irinajo rẹ lo bẹrẹ si i ṣe tikọ tikọ loju ọna, irin rẹ ko ja geere mọ, ẹnjinni ọkọ naa ko si ṣiṣẹ daadaa. Wọn ni inu igbo to wa lagbegbe Dutse, nijọba ibilẹ Chikum, nipinlẹ Kaduna, lo taku si.Kia lawọn ẹnjinnia to n ba ọkọ naa ṣiṣẹ ti bẹrẹ si i yẹ agbari rẹ wo, wọn kọkọ tun un ṣe, wọn ṣina fun un, wọn si sọ pe kawọn ero to ti bọ silẹ wọle pada, ṣugbọn bo ṣe rin siwaju diẹ lo tun taku.Bẹẹ lo ṣe lẹẹkeji ati lẹẹkẹta, eyi lo bi awọn ero naa ninu, tori o ti mu ki ọpọlọpọ tase aago ti wọn fẹẹ dẹnu okoowo ati ọfiisi wọn.Ọkan ninu awọn ero to wọ reluwee naa, Ọgbẹni Midat Joseph, to jẹ Igbakeji akọwe ẹgbẹ awọn oniroyin Naijiria royin pe iṣẹlẹ naa baayan ninu jẹ gidi, tori inu igbo ni reluwee yii n taku si, jinnijinni nla lo si da bo awọn ero tori eto aabo to mẹhẹ lasiko yii, niṣe ni kaluku n gbadura kawọn janduku agbebọn ma lọọ ka wọn mọ.O ni iriri buruku ni, o si ya oun lẹnu pe ọkọ tuntun tijọba lawọn ṣẹṣẹ ra lo ti di daku daji yii.Ọkunrin naa sọ pe “Aago mẹsan-an aarọ lo yẹ ki n wọṣẹ l’Abuja, ṣugbọn wọn o ri reluwee yii tunṣe titi di aago mẹwaa aabọ, ninu igbo kijikiji. Mi o gbadura ki iru nnkan yii tun ṣẹlẹ, ko daa rara.”Ọkan ninu awọn ero mi-in sọ pe, laye oun, oun o tun ba wọn wọ reluwee naa mọ. O ni Ọlọrun lo yọ awọn ti awọn ko ko sọwọ awọn ajinigbe lasiko naa, niṣe ni wọn iba ru gbogbo awọn lọ sinu igbo."},{"question":"Inona avy ireo endrika mety isehoan'ny famadihana ho an'ny foko samihafa?","answer":"Samy manana ny fomba fanatanterahany ny famadihana ny faritra na foko. Amin'ny Sakalava ohatra ny atao hoe Fafa Lolo dia fanadiovana ny ivelan’ny fasana. Ho an' ny anosy sy Antaisaka, atao hoe Takombato : fananganana tsangam-bato asiana tandrok’omby novonoina  nandritra ny lanonana. Ho an'ny Betsileo atsimo kosa atao hoe Mandofo Razana : tsy mikasika razana fa rakofana lamba avy eo ambony (saforana)."},{"question":"¿Qué político fue presidente de los EE. UU. mientras también era barman con licencia?","answer":"El político que fue presidente de los Estados Unidos y también era barman con licencia fue Abraham Lincoln. Antes de entrar en la política y ser elegido como el decimosexto presidente de los Estados Unidos en 1861, Lincoln tenía una licencia de bartender y trabajó en la industria de la hostelería en su juventud. Su experiencia como barman fue solo una de las muchas facetas interesantes de su vida antes de dedicarse a la política y liderar al país durante la Guerra Civil."},{"question":"لدي مقال طويل، هلي يمكنك تلخيصه؟ قدر الفنان أيمن السرحاني يحقق نسبة مشاهدة مرتفعة لكليب أغنيتو الجديدة في ظرف قصير. وقدرات أغنية السرحاني “طلعتك بزاف” أنها تحقق 10 مليون مشاهدة على قناة المغني في يوتوب في ظرف 72 ساعة، وحتلات الطوندونس لمدة يومين. أيمن السرحاني غبر واحد المدة على الساحة الفنية وما حطش الجديد لمدة أكثر من عام، وبعدها قرر يصدر الجديد ديالو. .","answer":"نعم بالتأكيد. هذا تلخيص للمقال السابق: في 4 ايام.. أغنية السرحاني شادة الطوندونس ب10 مليون مشاهدة."},{"question":"Fenoy ny banga amin'ny fehezanteny manaraka. \\"Mahafinaritra ery ny ____ ny fitsikinao.\\"","answer":"Ny valiny dia: \\"Mahafinaritra ery ny mahita ny fitsikinao.\\""},{"question":"次の段落にマッチするタイトルをつけてください： 関東大震災を撮影したカメラマンのドキュメンタリー映画ができました。古いフィルムの映像を保存している団体が作りました。映画には3人のカメラマンが撮影した映像を使っています。団体は映像から撮影した場所や時間を調べました。そして家族の話や本人が書いた文章などから、3人がどのような人たちだったのかを伝えています。28日に東京で映画を見る会があって、100人ぐらいが集まりました。映画を見た大学生は「今私たちが住む、スカイツリーなどがある町でこんな災害があったんだとよくわかりました」と話しました。専門家は「カメラマンたちがどんな気持ちで災害を撮影したのか、映画で体験できることは大切なことです」と話しています。この映画は、東京都や横浜市などの映画館で8月26日から見ることができます。","answer":"100年前の関東大震災を撮影したカメラマンの映画ができる"},{"question":"Inona no niseho teto Madagasikara tamin'ny 29 avrily 1959?","answer":"Tamin'ny 29 avrily 1959 dia nisy fandaniana ny Lalàmpanorenan’ny Repoblika voalohany."},{"question":"ചോദ്യം: ഫലങ്ങളുടെ അനിശ്ചിതത്വമോ സാധ്യതയോ വിലയിരുത്തുന്നതും കണക്കാക്കുന്നതും ഉൾപ്പെടുന്ന ഒരു തരം ലോജിക്കൽ യുക്തിവാദമാണ് പ്രോബബിലിസ്റ്റിക് ന്യായവാദം. ഇനിപ്പറയുന്ന സാഹചര്യം കണക്കിലെടുക്കുമ്പോൾ: \\"നാളെ മഴ പെയ്യാൻ 70% സാധ്യതയുണ്ട്.\\" നാളെ മഴയുടെ സാധ്യതയെക്കുറിച്ച് നമുക്ക് എന്ത് നിഗമനം ചെയ്യാം?","answer":"ഉത്തരം: മഴ പെയ്യാൻ 70% സാധ്യതയുണ്ട്."},{"question":"Aarọ kutu ni Ogunnaike lọọ digun ja oni POS lole, lọlọpaa ba mu un l’Abẹokuta","answer":"Bi Rafiat Wahab, ọmọbinrin kan to ni ṣọọbu ti wọn ti n fowo ranṣẹ tabi gba owo ti ko ba pọ pupọ (POS Operator), ṣe n ṣilẹkun ṣọọbu ẹ lọjọ kẹrinleogun, oṣu kẹrin, ọdun 2021, ọwọ ọkunrin kan to ti n ṣọ ọ tipẹ, Ogunnaike Philips, ẹni ọdun mẹrindinlọgbọn, lo ṣilẹkun ọhun si. Iyẹn ni ṣọọbu ẹ to wa ni Adehun, Rounder, l’Abẹokuta.Niṣe ni Philips yọ ada si Rafia, to ni ko gbe baagi owo to fi n ṣowo le oun lọwọ, ai jẹ bẹẹ,oun yoo ṣa a pa ni.Ibẹru mu Rafiat, o gbe baagi fun Ogunnaike, niyẹn ba sare jade, lo n sa lọ. Ṣugbọn nigba ti ori rẹ yoo ta ko o, nibi to ti n ṣọṣẹ ọhun lọwọ lawọn kan ti ta ọlọpaa lolobo, ko si ti i rin jinna laduugbo naa tọwọ fi tẹ ẹ.Kawọn ọlọpaa too de lawọn kan ti mu un silẹ, wọn lu u bii ko ku, wọn tun fi ada rẹ to fi halẹ mọ oniṣọọbu naa ṣa a lapa, iyẹn si jinlẹ gidi.Nibi ti Philips ti n jiya rẹ yii lọwọ ni Isaiah Onifade naa ti waa woran rẹ, lo ba n sọ fawọn araadugbo pe ki wọn mu un daadaa o, ole ni, bo ṣe n jale kiri niyẹn, ki wọn ma jẹ ko pẹ ki wọn too pa a.Ohun ti Isaiah sọ yii bi Ogunnaike ninu, nigba naa lo ni ki wọn jẹ koun sọrọ kan fun wọn, ki wọn ma ti i lu oun pa.Ogunnaike, nigba to n ṣalaye ohun to ṣẹlẹ naa fun ALAROYE ni Eleweeran, l’Abẹokuta,  l’Ọjọbọ to kọja yii, sọ pe boun ṣe ri Isaiah to n sọ pe kawọn araadugbo mu oun daadaa loun jẹwọ fun wọn pe awọn jọ n jale ni.O ni oun ko mọ Rafiat tẹlẹ, Isaiah Onifade toun mu bii aburo laduugbo lo sọ foun pe owo buruku wa lọwọ obinrin to n ṣe POS naa, pe koun lọọ fi ada halẹ mọ ọn.O tẹsiwaju pe Isaiah ko tẹle oun wọnu ṣọọbu naa ni, ṣugbọn o duro si itosi ibẹ, o si n ṣọ bi nnkan ṣe n lọ.O ni nigba tọwọ palaba oun waa segi tan, to waa jẹ Isaiah, ẹni ọdun mejilelogun, toun mu bii aburo lo waa n ta ko oun loju awọn eeyan, o lohun to jẹ koun jẹwọ fun wọn pe awọn jọ mọ nipa ẹ niyẹn, ni wọn ba mu Isaiah Onifade naa.Nigba to n ṣalaye tiẹ f’ALAROYE, Isaiah sọ pe oun ti fun Ogunnaike lọwọ lori bi yoo ṣe ṣiṣẹ naa tẹlẹ, oun si ti pada sile lẹyin igba toun ti ba a ṣọ agbegbe naa diẹ.O ni nibi toun ti n fọṣọ lọwọ loun ti gbọ pe wọn ti mu un, toun si lọọ wo o, bo ṣe sọ fun wọn pe awọn jọ mọ nipa ẹ ni niyẹn.Owo to din diẹ lẹgbẹrun lọna ọọdunrun naira ( 238, 850) lawọn ọlọpaa sọ pe o wa ninu baagi Rafia ti Ogunnaike gba, bẹẹ ni wọn ri ẹrọ POS to fi n ṣiṣẹ naa gba lọwọ ọdaran to ja a lole yii pẹlu.Bi kootu ba ti bẹrẹ iṣẹ pada, Ogunnaike ati Onifade yoo foju bale-ẹjọ bawọn ọlọpaa ṣe wi."},{"question":"Kedu ihe Chris Ngige gụrụ na mahadum?","answer":"Ihe ọgụrụ bụ dọkịta"},{"question":"Joxeel péeteg waat yi ci kàddu gii: Kenn xaaru ci kenn mbaa lenn i bitim réew.","answer":"Waat yi nekk ci kàddu gii di \\"Kenn xaaru ci kenn mbaa lenn i bitim réew.\\" ak séen i péete ñoo di:Kenn: PRONxaaru: VERBci: ADPkenn: PRONmbaa: CCONJlenn: PRONi: ADPbitim: NOUNréew: NOUN.: PUNCT"},{"question":"Había una tormenta, se creía que estaba furioso. Era un dios con temperamento humano.En todas las culturas, los dioses son esencialmente personas, hasta cuando tienen otras formas o carecen de forma física.En la actualidad, muchos psicólogos piensan que creer en dioses es una extensión de nuestro reconocimiento, como animales sociales, de la existencia de otros, y de nuestra tendencia a ver el mundo en términos humanos.Proyectamos pensamientos y sentimientos humanos en otros animales ... Escribe el resto del artículo. ","answer":"Causa-efecto, la religión puede proveer una variedad de estrategias para dar significado.Las creencias religiosas le ayudan a los humanos a ordenar y encontrarle el sentido a sus vidas. Y los rituales en particular pueden \\"darle puntuación\\" a nuestras vidas, marcando los eventos más cruciales.Y los rituales son comunes en todos los grupos sociales humanos, incluidos los de ateos.Cuando nace un bebé, generalmente hay ya sea un bautizo o una ceremonia para nombrarlo: eso marca la nueva identidad del chico y le da la bienvenida al grupo social.Aunque ni la neurociencia, ni la antropología y ni siquiera la filosofía tienen la respuesta definitiva a la pregunta \\"¿Existe Dios?\\", todas esas disciplinas dan pistas sobre cómo respondemos a nuestras más profundas necesidades humanas.Quizás no estemos programados para creer en Dios o en un poder sobrenatural, pero somos animales sociales con la necesidad evolutiva de estar conectados con el mundo y con otros.De pronto las religiones son sencillamente canales para posibilitar tan significativas conexiones."},{"question":"人を怒らせることを「逆鱗に触れる」などといいますが、この「逆鱗」とは、想像上のどんな動物の鱗のことでしょう？","answer":"竜"},{"question":"உமக்குப் பிடித்த காய்கள், பழங்கள் எவை? ஏன்?","answer":"எனக்குப் பிடித்த காய்கள், பழங்கள் : கத்தரிக்காய், வெண்டைக்காய், அவரைக்காய், பாகற்காய், முள்ளங்கி, காரட், பீன்ஸ், உருளைக்கிழங்கு, பீட்ரூட், பூசணிக்காய், எல்லா வகையான கீரைகள், அன்னாசிப்பழம், கொய்யாப்பழம், மாம்பழம், திராட்சைப்பழம், பப்பாளிப்பழம் ஆகிய அனைத்தும் எனக்குப் பிடித்தவை.இவற்றை உண்பதற்கான தனித்தனிக் காரணங்கள் ஏதும் இல்லை. காய்கறிகளிலும் பழங்களிலும் தனித்தனி மருத்துவக்குணம் உள்ளது.பொதுவாகக் காய்கறிகளையும் பழங்களையும் உண்பதால் நம் உடலுக்குத் தேவையான ஊட்டச்சத்து கிடைக்கிறது. உயிர்ச்சத்து மற்றும் தாது உப்புகள் கிடைக்கும். நோய் எதிர்ப்புச் சக்தி கூடுகிறது. அதனால் நோயற்ற வாழ்வு வாழ இயலும்."},{"question":"काठमाडौं उपत्यकाको वास्तुकला र सांस्कृतिक गतिशीलतालाई आकार दिन नेवार बस्ती र शहरी योजनाको भूमिकाबारे चर्चा गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"नेवार बस्ती र शहरी योजनाले काठमाडौं उपत्यकाको वास्तुकला र सांस्कृतिक गतिशीलतालाई आकार दिन महत्त्वपूर्ण भूमिका खेलेको छ। आंगन र मन्दिरहरू सहित सहरहरूको रूपरेखाले नेवार सभ्यताको सावधानीपूर्वक योजना झल्काउँछ।"},{"question":"Tsumo inotevera inorevei?Chidamoyo hamba yakada makwati","answer":"Munhu anoita zvaanoda kana zvaafunga haafanirwi kuzorwadziwa nazvo."},{"question":"일반적으로 불이 나면 젖은 손수건으로 코와 입을 막고 몸을 최대한으로 낮추고 대피하라고 하는데... 몸을 낮춰야하는 이유를 모르겠어. 몸을 낮추면 멀리가 안보여서 탈출로가 안보이잖아. ","answer":"화재 대피 시 몸을 낮추는 것은 연기와 열로부터 안전을 유지하기 위한 것입니다. 화재로 발생하는 연소가스를 포함한 연기에는 수많은 독성 물질을 함유하고 있습니다. 이 연소가스는 화재 시 인명피해의 가장 커다란 원인이 됩니다. 이 연기의 증기 비중은 공기보다 가볍기 때문에 화재 시 천장부터 쌓이게 돼요. 그래서 연기 차단 경계벽 같은 경우 발생한 연기가 위층까지 퍼지는데 일정 시간을 지연시켜 줍니다. 따라서 몸을 낮추는 것은 화재 대피의 중요한 안전 절차 중 하나이며, 연기와 열로부터 피하고 안전한 경로를 찾는 데 도움이 됩니다."},{"question":"كنت أقرأ في تويتر ووجدت الجملة التالية '\\"ظروفك الخاصة لك وحدك ، وأدبك في الكلام حق للجميع ، لا تخلط مشاكلك وظروفك النفسية بتعاملك مع الآخرين !\\"'. هل التغريدة السابقة إيجابية سلبية او محايدة؟","answer":"التغريدة السابقة تعبر عن مشاعر سلبية."},{"question":"شكون هو النبي اللي حولات تغويه سيده القصر والبيت اللي كان تيعيش فيه؟","answer":"الإجابة:هو نبي الله يوسف عليه السلام لما كان يخدم فقصر العزيز. فبسبب جماله حولات زوجه العزيز انها تغويه وتمارس معاه الفاحشه ولكن رفض ."},{"question":"歌手/女優・元天才子役・２４時間テレビの１００ｋｍマラソンランナーで知られる女性は？","answer":"杉田かおるです。"},{"question":"ما هو مفهوم البيانات الضخمة. ","answer":" البيانات الضخمة هي مجموعات بيانات كبيرة ومعقدة مع مجموعة واسعة من التنسيقات والمصادر. يمكن أن تتضمن عينة من البيانات الضخمة مجموعة بيانات للمعاملات المالية لشركة، أو بيانات المستخدمين من منصة ألعاب عبر الإنترنت، أو بيانات حركة المرور من شبكة من الحساسات. يتم جمع هذه البيانات وتخزينها في شكلها الخام، مع إمكانية تحليلها واستخدامها لإنشاء رؤى عن المستقبل. يمكن أن تتضمن البيانات ملايين السجلات الفردية، مما يجعلها كبيرة ومعقدة جدًا لتطبيقات معالجة البيانات التقليدية. وتحتاج الى عده تقنيات من اجل تحليلها واستخراج المعلومات منها."},{"question":"Đọc đoạn văn sau và đưa ra một tiêu đề phụ hợp với nội dung:\\"BANGKOK — The Vietnamese Embassy in Thailand has swiftly contacted and provided necessary information about legal procedures for relatives of two Vietnamese citizens who drowned on Phuket Island on the morning of July 31.The victims are a woman born in 1970 and her daughter born in 2006, who are residing in Quang Trung Ward, Đống Đa District, Hà Nội. They came to Phuket with their relatives to meet business partners and travel.Lê Trung Kiên, the official in charge of citizen protection at the embassy, said the agency was coordinating with local authorities to issue necessary documents for the victims’ family members, assisting them in procedures to repatriate the bodies as soon as possible.According to the embassy, in case of needing urgent assistance in Thailand, Vietnamese citizens can contact the embassy at the hotline: +66 898966653 or directly come to the embassy at 83/1 Wireless Road, Lumpini, Pathumwan, Bangkok 10330.The embassy also urged Vietnamese citizens to be mindful of personal safety and adhere to the regulations and recommendations of the host country to avoid regrettable incidents.Thai police said there were three people involved in the drowning incident, but one survived.Initial information said the beach still had red flags warning tourists not to swim due to strong winds and rough sea waves.The two Vietnamese victims were carried 20m away from the shore, where they drowned. People who brought them to shore provided first aid but they were pronounced dead by the hospital on arrival.:","answer":"Embassy supports Vietnamese citizens drowned in Thailand"},{"question":"Гармоникалык теңдөө деген эмне ?","answer":"Гармоникалык теңдөө — сызыксыз элементтерди эквиваленттүү сызыкка келтирүү (линеаризация) принциби.Мында сызыксыз элемент зыктуу элемент менен окшош каралат. Сызыктуу элементтин гармоникалык таасирге карата реакциясы ошол таасирге карата сызыксыз элементтин реакциясынын биринчи гармоникасына дал келиш керек. Ошондо гана сызыктуу элемент сызыксыз элементке эквиваленттүү деп эсептелет.Эквиваленттүү сызыктуу элементтин иараметрлери гармоникалык таасирдин амплитудасына көз каранды."},{"question":"السؤال: ما هي أوَّل صلاة صلَّاها الرسول محمد صلَّى الله عليه وسلَّم؟","answer":"الجواب: صلاة الظهر."},{"question":"வினா : சென்னை உயர்நீதி மன்றத்தின் கிளை எங்குள்ளது?","answer":" விடை: சென்னை உயர் நீதிமன்ற மதுரைக் கிளை சென்னை உயர் நீதிமன்றத்தின் மதுரை அமர்வு இந்தியாவின் தமிழக மாநிலத்தின் மதுரை மாவட்டத்தில் இயங்கும் மாநில உயர் நீதிமன்றக்கிளையாகும்.தென் மாவட்ட மக்களின் நீண்ட போராட்டத்திற்குப் பின் மத்திய அரசு 1981ல் நீதிபதி ஜஸ்வந்த் சிங் கமிஷனை அமைத்தது. 5 ஆண்டுகளுக்குப் பிறகு மதுரையில் நிரந்தரக் கிளையமைக்க கமிஷன் பரிந்துரைத்தது.அதன் பின்னரும் ஏற்பட்ட தாமதத்தை எதிர்த்த மதுரை வழக்கறிஞர்களின் போராட்டத்தினாலும் 2002ல் பதவியேற்ற தலைமை நீதிபதி சுபாஷன் ரெட்டியின் உறுதியான முயற்சியாலும் நிலங்கள் கையகப்படுத்தப்பட்டு நீதிமன்றக் கட்டிடங்களும் உருவாயின. குடியரசுத் தலைவரின் அறிவிக்கைக்குப் பிறகு 24.7.2004ல் நிர்ணயிக்கப்பட்ட 12 நீதிபதிகளுடன் மதுரைக் கிளை 13 தென் மாவட்டங்களுக்கு நீதி பரிபாலனத்தைத் தொடங்கியது."},{"question":"เขียนประโยคต่อจากย่อหน้าต่อไปนี้ - กลุ่มเอชของฟุตบอลชิงแชมป์แห่งชาติยุโรป 2020 รอบคัดเลือก เป็นหนึ่งในสิบกลุ่มที่ใช้ตัดสินหาทีมเข้ารอบสำหรับทัวร์นาเมนต์ ฟุตบอลชิงแชมป์แห่งชาติยุโรป 2020","answer":"รอบสุดท้ายกลุ่มเอช ประกอบไปด้วยหกทีม: แอลเบเนีย, อันดอร์รา, ฝรั่งเศส, ไอซ์แลนด์, มอลโดวา และตุรกี โดยที่พวกเขาจะลงเล่นในการพบกันหมดในรูปแบบเหย้าและเยือน"},{"question":"දීප්තිමත් නොවන වස්තූන් පෙනෙන්නේ ඇයි?","answer":"දීප්ත වස්තු මගින් නිකුත් කරන ආලෝකය තිබීම නිසා දීප්ත නොවන වස්තූන් දෘශ්‍යමාන වේ."},{"question":"¿Qué significa la palabra OVNI?","answer":"OVNI significa Objeto Volador No Identificado. Es un término que fue acuñado por primera vez en los Estados Unidos (como UFO o Unidentified Flying Object en inglés) en el año 1953."},{"question":"महाराष्ट्रामध्ये कोणत्या जातीच्या शेळ्या प्रसिद्ध आहेत?(A) सुरती(B) चंबा(C) जमुना – पारी(D) गुड्डी=> ","answer":"(A) सुरती"},{"question":"පහත ගීතය ගයනා  කරන්නේ කව්ද ?මගේ නීල නෙතු සඟලින්මොනවද ඔබ ඉල්ලන්නේනළලේ කුංකුම තිලකයඔබට නේද අමතන්නේමිදුලේ නිල් පුනීල මල්හැන්දෑවේ කාන්තියෙන්ඔබ මට දුන් ඔබේ කවියඋදුරා ගෙන කියවනවාහඳ එළියේ හාන්සි වීඒ කවියේ රස වින්දාඑදා රැයේ මගේ දෑසඔබේ නමින් ඉකි බින්දා","answer":"ඉන්ද්‍රානි බෝගොඩ"},{"question":"Који су најефикаснији начини употребе лековитих биљака у кухињи и које биљке се препоручују за различите здравствене проблеме?","answer":"У кухињи се лековите биљке користе на различите начине, не само као допуна јелу, већ и као помоћник у одржавању општег здравља. На пример, прављење чајева од различитих биљака садржи мноштво витамина и минерала, а могу се припремати на неколико начина: као мацерат, инфузи или декоти. Неки од најкориснијих чајева укључују хајдучку траву за женске проблеме и плућа, нану за варење, матичњак за успокојење, коприву за крвне судове и анемију, и шипурак за јачање имунитета.Тинктуре су још један избор, иако не садрже витамине и минерале, остају лековите супстанце. Обично се припремају са 70% алкохола или воћном ракијом и одстоје 30-40 дана. Тинктура од белог лука је, на пример, одлична за чишћење крвних судова.Мед је и сам по себи врло лековит и често се користи у комбинацији са различитим биљкама. Овај природни заслађивач садржи концентрације витамина, минерала и антиоксиданата. Мед се може мешати са различитим биљкама као што су куркума, бели лук, или чак босилјак, и тако се користи за различите здравствене проблеме, од костано-мишићног система до женског репродуктивног система.За оне који желе нешто другачије, постоје и биљна вина као што је орахова траварица која је добра за штитну жлезду, или лековита уља која могу обогатити салате. На крају, не треба занемарити ни употребу зачинског биља у оброцима, као што је босилјак, који може послужити и као чај и као зачин."},{"question":"فين وصى نزار القباني باش يتدفن ؟","answer":"دمشق"},{"question":"Marina sa diso ito fanambarana manaraka ito:ny ankizy tsy ampy taona dia mahazo mitondra fiara ao Madagasikara.","answer":"Tsia diso io fanambarana io. Raha araka ny lalana ao Madagasikara dia ny olona ampy taona ka manana fahazoan-dalana ihany no mahazo mitondra fiara."},{"question":"கேள்வி:நாம் வளரும் போதே நம்முடன் சேர்ந்து வளர்வது தமிழ்மொழி எவ்வாறு? கலந்துரையாடுக.","answer":"பதில் :மாறன் : நாம் பேசுவது என்ன மொழி?கமலா : நாம் பேசுவது தமிழ்மொழி.மாறன் : நாம் ஏன் தமிழ்மொழியிலஂ பேசுகிறோம்?கமலா : தமிழ் நம் தாய்மொழி அதனாலேயே பேசுகிறோம்.மாறன் : ஏன் நாம் தமிழ்மொழியைப் பேச வேண்டும்?கமலா : நாம் தமிழ்நாட்டில் பிறந்ததனால் நமக்குத் தமிழ்மொழி தாய்மொழியாகவிளங்குகிறது. ஒவ்வொருவருக்கும் தாய்மொழி என்பது உயிர் போன்றது. உயிரை யாராவது வெறுப்பார்களா? அதனாலயே தாய்மொழியாகிய தமிழ்மொழியைப் பேச வேண்டும்.மாறன் : அப்படியானால் நாம் வளரும் போதே நம்முடன் சேர்ந்து வளருமா நம்முடைய தாய்மொழி?கமலா : ஆம் கட்டாயமாக வளரும். எப்படியென்றால், நாம் முதலில் சொல்லிப்பழகிய எழுத்து ‘அ, ஆ’ சொல்லிப் பழகிய வார்த்தை ‘அம்மா, அப்பா’. ஆனால் இன்று தமிழ் எழுத்துகள் அனைத்தையும் அறிந்துள்ளோம், வாசிக்கின்றோம். அதைப்போல அதிகமான சொற்களைப் பேசுகின்றோம், எழுதுகின்றோம், வாசிக்கின்றோம். அப்படியென்றால் நம்முடன் சேர்ந்து தமிழ் மொழியும் வளர்ந்துள்ளது என்றுதானே அர்த்தம். அதுதான் உண்மையும் கூட என்பது புரியவில்லையா?மாறன் : புரிந்து கொண்டேன். உண்மைதான் புரியவைத்ததற்கு நன்றி!"},{"question":"සාගරයේ ගැඹුරුම ස්ථානය කුමක්ද?","answer":"සාගරයේ ගැඹුරුම ස්ථානය පැසිපික්‌ සාගරයේ මරියානා ආගාධයයි. ගැඹුර මීටර 12000 යි. බටහිර ශාන්තිකර සාගරයෙහි එය පිහිටා ඇත්තේ, මරියානා දූපත් වලට නැගෙනහිර දෙසට වන්නටය. අගාධය 2,550 කිලෝමීටර (1,580 mi) පමණ දිගු වන අතර දළ වශයෙන් එහි පළල වන්නේ 69 කිලෝමීටර (43 සැතපුම්) ක් පමණි. ගැඹුරුතම කොටස 11.03 කිලෝමීටර (6.85 සැතපුම්) යැයි එක් වරක් පමණත් සිදු කල සමහරක් මිනුම් ඇසුරෙන් ප්‍රකාශ කෙරුනත් එහි දකුණු දිශා කෙලවරෙහි, පතුලෙහි පිහිටි ඇලි-හැඩැති කුඩා නිම්නයක් වන චැලෙන්ජර් ඩීප් හිදී, එහි උපරිම-ගැඹුර වන 10.91 කිලෝමීටර (6.78 සැත) (35,800 අඩි) පමණ ප්‍රමාණය වාර්තා වී ඇත."},{"question":"Nahoana no zava-dehibe ny fitantanana ny ala maharitra?1-Mba hisorohana ny fandripahana ala2-Mba hiarovana ny elefanta3-Ho fanohanana ny indostrian'ny hazo","answer":"Valiny: 1. Mba hisorohana ny fandripahana ala"},{"question":"漢字で魚へんに里と書くとコイ。では魚へんに平と書くと何？","answer":"ひらめです。"},{"question":"Tama o mali: Ang Laguna de Bay ang pinakamalaking lawa sa Pilipinas.","answer":"Tama. Ang Laguna de Bay ay may lawak na 911.7 kilometro kwadrado."},{"question":"Ndi mzinda uti wa ku Africa womwe umakhulupirira kuti ndi wakale kwambiri ku Africa?","answer":"Mzinda Wakale Kwambiri ku Africa: Mzinda wa ThebesMzinda wakale kwambiri mu Africa unali mzinda wa Thebes. Uwu unali likulu la ufumu wotchuka wa Egypt m’nthawi ya Middle and New Kingdoms. Unali pa mtsinje wa Nile, pafupifupi makilomita 900 kum’mwera kwa Cairo. Idakhalapo kuyambira 1500 mpaka 1000 BCE."},{"question":"Lan mooy Y en a marre ?","answer":"Ag kuréel la gu sosu ci Senegaal ci saawiye 2011, mu boole ay rapkat, saabalkat, liggéeykat ak i jàngalekat."},{"question":"次の文章から重要な語彙を探し、その意味を説明しなさい。 ブラジルのサンパウロで、日本の生活の中にあるデザインを紹介する展示会が始まりました。日本政府がつくった「ジャパン・ハウス」が開いています。会場には、岩手県の縄文時代の遺跡で見つかった、土で作った入れ物などが展示されています。1万年前の生活の中にも細かいデザインがあったことがわかります。船のプロペラは岡山県の会社が作りました。いちばんいい形をいろいろ考えて、美しくてむだがないデザインになりました。ジャパン・ハウスの人は「生活の中にデザインや美しさがあるという日本の考えは、私たちブラジル人にも勉強になります」と話していました。","answer":"この文章に出てくる重要な語彙とその意味は次の通りである。- デザイン: 1）物を作るときに、形や色などを工夫すること。2）行おうとすることについて、そのやり方を考えること。3）図案。意匠。- 展示: 1）品物を並べて、多くの人に見せること。- 政府: 1）国の政治を行うところ。2）内閣。- 縄文時代: 1）縄文土器を作って使っていた時代。12000年ほど前から2300年前ごろの間。- 遺跡: 1）歴史的な出来事や建物のあった場所。- 土: 1）岩や石がくだけて、粉になったもの。どろ。2）陸地の表面。地面。- 入れ物: 1）物を入れる器。- プロペラ: 1）軸の周りを回る、回転羽根。飛行機や船などを動かすもの。- むだ: 1）役に立たないこと。効果がないこと。- 考え: 1）考えること。また、考えた内容。"},{"question":"Тоголок Молдо ким болгон?","answer":"Байымбет Абдракман уулу (1890-1942).Кыргыз элинин демократ, агартуучу, классик-жазма акыны Байымбет Абдыракман уулу(Тоголок Молдо) 1860-жылы кулжа айында Тянь-Шань областынын Ак-Талаа районундагы Куртка деген айылда, орто дыйкандын үй-бүлөсүндө туулган.Байымбеттин атасы-Абдыракман өз оокатына тын, \\"айыл ичинде кээде ырдай коюп журген адам болгон. Байымбетти кичинесинен эле айылдагы балаокуткан молдого берет. Зээндүү Байымбет кыска убакыттын ичинде кат таанып, китеп окууга жарайт.Өн төртүндүдө атасы Абдыракман дүйнөдөн кайтып, Байымбет өзүнүн кичүү иниси Байтымбет, карындаштары Каныкей, Канышай болуп чон атасы Му-зоокенин колунда калат. Музооке эл арасына белгилүү чон комузчу жана текме ырчы болгон. Болочок акындын талантынын өсүшүнө зор таасирин тийгизген."},{"question":"En iyi 2 futbolcu kim Ronaldo?","answer":"Listenin birinci sırasında Lionel Messi yer alırken, Cristiano Ronaldo, Maradona'nın ardından üçüncü sıranın sahibi oldu. Galatasaray'ın unutulmaz isimlerinden olan ve sarı-kırmızılı formayla birçok kupa kazanan George Hagi ise listeye 100. sıradan girmeyi başardı."},{"question":"Ci gan kembaar la réewum Ghana nékk?","answer":"Réewum Ghana mu ngi nékk ci kembaar bi ñuy wakh Afrique."},{"question":"Дати стисле визначення слову \\"легенда\\" згідно змісту наступного тексту: Легенда — жанр фольклору і літератури, прозова малосюжетна оповідь міфологічного, апокрифічного чи історико-героїчного змісту з обов'язковою спрямованістю на вірогідність зображуваних подій та специфікою побудови сюжету на основі своєрідних композиційних прийомів (метаморфози, антропоморфізації предметів, явищ природи тощо). В переносному значенні легенда — вигадана чи прикрашена розповідь. ","answer":"Легенда - це оповідь міфологічного чи історичного змісту, а в переносному значенні - вигадана розповідь."},{"question":"Ayat 1: Sistem baru CCE juga dilaksanakan di sekolah untuk penilaian pelajar secara menyeluruh dan berterusan. Ayat 2: Sistem baru CCE juga dilaksanakan di sekolah untuk penilaian pelajar secara berterusan dan menyeluruh. Soalan: Apakah ayat 1 dan ayat 2 menyatakan makna yang sama? Ya atau tidak?","answer":"Ya, betul."},{"question":"Qual país produz mais lã?","answer":"Até 2023, a China vem sendo de longe o maior produtor de lã do mundo, seguida de perto pela Austrália e Nova Zelândia. Embora os níveis de produção variem ano a ano em cada país, eles permanecem em grande parte inalterados nas quantidades mais altas anualmente."},{"question":"కింది వాక్యాన్ని ఏ రీతి వాక్యం అని గుర్తించి రాయండి.దయచేసి నన్ను కాపాడు.","answer":"ప్రార్థనాద్యర్థక వాక్యం"},{"question":"Indro  misy fanehoan-kevitra:\\"Raha ny avy any Afrika dia tsy antenaiko fa vahoaka mahantra no any.\\"Maneho endrika fanavakavahana na fanafintohinana ve io fanehoan-kevitra io?","answer":"Maneho fanavakavahana ara-piaviana io fanehoan-kevitra io satria tsy manome fitokisana olona noho ny izy avy any Afrika."},{"question":"السؤال: من الذي بعثه الرسول صلى الله عليه وسلم إلى كسرى ؟","answer":"الإجابة: عبدالله بن حذافة السهمي"},{"question":"Nitori agidi, ọkọ kọ Basira silẹ n’Ibadan, o loun ko ṣe mọ","answer":"Oloye Ademọla Ọdunade, ẹni ti ṣe Aarẹ kootu k’ọkọ-k’ọkọ to wa ni Mapo, niluu Ibadan, ipinlẹ Ọyọ, ti tu igbeyawo ọdun mẹrinlelogun kan lori wahala buruku tawọn lọkọ-laya n ba ara wọn fa ka.Ọlalekan Ṣoẹtan ati iyawo ẹ, Basirat, ni wọn jọ wọra wọn lọ siwaju adajọ ọhun, nibi ti ọkọ ti fẹsun kan iyawo ẹ pe alagidi ni. O ni ki i gbọnran, bẹẹ lawọn obi ẹ paapaa fara mọ gbogbo iwa ti obinrin naa hu si oun lọọdẹ, ati pe ẹnu oun ko ka a mọ rara.Ọkunrin oniṣowo yii ti waa bẹ Aarẹ ile-ẹjọ naa ko tu awọn ka, ki kaluku maa ba tiẹ lọ.Ni bayii, Oloye Ademọla Ọdunade ti ni ki awọn ọmọ meji to dagba ju ninu awọn ọmọ ti tọkọ-taya yii bi funra wọn maa ba baba wọn, Ṣoẹtan gbe, nigba ti eyi to kere ju laarin wọn gbọdọ maa gbe lọdọ Basirat, iyẹn iya wọn.O ni ki alaafia le jọba laarin awọn mejeeji loun ṣe gbe idajọ ọhun kalẹ, ati pe ohun to foju han ni pe ko si ifẹ ati irẹpọ gidi mọ laarin wọn. Bakan naa lo ti paṣẹ fun ọkunrin yii lati maa fun iyawo ẹ ni ẹgbẹrun marun-un naira (N5000) gẹgẹ bii owo ounjẹ fun itọju ọmọ.Ninu ọrọ Basira lo ti bẹ adajọ ko fun oun lanfaani lati ko awọn ọmọ oun sọdọ nitori igbeyawo ọhun ti su oun naa paapaa, ati pe ọkunrin kan ti ko nilaari rara, ti ki i ṣe ojuṣe ẹ deede ni Ọlalekan n ṣe."},{"question":"tell me some interesting Do you know in Urdu.","answer":"کیا آپ جانتے ہیں: • …کہ دنیا کا سب سے لمبا پہاڑی سلسلہ کوہ انڈیز ہے جو جنوبی امریکہ میں واقع ہے۔ • …کہ ایڈا لولیس (تصویر میں) کو دنیا کی سب سے پہلی کمپیوٹر پروگرامر کے طور پر جانا جاتا ہے۔ • …کہ دنیا کا بدترین زلزلہ 1556ء کو چین میں آیا جس کے نتیجے میں 8 لاکھ 30 ہزار افراد ہلاک ہو ئے۔ • …کہ آرمینیا 301 عیسوی میں عیسائیت کو مذہب کے طور پر قبول کرنے والا پہلا ملک تھا۔ • …کہ اسنوکر کی ابتدا 1875ء میں ہندوستان سے شروع ہوئی۔ • … کہ فرڈیننڈ میگلان نے پہلی بار کرہ ارض کا بحری چکر مکمل کرنے کی کوشش کی، مگر وہ فلپائن کے قریب مر گیا تو اس کے جہاز پر موجود ایک دوسرے مہم جو خوان سباسٹین ایلکانو نے اس بیڑے کی قیادت کی اور اس طرح وہ پہلا شخص بن گیا جس کی سرکردگی میں انسان نے زمین کے گرد پہلا بحری سفر مکمل کیا۔ • … کہ ارشمیدس کی ایجاد کردہ توپیں اس قدر مضبوط تھیں کہ سیراکیوز کامحاصرہ کرنے والے جنرل کلاڈیس کو شہر پر قبضہ کرنے میں پورے تین سال لگے۔ سیراکیوز پر قبضہ کرنے کے بعد کلاڈیس نے ارشمیدس کومعاف کرنے کا حکم جاری کیا۔ لیکن ایک سپاہی نے اُسے غلطی سے قتل کر دیا۔ • … کہ تاریخ کی سو انتہائی متاثر کن شخصیات نامی کتاب میں مائیکل ایچ ہارٹ نے عمر بن خطاب کو آج تک کی 100 متاثر کن شخصیات کی فہرست میں باون درجہ پر رکھا ہے۔ • …کہ سندھ میں واقع قلعہ رانی کوٹ دنیا کا سب سے بڑا قلعہ ہے اور اس کی لمبائی تقریباً 32 کلومیٹر (20 میل) ہے۔ • …کہ برطانوی پرچم 1707ء میں اسکاٹ لینڈ ، انگلینڈ اور شمالی آئرلینڈ کے پرچم کو ملا کر بنایا گیا تھا۔ • …کہ صبیحہ گوکچن (تصویر میں) دنیا کی پہلی خاتون ہوا باز تھیں اور وہ ترکیہ کے پہلے صدر مصطفٰی کمال اتاترک کی سوتیلی بیٹی تھیں۔ • …کہ مراکش میں واقع مسجد حسن ثانی کا مینار دنیا کا سب سے بلند مینار ہے جس کی بلندی 210 میٹر(689 فٹ) ہے۔ • …کہ ترکیہ کا شہر استنبول دنیا کا واحد شہر ہے جو دو براعظموں میں واقع ہے۔"},{"question":"Aşure şeker yükseltir mi?","answer":"İnsülin direnci: Aşure, içerdiği yüksek karbonhidrat ve şeker nedeniyle insülin seviyelerini yükseltebilir."},{"question":"කව්පි යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"කව්පි (Cowpea) යනු ආහාරයට ගන්නා ඇට වර්ගයකි. කවුපී (Black-eyed pea) උපවිශේෂයක් වේ."},{"question":"\\"Budapest\\" no renivohitr'i Romania . Marina sa diso?","answer":"Diso. \\"Budapest\\" dia renivohitr'i Hongria . \\"Bucarest\\" no renivohitr'i Romania."},{"question":"س296- شكون هو الخليفه العباسي الثامن اللي تزوج ثمانيه دالمرات وعندو ثمانيه ديال الاولاد وحكم ثمن سنين ؟","answer":"ج296- المعتصم بالله"},{"question":"msinjiro ndi chani?","answer":"ndi ntedza osinja ndipo utha kuphikidwa limodzi ndi ndiwo zosiyana siyana monga masamba, usipa wa bonya. Nsinjiro zitha kuphikidwa limodzi ndi  mphara la mpunga ndi la ufa wa chimanga."},{"question":"Мага кызыктуу факты жазып бересиңби?","answer":"Албетте, мына сизге кызыктуу факты: Булгаары буюмдарынан чыккан жыттар бул- \\"булгаары жыты\\" жыпар жыттары.  Чыныгы  тери жыттанбайт."},{"question":"ਬੰਗਲੌਰ ਦੇ ਯੇਲਹਾਂਕਾ ਫ਼ੌਜੀ ਹਵਾਈ ਅੱਡੇ ਦੀ ਪਾਰਕਿੰਗ ਵਿੱਚ ਲੱਗੀ ਅੱਗ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਮੌਕੇ ਦਾ ਜਾਇਜ਼ਾ ਲੈਂਦੇ ਹੋਏ ਰੱਖਿਆ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਨਿਰਮਲਾ ਸੀਤਾਰਾਮਨ।ਅੱਗ ਕਿੱਥੇ ਲੱਗੀ?","answer":"ਬੈਂਗਲੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਯੇਲਹੰਕਾ ਮਿਲਟਰੀ ਏਅਰਪੋਰਟ ਦੀ ਪਾਰਕਿੰਗ ਵਿੱਚ ਅੱਗ ਲੱਗ ਗਈ।"},{"question":"Compare and contrast the literary styles of William Shakespeare and Ernest Hemingway.","answer":"William Shakespeare, a playwright and poet from the Elizabethan era, and Ernest Hemingway, a 20th-century American novelist, had vastly different literary styles shaped by their respective times and personal experiences. Shakespeare's language is characterized by its rich, poetic, and often iambic pentameter structure. He employed elaborate metaphors, soliloquies, and intricate wordplay. His works, ranging from tragedies to comedies, explored universal themes of love, betrayal, ambition, and political intrigue. Ernest Hemingway, on the other hand, is known for his concise and straightforward prose. He often employed the \\"Iceberg Theory,\\" suggesting that there's more beneath the surface of his simple sentences than meets the eye. His narratives are typically sparse, with a focus on showing rather than telling. Hemingway's works often delve into themes of war, love, loss, and human endurance. While Shakespeare's style is ornate and filled with lyrical beauty, Hemingway's is terse and direct. Both, however, have left indelible marks on the literary world with their unique voices and perspectives."},{"question":"Hãy đặt một tiêu đề phù hợp với đoạn văn sau: Theo Thiếu tướng Joseph McGee - Tư lệnh Sư đoàn Nhảy dù 101 của Mỹ, việc triển khai quân đội đến các quốc gia ở sườn đông nam của NATO cho thấy cam kết của Mỹ ở khu vực. \\"Việc triển khai quân đội tham gia cuộc tập trận này, và quan trọng hơn, việc triển khai của chúng tôi tới Romania, Bulgaria, Hungary và Slovakia là nhằm thể hiện những cam kết chặt chẽ của Mỹ đối với các đồng minh NATO. Những quốc gia này cũng đã cùng tham gia các chiến dịch của quân đội Mỹ tại Afghanistan và thật vinh dự khi được diễn tập cùng họ\\", Thiếu tướng Joseph McGee nêu rõ. Trong cuộc tập trận này, các binh sĩ thuộc Sư đoàn Nhảy dù 101 của Mỹ đã thực hiện các bài diễn tập chiến đấu từ trực thăng và máy bay phản lực bay theo đội hình. Trong một tuyên bố trên trang web, lực lượng quân đội Mỹ ở châu Âu cho biết, các binh sĩ thuộc Lực lượng Nhảy dù 101 đã bắt đầu đến Romania từ cuối tháng 6 vừa qua. Động thái này là một phần trong sứ mệnh hỗ trợ các lực lượng NATO của Mỹ, trấn an các đồng minh, đồng thời thể hiện cam kết \\"sắt đá\\" của Mỹ tại các khu vực ở sườn phía Đông trong bối cảnh căng thẳng giữa Nga và Ukraine. *, Trong khi đó, Mỹ, Nhật Bản, Hàn Quốc sẽ bắt đầu khởi động cuộc tập trận tên lửa chung nhằm phát hiện và theo dõi tên lửa đạn đạo ở vùng biển ngoài khơi Hawaii, vào ngày mai (1/8). Theo nguồn tin từ quân đội Hàn Quốc, ba nước sẽ tiến hành tập trận chung mang tên \\"Rồng Thái Bình Dương\\" (Pacific Dragon) kéo dài cho đến hết ngày 14/8 tới. Cuộc diễn tập quân sự này được khởi động đúng thời điểm diễn ra tập trận hàng hải đa quốc gia Vành đai Thái Bình Dương (RIMPAC) 2022, tập trung vào việc cải thiện khả năng phối hợp chiến thuật và kỹ thuật giữa các bên tham gia, bao gồm phát hiện, theo dõi và báo cáo các mục tiêu đạn đạo. Dự kiến 8 tàu nổi và 2 máy bay sẽ tham gia tập trận, trong đó đáng chú ý là Hàn Quốc sẽ triển khai khu trục hạm lớp Sejong Đại đế. Hải quân Hàn Quốc từng tham gia cuộc tập trận chung được tổ chức hai năm một lần này vào năm 2018 và 2020 dưới thời chính quyền của cựu Tổng thống Moon Jae-in, song không tiết lộ thông tin chi tiết về cuộc tập trận này vào thời điểm đó.","answer":"Mỹ tập trận với Romania gần Biển Đen"},{"question":"次の文章を読んで、その内容に適したタイトルを付けてください： 今月8日、台風13号が原因で雨がとてもたくさん降って、福島県や千葉県、茨城県などで被害が出ました。福島県いわき市では1200ぐらいの家に水が入りました。宮小学校と宮幼稚園は、川の水が建物の中に入って電気や水道が止まっているため、休みになっています。千葉県では鉄道に大きな被害が出ました。JR外房線は、線路の近くの土が流れたため、誉田駅と大網駅の間で運転できなくなっています。JRは、この駅の間はバスで客を運んでいます。いすみ鉄道は、線路の下の土が崩れて、線路が浮いている所があります。いすみ鉄道も運転できない駅の間でバスを使っています。小湊鐵道も運転できなくなっている所があります。茨城県日立市では、市役所の近くの川の水があふれました。市役所は、地下に水が入って電気が止まったため、10日の朝まで仕事ができませんでした。","answer":"福島県と千葉県と茨城県　雨がたくさん降って被害が出た"},{"question":"Hai phương pháp Lasik và Femto Lasik đều là Lasik. Vậy cho cháu hỏi hai phương pháp này có gì khác nhau? Phương pháp nào an toàn hơn ạ?","answer":"Chào bạn, Lasik là phương pháp cắt vạt giác mạc bằng dao cơ học. Trong quá trình cắt, có thể xảy ra biến chứng như hớt vạt, rách vạt… Để thay thế dao cơ học, người ta sử dụng tia laser Femto để cắt vạt, giúp tăng độ chính xác và giảm biến chứng, nên gọi là Femto – Lasik."},{"question":"Indro misy lahatsoratra:Any atsimo andrefana, tsy lavitra an’i Toliara no misy ny tanàna kely antsoina hoe Tanambe Manirisoa izay faritra maina, voahodidina raketa. Ny faharatsian’ny kalitaon’ny tany sy ny tsy fikojakojana ny lava-drano fatsakana misy eo an-toerana no nahatonga olona manodidina ny 250 eo ho eo mampiasa rano ambanin’ny tany ho an’ny filàn’izy reo andavanandro, indrindra ho an’ny fidiovana, fandrahoan-tsakafo, fanasan-damba ary hatramin’ny rano ho an’ny biby fiompy, ny fambolena nandritra ny 7 taona mahery.Avy aiza ny rano ampiasain'ny olona manodidina ny 250 ao Tanambe Manirisoa?","answer":"Avy any ambanin'ny tany ny rano ampiasain'ireo olona manodidina ny 250 ao Tanambe Manirisoa."},{"question":"烤肉需要哪些工具？","answer":"答：烤肉通常需要烤架、炭火或煤气炉、食品夹子或叉子、刷子（用于刷油或酱汁）、切割工具等。"},{"question":"اشرح قانون مور بشكل مبسط.","answer":"قانون مور هو ملاحظة صنعها مؤسس شركة إنتل غوردون مور بأن عدد الترانزستورات في المعالج الدقيق يتضاعف كل عامين، مما يزيد من سرعة وأداء الحواسيب بشكل متسارع. وقد استمر هذا الاتجاه منذ توقعه في عام 1965، وتم اتباعه من قبل الصناعات من أجل الحفاظ على وتيرة الابتكار السريعة."},{"question":"Mwanamke ","answer":"Huyu ni mwanadamu mwenye jinsia ya kike , ambaye ameisha olewa na mme, na kupata watoto "},{"question":"Hãy tiếp tục đoạn văn sau: Đơn kiện được đệ trình chỉ vài giờ sau khi thẩm phán Kathaleen McCormicl của Toà án Delaware ấn định phiên toà xét xử vào ngày 17.10 và kéo dài trong 5 ngày. Động thái này của Elon Musk được đánh giá sẽ khiến căng thẳng giữa vị tỉ phú và Twitter ngày càng leo thang. Đơn kiện dài 164 trang được đội ngũ pháp lý của Elon Musk đệ trình lên Toà án Delaware và yêu cầu \\"bảo mật thông tin\\". Mặc dù vậy, theo quy định của toà án, một bản tóm tắt sẽ sớm được công bố rộng rãi. Mặc dù hai bên về cơ bản đã đồng ý với phiên toà xét xử vào ngày 17.10, nhưng lại phát sinh mâu thuẫn về việc phát hiện và tiếp cận các tài liệu nội bộ cùng các bằng chứng khác. Trong tuần","answer":"này, Elon Musk cáo buộc Twitter đã cố tình chậm trễ trong việc phản hồi những yêu cầu của ông, trong khi Twitter phản bác rằng vị tỉ phú đang tìm kiếm một lượng lớn dữ liệu không liên quan đến vấn đề chính của vụ kiện. Trước đó, vào tháng 4, Elon Musk tuyên bố sẽ mua lại Twitter với giá 44 tỉ USD. Tuy nhiên, 3 tháng sau khi ký thoả thuận, vị tỉ phú muốn chấm dứt thương vụ, viện dẫn lý do Twitter không cung cấp thông tin về số lượng tài khoản giả mạo trên nền tảng mà ông yêu cầu. Ngay sau đó Twitter đã đệ đơn kiện lên Toà án Delaware, cáo buộc Elon Musk không tuân thủ thoả thuận và gây ra nhiều thiệt hại cho công ty. Twitter muốn thực hiện các hành động pháp lý để ép CEO Tesla phải hoàn tất thương vụ. Ngoài ra, Elon Musk cũng phải đối mặt với một phiên tòa kéo dài một tuần ở Wilmington, Delaware, bắt đầu từ 24.10. Một cổ đông Tesla đã kiện ông Musk vì làm lãng phí nguồn lực công ty và làm giàu bất chính với gói trả lương 56 tỉ USD của mình. Elon Musk còn bị Luigi Crispo, một cổ đông của Twitter kiện. Người này cho rằng vị tỉ phú đã vi phạm nghĩa vụ uỷ thác của mình đối với các cổ đông Twitter và phải bồi thường thiệt hại cho những tổn thất mà ông gây ra."},{"question":"How does a SWOT analysis contribute to project feasibility assessment?","answer":"SWOT analysis systematically evaluates Strengths, Weaknesses, Opportunities, and Threats to understand project feasibility and establish achievable project goals."},{"question":"ಮುಂದಿನ ಪ್ರಶ್ನೆಗೆ ಉತ್ತರ ನೀಡಿ: ಯಾರು ಸೌಂದರ್ಯ ಮತ್ತು ಬೀಸ್ಟ್ನ ಕೊನೆಯಲ್ಲಿ ಹಾಡನ್ನು ಹಾಡುತ್ತಾರೆ","answer":"ಜೋಶ್ ಗ್ರೋಬನ್"},{"question":"Tani ọba Benin lọ́wọ́lọ́wọ́ ní Nàìjíríà?","answer":"Ewuare II"},{"question":"Tambaya: Shin ya Halatta ayi magana yayin huɗubar Juma’a?","answer":"Amsa: Haramun ne a yi magana yayin huɗubar Juma’a koda ko umarni da kyakkyawa da hani da mummuna ne, wannan babu saɓani tsaƙanin maluma akan haramcin haka"},{"question":"ما اسم المعركة الأهلية الأمريكية التي شهدت أعلى نسبة قتلى خلال يوم واحد فقط؟  ","answer":"معركة أنتيتام."},{"question":"Dựa trên tiêu đề sau, hãy viết một bài báo nói về chủ đề này: Giá xăng ngày mai liệu có giảm?","answer":"Trên thị trường thế giới, giá dầu thô mấy ngày gần đây có xu hướng tăng trở lại. Theo dữ liệu từ Oilprice, vào lúc 10 giờ sáng nay, 31-7 (giờ Việt Nam), giá dầu thô Brent được giao dịch ở mức 104 USD/thùng, tăng 2,1% so với ngày hôm qua. Cùng thời điểm, giá dầu ngọt nhẹ WTI được giao dịch ở mức 98,62 USD/thùng, tăng 2,28% so với ngày hôm qua. Do giá xăng, dầu thế giới có xu hướng tăng nên giá bán lẻ xăng dầu trong nước tại kỳ điều hành ngày mai 1-8 được dự báo sẽ tăng theo giá xăng, dầu thế giới. Lãnh đạo một số doanh nghiệp đầu mối kinh doanh xăng dầu cho biết, giá bán lẻ xăng trong nước đang cao hơn giá xăng thành phẩm trung bình tại thị trường Singapore khoảng 208-343 đồng/lít. Giá dầu diesel, dầu hỏa trong nước cũng đang cao hơn thị trường Singapore khoảng 632-847 đồng/lít. Vì vậy, trong kỳ điều hành ngày 1-8, nếu cơ quan quản lý không trích Quỹ bình ổn giá xăng dầu thì mức giảm sẽ tương đương mức chênh. Theo đó, giá xăng có thể giảm khoảng 200-350 đồng/lít, còn giá dầu có khả năng giảm từ 600-850 đồng/lít. Tuy nhiên, mức giảm này còn phụ thuộc vào việc trích lập Quỹ bình ổn giá xăng, dầu. Nếu cơ quan quản lý chi Quỹ bình ổn nhiều thì giá xăng, dầu trong nước vào ngày 1-8 chỉ giảm rất nhẹ. Nếu đúng như dự báo, giá xăng trong nước sẽ có lần giảm thứ 4 liên tiếp. Tính từ đầu năm tới nay, giá xăng dầu đã trải qua 19 lần điều chỉnh giá, trong đó có 13 lần tăng và 6 lần giảm. "},{"question":"Ọlọrun ti kọyin si ẹgbẹ APC – Makinde","answer":"Gomina ipinlẹ Ọyọ, Ẹnjinnia Oluṣeyi Makinde ti ṣọ pe o yẹ kawọn ọmọ Naijiria fura bayii pe Ọlọrun ti kọyin si ẹgbẹ oṣelu to n ṣejọba lọwọ yii, iyẹn APC, o ni omi ti tan lẹyin ẹja wọn.Atẹjade kan ti gomina naa fi sode lẹyin ipade to ṣe pẹlu awọn adari ẹgbẹ oṣelu PDP lati ẹkun Iwọ-Oorun l’Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee yii, eyi to waye nile ijọba to wa l’Agodi, n’Ibadan, lo ti sọrọ naa pe gbogbo awọn ti wọn ti n polongo ibo silẹ de ọdun 2023, atawọn to ṣẹṣẹ fẹẹ bẹrẹ, ṣugbọn to jẹ ẹgbẹ APC yii ni wọn fẹẹ ba jade maa kabaamọ gbẹyin ni, tori ẹgbẹ t’Ọlọrun ti kọyin si ni.Ọgbẹni Taiwo Adisa to jẹ Akọwe iroyin gomina lo sọ eyi di mimọ ninu atẹjade kan to tẹ akọroyin wa lọwọ pe Ṣeyi Makinde ṣekilọ fawọn aṣaaju ẹgbẹ PDP ti wọn n jẹjọ lọdọ ajọ EFCC, ti wọn fẹẹ tori ẹ kuro lẹgbẹ ọhun pe ki wọn tun ero wọn pa.O ni ẹwọn ti wọn n sa fun naa lẹgbẹ APC ṣi maa ran wọn tori bo ṣe ṣẹlẹ si gomina ipinlẹ Plateau tẹlẹ, Joshua Dariye, niyẹn, gomina ipinlẹ Taraba tẹlẹ, Rẹfurẹndi Jolly Nyame, titi kan tipinlẹ Abia igba kan, Orji Uzor Kalu, to ṣẹṣẹ jade lẹwọn laipẹ yii.O ni arun oju ni bi iṣejọba APC ṣe ri, ko sẹni to wa lorileede yii ti ko mọ bi iṣakoso naa ṣe nira to.Makinde waa rọ awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ oṣelu rẹ tinu n bi lati duro de igbimọ apẹtusaawọ ti Ọlagunsoye Oyinlọla ṣe alaga rẹ, ki wọn baa le ojutuu si ohunkohun to ba n bi wọn ninu. O lo da oun loju pe didun lọsan yoo so."},{"question":"Emi o sa lọ o, mo wa nilẹ Benin lati ṣatilẹyin fun Sunday Igboho ni-Ọjọgbọn Akintoye","answer":"Olori Ilana Oodua, Ọjọgbọn Banji Akitoye, ti sọ pe irọ to jinna si ootọ ni pe oun sa kuro ni orileede Naijiria. Baba to ti figba kan jẹ olukọ lawọn ileewe giga yunifasiti ni Amẹrika yii sọ pe oun wa ni orileede Olominira Benin lati ṣe atilẹyin fun Sunday ni, bi wọn ba si ti fi ajijagbara ọmọ Yoruba naa silẹ loun n pada bọ nile.Baba ṣalaye ọrọ yii ninu atẹjade kan ti akọwe iroyin rẹ, Maxwell Adelẹyẹ, gbe jade lọjọ Aiku, Sannde, ọsẹ yii.‘Loootọ ni mo wa ni ilẹ Olominira Benin, ṣugbọn ki i ṣe pe mo sa lọ, mo wa nibẹ lati mojuto gbogbo igbokegbodo awọn agbẹjọro ati gbogbo igbesẹ to ba yẹ lati ri i pe a gba Sunday Adeyẹmọ ti gbogbo eeyan mọ si Igboho kuro lahaamọ ni.’Akintoye ni bo ṣe jẹ pe Igboho ko ṣẹ ẹṣẹ kankan loun naa ko ṣẹ ẹnikẹni, oun ko si ṣe lodi sofin Naijiria ti yoo fi di pe ẹnikan yoo maa halẹ mọ oun tabi mu oun.‘Ominira Yoruba ni a n wa, ofin agbaye fara mọ ọn, ofin Naijiria paapaa ko lodi si ki a beere fun iru nnkan bayii. Ohun yoowu ti ijọba Buhari le maa gbero si mi, mo fẹẹ fi da yin loju pe mo n pada bọ ni Naijiria, nitori mi o ṣẹ si ofin kankan to le mu ki wọn maa wa mi kiri tabi halẹ mọ mi.‘Gẹgẹ bii akọni ologun, mo ṣetan lati pada si orileede Naijiria bi ohun gbogbo lori ọrọ Sunday Igboho ba ti yanju.’ Bẹẹ ni Baba Akintoye sọ ninu apa kan ninu atẹjade naa."},{"question":"ഇനിപ്പറയുന്ന ചോദ്യത്തിന് ഉത്തരം നൽകുക. ചോദ്യം: എന്താണ് മോണ്ട് ബ്ലാങ്ക്?","answer":"ഫ്രാൻസിനും ഇറ്റലിക്കും ഇടയിലുള്ള അതിർത്തിയിൽ ആൽപ്‌സിലെയും പടിഞ്ഞാറൻ യൂറോപ്പിലെയും ഏറ്റവും ഉയരം കൂടിയ കൊടുമുടിയാണ് മോണ്ട് ബ്ലാങ്ക്. പർവതാരോഹണത്തിന് പേരുകേട്ട ഇത് ലോകമെമ്പാടുമുള്ള സാഹസികരെയും മലകയറ്റക്കാരെയും ആകർഷിക്കുന്നു. മോണ്ട് ബ്ലാങ്ക് അതിമനോഹരമായ കാഴ്ചകൾ പ്രദാനം ചെയ്യുന്നു, ഈ മേഖലയിലെ ടൂറിസം വ്യവസായത്തിന്റെ ഒരു പ്രധാന ഭാഗമാണിത്."},{"question":"السؤال: أي طائر هو رمز عالمي للسلام؟","answer":"الإجابة: الحمامة"},{"question":"Fenoy ny banga _ :\\" Ny tsiny izany dia _ ataon’ny mpiara-belona amin’ny olona iray noho ny fahadisoana nataony na tandrina na tsy tandrina izany. Mety tsy fahafaham-po na tsy fahafenoana na kilema ihany koa ny tsiny, araka ny fitenenana hoe: “Indrokelin’ny mpandrafitra” sy ny hoe “tovovavy tsara tarehy petak’orona ka voatandro iray no tsininy.”\\"","answer":" Ny tsiny izany dia fanamelohana ataon’ny mpiara-belona amin’ny olona iray noho ny fahadisoana nataony na tandrina na tsy tandrina izany. Mety tsy fahafaham-po na tsy fahafenoana na kilema ihany koa ny tsiny, araka ny fitenenana hoe: “Indrokelin’ny mpandrafitra” sy ny hoe “tovovavy tsara tarehy petak’orona ka voatandro iray no tsininy.”"},{"question":"Inona avy ireo fiovana eo amin'ny fihetsika hateraky ny testosterona amin'ny vehivavy?","answer":"Ny testosterona amin'ny vehivavy dia miteraka fiovana eo amin'ny fihetsika toy ny:-Herisetra-Fahasahina-Fiakaran'ny fanirina hanao firaisana ara-nofo"},{"question":"Takip eden paragrafı tamamlayınız: Vejetaryanlar, hayvanların haklarına ve refahlarına saygı duyar. Endüstriyel hayvan yetiştirme ve kesim yöntemlerinin, hayvanların acı çekmesine ve ","answer":"kötü koşullarda yaşamasına yol açabileceğini düşünürler. Et tüketiminin azaltılması veya durdurulması, bu sorunların azalmasına katkıda bulunabileceğine inanırlar."},{"question":"Туулган күнгө карата куттуктоо жазып бере аласыңбы  ?","answer":"Туулган күнүңүз жакшы болуп, өмүрүңүздө эч качан көгөрбөңүз. Себеби сиздин жылмайганыңыз биз үчүн маанилүү."},{"question":"Berikan jawapan kepada soalan rumit ini: Tahun apakah universiti yang Kristine Moore Gebbie bekerja sebagai profesor ditubuhkan?","answer":"Tahun 1966"},{"question":"குசந்தை பிறந்த 15 நாட்களுக்குள் எந்த நோய்த்தடுப்பு மருந்து கொடுக்கப்பட வேண்டும்?","answer":"விடை: \\"ஓ\\" போலியோ."},{"question":"Cho hỏi: Làm thế nào để tránh bị cận thị cho trẻ nhỏ? Cận thị có bị di truyền không? Con gái 5 tuổi nhà em hay xem máy tính, điện thoại, tivi hay nhìn nghiêng thì có phải bị cận thị không? Ba mẹ không bị cận thị.","answer":"Chào bạn, cận thị có 2 loại là cận thị bẩm sinh và cận thị mắc phải. Cận thị bẩm sinh là trẻ sinh ra đã mắc độ cận cao. Cận thị có thể di truyền. Cận thị mắc phải hay gặp ở lứa tuổi học đường khi các cháu đọc, xem nhiều, ngồi học không đúng tư thế, không đủ ánh sáng, để mắt hoạt động nhìn gần liên tục trong hơn 1 tiếng… Dấu hiệu nhìn nghiêng có thể do cháu bị cận thị, nhưng cũng có thể là do cháu bắt chước các bạn khác. Bạn nên cho cháu đi khám để bác sĩ ở các cơ sở y tế uy tín có kết luận chính xác."},{"question":"Bada Tatsuniyar Gizo da Noman Gyaɗa?","answer":"Wata rana Gizo da Ƙoƙi, abin duniya ya yi musu zafi. Sai Ƙoƙi ta ce da Gizo, “Ina ga da za mu yi noma da mun samu sauƙi”. Da Gizo ya ji haka sai ya ce, “Ƙwarai hakan ya dace”. Sai Ƙoƙi ta ce, “to me ka ke ganin zamu noma? Mu shuka shinkafa ne, ko alkama, ko kuma acca?” Sai Gizo ya ce, “a’a, mu shuka gayaɗa kawai”. Sai suka yarda akan cewa za su shuka gyaɗa. Amma ashe shi Gizo yana nufin ya yiwa Ƙoƙi wayo da wannan shawara tasa.Da aka tashi yin shuka, sai Gizo ya ce da Ƙoƙi, ai ba a shuka gyaɗa sai an soya ta. Sai Ƙoƙi ta amince ta soya gyaɗa, ta baiwa Gizo ta ce ya je ya shuka. Da Gizo ya je gona dan yin shukar gyaɗa, sai ya ɗaura lilo a jikin bishiya, ya hau lilon nan yana cin gyaɗa, yana rera waƙa kamar haka:Da haka-da haka, yau ya je gona, gobe ya je, har wannan gyaɗa ta ƙare, ba tare da ya shuka ba.Da damina ta yi nisa, sai ƙoƙi ta fara tambayarsa maganar gona, shi kuwa Gizo sai ya hau bada labari yana cewa, “Ai gonar nan ta yi kyau sosai”.Da kakar gyaɗa ta fara yi, sai Ƙoƙi ta ce da Gizo ya fara ciro musu wannan gyaɗa su riƙa ɗan taɓawa kafin a farɗe ta. Saboda haka a duk lokacin da Ƙoƙi ta buƙaci gyaɗa sai Gizo ya je gonar mai gari ya yago ya kai mata. Sannu a hankali Gizo ya kusa cire gyaɗar gonar mai gari baki ɗayanta.Wata rana sai mai gari ya gane cewa ana cirar masa gyaɗa, saboda haka sai ya zuba masu gadi a gonar suka ɓoye a gurin da ba mai ganinsu. Can sai ga Gizo ya zo cirar gyaɗa. Caraf, masu gadin nan suka cafke Gizo, suka tafi da shi gurin mai gari. Daga nan aka yanke masa hukunci, aka kore shi daga gari.Tunƙurunƙus, badan Gizo ba da na yi ƙarya."},{"question":"“Сынган кылыч” романында Нүзүптүн башын ким алууга буйрук берген?","answer":"Нүзүптүн башын алууга - Шерали хан буйрук берген."},{"question":"O que é o Titicaca?","answer":"O Titicaca é o lago com maior volume de água na América do Sul e está localizado entre o Peru e a Bolívia. Ele possui cerca de 8.300km² e sua superfície está a uma altitude de 3.821 metros acima do nível do mar. Além de ser o lago com maior volume de água do continente sul americano, ele é o segundo maior em extensão, sendo superado apenas pelo lago venezuelano Maracaibo. O Titicaca tem uma profundidade média de 140 a 180 metros, e uma profundidade máxima de 280 metros. Além disso, ele possui uma extensão de 190 quilômetros e largura máxima de 80 quilômetros. O lago Titicaca é uma atração turística principalmente por conta de suas ilhas naturais e artificiais povoadas por povos Indígenas, como os Uros."},{"question":"ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਸਤਰਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਪੜੋ।ਪ੍ਰਸ਼ਨ: ਇਸ ਪੈਰੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਕਿਹੜੇ-ਕਿਹੜੇ ਸ਼ਹਿਰਾਂ ਦੇ ਨਾਂ ਆਏ ਹਨ ?ਪੰਜਾਬ ਨੂੰ ਭੂਗੋਲਿਕ ਆਧਾਰ ‘ਤੇ ਮੁੱਖ ਰੂਪ ਵਿੱਚ ਤਿੰਨ ਭਾਗਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਵੰਡਿਆ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ : ਮਾਝਾ, ਦੁਆਬਾ ਅਤੇ ਮਾਲਵਾ । ਬਿਆਸ ਦਰਿਆ ਤੋਂ ਪਾਕਿਸਤਾਨ ਦੀ ਹੱਦ ਤੱਕ ਫੈਲੇ ਖੇਤਰ ਨੂੰ “ਮਾਝਾ’ ਕਿਹਾ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ । ਬਿਆਸ ਅਤੇ ਸਤਲੁਜ ਦਰਿਆਵਾਂ ਦੇ ਵਿਚਕਾਰਲੇ ਖੇਤਰ ਨੂੰ ‘ਦੁਆਬਾ’ ਕਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ । ਸਤਲੁਜ ਦਰਿਆ ਤੋਂ ਹਰਿਆਣਾ ਅਤੇ ਰਾਜਸਥਾਨ ਦੀ ਹੱਦ ਤੱਕ ਫੈਲਿਆ ਖੇਤਰ ‘ਮਾਲਵਾ ਅਖਵਾਉਂਦਾ ਹੈ । ਪੰਜਾਬ ਦੇ ਕੁੱਲ 22 ਜ਼ਿਲ੍ਹੇ ਹਨ ।ਚੰਡੀਗੜ੍ਹ ਪੰਜਾਬ ਦੀ ਰਾਜਧਾਨੀ ਹੈ । ਅੰਮ੍ਰਿਤਸਰ, ਪਟਿਆਲਾ, ਲੁਧਿਆਣਾ, ਜਲੰਧਰ, ਬਠਿੰਡਾ ਆਦਿ ਪੰਜਾਬ ਦੇ ਪ੍ਰਮੁੱਖ ਸ਼ਹਿਰ ਹਨ, ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਨਾਂ ਵੱਖ-ਵੱਖ ਕਾਰਨਾਂ ਕਰਕੇ ਦੇਸ਼ ਅਤੇ ਸੰਸਾਰ ਵਿਚ ਪ੍ਰਸਿੱਧ ਹਨ । ਅੰਮ੍ਰਿਤਸਰ ਸਿੱਖ ਧਰਮ ਦਾ ਪਵਿੱਤਰ ਸਥਾਨ ਹੈ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਹਰਿਮੰਦਰ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਅੰਮ੍ਰਿਤਸਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਹੀ ਸਥਿਤ ਹੈ। ਪਟਿਆਲਾ ਪੰਜਾਬ ਦਾ ਇੱਕ ਪ੍ਰਸਿੱਧ ਇਤਿਹਾਸਿਕ ਸ਼ਹਿਰ ਹੈ । ਇੱਥੇ ਬਹੁਤ ਸਾਰੀਆਂ ਇਤਿਹਾਸਿਕ ਇਮਾਰਤਾਂ ਹਨ । ਇਸ ਰਾਜ ਦਾ ਮੁੱਖ ਉਦਯੋਗਿਕ ਸ਼ਹਿਰ ਲੁਧਿਆਣਾ ਹੈ । ਜਲੰਧਰ ਖੇਡਾਂ ਅਤੇ ਲੁਧਿਆਣਾ ਹੌਜ਼ਰੀ ਦਾ ਸਮਾਨ ਤਿਆਰ ਕਰਨ ਲਈ ਦੁਨੀਆ ਭਰ ਵਿਚ ਪ੍ਰਸਿੱਧ ਹੈ । ਬਠਿੰਡਾ ਵਿੱਚ ਇੱਕ ਇਤਿਹਾਸਿਕ ਕਿਲ੍ਹਾ ਹੈ । ਇੱਥੇ ਏਸ਼ੀਆ ਮਹਾਂਦੀਪ ਦੀ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਵੱਡੀ ਛਾਉਣੀ ਅਤੇ ਇੱਕ ਵੱਡਾ ਰੇਲਵੇ ਜੰਕਸ਼ਨ ਹੈ ।","answer":"ਚੰਡੀਗੜ੍ਹ, ਅੰਮ੍ਰਿਤਸਰ, ਪਟਿਆਲਾ, ਲੁਧਿਆਣਾ, ਜਲੰਧਰ ਤੇ ਬਠਿੰਡਾ ।"},{"question":"කුරුණෑගල දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේ පෙළපත් නාම ගැන විස්තරයක් හොයාගන්න මූලාශ්‍රයක් දෙන්න.","answer":"කුරරනැගල විස්තරය, වන්නි විත්ති, මලල බංඩාරවලි බලන්න"},{"question":"एरोस्पेस इन्जिनियरहरूले कसरी अन्तरिक्ष अन्वेषण मिशनहरूमा योगदान गर्छन्?","answer":"एरोस्पेस इन्जिनियरहरूले अन्तरिक्ष यान, प्रोपल्सन प्रणाली, र मिशन नियन्त्रण प्रणालीहरू डिजाइन गरेर अन्तरिक्ष अन्वेषण मिशनहरूमा योगदान गर्छन्। तिनीहरू अन्तरिक्ष यात्रासँग सम्बन्धित चुनौतिहरूलाई सम्बोधन गर्छन्, जस्तै शून्य गुरुत्वाकर्षण, चरम तापक्रम, र सञ्चार ढिलाइ, अन्तरिक्ष अन्वेषण प्रयासहरूको सफलता सुनिश्चित गर्दै।"},{"question":"Jox ma beneen !","answer":"Donne- moi un autre!"},{"question":"Waxaad Sheegtaa goorma ayaa La Waajib Yeelay Soonka?","answer":" Waxa La Waajib Yeelay Sanadkii Labaad 2-aad Ee Hijriyada."},{"question":"Adete 1 hafta kala döllenme olur mu?","answer":"Doğurganlık çağındaki bir kadında yumurtlama beklenen adetten ortalama olarak 14 gün öncedir. Bu nedenle hiç bir kadında adete 2 gün kala gebelik oluşmaz."},{"question":"Daawooyinka la siiyo dadka nafaqo xumadaqabo.","answer":"1. Vitamin A. 2. Albendazole 3. Mebendazole 4. Measles vaccine 5. Iron/folate"},{"question":"Ci ban kembaar la réwum Cameroun nékk","answer":"Réwum Cameroun mu ngi nékk ci kembaar bi ñuy wakh Afrique"},{"question":"Hãy làm tròn số 2643235 đến:a) Hàng nghìnb) Hàng triệu","answer":"a) Để làm tròn số 2 643 235 đến hàng nghìn ta làm như sau:- Tìm chữ số hàng nghìn (hàng làm tròn). - Tìm chữ số hàng trăm (đứng ngay bên phải hàng làm tròn) và so sánh chữ số đó với 5.- Do chữ số hàng trăm là 2 (nhỏ hơn 5) nên trong số 2 643 235 ta giữ nguyên chữ số 3 ở hàng nghìn (hàng làm tròn) rồi thay lần lượt các chữ số đứng bên phải hàng làm tròn bởi chữ số 0: 2643235 ⇒ 2643235 ⇒ 2643000.Vậy 2643235 ≈ 2643000.b) Để làm tròn số 2643235 đến hàng triệu ta làm như sau:- Tìm chữ số hàng triệu (hàng làm tròn). - Tìm chữ số hàng trăm nghìn (đứng ngay bên phải hàng làm tròn) và so sánh chữ số đó với 5.- Do chữ số hàng trăm nghìn là 6 (lớn hơn 5) nên trong số 2643235 ta cộng thêm 1 vào chữ số 2 ở hàng triệu (hàng làm tròn): 2643235  ⇒ 3643235- Với số nhận được ở trên, thay lần lượt các chữ số đứng bên phải hàng làm tròn bởi chữ số 0:3643235 ⇒ 3000000Vậy 2643235 ≈ 3000000."},{"question":"ஈ. வெ. இராமசாமி மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":"உண்ண உணவும், உடுக்க உடையும், இருக்க இடமும், அதற்கான அறிவும் பெறுவதே சுயராஜ்யமாகும்."},{"question":"السؤال: كم عدد ركعات صلاة التراويح ؟","answer":"الإجابة: عشرون ركعة عدا الوتر"},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన పద్యానికి ప్రతిపదార్ధం మరియు తాత్పర్యం రాయండి:ఉ|| మాయురె దుందుభీ! ప్రబల మైన కృపాధిషణన్ దరిద్రనారాయణ పక్షమై ధన పరత్వము రోయుచు ‘జమ్ము’ ‘తుంగ’ లత్యాయతవృత్తి బెంచి నిలయమ్ముగ బాకను గూర్చి స్వాదుపానీయము నిచ్చి త్రావగ జనించిన ప్రేమను చిందె దీగతిన్","answer":"ప్రతిపదార్థం :మాయురె దుందుభీ ! = ఆహా దుందుభి !ప్రబలమైన = బలమైన, అధికమైనకృపాధిషణన్ = కరుణతోదరిద్రనారాయణ పక్షమై = పేదల వైపు ఉండిధన పరత్వము = ధనమే ప్రధానమనే గుణాన్నిరోయుచు = అసహ్యించుకుంటూజమ్ము, తుంగ ల = జనుమును, తుంగ అనే గడ్డినిఅతి + ఆయత వృత్తి = చాలా పొడుగ్గాబెంచి = పెంచినిలయమ్ముగ = నివాసంగాపాకను గూర్చి = గుడిసెను కట్టిస్వాదు పానీయమును = = తీయటి నీటినిత్రావగ ఇచ్చి = తాగడానికి ఇచ్చిజనించిన = పుట్టినప్రేమను = ప్రేమతోచిందెదు ఈ గతిన్ = ఈ విధంగా గంతులు వేస్తున్నావుతాత్పర్యం : ఆహా! ఓ దుందుభి! అధికమైన కరుణతో పేదల వైపు నిలిచి, ధనమే ప్రధానమని భావించే గుణాన్ని అసహ్యించుకుంటూ, జనుమును తుంగ గడ్డిని, చాలా పొడుగ్గా పెంచి, వారు నివసించడానికి గుడిసెలను కట్టి ఇచ్చి, తాగడానికి మంచి నీటిని ఇచ్చినందుకు కలిగిన సంతోషంతో గంతులు వేస్తున్నావు."},{"question":"在加拿大，第一阶段G1以及第二阶段G2司机，驾驶时酒精在血液中含量不能超过0.00%,超标者将有什么后果？","answer":"驾照会被暂停30天，并将受到刑事犯罪的指控"},{"question":"Apakah jawapan untuk teka-teki ini? Jika dipecah oleh awak, ia sejenis makanan yang berwarna putih kuning. Jika ia pecah sendiri, dia bernyawa.","answer":"Jawapannya ialah telur ayam "},{"question":"Name some animals which use their tongue as a tool for taking in food.","answer":"Frogs, lizards, garden lizards, chameleons, and echidna use their tongue as a tool for taking in food."},{"question":"Lazao amin’ny fomba hafa ity fehezanteny ity :«Lamban’akoho tokoa ny fanambadiana ka tsy maintsy atao izay ifandeferana. »","answer":"Mandra-maty izy ho vadiko ka tsy maintsy mifandamina izahay."},{"question":"Em quantas regiões o Brasil é dividido?","answer":"O Brasil é dividido em 5 regiões: Norte, Nordeste, Centro-Oeste, Sudeste e Sul. Cada região possui características geográficas, culturais e econômicas distintas."},{"question":"பெரியாரின் எழுத்துகளிலிருந்து  மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":"நாம் மானமுள்ள சமுதாயம் என்று சொல்லிக் கொள்ளும் நிலை ஏற்பட வேண்டுமானால், நம் எண்ணிக்கைக்கு உண்டான விதிப்படி கல்வி, உத்தியோகம், பதவி ஆதிக்கம் ஏற்பட்டுத் தீர வேண்டும்."},{"question":"Faber-Castell markasının sahibi kimdir?","answer":"2005 verilerine göre 887 milyon euro geliri olan Faber-Castell firmasını Alman girişimci Kasper Faber tarafından 1761 yılında kurulmuştur."},{"question":"Àwọn ìjọba ìbílẹ̀ wo ló wà ní ìpínlè Èkìtì?","answer":"Ìjọba ìbílẹ̀ Adó-Èkìtì, Ìjọba ìbílẹ̀ Ẹ̀fọ̀n, Ìjọba ìbílẹ̀ Èkìtì West, Ìjọba ìbílẹ̀ Ìkọ̀lé, Ìjọba ìbílẹ̀ Ìsẹ̀/Ọ̀rún, Ìjọba ìbílẹ̀ Ìkẹ́rẹ́, Ìjọba ìbílẹ̀ Èkìtì East, Ìjọba ìbílẹ̀ Emùré, Ìjọba ìbílẹ̀ Ìléjeméje, Ìjọba ìbílẹ̀ Mọ̀bà, Ìjọba ìbílẹ̀ Ọyẹ́, Ìjọba ìbílẹ̀ Èkìtì South-West, Ìjọba ìbílẹ̀ Ìdó-Òsi, Ìjọba ìbílẹ̀ Ìrẹ́pọ̀ọ́dùn/Ìfẹ́lódùn, Ìjọba ìbílẹ̀ Ayékire àti Ìjọba ìbílẹ̀ Ìjerò."},{"question":"Kto otrzymał Nagrodę Nobla z Literatury w 2003 roku?","answer":"W 2003. roku Nagrodę Nobla z dziedziny literatury otrzymał: John Maxwell Coetzee (Południowa Afryka). Książki laureata odznaczają się analityczną błyskotliwością i wymownymi dialogami."},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన పద్యానికి ప్రతిపదార్ధాలు మరియు తాత్పర్యం రాయండి:మూర్ఛ మునిఁగినధనదు సమ్ముఖముఁ జేరిశంఖ పద్మాది నిధులు విశ్రాంతి మాన్చెనంత దశ కంధరుఁడు నిట్టులన్నఁ గెలిచిసొలయకాతని నగరంబుసొచ్చి యచట.","answer":"ప్రతిపదార్థం :మూర్చమునిగిన = మూర్చపోయినధనదు = కుబేరునిసమ్ముఖమున్ = ఎదురుగాచేరి = చేరిశంఖ పద్మాది నిధులు = శంఖ పద్ముడు మొదలైనవారువిశ్రాంతి మాన్చె = పరిచర్యలు చేసిరిఅంత = అంతటదశకంధరుడు = రావణాసురుడుఇట్టుల = ఈ విధముగాఅన్నన్ = అన్న అయిన కుబేరునిగెలిచి = గెలిచిసొలయక = అలసట లేకఆతని = కుబేరునినగరంబు + చొచ్చి = నగరమైన అలకాపురి ప్రవేశించిఅచట = అచట (తరువాతి పద్యంతో అన్వయము)తాత్పర్యము :మూర్ఛపోయిన కుబేరుని శంఖ పద్మాదులు సేదదీర్చి పరిచర్యలు చేసారు. రావణుడు అన్నయైన కుబేరుని గెలిచి అలకాపురి పట్టణములో ప్రవేశించి అచట."},{"question":"Bu paragrafın devamını yazın: Etkinlikte Cesaro ve Sheamus, The Hardy Boyz'u yenerek ikinci kez Raw Takım Şampiyonluğu kemerlerini kazandı. Kişisel olarak Cesaro üçüncü kez bu kemeri alırken, Sheamus ikinci kez kemere sahip oldu. Ayrıca The Hardys, WWE'ye döndüğünden beri ilk mağlubiyetini aldı. İkili, telezviyonda gösterilen ilk kemer koruma maçını 12 Haziran \\"Raw\\" bölümünde Hardy Boyz'a karşı yaptı. 2 out of 3 falls maçında iki takım skoru 1-1'e getirdikten maç çift count-out ile bitti. 3 Temmuz \\"Raw\\" bölümünde WWE, Cesaro ve Sheamus'ın kemerlerini Great Balls of Fire","answer":"etkinliğinde The Hardy Boyz'a karşı 30 dakikalık Iron Man maçında savunacağını açıkladı. Etkinlikteki maçı 4-3 kazanan Cesaro ve Sheamus, kemerleri koruyarak The Hardy Boyz ile olan rekabetini sonlandırdı."},{"question":"Laburbildu artikulua.  Gehiegi esan dut? Ezaguna egiten zaizu Carole White? Agian ikusi duzuelako \\"Agentzia Modeloak\\"-en, Channel 4-en, Premierren inguruko dokumental batean, 1981ean sortu zuena. Bere lankideek \\"Sorgina\\" deitzen zioten. Zakila eskuetan duela, papar ahotsarekin, bere ahotsak arrosa kolorea du, larruazala Prada poltsa batekoak bezalako azalarekin... Ab Faburen Patsy eta Edina izebaordeak dirudite. Eta bere autobiografia berriak baieztatzen du modaren egiazko mundua telebistako ikuskizunen mundua baino gehiago dela. Linda Evangelista supermodeloak nazioartean ospe handiko modeloetako bat izan zen Premierren liburuetan 80ko hamarkadan. 1960ko hamarkadako nerabezaroan, Carol-ek Lucie Clayton modeloa izan zuen ibilbide laburra izan zuen, baina utzi egin zuen kamera aurrean auto-kontzientea zelako. 19 urterekin, mutil-lagun ez egoki batekin hasi zen (mutil gaizto eta guapoekiko ahultasuna duela aitortu du) eta bere alaba Simone haurdun geratu zen. Gizon egokiago bat ezagutu zuenean, berarekin ezkondu zen eta bere ametsetako lana lortu zuen, Lucie Clayton modelo-agentzia zaharrean. Ezkontzak ez zuen iraun, baina lanak bai. Bere alaba Kent-en utzi zuen gurasoekin (ez nuen Simone txikia asko ikusi garai hartan), eta Carolek bere burua bota zuen modelo, rock izar eta festa basatien mundu bohemiar batean. 1981eko Gabonak baino pixka bat lehenago, Bobtons, King's Road-eko agentzia, bertan lan egiten zuen, porrot egin zuen, eta 20 modelo inguru utzi zituen ordezkaririk gabe. Hamar egun geroago, bere anaiek maileguz emandako 10.000£-rekin, Carolek Bobtons neskak kontratatu zituen eta Premier jaio zen. Astebete beranduago, Eileen Ford, New Yorkeko modelo-gidari garrantzitsuena bulegora sartu zen. Agentzia berriarekin elkartu eta lanean hasteko eskatu zion. \\"Maggie Thatcher ezagutzea bezala izan zen\\", gogoratzen du Carolek. Ile horia zuen, ezti-kolorekoa eta zurruna, eta oso zuzena zen bere hizkeran... Ofizialki hitz egin dugu...","answer":"Carol White \\" Premier Model Management \\" enpresaren sortzaileetako bat da. 1981ean, 10.000 libera kobratu zizkion bere anaiek konpainiari. 1980ko hamarkadan Linda Evangelista eta Naomi Campbell agertu ziren bere liburuetan."},{"question":"je ni halali kuchumbia mpenzi kwa kutumia mitandao ya kijamii?","answer":"ni kweli kwamba watu wengine wameanzisha mahusiano kwa kutumia njia za mtandao, ukweli usiopingika ni kwamba mahusiano ambayo huanzishwa kwenye mitandao ya kijamii siyo salama sana, wengi wao huishia katika maumivu. "},{"question":"ભરત ત્રિવેદીની \\"આપણી જૂદાઈ\\" કવિતા લખો.","answer":"આપણી જૂદાઈનું છે ક્યાં કોઈ કારણ નવું,આમ મારું આવવું ને તે પછી તારું જવું !દર્પણો ચૂપચાપ છે આ ભાવસૂના ઓરડે,ફર્ક કોને તે પછી છે હું રહું કે ના રહું !શક્ય છે કે બંદગીનો પણ હશે કોઈ જવાબ,કશ્મકશમાં છું હવે કે હુ નમું કે ના નમું ?આમ તો ખામોશ છે પણ શું તને થાતું ખરું,રસ્મ જૂનીને નિભાવી હું ગઝલ આજે કહું ?"},{"question":"Kanus-a ka huling nag-ampo sa panahon sa kagubot o kalisod?","answer":"Kagahapon ko huling nag-ampo sa panahon sa kagubot ug gidumdom nako ang gahom sa Diyos sa tanang panahon."},{"question":"Ang isang lawa ay may pangkat na mga lily pad. Araw-araw, dumobole ang laki ng pangkat. Kung aabutin ng 48 araw para masakop ng pangkat ang buong lawa, gaano katagal bago masakop ng patch ang kalahati ng lawa?","answer":"Aabutin ng 47 araw para masakop ng pangkat ng lily pad ang kalahati ng lawa. Sinasabi sa sitwasyon na ang pangkat ay \\"dumodoble\\" sa laki, na nangangahulugang, sa anumang araw, ang lily pad ay kalahati ng laki noong nakaraang araw. Kaya't kung natakpan ng pangkat ang buong lawa sa ika-48 araw, nangangahulugan ito na ang lily pad ay kalahati ng laki ng lawa noong araw na 47."},{"question":"次の文章を読んで、その内容に適したタイトルを付けてください： 東京電力は今年1月、電気の料金を平均で29.3%上げたいと国に言いました。しかし、エネルギーの値段が下がっていることなどで経済産業省が認めなかったため、上げるのを17.6%にしました。電気の料金について、電気を利用する人などから意見を聞く会がありました。東京電力は「燃料の値段が上がって経営が難しくなっています」と話しました。会に出た人たちからは、「料金が上がったら、利用する人や会社がとても大変になります」という意見が出ました。「燃料の値段が上がり続けることや円安が続くという理由を言ってほしいです」など、料金が上がることに反対する意見や、よく考えたほうがいいという意見が多く出ました。経済産業省は、東京電力など7つの電気の会社が料金を上げたいと言っていることについて調べています。消費者庁とも相談して認めるかどうか決めると言っています。","answer":"電気の料金が上がることへの意見を聞く会　反対が多く出る"},{"question":"Que língua é falada em Fiji?","answer":"Nas ilhas Fiji são falados três idiomas considerados línguas oficiais do país desde a Constituição de 1997: o fijiano, idioma dos habitantes nativos das ilhas; o inglês, devido à colonização britânica no século XIX; e o fiji-hindi, falado pela população de origem indiana vinda em sua maioria duranto o período britânico."},{"question":"Dê um exemplo de uma pergunta da categoria Cinema","answer":"Quem é a pessoa com mais indicações ao Oscar? Meryl Streep"},{"question":"આ કહેવત નો અર્થ અને વિવરણ જાણવો:ધર્મ કરતાં ધાડ પડી.","answer":"અર્થ:સારું કરવા જતા નુકસાન થવુંવિવરણ: ઘણી વાર કોઈનું સારું કરવા જતા આપણી પોતાની ઉપર મુસીબત આવી જતી હોય છે. ધર્મ બધાને અન્યોનું સારું કરવાનું શીખવાડે છે માટે આપણે એને શક્ય હોય ત્યાં સુધી અનુસરીએ છીએ. પરંતુ ક્યારેક એ આપણા માટે અહિત નોતરી લાવે છે. દાન પુણ્ય કરવું એ ધર્મ છે. પરંતુ ક્યારેક વધુ પડતું દાન પુણ્ય કરવાથી ચોર-લુટારાઓની આંખે પણ ચડી જવાય અને પછી આપણી પોતાની ઘરે પણ ધાડ પડી શકે. આ પરિસ્થિતને સાંકેતિક રીતે ઉપયોગમાં લઈને આ કહેવત બીજી ઘણી પરિસ્થિતિઓમાં ઉપયોગમાં લઇ શકાય છે. મૂળ મુદ્દે તો જયારે આપણે કોઈ સારું કામ કરવા જઈએ અને નાહકના મુસીબતમાં મુકાઈ જઈએ ત્યારે આ કહેવત ઉપયોગમાં લેવાય છે.ઉદાહરણ - \\"મારે તો ધરમ કરતા ધાડ પડી. હું તો માત્ર એને એના પ્રોજેક્ટમાં મદદ કરવા ગયો હતો. પણ એને તો આખે આખો પ્રોજેક્ટ જ મારી માથે નાખી દીધો. હવે એણે કરેલી ભૂલો પણ મારે ભોગવવી પડશે.\\""},{"question":"Lẹyin ọdun mẹtala to ti jona, wọn tun aafin Ọwa Obokun kọ","answer":"Beeyan ba gun ẹṣin ninu Ọwa Obokun ti ilẹ Ijeṣa, Ọba (Dr) Gabriel Adekunle Aromọlaran 11, CFR, lonii, onitọhun ko ni i kọṣẹ. Odidi ọdun mẹta ni baba naa ko fi sun aafin, ṣugbọn ni bayii, inu aafin ni wọn aa maa gbe.Ohun to fa sababi ni pe inu oṣu keje, ọdun 2007, ni ina ọmọ-ọrara deede sẹ yọ ninu aafin naa, to si jo o gburugburu. Latigba naa ni Ọba Adekunle ti n gbe ninu ile rẹ to wa loju-ọna Ileṣa/Ijẹbu Jeṣa.Gbogbo igbiyanju awọn ọmọ ilu naa lati tun aafin naa kọ ni ko so eso rere, afigba ti wọn gbe igbimọ kan kalẹ loṣu mẹsan-an sẹyin labẹ alaga Oloye Yinka Faṣuyi.Igbimọ naa bẹrẹ iṣẹ takuntakun lori atunkọ aafin naa, wọn kan si awọn ọmọ ilu yii kaakiri agbaye, wọn si ko owo jọ lori rẹ.Gẹgẹ bi a ṣe gbọ, owo ti wọn fi tun aafin naa kọ to miliọnu lọna ọọdunrun un naira, ọjọ Abamẹta, Satide, ni wọn yoo ṣi aafin naa, ti wọn yoo si ko kọkọrọ le Ọwa Aromọlaran lọwọ."},{"question":"ఈ ఆర్టికల్ ను సంగ్రహించండి:  మంగళవారం న్యూజెర్సీ పరిసరాల్లో గ్యాస్ లీకేజీ కారణంగా భారీ పేలుడు సంభవించడంతో ఒక ఇల్లు 'విచ్ఛిన్నమైంది' మరియు ఐదుగురు వ్యక్తులు ఆసుపత్రికి తరలించబడ్డారు. న్యూజెర్సీ సహజ వాయువు కార్మికులు ఓక్ అవెన్యూలో స్టాఫోర్డ్ టౌన్షిప్ మంగళవారం ఉదయం పొరుగు ప్రాంతంలో ఒక అనుమానాస్పద వాసన నివేదికలు తర్వాత పిలిచారు. వీధి యొక్క తూర్పు చివర ఒక ఇల్లు పేలింది - వాయువులోకి మంటలను పంపి, చుట్టుపక్కల ఇళ్ల కిటికీలను పగులగొట్టి, మైలు చుట్టూ భూమిని కదిలించింది. పేలుడులో ఐదుగురు కార్మికులు గాయపడ్డారు - కనీసం ఒకరు చాలా క్లిష్టమైన స్థితిలో ఉన్నారు మరియు అక్కడికక్కడే సిపిఆర్ అవసరం. ఐదుగురు గ్యాస్ కార్మికుల ప్రస్తుత పరిస్థితి ప్రస్తుతం తెలియదు. వినాశకరమైన: న్యూ జెర్సీ సహజ వాయువు ఐదుగురు కార్మికులు గాయపడ్డారు - ఒక క్లిష్టమైన - ఒక లీకేజ్ ఒక భారీ పేలుడు కారణమైనప్పుడు న్యూ జెర్సీ తీరంలో ఒక ఇల్లు మంగళవారం ఉదయం సమం. పేలుడు సమీపంలో పార్క్ ఒక పోలీసు డాష్ కెమెరా ద్వారా పట్టుబడ్డాడు. పేలుడు తరువాత ఇల్లు చిన్న చిన్న ముక్కలుగా కూలిపోయింది. శిధిలాలు వీధి అన్ని మార్గం డౌన్ వెళ్లింది. హెలికాప్టర్ నుంచి తీసిన ఫొటోలో వీధిలో శిధిలాలు, పొగతో నిండిన గాలి, నేల లో ఒక రంధ్రం, నేలమట్టం చేసిన ఇంటిలో మిగిలి ఉన్నది నేలమాళిగ మాత్రమే కనిపిస్తున్నాయి. 'ఇల్లు కుప్పకూలిపోయింది' అని స్టాఫోర్డ్ టౌన్షిప్ మేయర్ జాన్ స్పోడోఫోరా ఎన్ బిసి న్యూయార్క్కు చెప్పారు. పేలుడు యొక్క శక్తి సమాజం అంతటా భావించబడింది, కొంతమంది భూకంపం వారి ఇళ్లను ఒక మైలు దూరంలో కదిలిందని చెప్పారు. 'ఇది ఒక చిన్న భూకంపం లాంటిది' అని పారుదల కాంట్రాక్టర్ మాక్స్ వాన్ న్యూస్ చెప్పారు. 'మీరు అది ఒక బాంబు వంటి భావించారు. ' 'ఇది యుద్ధ ప్రాంతం లాగా కనిపిస్తోంది. ఇది కేవలం విధ్వంసం. అన్ని చోట్ల శిధిలాలు ఉన్నాయి' అని మిస్టర్ వాన్ నెస్ అన్నారు. మిగతావన్నీ: పైన ఉన్న దృశ్యం పేలుడుకు ముందు ఒక ఇల్లు ఎక్కడ నిలబడిందో చూపిస్తుంది, ఇది నిర్మాణాన్ని వాస్తవంగా విచ్ఛిన్నం చేసింది. వినాశకరమైన: నివాసితులు మొదటి మంగళవారం ఉదయం 8:55 చుట్టూ గ్యాస్ వాసన నివేదించారు. భూమిని కదిలించేః కమ్యూనిటీ లో ఆ పేలుడు దాదాపు ఒక మైలు దూరంలో నుండి వారి ఇళ్ళు వణుకు అనుభూతి కాలేదు. ","answer":"న్యూజెర్సీలోని స్టాఫోర్డ్ టౌన్ షిప్ నివాసితులు మంగళవారం ఉదయం గ్యాస్ వాసన గురించి మొదట నివేదించారు. మొత్తం పేలుడు సమీపంలోని ఒక పోలీసు కారు యొక్క డాష్ కామ్ ద్వారా సంగ్రహించబడింది. న్యూ జెర్సీ సహజ వాయువు కార్మికులు సన్నివేశం స్పందించారు మరియు ఒక పేలుడు శివారు ఇంటి ద్వారా పగుళ్లు ఉన్నప్పుడు లీక్ దర్యాప్తు చేశారు. ఐదుగురు కార్మికులను ఆసుపత్రికి తరలించారు - వారిలో ఒకరు క్లిష్ట స్థితిలో ఉన్నారు. సుమారు 75 నుండి 100 కుటుంబాలు ఖాళీ చేయబడ్డాయి మరియు గ్యాస్ లైన్ మూసివేయబడింది."},{"question":"Sheeg sanadkii ay kala saxiixdeen labada dawladood ee Soomaaliya iyo Kenya heshiiskii  ahaa in la joojiyo dagaalka xuduudaha iyo in la soo celiyo xiriirkii diblomaasiyadeed ee labada dal?","answer":"Waxa ay kala saxiixdeen sanadkii 1964kii."},{"question":"Oviana no niforina ny orinasa JIRAMA?","answer":"Tamin'ny 17 oktobra 1975 no noforonina izy."},{"question":"what important event is this text about: Năm 1800, Masséna quay lại Ý và chỉ huy lực lượng Pháp trong cuộc Bao vây Genoa, một trong những chiến thắng lớn nhất của ông, cho đến trước Trận Marengo (ngày 14 tháng 6 năm 1800). Sau Trận Marengo, Masséna được cử làm tổng tư lệnh quân Pháp tại Ý, nhưng nhanh chóng bị cách chức vì để cho quân sĩ cướp bóc.","answer":"Văn bản này nói về cuộc Bao vây Genoa và vai trò của Masséna trong đó, cũng như việc ông bị cách chức sau Trận Marengo do để cho quân sĩ cướp bóc."},{"question":" Trong những khẳng định sau, khẳng định nào sai?A. Hình bình hành có 4 đỉnhB. Hình bình hành có bốn cạnhC. Hình có bốn đỉnh là hình bình hànhD. Hình bình hành có hai cạnh đối song song.","answer":"Trả lời:Hình bình hành có 4 đỉnh, có bốn cạnh, hai cạnh đối song song => A, B, D đúngHình có bốn đỉnh chưa chắc là hình bình hànhĐáp án cần chọn là: C"},{"question":"Qu'est-ce que la théorie de la relativité restreinte d'Einstein et comment a-t-elle révolutionné la physique moderne ?","answer":"La théorie de la relativité restreinte d'Einstein repose sur le postulat que les lois de la physique sont les mêmes pour tous les observateurs inertiels et que la vitesse de la lumière dans le vide est constante. Elle a révolutionné la physique en introduisant des concepts tels que la dilatation du temps et la contraction de la longueur, qui ont été confirmés par des expériences et sont désormais fondamentaux dans la physique moderne."},{"question":"நிரல் நிறையணி – இதில் ‘நிரை’ என்பதன் பொருள் ……………….அ) நிறுத்துதல்ஆ) வரிசைஇ) எடைஈ) கூட்டம்","answer":"விடை: ஆ) வரிசை"},{"question":"નરસિંહ મહેતા રચિત કવિતા \\"જળકમળ છાંડી જાને\\" લખો.","answer":"જળકમળ છાંડી જાને બાળા, સ્વામી અમારો જાગશેજાગશે તને મારશે મને બાળ હત્યા લાગશે.. હે જળકમળ..કહે રે બાળક તું મારગ ભૂલ્યો, કે તારા વેરીએ વળાવીઓનિશ્ચલ તારો કાળ ખૂટ્યો, અહીંયા તે શીદ આવીઓ.. હે જળકમળ..નથી નાગણ હું મારગ ભૂલ્યો, નથી મારા વેરીએ વળાવીઓ,મથુરા નગરીમાં જુગટુ રમતાં નાગનું શીશ હું હારીઓ.. હે જળકમળ..રંગે રૂડો રૂપે પુરો દિસંત કોડિલો કોડામણો,તારી માતાએ કેટલા જનમ્યાં તેમાં તું અળખામણો.. હે જળકમળ..મારી માતાએ બે જનમ્યાં તેમાં હું નટવર નાનેલોજગાડ તારા નાગને મારું નામ કૃષ્ણ કાનુડો.. હે જળકમળ..લાખ સવાનો મારો હાર આપું, આફું તુજને દોરીઓ,એટલું મારા નાગથી છાનું આપું તુજને ચોરીઓ.. હે જળકમળ..શું કરું નાગણ હાર તારો, શું કરું તારો દોરીઓ,શાને કાજે નાગણ તારે કરવી ઘરમાં ચોરીઓ.. હે જળકમળ..ચરણ ચાંપી મૂછ મરડી, નાગણે નાગ જગાડિયો,ઉઠોને બળવંત કોઇ, બારણે બાળક આવીયો.. હે જળકમળ..બેઉ બળિયા બાથે વળગ્યાં, કૃષ્ણે કાળીનાગ નાથિયો,સહસ્ત્ર ફેણ ફુંફવે, જેમ ગગન ગાજે હાથિયો.. હે જળકમળ.."},{"question":"請回答這個問題：韓國傳統料理中，用石頭燒烤的方式烹調肉類的是哪種菜餚？","answer":"答案：用石頭燒烤的方式烹調肉類的韓國傳統菜餚是石頭烤肉（돌구이）。石頭烤肉是將切好的肉類和蔬菜放在預熱的石頭上烤製而成，具有特殊的口感和風味。"},{"question":"موږ لاندې متن لرو: \\"ارجنټاین (هسپانوي تلفظ: [aɾxenˈtina] (واورئ))، په رسمي ډول د ارجنټاین جمهوریت، د سویلي امریکا په سویلي نیمایي کې یو هیواد دی. دا د برازیل څخه وروسته په جنوبي امریکا کې دویم لوی هیواد جوړوي، په امریکا کې څلورم لوی هیواد، او په نړۍ کې اتم لوی هیواد دی. دا په لویدیز کې د چیلي سره د سویلي مخروط لویه برخه شریکوي، او همدارنګه په شمال کې د بولیویا او پاراګوای، شمال ختیځ ته برازیل، په ختیځ کې یوراګوای او سویلي اتلانتیک بحر، او په سویل کې د ډریک پاسج سره ګډه پوله لري. د تیر متن په کارولو سره، د ارجنټاین په شمالي سرحدونو کې کوم هیوادونه دي؟","answer":"بولیویا او پاراګوای"},{"question":"Анероид","answer":"Анероид-абасы сордурулуп салынган серпилгичтүү металл кутунун деформациясынын өлчөмү менен атмосфералык басым өлчөнүн барометр: атмосфералык басым өзгөргөндө куту чоноет же жыйрылат да бул жебе аркылуу көрүнүп турат."},{"question":"Cari aspek dan polaritas sentimen dari kalimat ini:Tempatnya nyaman,bersih dan rapih...tempat di pusat kota bisa sambil maen ke gedung sate..menu banyak pilihan rasa top..harga terjangkau..","answer":"aspek: tempat - sentimen: positif karena mengandung kata bermakna positif yaitu nyaman,bersih dan rapih, di pusat kotaaspek: menu - sentimen: positif karena mengandung kata bermakna positif yaitu banyak pilihanaspek: rasa -  sentimen: positif karena mengandung kata bermakna positif yaitu topaspek: harga - sentimen: positif karena mengandung kata bermakna positif yaitu terjangkau"},{"question":"வினா: நாவல்பழத்தின் மருத்துவக் குணங்களைக் குறிப்பிடுக","answer":"விடை  :நாவல்பழத்தின் மருத்துவக் குணங்கள்:-நாவல் மரம் அனைத்து வகையிலும் ஒரு சிறப்பான மரமாக போற்றப்படுகிறது. நாவல்பழத்தில் கால்சியம், பாஸ்பரஸ், இரும்புச்சத்து, விட்டமின் B போன்ற  தாதுக்கள் நிறைந்துள்ளன. இதனால் நாவல் மரத்தின் பழம், இலை, மரப்பட்டை மற்றும் விதை என அனைத்துமே மருத்துவ குணங்கள் வாய்ந்தவையாக  உள்ளது.நாவல் மரத்தின் இலைக் கொழுந்தை நசுக்கி சாறு எடுத்து, ஒரு தேக்கரண்டி அளவு சாப்பிட வேண்டும். இதனை இரண்டு வேளைகள் என்று 3 நாட்களுக்கு  தொடர்ந்து சாப்பிட்டு வந்தால் பேதியை கட்டுப்படுத்தலாம். பித்தத்தைத் தணிக்கும், மலச்சிக்கலைக்குணப்படுத்தும், இதயத்தை சீராக இயங்கச் செய்யும். இரத்த சோகைநோயைக் குணப்படுத்தும். சிறுநீரகத்தில் ஏற்படும் வலியையும் நிவர்த்திசெய்யும். சிறுநீரகக் கற்கள் கரையவும், மண்ணீரல் கோளாறுகளைச் சரிசெய்யவும் நாவற்பழம் உதவுகிறது.  நீரிழிவு நோயை தடுக்கும் பழம் நாவல்பழம் சாப்பிட்டால் நீரிழிவு நோய் கட்டுப்பாட்டில் இருக்கும். கல்லீரல்கோளாறுகள், குடற்புண் போன்றவற்றைப் போக்க  வல்லது.  நாவல் பழத்தின்விதையில் ஜம்போலைன் என்ற குளூக்கோசைட் உள்ளது, இதன் செயல்பாடுஉடலுக்குள் ஸ்டார்ச்சை சர்க்கரையாக மாற்றும் செயல்பாடு  தடுக்கப்படுகிறது.  நீரிழிவு நோயாளிகள், நாவல் பழத்தின் விதைகளை இடித்து எடுக்கப்பட்ட தூளை தினமும் ஒரு கிராம் வீதம் காலையிலும், மாலையிலும் தண்ணீருடன் கலந்து உட்கொண்டு சிறுநீர்ப்போக்குக் குறையும்.  நாவல்பழச்சாற்றை தினமும் மூன்றுவேளை தவறாமல் உட்கொண்டு வந்தால் நீரிழிவு நோயாளியின் சர்க்கரையின் அளவு 15 நாட்களில் பத்து சதவிகிதம் குறைத்துவிடலாம். மூன்று மாதத்திற்குள் முற்றிலும் கட்டுப்படுத்திவிடலாம்."},{"question":"Эртең менен ойгону ыкмасы...","answer":" Ысык жана муздак душ кабыл алыңыз. Эртең менен эрте ысык жана муздак сууну улам алмаштырып агызып душ кабыл алуу менен уйкуңуз бат ачылат. Эгер душ кабыл албайм десеңиз, колуңузду ошондой эле сууга салсаңыз болот."},{"question":"Sanwo-Olu paṣẹ ki wọn tu awọn tọlọpaa mu lasiko iwọde SARS silẹ","answer":"Gomina ipinlẹ Eko, Babajide Oluṣọla Sanwo-Olu, ti paṣẹ pe kileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ati ẹka eto idajọ nipinlẹ naa tete tu gbogbo awọn ti wọn mu fun ẹsun kan tabi omi-in lasiko iwọde ta ko SARS to kọja laipẹ yii silẹ, ki kaluku wọn maa lọ sile rẹ lalaafia.Amofin agba to tun jẹ kọmiṣanna feto idajọ nipinlẹ Eko, Adajọ Moyọsọrẹ Onigbanjo, ni gomina fi iṣẹ naa ran laaarọ ọjọ Aiku, Sannde yii.O ni lara ọtalelọọọdunrun o le ẹyọ kan (361) eeyan tileeṣẹ ọlọpaa mu pe wọn rufin lasiko iwọde ọhun, ọtalerugba o din meje (253) ninu wọn ni ẹka to n gba ẹjọ araalu ro, to si n fun adajọ nimọran (Directorate for Public Prosecution), ti lọọ ṣewadii wọn, ti wọn ko si ri idi kan lati ba wọn ṣe ẹjọ, tori ko si ẹri lati fi gbe ẹsun ti wọn fi kan wọn lẹsẹ.Latari eyi ni gomina fi paṣẹ pe ki wọn tu awọn eeyan naa silẹ nibikibi ti wọn ba fi wọn pamọ si, iba a jẹ ahamọ ọlọpaa tabi ọgba ẹwọn.Onigbanjo sọ siwaju pe ogoji ẹsun lawọn ọlọpaa ko wa sẹka eto idajọ lọjọ kẹrin si ikarun-un, oṣu yii, eeyan to ju ọgọrun-un lọ si lọrọ ẹjọ naa kan. Loju ẹsẹ lo lawọn ti fi awọn iwe ẹsun to kan ọgọrin eeyan lara wọn ṣọwọ sawọn ile-ẹjọ loriṣiiriṣii ki igbẹjọ le tete bẹrẹ lori wọn, awọn si da iwe ẹṣẹ eeyan mẹrindinlogun pada sọdọ awọn ọlọpaa fun iwadii lori ẹsun ti wọn fi kan wọn bii fifọ ile onile, biba dukia ẹlomi-in jẹ, ole jija, didana sun dukia ijọba, iṣikapaniyan ati dida omi alaafia ilu ru.Onigbanjo ni lati ọjọ Aje, Mọnde yii, ni igbẹjọ yoo bẹrẹ lori wọn."},{"question":"कारण बतायें।(i) भारत में अधिकांश वर्षा कुछ महीनों में केंद्रित होती है।(ii) तमिलनाडु तट पर शीतकालीन वर्षा होती है।(iii) पूर्वी तट का डेल्टा क्षेत्र अक्सर चक्रवातों से प्रभावित होता है।(iv) राजस्थान, गुजरात के कुछ हिस्से और पश्चिमी घाट का निचला हिस्सा सूखाग्रस्त है।","answer":"(i) भारत में अधिकांश वर्षा कुछ महीनों में केंद्रित होती है।भारत में दक्षिण-पश्चिम मानसून के आगमन से मौसम में पूर्ण परिवर्तन आता है। सीज़न की शुरुआत में, पश्चिमी घाट के घुमावदार हिस्से में 250 सेमी से अधिक, बहुत भारी वर्षा होती है। वर्षा छाया क्षेत्र में स्थित होने के बावजूद दक्कन के पठार और मध्य प्रदेश के कुछ हिस्सों में भी कुछ मात्रा में वर्षा होती है। इस ऋतु की सर्वाधिक वर्षा देश के उत्तर-पूर्वी भाग में होती है। खासी पहाड़ियों की दक्षिणी श्रृंखला में मावसिनराम में दुनिया में सबसे अधिक औसत वर्षा होती है। गंगा घाटी में वर्षा पूर्व से पश्चिम की ओर घटती जाती है। राजस्थान और गुजरात के कुछ हिस्सों में कम वर्षा होती है।(ii) तमिलनाडु तट पर शीतकालीन वर्षा होती है।उत्तरी मैदानी इलाकों में ठंड के मौसम की एक विशिष्ट विशेषता पश्चिम और उत्तर-पश्चिम से चक्रवाती विक्षोभों का आना है। ये निम्न दबाव प्रणालियाँ भूमध्य सागर और पश्चिमी एशिया के ऊपर से उत्पन्न होती हैं और पश्चिमी प्रवाह के साथ भारत की ओर बढ़ती हैं। वे मैदानी इलाकों में सर्दियों में बहुत जरूरी बारिश और पहाड़ों में बर्फबारी का कारण बनते हैं। हालाँकि स्थानीय स्तर पर 'महावत' के नाम से जानी जाने वाली शीतकालीन वर्षा की कुल मात्रा कम है, लेकिन 'रबी' फसलों की खेती के लिए उनका बहुत महत्व है। प्रायद्वीपीय क्षेत्र में कोई सुपरिभाषित ठंड का मौसम नहीं होता है। समुद्र के मध्यम प्रभाव के कारण सर्दियों के दौरान तापमान पैटर्न में शायद ही कोई उल्लेखनीय मौसमी बदलाव होता है।(iii) पूर्वी तट का डेल्टा क्षेत्र अक्सर चक्रवातों से प्रभावित होता है।उत्तर-पश्चिमी भारत में निम्न दबाव की स्थिति नवंबर की शुरुआत में बंगाल की खाड़ी में स्थानांतरित हो जाती है। यह बदलाव चक्रवाती अवसादों की घटना से जुड़ा है, जो अंडमान सागर के ऊपर उत्पन्न होते हैं। ये चक्रवात आम तौर पर भारत के पूर्वी तटों को पार करते हैं और भारी और व्यापक बारिश का कारण बनते हैं। ये उष्णकटिबंधीय चक्रवात अक्सर बहुत विनाशकारी होते हैं। गोदावरी, कृष्णा और कावेरी के घनी आबादी वाले डेल्टा अक्सर चक्रवातों से प्रभावित होते हैं, जो जीवन और संपत्ति को भारी नुकसान पहुंचाते हैं। कभी-कभी ये चक्रवात उड़ीसा, पश्चिम बंगाल और बांग्लादेश के तटों पर पहुँच जाते हैं।(iv) राजस्थान, गुजरात के कुछ हिस्से और पश्चिमी घाट का निचला भाग सूखा-प्रवण हैमानसून की प्रकृति के कारण, वार्षिक वर्षा वर्ष-दर-वर्ष अत्यधिक परिवर्तनशील होती है। कम वर्षा वाले क्षेत्रों जैसे राजस्थान, गुजरात के कुछ हिस्सों और पश्चिमी घाट के निचले हिस्से में परिवर्तनशीलता अधिक है। इस प्रकार, जहाँ अधिक वर्षा वाले क्षेत्र बाढ़ से प्रभावित होते हैं, वहीं कम वर्षा वाले क्षेत्र सूखा-प्रवण होते हैं।"},{"question":"仙台や平塚が有名な「たなばた」。このたなばたを漢字で書くときに使われる数字は？","answer":"七です。"},{"question":"The Smart Money Woman","answer":"The Smart Money Woman Jẹ fíìmù orílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà oloṣeṣe ti o da lórí aramada 2016 ti orukọ n je Arese Ugwu. Afihan akoko rẹ̀ jàde lórí AfricanMagic Showcase ní oṣù kẹsan ní ọdún 2020. A ṣè àwọn fíìmù náà lati ṣe iṣe iyasọtọ ati mu ohun ti o wa nínú iwe aramada náà wa si oju aye. Akoko Afihan ise yi, jàde ní ori AfricanMagic gege bi ise oni'pele mẹtala. Onkọwe Arese Ugwu àti Kemi Lala Akindoju lo gbe jàde. O ya Osas Ighodaro, Timini Egbuson, Ini Dima-Okojie, Kemi Lala Akindoju àti ọpọlọpọ àwọn miiran.The Smart Money Woman jẹ́ ìtàn àwọn obìnrin marun àti bí wọ́n se n ṣé iṣakoso inawo àti dukia, ìtàn aramada náà dale lórí eto inawo àwọn obìnrin ati bí o nse nipa ribiribi lori ojo iwaju inawo won.. ìtàn aramada náà tun sọrọ nípa àwọn ọrẹ, iwa nípa afarawe, àti bí àwọn ipa awujọ se n ṣé akoso inawo lawo li 'jo iwaju.Àwọn òṣèréOsas Ighodaro as ZuriKemi Lala Akindoju as AdesuwaToni Tones as LaraEbenezer Eno as LadunEku Edewor as BankeTimini Egbuson as BobbyIni Dima-Okojie as TamiSeun Ajayi as Soji"},{"question":"Berikan satu contoh ayat dengan peribahasa \\"bagai aur ditarik songsang\\".","answer":"“Jika kamu menelaah pelajaran apabila sudah hampir peperiksaan, kamu akan berhadapan dengan banyak masalah bagai aur ditarik songsang,” pesan cikgu kepada pelajarnya."},{"question":"Đọc đoạn văn sau và đưa ra một tiêu đề phụ hợp với nội dung: Sau khi khép lại 5 tập của show thực tế \\"Hoa hậu thể thao Việt Nam\\", top 30 thí sinh Hoa hậu Thể thao Việt Nam (Miss Fitness Vietnam) đã bước vào màn tranh tài cuối cùng trong đêm chung kết diễn ra tối 31/7 tại TPHCM. Kết quả, thí sinh Đoàn Thu Thủy (SN 1995, đến từ Phú Thọ) đã đăng quang ngôi vị cao nhất. Người đẹp cao 1,72 m, số đo 3 vòng là 83-63-94cm. Tân Hoa hậu nhận được vương miện trị giá hơn 2 tỷ đồng. Trong các tập của chương trình thực tế, Thu Thủy luôn nằm trong top thí sinh sáng giá, được đánh giá cao nhờ sự tin, thần thái thu hút. Trước đây, Thu Thủy từng lọt top 10 Siêu mẫu Việt Nam 2015. Ở phần thi ứng xử, người đẹp nhận câu hỏi: \\"Nếu trở thành Hoa hậu Thể thao 2022, em sẽ mang đến cộng đồng điều gì?\\". Cô trả lời: \\"Nếu có cơ hội trở thành Hoa hậu, tôi mong muốn có nhiều thời gian để quan tâm đến sức khỏe và thể thao học đường. Tôi tin rằng thời đại ngày nay, chúng ta không chỉ quan tâm đến kiến thức mà còn phải quan tâm đến sức khỏe, để các em có tinh thần rèn luyện thể chất và thay đổi được ngoại hình, vóc dáng. Từ khi học lớp 5, tôi đã sẵn sàng dậy lúc 4h30 sáng mỗi ngày để tập tennis. Cũng chính tinh thần đó đã giúp tôi hôm nay tự tin đứng trên sân khấu này\\". Á hậu 1 là Lê Phương Thảo (SN 1994). Cô cao 1,72m, số đo hình thể 85-60-92cm, từng vào top 45 Hoa hậu Hoàn vũ Việt Nam 2019. Á hậu 2 là Chu Thị Ánh (SN 1997), quê Thanh Hóa, hiện là một giáo viên hình thể. Cô cao 1,72 m, số đo hình thể 84-61-95 cm. Ở phần thi ứng xử, Chu Thị Ánh được hỏi về chế độ dinh dưỡng. Cô gây tranh cãi khi ứng xử ấp úng, gần như không thể hoàn thành trôi chảy câu trả lời. Ngoài top 3 chung cuộc, Ban Tổ chức cũng trao một số giải thưởng phụ của cuộc thi năm nay: Người đẹp tài năng: Chu Lê Vi Anh Người đẹp hình thể: Chu Thị Ánh Người đẹp nhân ái: Lê Xuân Anh Người đẹp truyền thông: Lê Phương Thảo Người đẹp truyền cảm hứng: Trương Thị Hoài Sang Đêm chung kết mở đầu bằng phần thi đồng diễn. Top 30 thí sinh diện trang phục màu đỏ nổi bật của nhà thiết kế Hà Nhật Tiến, sau đó lần lượt hô tên, giới thiệu bản thân. Điểm nhấn của cuộc thi chính là phần trình diễn bikini kết hợp dụng cụ thể thao. Mỗi thí sinh mang một dụng cụ, đại diện cho những bộ môn khác nhau đồng thời khoe hình thể gợi cảm. Hai \\"hot TikToker\\" là Lê Xuân Anh (Lê Bống) và Trần Thanh Tâm cũng thu hút sự quan tâm khi có mặt trong top 30 thí sinh xuất sắc của đêm chung kết. Lê Xuân Anh dừng chân ở top 10, còn Trần Thanh Tâm dừng chân tại top 30. Ngoài các ca sĩ tham gia trình diễn là Đông Nhi, Erik, Only C... đêm chung kết còn có sự đổ bộ của dàn mỹ nhân như Minh Tú, Thúy Vân, Kỳ Duyên... Ban giám khảo bao gồm Á hậu, siêu mẫu Võ Hoàng Yến, Hoa Hậu Trần Tiểu Vy, Hoa hậu Hoàn cầu 2017 Đỗ Trần Khánh Ngân, Hoa khôi Thể thao 1995 Nguyễn Thu Hương... Đây là lần đầu tiên Hoa hậu Thể thao Việt Nam được tổ chức nhằm tôn vinh vẻ đẹp hiện đại, khỏe khoắn, đại diện cho thế hệ trẻ có bản lĩnh và tài năng. Ở chương trình truyền hình thực tế Hoa hậu Thể thao Việt Nam 2022, các người đẹp Minh Tú, Kỳ Duyên, Thúy Vân trực tiếp đào tạo, hướng dẫn 42 thí sinh. Sau đó, cuộc thi loại 12 người, chọn ra 30 gương mặt vào chung kết.","answer":"Cô gái \\"dậy 4h30 mỗi sáng tập tennis\\" đăng quang Hoa hậu Thể thao Việt Nam | Báo Dân trí"},{"question":"Hãy tiếp tục đoạn văn sau: Shakespeare đã viết gần 40 vở kịch, tất cả đều dưới dạng thơ, được chia thành ba loại: hài kịch, bi kịch và lịch sử. Nghệ thuật hài kịch của Shakespeare đa dạng, phát triển rõ rệt từ những vở đầu tiên đến những vở cuối cùng. Cái hài xuất hiện ","answer":"trong cả kịch lịch sử và bi kịch nhưng tập trung hơn cả trong hài kịch.Giấc mộng đêm hè, Đêm thứ mười hai... là những vở hài kịch được biểu diễn rất nhiều lần sau khi Shakespeare qua đời cho đến tận ngày nay. Các vai hề trong hài kịch của ông tiêu biểu cho khiếu hài hước và trí tuệ.Chủ nghĩa hiện thực trong sáng tác hài kịch của Shakespeare được đánh giá là đạt đỉnh cao rực rỡ. Tác phẩm của ông là tiếng nói của lương tri tiến bộ, khát vọng tự do, lòng nhân ái bao la và niềm tin bất diệt vào khả năng hướng thiện, vươn dậy để khẳng định cuộc sống của con người."},{"question":"ప్రశ్న : సింధూ లోయ, నాగరికత తవ్వకాలలో పాల్గొన్నదెవరు?","answer":"1850లో బ్రిటీష్ ఇంజనీర్లు కరాచీ లాహోరు నగరాల మధ్య రైలు మార్గాలు వేయుటకు తవ్వకాలు జరుపుతుండిరి. ఆ తవ్వకాలలో వేలాది రాళ్ళు దొరికినవి రైలు మార్గాలు వేయుటకు ఆ రాళ్ళను ఉపయోగించాలని నిర్ణయించారు. ఆ రాళ్ళు అయిదు వేల సంవత్సరాల క్రితంవన్న సంగతి అప్పుడు తెలియదు. 1920లో పురావస్తు శాస్త్రవేత్తలు అక్కడ గొప్ప నాగరికత ఉండేదని గ్రహించారు. దీనినే సింధూలోయ నాగరికత అని హరప్పా నాగరికత అని అంటారు. 1921-22 సం॥లలో అప్పటి పురావస్తుశాఖ డైరెక్టర్ జనరల్ అయిన సజాన్ మార్నల్ ఆధ్వర్యంలో హరప్పాలో దయారాం సాహి, మొహంజోదారోలో ఆర్.డి. బెనర్జీలు త్రవ్వకాలను జరిపి సింధూ నాగరికత – విశేషాలను వెలుగులోకి తెచ్చారు."},{"question":"كم عدد مفاتيح الغيب التي لا يعلم بها الا الله سبحانه وتعالى؟","answer":"خمسة مفاتيح"},{"question":"Quelle stratégie puis-je utiliser pour réussir mon prochain test de mathématiques ?","answer":"Refais les exercices et vérifie tes réponses.Ce sont souvent les fautes d'inattention ou de compréhension qui sont les causes de mauvaises réponses. S'il te reste encore du temps, retourne faire les problèmes qui te font douter, ou bien ceux où tu avais mis un X. Commence par vérifier si ta réponse est plausible dans le contexte du problème. En algèbre, remplace ta réponse dans les données du problème pour voir si l'équation est vraie. En géométrie, est-ce que la mesure trouvée est réaliste selon les autres mesures données ? Si tu n'es pas certain, recommence le problème sur une feuille brouillon (n’efface surtout pas). Si tu n'obtiens pas la même réponse, essaie d'identifier l'endroit où les calculs pourraient diverger afin de trouver l'erreur et détermine la bonne version.L'important c'est de s'assurer d'avoir appliqué les bonnes notions mathématiques aux bons endroits. Il ne faut pas paniquer si on pense qu'une petite erreur de calcul s'est glissée."},{"question":"السؤال: كم عدد المناطق الزمنية الموجودة في روسيا؟","answer":"11 لإجابة: "},{"question":"Beyond the usual suspects: Who are some lesser-known Nobel laureates whose work has had a significant impact on our world?","answer":"While Nobel Prizes often celebrate the groundbreaking achievements of the scientific and intellectual elite, many impactful laureates fly below the radar. Here are a few examples:Elizabeth Blackburn: In 2009, she won the Nobel Prize in Physiology or Medicine for discovering telomerase, an enzyme crucial for maintaining the integrity of our DNA. This discovery has implications for aging, cancer, and regenerative medicine.Elinor Ostrom: The first woman to win the Nobel Prize in Economics (2009), she challenged traditional economic models by studying how communities manage common resources sustainably. Her work has influenced policies on everything from fisheries to forests.Rigoberta Menchú Tum: Awarded the Nobel Peace Prize in 1992 for her advocacy for indigenous rights in Guatemala, Menchú's powerful story of resilience and resistance against oppression continues to inspire activists worldwide."},{"question":" Waxaad sheegtaa ninkii jebiyey dhooshii Nebigaﷺ, dagaalkii Uxud","answer":" Wuxuu ahaa Cuqba binu abdi waqaas"},{"question":"Eikö ukonilmalla ole vaarallista olla lentokoneessa?","answer":"Salamat iskevät lentokoneisiin melko useinkin. Usein salamoita ei matkustaessa edes huomaa muuten ympärillä olevan salamoinnin seasta. Lentokoneet ovat erityisesti rakennettu kestämään salamaniskuja. Periaatteessa salama kulkee koneen runkoa pitkin ja jatkaa siitä matkaansa menemättä itse matkustamoon tai muihin koneen elektronisiin laitteisiin.Samaan tapaan auto on ukonilmalla melko turvallinen paikka. Salaman iskiessä autoon, salama matkaa auton metallikoria pitkin maahan eikä usein aiheuta mitään vahinkoa sisällä oleville. Toki aina poikkeuksia löytyy, mutta pääsääntöisesti vahinkoa aiheuttavia salamaniskuja on huomattavan vähän verrattuna kokonaistapausten määrään.Toki lentokapteenit pyrkivät välttämään kaikkein voimakkaimpia ukkossoluja, sillä niissä saattaa sataa useiden senttimetrejä halkaisijaltaan olevia rakeita ja nousuvirtaukset sekä laskuvirtaukset voivat pahimmillaan olla useita kymmeniä metrejä sekunnissa."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਮਾਝ ਮਹਲਾ ੩ ॥ਅੰਮ੍ਰਿਤੁ ਵਰਸੈ ਸਹਜਿ ਸੁਭਾਏ ॥ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਵਿਰਲਾ ਕੋਈ ਜਨੁ ਪਾਏ ॥ਅੰਮ੍ਰਿਤੁ ਪੀ ਸਦਾ ਤ੍ਰਿਪਤਾਸੇ ਕਰਿ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਤ੍ਰਿਸਨਾ ਬੁਝਾਵਣਿਆ ॥੧॥ਹਉ ਵਾਰੀ ਜੀਉ ਵਾਰੀ ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਅੰਮ੍ਰਿਤੁ ਪੀਆਵਣਿਆ ॥ਰਸਨਾ ਰਸੁ ਚਾਖਿ ਸਦਾ ਰਹੈ ਰੰਗਿ ਰਾਤੀ ਸਹਜੇ ਹਰਿ ਗੁਣ ਗਾਵਣਿਆ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਗੁਰ ਪਰਸਾਦੀ ਸਹਜੁ ਕੋ ਪਾਏ ॥ਦੁਬਿਧਾ ਮਾਰੇ ਇਕਸੁ ਸਿਉ ਲਿਵ ਲਾਏ ॥ਨਦਰਿ ਕਰੇ ਤਾ ਹਰਿ ਗੁਣ ਗਾਵੈ ਨਦਰੀ ਸਚਿ ਸਮਾਵਣਿਆ ॥੨॥ਸਭਨਾ ਉਪਰਿ ਨਦਰਿ ਪ੍ਰਭ ਤੇਰੀ ॥ਕਿਸੈ ਥੋੜੀ ਕਿਸੈ ਹੈ ਘਣੇਰੀ ॥ਤੁਝ ਤੇ ਬਾਹਰਿ ਕਿਛੁ ਨ ਹੋਵੈ ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਸੋਝੀ ਪਾਵਣਿਆ ॥੩॥ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਤਤੁ ਹੈ ਬੀਚਾਰਾ ॥ਅੰਮ੍ਰਿਤਿ ਭਰੇ ਤੇਰੇ ਭੰਡਾਰਾ ॥ਬਿਨੁ ਸਤਿਗੁਰ ਸੇਵੇ ਕੋਈ ਨ ਪਾਵੈ ਗੁਰ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਤੇ ਪਾਵਣਿਆ ॥੪॥ਸਤਿਗੁਰੁ ਸੇਵੈ ਸੋ ਜਨੁ ਸੋਹੈ ॥ਅੰਮ੍ਰਿਤ ਨਾਮਿ ਅੰਤਰੁ ਮਨੁ ਮੋਹੈ ॥ਅੰਮ੍ਰਿਤਿ ਮਨੁ ਤਨੁ ਬਾਣੀ ਰਤਾ ਅੰਮ੍ਰਿਤੁ ਸਹਜਿ ਸੁਣਾਵਣਿਆ ॥੫॥ਮਨਮੁਖੁ ਭੂਲਾ ਦੂਜੈ ਭਾਇ ਖੁਆਏ ॥ਨਾਮੁ ਨ ਲੇਵੈ ਮਰੈ ਬਿਖੁ ਖਾਏ ॥ਅਨਦਿਨੁ ਸਦਾ ਵਿਸਟਾ ਮਹਿ ਵਾਸਾ ਬਿਨੁ ਸੇਵਾ ਜਨਮੁ ਗਵਾਵਣਿਆ ॥੬॥ਅੰਮ੍ਰਿਤੁ ਪੀਵੈ ਜਿਸ ਨੋ ਆਪਿ ਪੀਆਏ ॥ਗੁਰ ਪਰਸਾਦੀ ਸਹਜਿ ਲਿਵ ਲਾਏ ॥ਪੂਰਨ ਪੂਰਿ ਰਹਿਆ ਸਭ ਆਪੇ ਗੁਰਮਤਿ ਨਦਰੀ ਆਵਣਿਆ ॥੭॥ਆਪੇ ਆਪਿ ਨਿਰੰਜਨੁ ਸੋਈ ॥ਜਿਨਿ ਸਿਰਜੀ ਤਿਨਿ ਆਪੇ ਗੋਈ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਨਾਮੁ ਸਮਾਲਿ ਸਦਾ ਤੂੰ ਸਹਜੇ ਸਚਿ ਸਮਾਵਣਿਆ ॥੮॥੧੬॥੧੭॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 119 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਮਰਦਾਸ ਜੀ ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਵਾਰਾਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਸਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਜਦੋਂ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਆਤਮਕ ਅਡੋਲਤਾ ਵਿਚ ਟਿਕਦਾ ਹੈ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਪ੍ਰੇਮ ਵਿਚ ਜੁੜਦਾ ਹੈ, ਤਦੋਂ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਅੰਦਰ ਆਤਮਕ ਜੀਵਨ ਦੇਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਨਾਮ-ਜਲ ਵਰਖਾ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ । ਪਰ (ਇਹ ਦਾਤਿ) ਕੋਈ ਉਹ ਵਿਰਲਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਹਾਸਲ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਜੋ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਦੱਸੇ ਰਾਹ ਤੇ ਤੁਰਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਆਤਮਕ ਜੀਵਨ ਦੇਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਨਾਮ-ਜਲ ਪੀ ਕੇ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਸਦਾ ਲਈ (ਮਾਇਆ ਵਲੋਂ) ਰੱਜ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ, (ਪ੍ਰਭੂ) ਮਿਹਰ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਤ੍ਰਿਸ਼ਨਾ ਬੁਝਾ ਦੇਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੧।ਮੈਂ ਸਦਾ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਤੋਂ ਸਦਕੇ ਹਾਂ ਕੁਰਬਾਨ ਹਾਂ, ਜੇਹੜੇ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸ਼ਰਨ ਪੈ ਕੇ ਆਤਮਕ ਜੀਵਨ ਦੇਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਨਾਮ ਜਲ ਪੀਂਦੇ ਹਨ ।ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਜੀਭ ਨਾਮ-ਰਸ ਚਖ ਕੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਪ੍ਰੇਮ ਰੰਗ ਵਿਚ ਸਦਾ ਰੰਗੀ ਰਹਿੰਦੀ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਆਤਮਕ ਅਡੋਲਤਾ ਵਿਚ ਟਿਕ ਕੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਗੁਣ ਗਾਂਦੇ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ।ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਨਾਲ ਕੋਈ ਵਿਰਲਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਆਤਮਕ ਅਡੋਲਤਾ ਹਾਸਲ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ,(ਜਿਸ ਦੀ ਬਰਕਤਿ ਨਾਲ) ਉਹ ਮਨ ਦਾ ਦੁਚਿੱਤਾ-ਪਨ ਮਾਰ ਕੇ ਸਿਰਫ਼ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ (ਦੇ ਚਰਨਾਂ) ਨਾਲ ਲਗਨ ਲਾਈ ਰੱਖਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਜਦੋਂ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ (ਕਿਸੇ ਜੀਵ ਉੱਤੇ ਮਿਹਰ ਦੀ) ਨਿਗਾਹ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਤਦੋਂ ਉਹ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਗੁਣ ਗਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਤੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਮਿਹਰ ਦੀ ਨਜ਼ਰ ਨਾਲ ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਵਿਚ ਲੀਨ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ ।੨।ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ! ਤੇਰੀ ਮਿਹਰ ਦੀ ਨਿਗਾਹ ਸਭ ਜੀਵਾਂ ਉੱਤੇ ਹੀ ਹੈ, ਕਿਸੇ ਉੱਤੇ ਥੋੜੀ ਹੈ ਕਿਸੇ ਉੱਤੇ ਬਹੁਤੀ ਹੈ । ਤੈਥੋਂ ਬਾਹਰ (ਤੇਰੀ ਮਿਹਰ ਦੀ ਨਿਗਾਹ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ) ਕੁਝ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੁੰਦਾ—ਇਹ ਸਮਝ ਉਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੂੰ ਪੈਂਦੀ ਹੈ ਜੋ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸ਼ਰਨ ਪੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੩।ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸਨਮੁਖ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੇ ਇਸ ਅਸਲੀਅਤ ਨੂੰ ਸਮਝਿਆ ਹੈ ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ! ਆਤਮਕ ਜੀਵਨ ਦੇਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਤੇਰੇ ਨਾਮ-ਜਲ ਨਾਲ ਤੇਰੇ ਖ਼ਜ਼ਾਨੇ ਭਰੇ ਪਏ ਹਨ, (ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸਨਮੁਖ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਜਾਣਦਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ) ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸ਼ਰਨ ਪੈਣ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਕੋਈ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨਾਮ-ਅੰਮ੍ਰਿਤ ਨਹੀਂ ਲੈ ਸਕਦਾ । ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਨਾਲ ਹੀ ਹਾਸਲ ਕਰ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ ।੪।ਜੇਹੜਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਸੋਹਣੇ ਜੀਵਨ ਵਾਲਾ ਬਣ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ,ਆਤਮਕ ਜੀਵਨ ਦੇਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਨਾਮ ਵਿਚ ਉਸ ਦਾ ਅੰਦਰਲਾ ਮਨ ਮਸਤ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਉਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦਾ ਮਨ ਉਸ ਦਾ ਤਨ ਨਾਮ-ਅੰਮ੍ਰਿਤ ਨਾਲ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਦੀ ਬਾਣੀ ਨਾਲ ਰੰਗਿਆ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਆਤਮਕ ਅਡੋਲਤਾ ਵਿਚ ਟਿਕ ਕੇ ਉਹ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਆਤਮਕ ਜੀਵਨ ਦੇਣ ਵਾਲੀ ਨਾਮ-ਧੁਨੀ ਨੂੰ ਸੁਣਦਾ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ ।੫।ਪਰ ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਦੇ ਪਿੱਛੇ ਤੁਰਨ ਵਾਲਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਕੁਰਾਹੇ ਪੈ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਪਿਆਰ ਵਿਚ (ਰੁੱਝ ਕੇ) ਸਹੀ ਜੀਵਨ-ਰਾਹ ਤੋਂ ਖੁੰਝ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਉਹ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਿਮਰਦਾ, ਉਹ (ਮਾਇਆ ਦਾ ਮੋਹ-ਰੂਪ) ਜ਼ਹਰ ਖਾ ਕੇ ਆਤਮਕ ਮੌਤ ਸਹੇੜ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।(ਗੰਦ ਦੇ ਕੀੜੇ ਵਾਂਗ) ਉਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦਾ ਨਿਵਾਸ ਸਦਾ ਹਰ ਵੇਲੇ (ਵਿਕਾਰਾਂ ਦੇ) ਗੰਦ ਵਿਚ ਹੀ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਸੇਵਾ-ਭਗਤੀ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਉਹ ਆਪਣਾ ਮਨੁੱਖਾ ਜਨਮ ਜ਼ਾਇਆ ਕਰ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੬।(ਪਰ ਜੀਵਾਂ ਦੇ ਭੀ ਕੀਹ ਵੱਸ ?) ਉਹੀ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਆਤਮਕ ਜੀਵਨ ਦੇਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਨਾਮ-ਜਲ ਪੀਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਜਿਸ ਨੂੰ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਆਪ ਮਿਲਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ,ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਨਾਲ ਉਹ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਆਤਮਕ ਅਡੋਲਤਾ ਵਿਚ ਟਿਕ ਕੇ (ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਚਰਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ) ਸੁਰਤਿ ਜੋੜੀ ਰੱਖਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਮਤਿ ਲੈ ਕੇ ਫਿਰ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਇਹ ਪ੍ਰਤੱਖ ਦਿੱਸਦਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਸਰਬ-ਵਿਆਪਕ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਹਰ ਥਾਂ ਆਪ ਹੀ ਮੌਜੂਦ ਹੈ ।੭।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ !) ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਪ੍ਰਭਾਵ ਤੋਂ ਉੱਚਾ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਹਰ ਥਾਂ ਆਪ ਹੀ ਆਪ ਮੌਜੂਦ ਹੈ ।ਜਿਸ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨੇ ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰਿਸ਼ਟੀ ਪੈਦਾ ਕੀਤੀ ਹੈ ਉਹ ਆਪ ਹੀ ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਨਾਸ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ ! ਤੂੰ ਉਸ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਸਦਾ ਆਪਣੇ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਸਾਂਭ ਰੱਖ । (ਨਾਮ ਸਿਮਰਨ ਦੀ ਬਰਕਤਿ ਨਾਲ) ਆਤਮਕ ਅਡੋਲਤਾ ਵਿਚ ਟਿਕ ਕੇ ਉਸ ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਵਿਚ ਲੀਨ ਰਹੀਦਾ ਹੈ ।੮।੧੬।੧੭।\\""},{"question":"பேப்பர் கிடையாது வாய்பாடு தெரியாது . கணக்கிலோ புலி அது என்ன?","answer":"கால்குலேட்டர்."},{"question":"“Maloto be ny tora-pasika ka tsy afaka nilomano izahay”. Inona ny fihetseham-po raketin'io fanambarana io?","answer":"Ity fanambarana ity dia maneho fihetseham-po ratsy. Diso fanantenana ilay olona noho ny toetry ny tora-pasika."},{"question":"Bagaimana cara bolos dari sekolah tanpa ketahuan guru?","answer":"Mohon maaf, saya tidak bisa menjawab pertanyaan tersebut. Jika Anda memiliki pertanyaan lain, saya akan dengan senang hati membantu. "},{"question":"வினா:வட்டெழுத்து என்றால் என்ன?","answer":"விடை:வட்டெழுத்து என்பது கி.பி மூன்றாம் நூற்றாண்டிலிருத்து கி.பி பத்தாம் நூற்றாண்டு வரை தமிழை எழுத பயன்படுத்தப்பட்டு வந்த ஓர் எழுத்து முறையாகும். வட்டெழுத்தை மலையாள மொழியினை எழுதவும் பயன்படுத்தினர். தற்கால தமிழ் எழுத்துக்கள் தமிழி எழுத்திலிருந்து தோன்றியவையே. வட்டெழுத்தை வட்டம் என குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளனர்."},{"question":"I wonder తొర్లికొండ గ్రామ విస్తీర్ణం ఎంత?Can you get me some context to answer this (in the same language as my question)?","answer":"తొర్లికొండ తెలంగాణ రాష్ట్రం, నిజామాబాద్ జిల్లా, జక్రాన్‌పల్లి మండలంలోని గ్రామం.[1]ఇది మండల కేంద్రమైన జక్రాన్‌పల్లి నుండి 9 కి. మీ. దూరం లోను, సమీప పట్టణమైన ఆర్మూర్ నుండి 8 కి. మీ. దూరంలోనూ ఉంది.గణాంకాలు2011 భారత జనగణన గణాంకాల ప్రకారం ఈ గ్రామం 1103 ఇళ్లతో, 4413 జనాభాతో 1952 హెక్టార్లలో విస్తరించి ఉంది. గ్రామంలో మగవారి సంఖ్య 2185, ఆడవారి సంఖ్య 2228. షెడ్యూల్డ్ కులాల సంఖ్య 1134 కాగా షెడ్యూల్డ్ తెగల సంఖ్య 147. గ్రామం యొక్క జనగణన లొకేషన్ కోడ్ 570888[2].పిన్ కోడ్: 503224.విద్యా సౌకర్యాలుగ్రామంలో ఒక ప్రైవేటు బాలబడి ఉంది. ప్రభుత్వ ప్రాథమిక పాఠశాలలు రెండు, ప్రైవేటు ప్రాథమిక పాఠశాల ఒకటి , ప్రభుత్వ ప్రాథమికోన్నత పాఠశాల ఒకటి , ప్రైవేటు ప్రాథమికోన్నత పాఠశాల ఒకటి, ప్రభుత్వ మాధ్యమిక పాఠశాల ఒకటి ఉన్నాయి.సమీప జూనియర్ కళాశాల, ప్రభుత్వ ఆర్ట్స్ / సైన్స్ డిగ్రీ కళాశాల ఆర్మూర్లోను, ఇంజనీరింగ్ కళాశాల చేపూర్లోనూ ఉన్నాయి. సమీప వైద్య కళాశాల హైదరాబాదులోను, పాలీటెక్నిక్‌ నిజామాబాద్లోను, మేనేజిమెంటు కళాశాల ఆర్మూర్లోనూ ఉన్నాయి. సమీప వృత్తి విద్యా శిక్షణ పాఠశాల, అనియత విద్యా కేంద్రం నిజామాబాద్లోను, దివ్యాంగుల ప్రత్యేక పాఠశాల ఆర్మూర్ లోనూ ఉన్నాయి.వైద్య సౌకర్యంప్రభుత్వ వైద్య సౌకర్యంతొర్లికొండలో ఉన్న ఒక ప్రాథమిక ఆరోగ్య ఉప కేంద్రంలో డాక్టర్లు లేరు. ఇద్దరు పారామెడికల్ సిబ్బంది ఉన్నారు.సమీప సామాజిక ఆరోగ్య కేంద్రం, ప్రాథమిక ఆరోగ్య కేంద్రం గ్రామం నుండి 5 నుండి 10 కి.మీ. దూరంలో ఉన్నాయి. పశు వైద్యశాల, కుటుంబ సంక్షేమ కేంద్రం గ్రామం నుండి 5 నుండి 10 కి.మీ. దూరంలో ఉన్నాయి. మాతా శిశు సంరక్షణ కేంద్రం, టి. బి వైద్యశాల గ్రామం నుండి 10 కి.మీ. కంటే ఎక్కువ దూరంలో ఉన్నాయి. అలోపతి ఆసుపత్రి, ప్రత్యామ్నాయ ఔషధ ఆసుపత్రి, డిస్పెన్సరీ, సంచార వైద్య శాల గ్రామం నుండి 10 కి.మీ. కంటే ఎక్కువ దూరంలో ఉన్నాయి.ప్రైవేటు వైద్య సౌకర్యంగ్రామంలో4 ప్రైవేటు వైద్య సౌకర్యాలున్నాయి. డిగ్రీ లేని డాక్టర్లు నలుగురు ఉన్నారు. రెండు మందుల దుకాణాలు ఉన్నాయి.తాగు నీరుగ్రామంలో కుళాయిల ద్వారా రక్షిత మంచినీటి సరఫరా జరుగుతోంది. గ్రామంలో ఏడాది పొడుగునా చేతిపంపుల ద్వారా నీరు అందుతుంది. బోరుబావుల ద్వారా కూడా ఏడాది పొడుగునా నీరు అందుతుంది. కాలువ/వాగు/నది ద్వారా, చెరువు ద్వారా కూడా గ్రామానికి తాగునీరు లభిస్తుంది.పారిశుధ్యంమురుగునీరు బహిరంగ కాలువల ద్వారా ప్రవహిస్తుంది."},{"question":"السؤال: ما حكم بلع الريق للصائم؟","answer":"الإجابة: يجوز للصائم أن يبتلع ريقه."},{"question":"Trong các câu dưới đây, chọn câu đúng khi muốn viết tập hợp các kết quả có thể xảy ra khi gieo một con xúc xắc 6 mặt.A.1; 2; 3; 4; 5; 6B.Y = 6C.6D.Y = {1; 2; 3; 4; 5; 6}","answer":"Câu trả lời đúng: DCác kết quả có thể xảy ra khi gieo một con xúc xắc 6 mặt là: 1 chấm, 2 chấm, 3 chấm, 4 chấm, 5 chấm, 6 chấm.Vậy tập hợp cần tìm làY = {1; 2; 3; 4; 5; 6}"},{"question":"足の裏にある体の臓器を活性化させるツボを刺激する健康法のことを、「反射」と「学問」を合わせた言葉で何というでしょう？","answer":"リフレクソロジー"},{"question":"ตามกฎหมายไทยลิขสิทธิ์จะหมดไปเมื่อไร","answer":"ลิขสิทธิ์จะหมดไปเมื่อผู้สร้างสรรค์ผลงานเสียชีวิตไปเป็นเวลา 50 ปี"},{"question":"Apakah bahan-bahan yang digunakan untuk membuat congkak? Jelaskan dalam ayat-ayat yang tidak melebihi 120 patah perkataan. ","answer":"Congkak selalunya diperbuat daripada kayu hutan seperti merbau, keruing, balau dan sebagainya. Terdapat juga papan congkak yang dibuat daripada kayu rambutan, nangka dan sebagainya, mengikut kemampuan si tukang pembuat congkak. Congkak juga dihasilkan daripada logam ataupun tanah di kawasan pedalaman. Tempurung kelapa digunakan supaya tangan tidak kotor terkena tanah.Congkak zaman moden kebanyakannya diperbuat daripada plastik keras atau kayu mampat, dan dengan pelbagai jenis rekaan. Congkak juga diubah suai menjadi mudah alih , dan boleh dibimbit untuk dibawa ke mana-mana sahaja.Buah congkak yang dipakai selalunya ialah biji guli, buah saga, biji plastik, batu kecil, dan biji getah. Namun demikian, buah congkak tidak mempunyai bentuk yang tetap; apa-apa sahaja yang agak bulat dan sesuai boleh digunakan."},{"question":"Ik wil een aankoop doen van een NAS voor een klant die fotograaf is. Voorkeur heeft voor minimaal 4 bays maar mag ook meer.Ik wil een nas hebben die snel communicatie met de pc heeft. Dit om vanaf de nas beelden te kunnen inladen op de pc en dit moet snel kunnen.Ik zie dan qnap hiermee adverteert mede door dat de nas een snelle thunderbolt aansluiting heeft of dat 2 netwerk aansluitingen gecombineerd kunnen worden voor hogere data snelheid.Wie heeft er hier mee ervaringen mee of zit in de zelfde sector?Bedankt voor het lezen van deze topic en voor jou reactie!","answer":"Hoeveel capaciteit?Ik zie genoeg mensen een 4 bay kopen en er vervolgens 8TB schijven in doen. Dan liever een 2-bay met 2x 18TB."},{"question":"Formule una respuesta a esta pregunta elaborada: ¿En qué año nació el gerente del Reading Football Club reemplazado por Steve Clarke en la temporada 2014-15?","answer":"Clarke remplazó a Nigel Adkins, nacido en el año 1965."},{"question":"Cilladaha iyo xanuunada ka dhasha fitamiin B Yarida:","answer":"Cudurka dhan-qallalka (stroke)Fitamiin B wuxuu door wayn ka ciyaaraa habka burburinta iyo dheefsiga cunnada. Waxaa la aaminsan yahay in fitamiinkani uu hoos u dhigo cudurka dhan-qallalka). Cunnooyinka qaniga ku ah fitamiin B waxay yareeyaan khatarta dhan qallalka.Wuxuu Ka hortagga cudurka beriberi.Fitamiin B1 oo jirka ku yaraadaa waxay keenta cudurka beriberi oo ah cudur saameeya wadnaha, hab dhiska dheefshiidka iyo habdhiska neerfaha. Cudurka beriberi waxaa halis ugu jira dadka ay nafaqo darradu hayso iyo dadka khamriga aadka u cabba. Fitamiin B1 (thiamine) wuxuu caawiyaa in unugyada jirka ay tamar ka dhigtaan karboohaydaraytka leh, wuxuu u muhiim u yahay dumarka uurka leh, wuxuu kaloo uroon yahay murqaha iyo caafimaadka wadnaha iyo unugyada neerfaha. Fimamiinkani waxa oo uu kordhiyaa wareegga dhiigga. Fitamiin B1 waxaa laga helaa boorashka, liinta oranjada, lawska, ukunta, digirta iyo misirta.Fitamiin B2 Wuxuu xoojiyaa difaaca jirka:Fitamiin B2 waxaa loo yaqannaa “riboflavin” wuxuu caawiyaa fitamiinnada kale, wuxuu ilaaliyaa caafimaadka maqaarka, unugyada iyo caloosha. Wuxuu kaloo ka hortagaa madax xanuunka dhanjafka, caadka indhaha iyo finanka. Ilaha fitamiin B2 laga helo waxaa ka mid ah lawska, caanaha xoolaha, hilibka iyo khudradda cagaaran.Fitamiin B3 wuxuu jirka siiyaa tamarFitamiin B3 waxaa loo yaqaannaa “niacin”, wuxuu cunnada u beddelaa tamar. Dumarku waxay u baahan yihiin 14 mg ragguna waxay 16 mg oo fitamiinkaan maalin kasta. Fitamiin B3 ku filan oo jirku uu heli waayo waxay keeni kartaa Xaaladda xusuus gabka ee dimenshiya (Dementia), shuban iyo culaysyo jireed iyo kuwo maskaxeed. Ilaha ugu fiican ee laga helo fitamiin B3 waxaa ka mid ah digirta, lawska, caanaha xoolaha, kalluunka iyo hilibka.Fitamiin B5 wuxuu caawiyaa caafimaadka hormoonnadaFitamiin B5 uxuu lagama maarmnaan u yahay soo saarista hormoonnada koriimada qaabilsan. Wuxuu qooyaa maqaarka, wuxuu kor u qaadaa caafimaadka dubka, wuxuuna daahiya astaamaha duqnimada. Fitamiin B5 waxaa laga helaa kaabajka, broccoli-ga, baradhada, siriyaalka laga sameeyo badarka iyo cunnooyinka caanaha laga sameeyo.Fitamiin B6 wuxuu hoos u dhigaa halista wadne xanuunka:Wuxuu jirka u sameeyaa unugyada cascas ee dhiigga, wuxuu kobciyaa shaqada maskaxda, wuxuuna ka hortagaa wadne xanuunka. Ilaha cunno ee laga helo fitamiin B6 waxaa ka mid ah; mooska, digirta, karootada, burcadka, digaaga, misirta, kalluunka noocyada tuunada iyo salmon, haleyga (shrimp). Cunnooyinkan oo la cuno waxay hoos u dhigtaa khatarta wadne xanuunka.Fitamiin B12 wuxuu ka hortagaa dhiig yarida:Fitamiin B12 wuxuu muhiim u yahay caafimaadka unugyada dhiigga iyo unugyada neerfaha, wuxuu ka qayb qaataa samayska unugyada cascas ee ku jira dhiigga. Haddii uu jirka ka dhacsan yahay fitamiin B12 waxaa lagu fahmaa dhiig yari ugaar ah fitamiinkan oo la yiraahdo “prenicious anemia” iyo dareenka neerfaha oo jirka ka taga gaar ahaan lugaha oo gaari kara heer in qofka uu curyaamo dartiis. Dadka waa wayn waxay u baahan yihiin 2.4 mcg oo fitamiinkaan ah maalin kasta. Waxaa laga helaa kalluunka iyo hilibka Folic acid wuxuu caawiyaa koriimada iyo kobaca uurjiifka:Folic acid waxaa kaloo yaqaannaa folate iyo fitamiin B9 waxay muhiim u tahay korriimada uurjiifka, waxay ka hortagtaa in ilmaha ay ku dhashaan cillad. Folic acid waxaa laga helaa badarka, khudaarta cagaaran, liin bambeelada, lawska, digirta, iyo digirta cagaaran ee lagu kariyo cunnada (peas). Cabirka loo bahaan yahay in la cuno xilliga uurka waa 800 micrograms.Fitamiin B wuxuu koriyaa timaha:Haddii aad ka cababanayso timo daadasho waa inaad ku dedaadaashaa cunnooyinkan qaniga ku ah fitamiin B. Fitamiin B wuxuu koriyaa tinta, wuxuu hagaajiyaa wareegga dhiigga ee basada, wuxuuna ka hortagaa in timuhu ay cirraystaan."},{"question":"شعر زیر از مولانا به چه معناست؟کز نیستان تا مرا ببریده اند   /   در نفیرم مرد و زن نالیده اند","answer":"از همان روزی که مرا از اصل و خاستگاهم ( نیستان ) جدا کرده اند ، مرد و زن در ناله های من، ناله های جانگداز خود را سر داده اند و همراه من از درد فراق نالیده اند .منظور بیت این است که از وقتی که روح لطیف آدمی از مرتبه الهی به این جهان مادی هبوط کرده، سخت غمگین است و اشتیاق دارد که به اصل خود رجوع کند ."},{"question":"Athini amahlelo esiXhosa ukuqala ku-1 uyophela ku 15. Impendulo ibengesiXhosa.","answer":"Nanga amahlelo:1. Umntu2. Abantu1A. Umama2A. Oomama3. Umthi4. Imithi5. Ilifu6. Amafu7. Isitya8. Izitya9. In + ja = Inja10. Izinja11. Uluthi14. Ubuntu15. Ukutya EsiXhoseni alikho ihlelo 12 (leshumi elinesibini) nehlelo 13. (leshumi elinesithathu)."},{"question":"Napisz ciąg dalszy tekstu: W mistrzostwach AAA Championship Car Oldfield startował od początku istnienia, od 1905 roku. W pierwszym sezonie kontynuował swoją passę z poprzednich lat. ","answer":"Wygrał pięć wyścigów i sześciokrotnie stawał na podium. Dorobek 22 punktów pozwolił mu zdobyć tytuł mistrzowski. Do 1912 roku Amerykanin stawał na podium tylko w niepunktowanych rundach, bądź w odrębnych wyścigach. Na podium mistrzostw powrócił w sezonie 1913, kiedy został sklasyfikowany na ósmym miejscu w klasyfikacji generalnej. Rok później wystartował w wyścigu Indianapolis 500, który w samochodzie Stutz ukończył na piątej pozycji. W mistrzostwach nie odniósł zwycięstwa, jednak trzykrotnie stawał na podium. Z dorobkiem 990 punktów uplasował się na czwartym miejscu w końcowej klasyfikacji kierowców. W sezonie 1915 pięciokrotnie stawał na podium, w tym dwukrotnie na jego najwyższym stopniu - na Venice Speedway i w Tucson. Jednak nie wystartował w Indy 500, co spowodowało mniejszy dorobek punktowy niż u rywali i siódmą pozycję w klasyfikacji generalnej. Na torze Indianapolis Motor Speedway Oldfield pojawił się ponownie w 1916 roku i ponownie dojechał do mety jako piętnasty. W mistrzostwach był 28. Ostatnie podium w AAA Championship Car Amerykanin zaliczył w sezonie 1918, kiedy został sklasyfikowany na trzynastym miejscu."},{"question":"Жаныбарлар бул?","answer":"Жаныбарлар-жер шарындагы баардык жаныбарлардын жыйындысы."},{"question":" வினா: கம்பரை ஆதரித்த வள்ளல் யார் ?","answer":"விடை: சடையப்ப வள்ளல்."},{"question":"请回答以下问题：问题：哪位英国首相领导了1940年的大撤退并鼓舞了英国人民的斗志？","answer":"答案：温斯顿·丘吉尔是领导了1940年的大撤退并鼓舞了英国人民的斗志的英国首相。"},{"question":"ਨੀਲ ਕੰਠ ਬਾਰੇ ਦੱਸੋ ।","answer":"ਇਸ ਦਾ ਪੇਟ ਹਲਕੇ ਪੀਲੇ ਰੰਗ ਦਾ ਅਤੇ ਛਾਤੀ ਲਾਲ ਭੂਰੇ ਰੰਗ ਦੀ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ । ਇਸ ਦਾ ਆਕਾਰ ਕਬੂਤਰ ਵਰਗਾ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ । ਇਸ ਦੀ ਖੁਰਾਕ ਕੀੜੇ-ਮਕੌੜੇ ਹੁੰਦੇ ਹਨ । ਇਸ ਦਾ ਆਲ੍ਹਣਾ ਰੁੱਖਾਂ ਦੀਆਂ ਖੋੜਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ।"},{"question":"Nitori bi korona ṣe pa ọkan ninu wọn, awọn aṣofin Eko bẹrẹ ayẹwo","answer":"Latari aṣẹ tileegbimọ aṣofin Eko  pa pa pe ki gbogbo awọn ọmọ ile aṣofin naa, atawọn oṣiṣẹ wọn latoke delẹ lọọ ṣe ayẹwo arun Korona lati mọ ipo ti onikaluku wọn wa, awọn aṣofin ọhun ti n lọ fun ayẹwo wọn lọkọọkan.Igbesẹ yii ni wọn lo pọn dandan latari bi kokoro aṣekupani naa ṣe n ṣọṣẹ nipinlẹ ọhun, leyii to ti yọri si pipadanu awọn aṣofin meji laarin ọsẹ meji aabọ sira wọn.Ọnarebu Temitọpẹ Adewale to n ṣoju agbegbe idibo Ifakọ Ijaye kin-in-ni sọ ninu atẹjade kan pe abajade esi ayẹwo COVID-19 toun ṣe fi han pe oun ko ni arun naa lara.Yatọ si pe awọn aṣofin naa atawọn oṣiṣẹ wọn lọọ ṣayẹwo, AKEDE AGBAYE tun gbọ pe wọn ti paṣẹ pe ki wọn fin kẹmika si gbogbo ọfiisi ati ile awọn aṣofin naa, tori oju lalakan fi n ṣọri, igbesẹ naa si ti bẹrẹ laarin ọsẹ to kọja.Aipẹ yii ni arun buruku naa gbọna ẹburu pa ọkan lara awọn aṣofin ọhun, Ọnarebu Tunde Buraimoh, to n ṣoju agbegbe idibo Kosọfẹ Keji lojiji, ọrẹ timọtimọ si ni Buraimoh pẹlu aṣofin Oloogbe Sẹnetọ Adebayọ Ọshinọwọ ti wọn tun un pe ni Pepperito, to n ṣoju ẹkun idibo Ila-Oorun Eko nileegbimọ aṣofin agba l’Abuja, ẹni tiku yọwọ ẹ lawo lọjọ kẹẹẹdogun, oṣu to kọja, lai ro tẹlẹ.Ababọ ayẹwo iku ọhun ni wọn ni ko ṣẹyin COVID-19 to gbaye kan bayii, eyi si ti da ibẹrubojo sọkan awọn aṣofin atawọn araalu, tori ewu akoran arun buruku naa."},{"question":"ગુજરાતી ગઝલો ની યાદી આપો.","answer":"ગુજરાતી ગઝલો ની યાદી:૧. નયન ને બંધ રાખીને૨. શાંત ઝરુખે ૩. કાજલ ભર્યા નયન ના૪. કંકોત્રી ૫. જ્યારે પ્રણય ની૬. અરમાન લઈ ને૭. દૂર દૂર પર્વત પર૮. તારી આંખ નો અફીની ૯. દિકરી તો પાર કી થાપણ ૧૦. વિરહ માં૧૧. જીવન મરણ છે એક૧૨. દરિયાના મોજા૧૩. મન ના મને૧૪. જુવો લીલા કોલેજ માં જઈ રહી છે૧૫. પાગલ છે જેમાંનો૧૬. ખુદા તારી કસોટીની ની૧૭. વરસો જવાને જોઈએ૧૮. દીકરો મારો લાડકવાયો ૧૯. આપનું મુખ જોઇ૨૦. માનવ ના થઈ શક્યો"},{"question":"Wangsulana pitakonan iki nganggo konteks ukara lan pilihan jawaban sing disedhiyakake.Konteks: Gelombang gempa direkam dening mesin seismograf. Pitakonan:Apa sing dikirim gelombang gempa? Pilih saka: (1). energi; (2). cahya; (3). partikel; (4). kacepetan;Wangsulan:","answer":"Gempa bumi (Lindhu) iku fenomena guncang sing dumadi ing lumahing bumi. Contohe, gempa utawa lindhu tektonik, sing disebabake dening pelepasan energi akumulasi antarane rong utawa luwih lempeng bumi sing jejer (saben-saben tansah obah nganti 10 cm saben taun). Jawaban pitakonan ing nduwur yaiku: (1). energi."},{"question":"Ity misy ampahan-dahatsoratra: \\"Ny ety ifotony no mahalala ny zavatra ilainy sy maika, mandroso ho azy ny tanàna\\"inona no mampandroso ho azy ny tanàna?","answer":"mandroso ho azy ny tanàna raha ny eny ifotony no hanankinana ny fitantanana, satria izy ihany no mahalala ny ilainy sy maika"},{"question":"Mety ve ny misara-panambadiana?","answer":"Mamela ny mpivady hisaraka ny Baiboly, kanefa antony iray ihany no ahafahany misaraka. Hoy i Jesosy: “Izay misaraka amin’ny vadiny ka manambady olon-kafa, dia manitsakitsa-bady, raha tsy hoe noho ny fijangajangana [firaisana amin’ny olona tsy vadiny] ihany angaha no antony isarahany.”—Matio 19:9.Halan’Andriamanitra ny olona fetsifetsy sy mamitaka mba hahafahana misara-panambadiana. Hataony ampamoaka izay olona mandao ny vadiny tsy amin’antony, indrindra raha hoe  noho izy te hiaraka amin’olon-kafa no mahatonga azy hanao izany."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਗਉੜੀ ਮਹਲਾ ੫ ॥ਸਹਜਿ ਸਮਾਇਓ ਦੇਵ ॥ਮੋ ਕਉ ਸਤਿਗੁਰ ਭਏ ਦਇਆਲ ਦੇਵ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਕਾਟਿ ਜੇਵਰੀ ਕੀਓ ਦਾਸਰੋ ਸੰਤਨ ਟਹਲਾਇਓ ॥ਏਕ ਨਾਮ ਕੋ ਥੀਓ ਪੂਜਾਰੀ ਮੋ ਕਉ ਅਚਰਜੁ ਗੁਰਹਿ ਦਿਖਾਇਓ ॥੧॥ਭਇਓ ਪ੍ਰਗਾਸੁ ਸਰਬ ਉਜੀਆਰਾ ਗੁਰ ਗਿਆਨੁ ਮਨਹਿ ਪ੍ਰਗਟਾਇਓ ॥ਅੰਮ੍ਰਿਤੁ ਨਾਮੁ ਪੀਓ ਮਨੁ ਤ੍ਰਿਪਤਿਆ ਅਨਭੈ ਠਹਰਾਇਓ ॥੨॥ਮਾਨਿ ਆਗਿਆ ਸਰਬ ਸੁਖ ਪਾਏ ਦੂਖਹ ਠਾਉ ਗਵਾਇਓ ॥ਜਉ ਸੁਪ੍ਰਸੰਨ ਭਏ ਪ੍ਰਭ ਠਾਕੁਰ ਸਭੁ ਆਨਦ ਰੂਪੁ ਦਿਖਾਇਓ ॥੩॥ਨਾ ਕਿਛੁ ਆਵਤ ਨਾ ਕਿਛੁ ਜਾਵਤ ਸਭੁ ਖੇਲੁ ਕੀਓ ਹਰਿ ਰਾਇਓ ॥ਕਹੁ ਨਾਨਕ ਅਗਮ ਅਗਮ ਹੈ ਠਾਕੁਰ ਭਗਤ ਟੇਕ ਹਰਿ ਨਾਇਓ ॥੪॥੧੫॥੧੩੬॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 209 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਮੈਂ ਹੁਣ ਆਤਮਕ ਅਡੋਲਤਾ ਵਿਚ ਲੀਨ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹਾਂ ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਕਾਸ਼-ਰੂਪ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ! (ਤੇਰੀ ਮਿਹਰ ਨਾਲ) ਮੇਰੇ ਉਤੇ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਜੀ ਦਇਆਵਾਨ ਹੋ ਗਏ(ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ!) ਗੁਰੂ ਨੇ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਤੇਰਾ (ਹਰ ਥਾਂ ਵਿਆਪਕ) ਅਸਚਰਜ ਰੂਪ ਵਿਖਾ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਨੇ ਮੇਰੀ (ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਮੋਹ ਦੀ) ਫਾਹੀ ਕੱਟ ਕੇ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਤੇਰਾ ਦਾਸ ਬਣਾ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਹੈ, ਮੈਨੂੰ ਸੰਤ ਜਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਸੇਵਾ ਵਿਚ ਲਾ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਹੈ, ਹੁਣ ਮੈਂ ਸਿਰਫ਼ ਤੇਰੇ ਹੀ ਨਾਮ ਦਾ ਪੁਜਾਰੀ ਬਣ ਗਿਆ ਹਾਂ ।੧।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ!) ਜਦੋਂ ਗੁਰੂ ਦਾ ਬਖ਼ਸ਼ਿਆ ਗਿਆਨ ਮੇਰੇ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਪਰਗਟ ਹੋ ਗਿਆ, ਤਾਂ ਮੇਰੇ ਅੰਦਰ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਹੋਂਦ ਦਾ ਚਾਨਣ ਹੋ ਗਿਆ, ਮੈਨੂੰ ਸਭ ਥਾਂ ਉਸੇ ਦਾ ਚਾਨਣ ਦਿੱਸ ਪਿਆ । ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਨਾਲ ਮੈਂ ਆਤਮਕ ਜੀਵਨ ਦੇਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ-ਰਸ ਪੀਤਾ ਹੈ, ਤੇ ਮੇਰਾ ਮਨ (ਮਾਇਆ ਦੀ ਤ੍ਰਿਸ਼ਨਾ ਵਲੋਂ) ਰੱਜ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ । ਮੈਂ ਉਸ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਵਿਚ ਟਿਕ ਗਿਆ ਹਾਂ ਜਿਸ ਨੂੰ ਕੋਈ ਡਰ ਪੋਹ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਕਦਾ ।੨।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ!) ਗੁਰੂ ਦਾ ਹੁਕਮ ਮੰਨ ਕੇ ਮੈਂ ਸਾਰੇ ਸੁਖ-ਆਨੰਦ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਕਰ ਲਏ ਹਨ, ਮੈਂ ਆਪਣੇ ਅੰਦਰੋਂ ਦੁੱਖਾਂ ਦਾ ਡੇਰਾ ਹੀ ਉਠਾ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਹੈ । ਜਦੋਂ ਤੋਂ (ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਨਾਲ) ਠਾਕੁਰ-ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਜੀ ਮੇਰੇ ਉਤੇ ਮਿਹਰਬਾਨ ਹੋਏ ਹਨ, ਮੈਨੂੰ ਹਰ ਥਾਂ ਉਹ ਆਨੰਦ-ਸਰੂਪ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਹੀ ਦਿੱਸ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ ।੩।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ! ਜਦੋਂ ਤੋਂ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਜੀ ਮੇਰੇ ਉਤੇ ਦਇਆਵਾਨ ਹੋਏ ਹਨ, ਮੈਨੂੰ ਨਿਸ਼ਚਾ ਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ ਕਿ) ਨਾਹ ਕੁਝ ਜੰਮਦਾ ਹੈ ਨਾਹ ਕੁਝ ਮਰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਇਹ ਸਾਰਾ ਤਾਂ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਪਾਤਿਸ਼ਾਹ ਨੇ ਇਕ ਖੇਲ ਰਚਾਇਆ ਹੋਇਆ ਹੈ ।ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ! ਆਖ—ਸਰਬ-ਪਾਲਕ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਅਪਹੁੰਚ ਹੈ, ਸਭ ਜੀਵਾਂ ਦੀ ਪਹੁੰਚ ਤੋਂ ਪਰੇ ਹੈ । ਉਸ ਦੇ ਭਗਤਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਉਸ ਹਰੀ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਦਾ ਹੀ ਸਹਾਰਾ ਹੈ ।੪।੧੫।੧੩੬।\\""},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਸਲੋਕੁ ॥ਦੁਰਮਤਿ ਹਰੀ ਸੇਵਾ ਕਰੀ ਭੇਟੇ ਸਾਧ ਕ੍ਰਿਪਾਲ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਪ੍ਰਭ ਸਿਉ ਮਿਲਿ ਰਹੇ ਬਿਨਸੇ ਸਗਲ ਜੰਜਾਲ ॥੧੨॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 299 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਜੇਹੜੇ ਵਡ-ਭਾਗੀ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦਇਆ-ਦੇ-ਘਰ ਗੁਰੂ ਨੂੰ ਮਿਲ ਪਏ ਤੇ ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਦੱਸੀ ਸੇਵਾ ਕੀਤੀ, ਉਹਨਾਂ ਨੇ (ਆਪਣੇ ਅੰਦਰੋਂ) ਖੋਟੀ ਮਤਿ ਦੂਰ ਕਰ ਲਈ । ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ! ਜੇਹੜੇ ਬੰਦੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਚਰਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਜੁੜੇ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ, ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੇ (ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਮੋਹ ਦੇ) ਸਾਰੇ ਬੰਧਨ ਨਾਸ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ ।੧੨।\\""},{"question":"Menene Rabe-Raben Wasan Kwaikwayo?","answer":"A dunƙule, wasan kwaikwayo ya rabu gida biyu:1. Na gargajiya: Shi ne wasan kwaikwayon da aka gada tun kaka-da-kakanni. Ana gudanar da wasannin kwaikwayon gargajiya ta hanyoyi da yawa, daga ciki akwai kiɗan ‘yan’kama, wasan bori, wasannin tashe kamar wasan Mairama da Daudu, da sauransu.2. Na zamani: Wasan kwaikwayo na zamani shi ne wanda aka same shi bayan zuwan turawa. Ana gudanar da wasan kwaikwayo na zamani ta hanyar radiyo, talabijin, da kuma yinsa a aikace a gaban jama’a a fili ko a kan dandamali (stage)."},{"question":"Người kể trong văn bản “Bố của Xi-mông” là ai? ","answer":"Người kể vắng mặt trong văn bản “Bố của Xi-mông” "},{"question":"问题：三星手机在发展过程中取得了哪些重要突破？","answer":"答案：三星手机在技术和创新方面取得了多项重要突破，如推出首款彩色屏幕手机和内置摄像头手机等。"},{"question":"Nomme moi plusieurs répères importants sur la géographie de la Rébulique Démocratique du Congo.","answer":"-La République démocratique du Congo est située en plein centre de l'Afrique. C’est le deuxième plus grand pays d'Afrique après l’Algérie et le douzième plus grand pays au monde. Il atteint la rive de l'océan atlantique. Le Congo a une superficie de 2 345 000 km2 -Le territoire est composé de vastes savanes, de forêts et de montagnes. Le Congo a plein de lacs et de rivières dont les Grands Lacs et le fleuve Congo qui est le cinquième plus grand fleuve au monde pour sa longueur (4700km). La RDC possède une des plus grandes réserves d’eau douces de la Terre avec un réservoir de 16% de l’eau potable en Afrique. -Les températures sont hautes. Il fait chaud et humide la plupart du temps. C’est un climat tropical avec 2 saisons principales : la saison sèche et la saison des pluies. Les saisons ont des durées différentes selon la position de la région par rapport à l’équateur.  -Le Congo est un pays très riche en ressources naturelles, notamment en minerais précieux comme le diamant, l’or, le cuivre, l’uranium, le coltan et l’étain. "},{"question":"1 röntgen ne kadar radyasyon yayar?","answer":"Fokal uzaklığı 20 cm olan bir röntgen cihazı ile 65 kilovolt ve 10 miliamperde orta hızda bir film ile filtresiz olarak yapılan grafilerde hasta film başına 8.72 R (Roentgen) ve bütün ağız grafisi için ortala- ma 147.2 R'lik direkt radyasyon dozuna maruz kalmaktadır."},{"question":"අවසානය යන වචනයට අදහසක් ගෙන දෙන වචනය ලියා  දක්වන්න.","answer":"අවසානය යන්නට විරුද්ධ අර්ථයක් ඇති පදය ආරම්භය වේ. "},{"question":"የሴኔጋል ቱባ ከተማ በነዋሪ ብዛት ስንተኛው ነው?","answer":"ሁለተኛው"},{"question":"Sheekada Gunaanadka Dunida 15?","answer":"Gunaanadka Dunida (15) | Astaamaha Saacadda ee aan Weli Dhicin.Haddii aynu soo aragnay astaamaha saacadda ee yaryar kuwaas oo dhacay, waqti kastana sii kordhaya, maanta waxaynu baran doonnaa astaamaha saacadda ee yaryar, ee aan weli dhicin. Kuwan waxa ka mid ah: go'doominta magaalada Madiina, badashada dummarka iyo yaraanta ragga, hadlidda dugaagga iyo manoolayaasha, iyo soo banbixidda shayaadiin Quraan akhriyaya.1. Go'doominta Madiina.Ibnu Cumar (rc) waxa laga weriyay inuu yidhi, Rasuulka Ilaahay (scw) ayaa yidhi, \\"Waxa dhow in muslimiinta lagu soo go'doomiyo magaalada Madiina, heer uu noqdo dhufayskooda ugu shisheeyaa goobta Salaax.\\"¹• Salaaxna waa meel u dhow Khaybar.Xadiiskani wuxuu tilmaamayaa marka uu dhammaystirmayo weetaynta ay gaaladu ku hayaan muslimiinta, heer ay ku soo ururin doonaan magaalada Madiina iyo hareeraheeda xilliga aakhiru-sabaanka, gaar ahaanna waqtiga Dajaal.2. Badashada Dummarka iyo Yaraanta Ragga.Abi Muusa (rc) wuxuu ka weriyay Nebiga (scw) inuu yidhi, \\"Waxa ku soo fool leh dadka  xilli uu ninku la wareegayo sadaqo dahab ah, kadibna aanu helay cid ka qaadata. Waxa la arkayaa ninka ragga ah ee keliya oo ay daba-socdaan afartan dumar ah oo gabbaad ka dhiganayaa; taasna waxa keenaya yaraanta ragga iyo badnaanta haweenka.\\"Werin kale ayaa ah, \\"Dumarka ayaa badanaya ragguna way yaraanayaan, illaa uu ku soo hagaago kontonka haweenka ah, nin qummiye keliyi.\\"Cabdillaahi ibnu Mascuud (rc) wuxu yidhi, Rasuulka Ilaahay (scw) ayaa yidhi, \\"Saacaddu ma dhacayso illaa masaajidda laga dhigto waddooyin; iyo illaa uu ninku u salaamo ninka kale wejigarasho; iyo illaa ay wada ganacsadaan ninka iyo ooridiisu; iyo illaa ay qaaliyoobaan fardaha iyo haweenku, kadibna ay jabaan labadooduba; iyaga oo aan dib u qaaliyoobayn illaa qiyaamuhu ka dhacayo.\\"Sababta ugu weyn ee ay raggu u yaraanayaan waa badnaanta fidnooyinka iyo dagaallada, kuwaas oo ay raggu ku dhammaanayaan, dumarkana ku hadhayaan. Wuxu yidhi imaam al Nawawi, \\"Sababta ay raggu u yaraanayaan, ee ay dumarkuna u badanayaan waa dagaallada iyo dilka dhacaya aakhiru-sabaanka iyo badnaanta dagaallada hilbawadhooyinka (al-Malaaxim).3. Hadalka Dugaagga iyo Manoolayaasha.Abi Saciid al Khudari (rc) waxa laga weriyay inuu yidhi, Rasuulka Ilaahay (scw) wuxu yidhi, \\"Eebbaha naftaydu gacantiisa ku jirto ayaan ku dhaartaye, saacaddu ma dhacayso illaa ay dugaaggu la hadlaan dadka; iyo illaa uu ninka la hadlo cidhifka jeedalkiisa iyo taxa kabahiisu; iyo illaa ay bawdadiisu uga warranto wixii ay qoyskiisu sameeyeen isaga gadaashii.\\"Xadiiskani wuxuu tilmaamayaa isbeddel halbawle ah oo ku dhacaya xeerarka walxaha, waxaana buraya naamuuskii la qabatimay. Xadiisku wuxuu toos u tilmaamayaa mayeedhaanka iyo manoolayaasha sida dugaagga iyo agabka, tanina waa arrin aan loo baran, oo naamuuska lid ku ah. Balse inuu yahay arrin ugub ahi kama dhigayso wax masuurtawdo ah; waayo xilligii nebigaba waxa soo aroortay axaadiis badan oo tilmaamaya dhacdooyin kuwan la mid ahi inay dhaceen.Abu Hurayra (rc) waxa laga weriyay inuu yidhi, Nebiga (scw) ayaa yidhi, \\"Xilli uu nin adhijire ahi xoolihiisa la joogo ayaa waxa soo weeraray yey, neef ayaanu ka qaatay. Markii uu eryaday adhijirihii waxa soo eegay yeygii, waxaanu ku yidhi: Yaa iga celin doona maalinta dugaagga, maalinta aanay lahayn adhigu waardiye aan aniga ahayn. Sida oo kale, xilli kale oo uu nin hoggaaminaya sac uu raray, ayay soo eegtay, waanay la hadashay. Waxay tidhi: rarkan layma abuurin aniga, ee waxa lay abuuray beer falista. Dadkii ayaa yidhi: Subxaan Allaah! Nebiga ayaa yidhi, \\"Anigu waan rumaystay arrinkaas, Abu Bakar iyo Cumar binu Khaddaabna way rumeeyeen.\\"Akhriste haddii ay maanta awoodda aadamuhu gaadhay inay sameeyaan taleefanno qaaradaha xidhiidhinaya; tignoolajiyadda garaadka macmalka ah (AI) iyo waxyaabo dhakafaar loo arkay markii ay soo baxeen, miyaad la yaabaysaa Ilaahii abuuray haddii uu dhagaxa ka hadliyo. Saw Quraankaba kuma taallo inuu nebi Saleebaan qudhaanjada, dabaysha, jinka  iyo shinbirahaba af yaqaannay. 4. Banbixidda Shayaadiin Quraan Akhriyaysa.Cabdillaahi ibnu Camar (rc) wuxu yidhi, \\"Badda waxa ku jira shayaadiin xidhan, oo uu tigtigay nebi Saleebaan; waxa dhow inay soo baxaan, oo ay dadka u akhriyaan Quraan.\\"Imaam al-Nawawi wuxu yidhi, \\"Waxay akhriyaysaa wax aan Quraan ahayn, waxaanay odhanayaan waa Quraan, si ay ugu dagaan caamada; kumana dagmayaan.\\"¹Wuxu yidhi Ibnu Mascuud (rc), \\"Shaydaanku wuxuu isku soo eekaysiinayaa qaab nin, kadibna ragga ayuu u imanayaa, kadibna wuxuu uga sheekaynayaa xadiis been ah, waanay ka kala firdhanayaan. Kadib midkood ayaa odhanaya: waxaan maqlay nin aan wejigiisa garanayo, balse aanan magaciisa garanayn oo xadiis ka sheekaynaya.\\"¹La soco...______1. Waxa soosaaray Abu Daa'uud iyo Ibnu Xabbaan (وقال محقق صحيح ابن حبان: حديث صحيح)2. Waxa soosaaray Bukhaari, lanbarka 1414 iyo Muslin, lanbarka 1012.3. Waxa soosaaray Bukhaari, lanbarka 812.4. Waxa soosaaray Xaakim, Axmed iyo Dabaraani. (وقال الحاكم: هذا حديث صحيح الإسناد)5. Dr. Maxamed al-Mubayad, Al Mawsuuca fi al-Fitan wal al-Malaaxim wa Ashraad al-Saaca, bogga 334.6. Waxa soosaaray Tirmidi, lanbarka 2272. (وقال: هذا حديث حسن صحيح)7. Tixraaca 5aad, bogga 337.8. Waxa soosaaray Bukhaari, lanbarka 3663.9. Waxa soosaaray Muslin (في المقدمة)10. Tixraaca 5aad, bogga 339.11. Waxa soosaaray Muslin (في المقدمة)"},{"question":"Hãy đặt một tiêu đề phù hợp với đoạn văn sau: Sự nguy hiểm của mạng xã hội Chuyến đi Team Building (trò chơi tập thể) của công ty TNHH thương mại N.N ở biển Cửa Lò đã có sức lan tỏa ngoài dự tính. Ngay cả khi đại diện công ty nói lời xin lỗi, người quản trò bị phạt 400 ngàn đồng – những tranh cãi vẫn bất phân thắng bại trên khắp các diễn đàn mạng xã hội. Cho đến đêm 31.7, đề tài về chuyến Team Building và người chơi để \\"ngực trần\\" ở Cửa Lò vẫn là đề tài nóng nhất mạng xã hội, thu hút những bình luận \\"nảy lửa\\". Tốc độ chia sẻ video vẫn chóng mặt kèm theo những lời bình luận về ngoại hình của những người phụ nữ tham gia cuộc chơi. Những hình ảnh mang tính biểu tượng được mang ra so sánh, có thể kể đến như: \\"mướp\\", \\"bụng bia\\", \\"đuông dừa\\"... Một làn sóng thể hiện sự giận dữ, mỉa mai, miệt thị ngoại hình bùng nổ khắp các diễn đàn. Một hình ảnh khác được chia sẻ rộng rãi là người phụ nữ với gương mặt bầm tím, đôi môi sưng, kèm theo những lời bình (không kiểm chứng) cho rằng, \\"Đi Cửa Lò về bị chồng đánh cho đáng đời\\". Sự độc hại, mặt trái của mạng xã hội từng được đề cập đến nhiều lần, nhưng phải đến khi xảy ra sự vụ, mới thấy hết sự \\"khủng khiếp\\" (chữ dùng của Tiến sĩ về văn hóa Đặng Thiếu Ngân). Rất đông bình luận \\"ấm ức\\" vì án phạt dành cho người quản trò còn nhẹ, chưa đủ tính răn đe. Không ai bình luận về việc quay video, phát tán video có đáng bị xử phạt hay không? Cũng không ai nhận thấy việc miệt thị, xúc phạm ngoại hình người khác có giúp hình ảnh mình tốt hơn không? Không ai nhớ đến Nghị định 15/2020 có hiệu lực từ 15.4.2020 về việc – người có lời lẽ thiếu văn minh, bình phẩm, chê bai, miệt thị ngoại hình, chê người khác \\"béo, lùn, xấu, ế\\" trên không gian mạng có thể sẽ bị phạt đến 30 triệu đồng. Theo một công bố của Microsoft  qua khảo sát 500 người từ 13 đến 74 tuổi cho thấy: Tại Việt Nam tỉ lệ các tin nhắn, bình phẩm tiêu cực về ngoại hình người khác trong môi trường Internet chiếm tới 35%. Đối tượng bị bình phẩm chủ yếu là phụ nữ. Thực tế đã chứng minh nhiều trường hợp mắc chứng trầm cảm, stress thậm chí tìm cách tự tử vì không chịu nổi những lời bình luận ác ý trên không gian mạng. Một nghiên cứu được công bố năm 2020 trên chuyên san American Journal of Preventive Medicine từng chứng minh, khi bạn dành thời gian quá nhiều trên Facebook, Instagram, TikTok hoặc các mạng xã hội khác có thể gây ra các triệu chứng trầm cảm. Khi đọc những lời chê bai ác ý trên mạng xã hội, bạn sẽ thấy mọi chuyện với bản thân thật tồi tệ. Người ta có thể dẫn đến tình trạng căm ghét bản thân khi đọc những lời chê bai, xúc phạm, miệt thị. Câu chuyện chuyến đi Team Building ở Cửa Lò còn cho thấy việc bất cứ ai, trong đó có chúng ta, có thể dễ dàng bị chụp trộm, bị quay lén hình ảnh cá nhân như thế nào. Giữ hình ảnh nơi công cộng trở thành một kỹ năng sống Việc tham gia một trò chơi phản cảm nơi công cộng đã khiến những phụ nữ trong video phải đối diện với \\"cái giá phải trả\\" mà chính họ đã không thể lường trước được. Thời đại mạng xã hội phát triển như vũ bão, nơi mà mỗi nền tảng đều có hàng tỉ người dùng, và mỗi người dùng đều là một kênh tin tức, đều có quyền đăng tải, chia sẻ, bình luận thông tin... sẽ rất dễ dẫn đến sự hỗn loạn, khủng hoảng, mất kiểm soát. Cũng trong bối cảnh mạng xã hội phát triển, những câu chuyện cá nhân có yếu tố giật gân, câu khách sẽ trở thành \\"miếng mồi ngon\\" của hàng tỉ người dùng trên các nền tảng mạng xã hội, trong các hội nhóm, diễn đàn mạng xã hội. Chỉ cần một điện thoại thông minh, hàng tỉ người tham gia mạng xã hội có thể chụp ảnh, quay video bất kỳ ai, bất kỳ câu chuyện hấp dẫn, giật gân nào và \\"post\\" lên mạng trong tích tắc. Bởi vậy, nếu không muốn trở thành tâm điểm dư luận, không muốn đứng trong cơn bão chỉ trích của các hội nhóm, bạn hãy chuẩn bị cho mình một kỹ năng sống: giữ hình ảnh nơi công cộng. Đừng quên, thời đại của mạng xã hội, camera đang được lắp đặt khắp chốn, điện thoại thông minh có khả năng quay chụp xuất hiện muôn nơi, nhất cử nhất động của bạn đều có thể bị ghi hình lại.","answer":"\\"Tác động độc hại của mạng xã hội và sự cần thiết của việc bảo vệ hình ảnh cá nhân\\""},{"question":"Ọga Kọsitọọmu bẹ awọn ọdọ to ji ibọn wọn gbe ni Ṣaki lati da a pada","answer":"Ọga awọn aṣọbode to wa niluu Ṣaki, nipinlẹ Ọyọ, CSC Shehu Minna, ti parọwa sawọn ọdọ ilu Ṣaki tinu n bi lakooko akọlu to waye lọjọ kẹrinla, oṣu kẹjọ, ọdun yii, pe ki wọn jọwọ, ba awọn da ibọn ijọba to wa lọwọ wọn pada.O parọwa yii lakooko tawọn ẹgbẹ akọroyin ipinlẹ Ọyọ, eyi ti alaga wọn, Kọmureedi Demọla Babalọla, ko sodi lati lọọ ba ileeṣẹ kọsitọọmu naa kẹdun lori iṣẹlẹ naa.Tẹ o ba gbagbe, ọsan ọjọ kẹtala, oṣu kẹjọ, to kọja yii, niṣẹlẹ buruku naa waye, nigba ti ọkan lara awọn ọdọ ilu naa padanu ẹmi rẹ nibi ti aawọ kan ti waye laarin awọn aṣọbode atawọn onifayawọ. Iṣẹlẹ yii lo mu ki awọn ọdọ ilu naa fariga, ti wọn lọọ fibinu gbẹsan ohun to ṣẹlẹ naa, ti wọn pa aṣọbode ti wọn ba lọọfiisi wọn, wọn dana sun ọfiisi naa, wọn si tun gbe ibọn ti wọn fi n ṣiṣẹ lọ titi doni.Alaga ẹgbẹ awọn akọroyin naa ṣapejuwe iṣẹlẹ ọhun gẹgẹ bii eyi to buru jai, o ni ohun ti ko yẹ ko waye rara ni, lẹyin eyi lo parọwa si ọga aṣọbode naa pe ko ṣeto lati jẹ ki asọye maa wa laarin awọn oṣiṣẹ rẹ ataraalu, eyi to ṣee ṣe ko dena iru iṣẹlẹ bẹẹ lọjọ iwaju.CSC Shehu Minna waa gboriyin fun ẹgbẹ awọn akọroyin orileede yii, paapaa ẹka ti ipinle Ọyọ. O ni wọn ni iṣẹ ribiribi lati ṣe lati jẹ ki awọn araalu mọ ojuṣe wọn nipa lila wọn lọyẹ lori ofin tijọba fi de kiko ẹru ti ko bofin mu wọle si orileede yii, yala lori ilẹ, ori omi, ati oju ofurufu.O ni iṣẹ awọn aṣọbode faaye silẹ fun ifikunlukun lati jiroro lori bi ijọba yoo ṣe pa owo wọle lati ara sisan owo-ori ọja gbogbo.Ọkunrin yii ni idi toun fi pariwo sita lori ibọn to wa nikaawọ awọn ọdọ wọnyi ni pe awọn oloṣelu le lo awọn ọdọ wọnyi ati ibọn naa fun ete imọtara-ẹni-nikan, tabi ki wọn lọọ fi ibọn naa jale nibikan, eyi si maa ṣakoba fun ileeṣẹ kọsitọọmu ati orukọ rere rẹ. O waa rọ awọn oniroyin lari parọwa sawọn ọdọ ọhun lati da ibọn to wa lọwọ wọn pada, tori ole to gbe kakaaki ọba lọrọ naa jẹ fun wọn, ko si ibi ti yoo ti fọn ọn."},{"question":"ආමාශයික ප්‍රධාන සෛල මොනවාද?","answer":"ආමාශයික ප්‍රධාන සෛල (හෙවත් පෙප්ටික් සෛල, හෙවත් ආමාශයික සයිමෝජනික සෛල) යනුවෙන් හැඳින්වෙන්නේ පෙප්සිනෝජන් සහ ආමාශයික ලයිපේස් මුදාහරින ආමාශයේ පිහිටි සෛල විශේෂයකි. මෙය රෝමාන්ථයන්ගේ කයිමොසින් ස්‍රාවය සිදුකරන සෛල වර්ගය ද වේ. මෙම සෛලවල සෛල ප්ලාස්මයේ විශාල වශයෙන් පැතිරී ඇති රළු අන්තඃප්ලාස්මීය ජාලිකා නිසා H&E වර්ණකය සමබ භස්මකාමී අයුරින් වර්ණගැන්වේ. ආමාශයික ප්‍රධාන සෛල සාමාන්‍යයෙන් පිහිටියේ ආමාශ ආස්තරණයේ ශ්ලේෂ්මලක ස්තරයේ ගැඹුරිනි."},{"question":"ධ්වනි ගුණය යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"එකම තාරතාවය සහ එකම විපුලතාවය(හඬේ සැර), එනම් එකම සංඛ්‍යාතය හා එකම විස්ථාරය ඇති ධ්වනි ස්වර 2ක් උපකරණ 2කින් නිකුත් කල විට ඒවායේ වෙනස හඳුනාගත හැකි වීමට හේතුව ස්වර 2හි ධ්වනි ගුණය වෙනස් වීමයි. ධ්වනි ගුණය රඳා පවතින්නේ තරංග ආකෘතියේ  හැඩය මතයි. වෙනස් උපකරණ වලින් නිකුත් කරන ධ්වනි ස්වර වල තරංග ආකෘතියේ හැඩය වෙනස් වේ."},{"question":"   வினா  2019 ம் ஆண்டில் உலகக் கோப்பை கிரிக்கெட் நடைபெற்ற  நாடு எது ?","answer":" விடை 2019 ஐசிசி கிரிக்கெட் உலகக் கோப்பை 12 வது கிரிக்கெட் உலகக் கோப்பை ஆகும், இது நான்கு ஆண்டுகளுக்கு ஒரு நாள் சர்வதேச கிரிக்கெட் போட்டியாகும், இது ஆண்கள் தேசிய அணிகளால் போட்டியிட்டு சர்வதேச கிரிக்கெட்  மன்றம்  (ஐசிசி) ஏற்பாடு செய்தது. மே 30 முதல் ஜூலை 14 வரை இங்கிலாந்தில் 10 மைதானங்களிலும் வேல்சி ஒரு மைதானத்திலும் போட்டிகள் நடத்தப்பட்டன. இங்கிலாந்து உலகக் கோப்பையை நடத்துவது இது ஐந்தாவது முறையாகும், அதே நேரத்தில் வேல்சுக்கு இது மூன்றாவது முறையாகும்."},{"question":"विशाखादत्तने चंद्रगुप्त मौर्य व चाणक्याविषयी कोणते नाटक लिहिले आहे ?","answer":"मुद्राराक्षस"},{"question":"வினா :வான்சிறப்பில்  உள்ள திருக்குறள்களையும்  அதன் பொருளையும் விளக்கவும் ?","answer":" விடை:அதிகாரம் : வான்சிறப்புகுறள் : 11வான்நின்று உலகம் வழங்கி வருதலால்தான்அமிழ்தம் என்றுணரற் பாற்று.பொருள் : மழை பெய்ய உலகம் வாழ்ந்து வருவதால், மழையானது உலகத்து வாழும் உயிர்களுக்கு அமிழ்தம் என்று உணரத்தக்கதாகும்.அதிகாரம் : வான்சிறப்புகுறள் : 12துப்பார்க்குத் துப்பாய துப்பாக்கித் துப்பார்க்குத்துப்பாய தூஉம் மழை.பொருள் : உண்பவர்க்குத் தக்க உணவுப் பொருள்களை விளைவித்துத் தருவதோடு, பருகுவோர்க்குத் தானும் ஓர் உணவாக இருப்பது மழையாகும்.அதிகாரம் : வான்சிறப்புகுறள் : 13விண்இன்று பொய்ப்பின் விரிநீர் வியனுலகத்துஉள்நின்று உடற்றும் பசி.பொருள் : மழை பெய்யாமல் பொய்படுமானால், கடல் சூழ்ந்த அகன்ற உலகமாக இருந்தும் பசி உள்ளே நிலைத்து நின்று உயிர்களை வருத்தும்.அதிகாரம் : வான்சிறப்புகுறள் : 14ஏரின் உழாஅர் உழவர் புயல்என்னும்வாரி வளங்குன்றிக் கால்.பொருள் : மழை என்னும் வருவாய் வளம் குன்றி விட்டால், ( உணவுப் பொருள்களை உண்டாக்கும்) உழவரும் ஏர் கொண்டு உழமாட்டார்.அதிகாரம் : வான்சிறப்புகுறள் : 15கெடுப்பதூஉம் கெட்டார்க்குச் சார்வாய்மற் றாங்கேஎடுப்பதூஉம் எல்லாம் மழை.பொருள் : பெய்யாமல் வாழ்வைக் கெடுக்க வல்லதும் மழை; மழையில்லாமல் வளம் கெட்டு நொந்தவர்க்கும் துணையாய் அவ்வாறே காக்க வல்லதும் மழையாகும்.அதிகாரம் : வான்சிறப்புகுறள் : 16விசும்பின் துளிவீழின் அல்லால்மற் றாங்கேபசும்புல் தலைகாண்பு அரிது.பொருள் : வானத்திலிருந்து மழைத்துளி வீழ்ந்தால் அல்லாமல், உலகத்தில் ஓரறிவுயிராகிய பசும்புல்லின் தலையையும் காண முடியாது.அதிகாரம் : வான்சிறப்புகுறள் : 17நெடுங்கடலும் தன்நீர்மை குன்றும் தடிந்தெழிலிதான்நல்கா தாகி விடின்.பொருள் : மேகம் கடலிலிருந்து நீரைக் கொண்டு அதனிடத்திலேயே பெய்யாமல் விடுமானால், பெரிய கடலும் தன் வளம் குன்றிப் போகும்.அதிகாரம் : வான்சிறப்புகுறள் : 18சிறப்பொடு பூசனை செல்லாது வானம்வறக்குமேல் வானோர்க்கும் ஈண்டு.பொருள் : மழை பெய்யாமல் போகுமானால் இவ்வுலகத்தில் வானோர்க்காக நடைபெறும் திருவிழாவும் நடைபெறாது; நாள் வழிபாடும் நடைபெறாது.அதிகாரம் : வான்சிறப்புகுறள் : 19தானம் தவம்இரண்டும் தங்கா வியன்உலகம்வானம் வழங்கா தெனின்.பொருள் : மழை பெய்யவில்லையானால், இந்த பெரிய உலகத்தில் பிறர் பொருட்டு செய்யும் தானமும், தம் பொருட்டு செய்யும் தவமும் இல்லையாகும்.அதிகாரம் : வான்சிறப்புகுறள் : 20நீர்இன்று அமையாது உலகெனின் யார்யார்க்கும்வான்இன்று அமையாது ஒழுக்கு.பொருள் : எப்படிப்பட்டவர்க்கும் நீர் இல்லாமல் உலக வாழ்க்கை நடைபெறாது என்றால், மழை இல்லையானால் ஒழுக்கமும் நிலைபெறாமல் போகும்."},{"question":"කමත් බසෙන් බොල කැපීම  යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"බොල් ඉවත් කිරීම"},{"question":"Viết bài báo có tiêu đề sau: Ukraine nguy cơ trả giá vì chọc giận Ba Lan","answer":"Tranh cãi với Ba Lan về ngũ cốc khiến Ukraine đối mặt nguy cơ mất đi một đồng minh thân cận ở thời điểm họ cần mọi hỗ trợ có thể.Thủ tướng Ba Lan Mateusz Morawiecki ngày 20/9 tuyên bố ngừng cung cấp vũ khí cho Ukraine để tập trung xây dựng nền quốc phòng trong nước. Ông đưa ra phát biểu khi được hỏi liệu Warsaw có duy trì ủng hộ Kiev giữa lúc hai nước căng thẳng vì vấn đề xuất khẩu nông sản hay không.Bộ Ngoại giao Ba Lan trước đó triệu đại sứ Ukraine Vasyl Zvarych để phản đối phát biểu của Tổng thống Volodymyr Zelensky rằng việc các \\"yếu tố chính trị\\" liên quan đến hoạt động xuất khẩu nông sản của Kiev chỉ mang lại lợi ích cho Nga.Ba Lan cuối tuần qua cho biết sẽ không tuân thủ quyết định của Liên minh châu Âu (EU) về việc dỡ bỏ lệnh cấm đối với nhập khẩu nông sản Ukraine. Warsaw cho rằng lệnh cấm là cần thiết để bảo vệ nông dân Ba Lan, những người phàn nàn rằng ngũ cốc giá rẻ từ Ukraine đã làm suy yếu thị trường của họ.Không lâu sau đó, cả Hungary và Slovakia cũng tiếp bước Ba Lan.Đại diện Thương mại Ukraine Taras Kachka hôm 18/9 cho rằng các biện pháp của Ba Lan sẽ ảnh hưởng đáng kể đến hàng xuất khẩu của nước này. Ông đồng thời cảnh báo Ukraine có thể thể áp đặt biện pháp tương ứng, như cấm nhập khẩu trái cây, rau quả từ Ba Lan nếu Warsaw không dỡ bỏ lệnh cấm bổ sung.Ukraine cùng ngày khiếu nại lên Tổ chức Thương mại Thế giới (WTO) vì hành động của Ba Lan, Hungary và Slovakia.Theo giới quan sát, những bình luận gay gắt của Ukraine nhằm vào Ba Lan cũng như tranh cãi về lệnh cấm nông sản đang khiến mối quan hệ giữa hai quốc gia láng giềng rơi xuống mức thấp nhất từ trước đến nay. Mặt khác, Kiev cũng có nguy cơ bị phản đòn vì cách phản ứng của mình."},{"question":"هل الخليل هي عاصمة فلسطين؟","answer":"لا، الخليل ليست عاصمة فلسطين. عاصمة فلسطين هي القدس. و الخليل مدينة فلسطينية، ومركز محافظة الخليل. تقع في الضفة الغربية إلى الجنوب من القدس بحوالي 35 كم. أسسها الكنعانيون في العصر البرونزي المبكر، وتُعد اليوم أكبر مدن الضفة الغربية من حيث عدد السكان والمساحة، حيث بلغ عدد سكانها في عام 2016 بقرابة 215 ألف نسمة، وتبلغ مساحتها 42 كم2. تمتاز المدينة بأهمية اقتصادية، حيث تُعد من أكبر المراكز الاقتصادية في الضفة الغربية. وللخليل أهمية دينية للديانات الإبراهيمية الثلاث، حيث يتوسط المدينة المسجد الإبراهيمي الذي يحوي مقامات للأنبياء إبراهيم، وإسحق، ويعقوب، وزوجاتهم."},{"question":"පරිගණකයේ පියා ලෙස හඳුන්වන්නේ කවුද?","answer":"පරිගණකයේ පියා ලෙස හඳුන්වන්නේ චාල්ස් බැබේජ් (Charles Babbage) මහතා ය."},{"question":"మీ ఆహారంలో విటమిన్ ‘A’ లోపించినట్లైతే వచ్చే’ వ్యాధిలో లక్షణాలు ఉండవచ్చు?A) తక్కువ కాంతిలో చూడలేకపోవుటB) ఆకలి లేకపోవడంC) వెలుతురు చూడలేకపోవడంD) నీటి విరేచనాలు","answer":"A) తక్కువ కాంతిలో చూడలేకపోవుట"},{"question":"GAYAANKA GUURSO!","answer":"GAYAANKA GUURSO!Arimaha loo baahan yahay in ahmiyad la siiyo kolka la dooranayo lammaanaha nolosha waxa ugu horreeya diinta iyo dabeecadda sidaynu horeba usoo sheegnay, waxase aan la inkiri karin inay jiraan umuuro kale oo iyaga laftoodu ahmiyaddooda leh, waxaana kamid ahfarqiga u dhexeeya da'da ninka iyo da'da inanta uu guurkeeda doonayo Abuubakar (RC) iyo Cumar (RC) ayaa mid waliba goonidiisa usoo doontay, Faadumo binti Rasuul (Sallallaahu calayhi wasallam), markaas buu Rasuulku (Sallallaahu calayhi wasallam) goonidiisa ugu sheegay inay gabadhu mid walibayartahay. Ha yeeshee kolkuu Cali (RC) soo doontay, waa uu siiyay, waxanay culimada qaar taa ku micneeyeen in Rasuulku (Sallallaahu calayhi wasallam) doonavey inuu gabadhiisa u guurivo nin ay isku da' dhowyihiin, waxana markaasi Faadumo (RC) ay jirtay shan iyo toban sano iyo shan bilood, halka uu Cali (RC) ka jiray koow iyo labaatan sano iyo afar bilood.Waxaa laga yaabaa inuu maskaxdaada ku soo dhoco guurkii Rasuulkeenna (Sallallaahu calayhi wasallam) iyo Sayidah Caa' ishah (RC) 0o iyadu aad uga da' yarayd Rasuulka (Sallallaahu calayhi wasallam), ha yeeshee qoraaga kitaabka (Tuxfatul-Caruus) Maxamuud Al-Istambuuli waxa uu ku doodayaa in umuurtaasi aanay ahayn mid lagu dayan karo sababahaan soo socda awgood:--Dadnimada Rasuulka (Sallallaahu calayhi wasallam) oo dadnimo qof lala simaahi jirin, taasi oo keentay inay Caa'ishah farxad kula noolayd, isaganaka door bidday nin kasta oo dhallinyaro ahaa o0 soo doontay.-Ulajeeddada siyaasadeed ee ka dambeysay arooskaasi oo loola jeeday in dhidibbada loo aaso xiriir dhexmara Rasuulka (Sallallaahu calayhi wasallam) iyo Abuu-Bakar Al-Siddiq (RC) saaxiibtinnimada soojireenka ah ee ka O0 dhexeeysay asaga iyo Rasuulka (Sallallaahu calayhi wasallam) ka sokow,  kamid ahaa hogaamiyeyaasha Carabta, loona fududeeyo maslaxadda kadhaxaysay labadooda, maadaama uu Abuu-Bakar mar waliba tegi jiray guriga Rasuulka (Sallallaahu calayhi wasallam) si dardarsiimo lo geliyo Dacwada Islaamka.-Caa'ishah o0 ahayd qof aad u diin badan, marnabana aan cabsi looga qabin inay gef ka geysato guurkaasi.-Rasuulka (Sallallaahu calayhi wasallam) oo la siiyay awood ragannimo u dhiganta afartan ragga Saxaabadiisa ah awooddood sida ku soo aroortay Xadiiska Saxiixa ah)Dhammaad faalladii Istambuuli."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਮਃ ੩ ॥ਹੋਰੁ ਬਿਰਹਾ ਸਭ ਧਾਤੁ ਹੈ ਜਬ ਲਗੁ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਪ੍ਰੀਤਿ ਨ ਹੋਇ ॥ਇਹੁ ਮਨੁ ਮਾਇਆ ਮੋਹਿਆ ਵੇਖਣੁ ਸੁਨਣੁ ਨ ਹੋਇ ॥ਸਹ ਦੇਖੇ ਬਿਨੁ ਪ੍ਰੀਤਿ ਨ ਊਪਜੈ ਅੰਧਾ ਕਿਆ ਕਰੇਇ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਜਿਨਿ ਅਖੀ ਲੀਤੀਆ ਸੋਈ ਸਚਾ ਦੇਇ ॥੨॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 83 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਮਰਦਾਸ ਜੀ ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਵਾਰਾਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਸਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਜਦ ਤਾਈਂ ਮਾਲਕ ਨਾਲ ਪ੍ਰੀਤਿ (ਉਤਪੰਨ) ਨਹੀਂ ਹੁੰਦੀ, ਹੋਰ ਪਿਆਰ ਸਭ ਮਾਇਆ (ਦਾ ਪਿਆਰ) ਹੈਤੇ ਮਾਇਆ ਵਿਚ ਮੋਹਿਆ ਇਹ ਮਨ (ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨੂੰ) ਵੇਖ ਤੇ ਸੁਣ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਕਦਾ ਅੰਨ੍ਹਾ (ਮਨ) ਕਰੇ ਭੀ ਕੀਹ ? (ਪ੍ਰਭੂ) ਪਤੀ ਨੂੰ ਵੇਖਣ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਪ੍ਰੀਤਿ ਪੈਦਾ ਹੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੋ ਸਕਦੀ ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ ! (ਮਾਇਆ ਵਿਚ ਫਸਾ ਕੇ) ਜਿਸ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨੇ ਅੰਨ੍ਹਾ ਕੀਤਾ ਹੈ, ਉਹੀ ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਮੁੜ ਅੱਖਾਂ ਦੇਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੨।\\""},{"question":"रामाय रामभद्राय रामचन्द्राय वेधसे।रघुनाथाय नाथाय सीतायाः पतये नमः॥","answer":"अर्थ : भूतलावर अवतरित होऊन भक्तजनांचे मनोरथ पूर्ण करणार्‍या, रामचंद्र, प्रजापती, रघुनाथ, नाथ, सीतापती रामश्रेष्ठाला मी वंदन करतो."},{"question":"Реабилитация деген эмне ?","answer":"Реабилитация-укугунан айрылган адамды укугуна кайра ээ кылуу"},{"question":"ചോദ്യം: എപ്പോഴാണ് ബ്രോങ്കോസ് അവസാനമായി ഒരു സൂപ്പർ ബൌൾ നേടിയത് ഉത്തരം:","answer":"2016ൽ സൂപ്പർ ബൗൾ 50"},{"question":"சோழர் காலச் சிற்பத்திறனுக்குச் சான்றுகளாக விளங்குபவை?","answer":"தஞ்சைப் பெரிய கோவிலில் காணப்படுகின்ற பதினான்கு அடி உயரமுள்ள வாயிற்காவலர் உருவங்களும் மிகப்பெரிய நந்தியும் வியப்பூட்டும் வேலைப்பாடுகள் கொண்ட தூண்களும் சோழர்காலச் சிற்பத்திறனுக்குச் சான்றுகளாக விளங்குகின்றன."},{"question":"Inona no trangan-javatra voajanahary mahatonga ny onjan-dranomasina?","answer":"Ny fisehoan-javatra voajanahary tompon'andraikitra amin'ny fisondrotan'ny ranomasimbe dia ny fisarihana misintona eo amin'ny Tany, ny Volana ary ny Masoandro."},{"question":"नेपालका पादरी समुदायहरूमा \\"गोथालो\\" (परम्परागत गोठालाहरू) को भूमिकाबारे चर्चा गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"गोथालो गोठालाहरू हुन् जसले पशुपालन समुदायमा महत्त्वपूर्ण भूमिका खेल्छन्, पशुधनको हेरचाह गर्छन् र मौसमी बसाइसराइलाई सहज बनाउँछन्।"},{"question":"வினா : நுண் உயரியியலின் தந்தை?","answer":"விடை : ஆண்டன் வான் லூவன் ஹாக்"},{"question":"Inona ny atao hoe lahatsoratra manoritsoritra?","answer":"Lahatsoratra mandoko zavatra iray ka manasongadina ny toetrany, ny endriny, ny fihetsiny, ny bikany, ary ny zavatra hita eo aminy ny lahatsoratra manoritsoritra."},{"question":"Wo àyọkà tó wà nísàlẹ̀ yìí, kó o sì dáhùn ìbéèrè tó wà lẹ́yìn náà ní èdè kan náà tí àyọkà náà wà:  Passage: Domain classes <unk> all levels of the IP Addressing information required to deliver web pages and content. Ìsọfúnni tí ó pọn dandan láti gbé àwọn ojúewé àti ìsọfúnni tí ó pọn dandan láti gbé àwọn ojúewé àti ìsọfúnni tí ó pọn dandan.  Ìbéèrè: Kí ló ń ṣe àwùjọ ìkápá?","answer":"gbogbo ìpele tí IP Addressing àlàyé tí à béèrè láti fi Ojú-ìwé ayélujára àti àkóónú ránṣẹ́."},{"question":"ஞானசம்பந்தம் என்ற மாதஇதழ் நடத்தும் மடம் எது?","answer":"ஞானசம்பந்தம் என்ற மாதஇதழ் நடத்தும் மடம் தருமபுர ஆதினம்."},{"question":"Салам алейкум.","answer":"Алейкум салам."},{"question":"What was the main aim of the French revolutionaries?","answer":"The main aim of the French revolutionaries was to create a sense of collective identity amongst the French people. They proclaimed that it was the people who would constitute the nation and shape its decisions."},{"question":"السؤال: عرف الدولة ؟","answer":"الإجابة: الدولة هي مجموعة من الناس يعيشون على مساحة من الأرض يخضعون لسلطة سياسية."},{"question":"Inona no anjara asan'ny harena voajanahary matetika amin'ny ady an-trano?","answer":"Ny harena voajanahary, toy ny solika na mineraly sarobidy, dia mety ho olana manan-danja ary manampy amin'ny fanamafisana ny fifandirana."},{"question":"以下の段落に関連する内容を記入しなさい： 7月はとても暑い日が続きました。気象庁によると、7月の平均の気温はいつもの年より1.91℃高くて、1898年に調べ始めてからいちばん暑くなりました。 気象庁はこれから1週間ぐらい暑い日が続きそうだと言っています。熱中症にならないように気をつけてください。","answer":"神奈川県鎌倉市の寺、高徳院には高さ13m以上の大仏があります。大仏の中に入ることができて、人気があります。 しかし、大仏は銅でできているため、中は外より暑くなります。このため寺は、8月1日から31日まで、大仏の中に入ることを中止にしました。 寺によると、今年は大勢の外国人が観光に来ています。アメリカから来た人は「中に入ることができませんでしたが、大仏はとても美しかったです。必ずまた来ます」と話していました。"},{"question":"Σε ποιο σημαντικό γεγονός αναφέρεται το κείμενο: Οι Μακί, ομάδες μαχητών της Γαλλικής αντίστασης ήταν ιδιαίτερα ενεργοί στην περιοχή. Στις 15 Αυγούστου 1944 έγινε η Απόβαση στην Προβηγκία, αποβιβάστηκαν αμερικανικές και ελεύθερες γαλλικές δυνάμεις στο Σαιν-Τροπέ, το Σαιντ-Μαξίμ και το Σαιν-Ραφαέλ. Ο ελεύθερος γαλλικός στόλος έφτασε στην Τουλόν στις 13 Σεπτεμβρίου.","answer":"Απόβαση στην Προβηγκία"},{"question":"Bu yazı hangi önemli olayla ilgilidir?: 24 Haziran 1945'te SSCB başkenti Moskova'da zafer geçidi töreni düzenlenerek Sovyet zaferi anıldı.","answer":"Bu yazı, 24 Haziran 1945 tarihinde SSCB'nin başkenti Moskova'da gerçekleşen zafer geçidi töreni ile ilgilidir."},{"question":"Ολοκλήρωσε το κείμενο: Τη δεκαετία του 1990 ίδρυσε μαζί με άλλους έξι Σέρβους καλαθοσφαιριστές (Τζόρτζεβιτς, Πάσπαλι, Σάβιτς, Ρέμπρατσα, Ντανίλοβιτς και Μποντίρογκα) τη μη κερδοσκοπική οργάνωση «Γκρουπ 7». Κατά την παραμονή του στις ΗΠΑ, ο Ντίβατς ίδρυσε τον φιλανθρωπικό οργανισμό Humanitarian Organization Divac. Αργότερα, τον Ιούνιο του 2007, δημιούργησε μαζί με τη σύζυγό του, τη μη κερδοσκοπική οργάνωση \\"Ana and Vlade Divac Foundation\\" («Ίδρυμα Άνας και Βλάντε Ντίβατς»), με σκοπό την ανακούφιση και τη βελτίωση των συνθηκών ζωής των προσφύγων και των εκτοπισμένων ανθρώπων. Μεταξύ άλλων, το συγκεκριμένο ίδρυμα έχει συνδράμει οικογένειες από την περιοχή του Κοσσυφοπεδίου, καθώς και πρόσφυγες από τη Μέση Ανατολή","answer":". Παράλληλα, τα Χριστούγεννα του 1999 οργάνωσε από κοινού με τον - συμπαίκτη του στους Σακραμέντο Κινγκς και συμπατριώτη του - Πέτζα Στογιάκοβιτς, φιλανθρωπική εκδήλωση για τη συλλογή παιδικών παιχνιδιών, τα οποία στάλθηκαν σε παιδιά της Γιουγκοσλαβίας. Επιπλέον, το 2003 οι δύο καλαθοσφαιριστές οργάνωσαν συλλογή χρημάτων για την ανακαίνιση του σερβικού ορθόδοξου ναού της Κοιμήσεως της Θεοτόκου στο Σακραμέντο."},{"question":"¿Cuándo se abrió la primera estación de tren de Reading?","answer":"La primera estación Reading fue inaugurada el 30 de marzo de 1840 como la terminal occidental temporal de la línea original del Great Western Railway (GWR). Reading es la novena estación más ocupada en el Reino Unido fuera de Londres y la segunda estación de transbordo más concurrida fuera de Londres con más de 3,8 millones de pasajeros cambiando de tren en la estación anualmente."},{"question":"ಇದಕ್ಕೆ ಉತ್ತರ ಕೊಡಿ: ನಮ್ಮ ದೇಹದಲ್ಲಿ ಜೀವಕೋಶ ವಿಭಜನೆ ನಿರಂತರವಾಗಿ ನಡೆಯುತ್ತಿದೆ ಎಂಬುದಕ್ಕೆ ಯಾವುದು ಅತ್ಯುತ್ತಮ ಸಾಕ್ಷಿ? ನಿಮ್ಮ ಉತ್ತರವನ್ನು ಆಯ್ಕೆ ಮಾಡಿ: [i] ದೇಹವು ಗಡಿಯಾರದ ಸುತ್ತ ಉಸಿರಾಡುತ್ತಲೇ ಇರಬೇಕು. [ii] ಸಕ್ರಿಯ ಜನರಿಗೆ ಸಾಮಾನ್ಯವಾಗಿ ನಿಷ್ಕ್ರಿಯರಿಗಿಂತ ಹೆಚ್ಚಿನ ಆಹಾರ ಬೇಕಾಗುತ್ತದೆ. [iii] ಮಾನವ ದೇಹದಲ್ಲಿ ಅನೇಕ ವಿಭಿನ್ನ ರೀತಿಯ ಅಂಗಾಂಶಗಳಿವೆ. [iv] ಮಾನವರು ಲಕ್ಷಾಂತರ ಶ್ವಾಸಕೋಶಗಳನ್ನು ಚೆಲ್ಲುತ್ತಾರೆ.","answer":"[iii] ಮಾನವ ದೇಹದಲ್ಲಿ ಅನೇಕ ವಿಭಿನ್ನ ರೀತಿಯ ಅಂಗಾಂಶಗಳಿವೆ. "},{"question":"أريد إنشاء قصيدة مدح من بحر الكامل. هل يمكنك مساعدتي؟","answer":"إليك هذه القصيدة من البحر الكامل:تَمضي العُلى وَإِلى ذَراكُم تَرجِعُشَمسٌ تَغيبُ لَكُم وَأُخرى تَطلُعُإِنَّ الصَفا العاديَّ يُقرَعُ بِالأَذىمِن غَيرِكُم وَصَفاكُمُ لا يُقرَعُمُتَداوِلينَ لِباسَ أَثوابِ العُلىهَذا يُجابُ لَهُ وَهَذا يُنزَعُفي كُلِّ يَومٍ لِلنَواظِرِ مِنكُمُأَعلامُ عَلياءٍ تُحَطُّ وَتُرفَعُلا مِثلَ مَن مَلَكَ العُلى مُستَقبَلٌفينا وَمَن طَوَتِ المَنونُ مُوَدَّعُعَينانِ عَينٌ لِلمَزيدِ قَريرَةٌمِنّا وَعَينٌ لِلنَقيصَةِ تَدمَعُوَإِذا اِطمَأَنَّ مِنَ العَطِيَّةِ مَضجَعٌيَوماً أَقَضَّ مِنَ الرَزِيَةِ مَضجَعُفَلَئِن فَرِحنا إِنَّ ذَلِكَ مُفرِحٌوَلَئِن جَزِعنا إِنَّ ذَلِكَ مُجزِعُلِلمَجدِ مِن عَلياكُمُ وَمَصابِكُمأَنفٌ بِهِ شَمَمٌ وَآخَرُ أَجدَعُبُؤسى وَنُعمى أَعقَبَت فَكَأَنَّمارُدَّت عَلى أَعقابِهِنَّ الأَدمُعُلَولا الأَعَزُّ أَبو شُجاعٍ لَم يَكُنوَهِيَ النَوائِبِ عَن قَليلٍ يُرقَعُلَولاهُ ما اِنجَبَرَ الكَسيرُ وَلا سَماطَرفُ الحَسيرِ وَلا سَلا المُتَفَجِّعُما كانَتِ العَلياءُ بَعدَ مَصابِهالَولاهُ بِالبَدَلِ المُجَدَّدِ تَقنَعُنَثَلوا كَنائِنَ مَجدِهِم فَتَخَيَّروامِنهُنَّ أَقوَمَ نَصلَةٍ لا تُنزَعُسَهماً رَمى غَرَضَ العُلى مِن بَعدِمالَم يَبقَ في قَوسِ المَعالي مَنزَعُلا يَطمَعُ الأَعداءُ مَطلَعَ نَجدِهِقَد ضاقَ إِلّا عَنهُ ذاكَ المَطلَعُطَلَبَتكَ قَد قَلِقَت إِلَيكَ نُصولُهاحَتّى اِستَقَرَّ بِها النِصابُ الأَمنَعُظَمأى إِلَيكَ وَأَينَ عَنكَ مَحيدُهاوَالرَعيُ عِندَكَ وَالرُوا وَالمَرتَعُما كانَ غارِبُها بِغَيرِكَ يُمتَطىيَوماً وَطينَتُها بِغَيرِكَ تُطبَعُسَبَقَت بِبَيعَتِكَ القُلوبُ أَكُفَّهاأَيدٍ أَطَعنَكَ وَالضَمائِرُ أَطوَعُمِن مُضمَرٍ يَخشى الهَوى لا يَنثَنيأَو صافِقٍ بِيَدِ الرِدى لا يَرجِعُأَعطَت تَخايُلَها الصُدورُ وَرُبَّماتُعطي يَدٌ وَلَها ضَميرٌ يَمنَعُاللَهُ أَيَّدَ مُلكَكُم وَسَما بِهِمَجدُ القَواعِدِ وَالبِناءُ الأَرفَعُبَيتٌ يُسَقَّفُ بِالسَماءِ رِواقُهُوَتَهابُ ذُروَتَهُ الحَمامُ الوُقَّعُأَطنابُ قُبَّتِهِ أَنابيبُ القَناوَسُجوفُ ظِلَّتِهِ المَواضي اللُمَّعُإِن ساخَتِ الأَركانُ أَشرَفَ رُكنُهُأَو ضُعضِعَ البُنيانُ لا يَتَضَعضَعَكَم مُصعَبٍ مَنَعَ الخِطامَ تَرَكتَهُتَحتَ الرَحالَةِ يَستَقيمُ وَيَظلَعُأَو خالِعٍ قَصُرَت يَداهُ عَنِ العُلىبوعٌ لَكُم تَقِصُ الرِقابَ وَأَذرُعُفَسَبَقتُمُ وَكَبا بِهِ مِن جَدِّهِدونَ المُنى قَصفُ الفَقارِ مُوَقَّعُتَخفى مَكائِدُه وَيَظهَرُ سَطوُكُمالذَرُّ يَقرُصُ وَالأَراقِمُ تَلسَعُلا ثُلَّ عَرشُ بَنَي بُوَيهٍ أَنَّهُمغُدُرُ المَكارِمِ وَالجَنابُ الأَمرَعُفَعَلى رُوائِهِمُ يَحومُ المُعتَفيوَإِلى رُوائِهِمُ تُشيرُ الإِصبَعُإِن قارَبوا فَهُمُ الشِهادُ المُجتَنىوَإِذا أَبوا فَهُمُ السِمامُ المُنقَعُأَيديهِمُ طُرُقُ النَدى وَجِباهُهُمأَبهى مِنَ التيجانِ لا بَل أَلمَعُفَهُمُ لِأَيّامِ الحَفائِظِ مَفزَعٌوَهُمُ لِأَيّامِ المَكارِمِ مَطمَعُهَتَفَ العَلاءُ بِهِم إِلى غاياتِهِفَتَضَرَّعَ القَومُ اللِئامُ وَأَسرَعواأَنا غَرسُكُم وَالغُصنُ لَدنٌ وَالصِباغَضٌّ وَلِلعيسِ القِيادُ الأَطوَعُرِشتُم سِهامي لِلعِدى وَتَرَكتُمُقَدَمي إِلى أَمَدِ المَعالي تَتبَعُوَحَثَثتُمُ حَظّي لِيَلحَقَ شَأوَكُمحَتّى اِستَمَرَّ وَحَظُّ غَيري يُقدَعُوَصَنَعتُمُ فَعَرَفتُ قَدرَ صَنيعِكُموَلَرُبَّما غَلِطَ الطَريقَ المُصنِعُوَحَفِظتُ ما اِستَودَعتُ مِن نِعمائِكُمإِنَّ الوَفاءَ أَمانَةٌ تُستَودَعُيا بانِيَ الشَرَفِ المُوَطَّدِ حَيثُ لاتَصِلُ العُيونُ وَلا تَنالُ الأَذرُعُوَسَليلَ مُحصَنَةِ العُلى في حِجرِهامُستَودَعٌ وَبِدَرِّها مُستَرضَعُتَحنو المُلوكُ عَلَيهِ مِن جَنَباتِهِكَالقَلبِ حانِيَةٌ عَلَيهِ الأَضلُعُأَرتِق لَها فَتقَ النَوائِبِ بِالنَدىأَو بِالقَنا وَلِكُلِّ خَرقٍ مَرقَعُوَاِسكُك سَبيلَ أَبيكَ إِنَّ سَبيلَهلَقَمٌ يُجيزُ إِلى المَناقِبِ مَهيَعُوَاِطلُب عَلى أَيّامِهِ وَجِيادُهُحَسرى يَرِدنَ عَلى الطِعانِ وَظُلَّعُتَدِقُ الغِوارَ عَلى الغِوارِ كَأَنَّهاوَطغاءُ تَحفِزُها بَليلٌ زَعزَعُوَالصِبحُ مُنقَدُّ القَميصِ كَما جَلاعَن حُرِّ مَفرَقِهِ البُجالُ الأَنزَعُوَاِستَقبِلِ الأَيامَ غَيرَ جَوامِحٍيَثني إِلَيكَ بِها عِنانٌ طَيِّعُتَعنولِأَخمَصِكَ الخُطوبُ ذَليلَةًبَعدَ العِراكِ وَخَدُّهُنَّ الأَضرَعُإِن سَرَّ أَمسُك كانَ يَومُكَ فَوقَهوَيَقِلُّ عِندَ غَدٍ لِما يُتَوَقَّعُ"},{"question":"Àwọn ìlú wo ni wọ́n máa ń kọ Dadakúàdà? ","answer":"Ìlú Ìlọrin ni."},{"question":"Tohizo izao ohabolana izao : \\"  ny henatra tsy ........................................\\"","answer":"\\"  ny henatra tsy ahavitan-draharaha \\""},{"question":"निम्नलिखित कहानी की एक संभावित अंत लिखें -आपका छोटा भाई बहुत दिनों से खुश नहीं दिख रहा है। आप उससे पूछते हैं,","answer":"\\"भाई, मैं देख रहा हूँ कि तुम खुश नहीं हो। क्या हुआ? तुम्हारे लिए बड़े भाई के पास एक सरप्राइज़ है जो तुम्हारे मुस्कराने की वजह बन सकती है। तुम्हारे दिल की बात मुझसे बात करो, हम मिलकर समस्या का समाधान निकालेंगे।\\""},{"question":"السؤال: ما هي السورة التي يجب قراءتها في كل ركعة في الصلاة؟","answer":"الإجابة: الفاتحة"},{"question":"వాక్యం 1: శీతాకాలంలో వాతావరణం మధ్యస్తంగా వెచ్చగా ఉంటుంది, వేసవిలో ఇది చల్లగా ఉంటుంది. వాక్యం 2: శీతాకాలంలో వాతావరణం చల్లగా ఉంటుంది, వేసవిలో వెచ్చగా ఉంటుంది. ప్రశ్న: 1వ వాక్యం, 2వ వాక్యం రెండూ ఒకే అర్థాన్ని ఇస్తున్నాయా? అవును లేదా కాదు?","answer":"లేదు రెండు వాక్యాలు వేరు వేరు అర్థాలను ఇస్తున్నాయి . "},{"question":"What city hosted the 2002 Winter Olympic Games?","answer":"The 2002 Winter Olympic Games were hosted in Salt Lake City, Utah, USA."},{"question":"గ్రూపులో పై నుండి క్రిందికి వెళ్ళే కొలదీ అయనీకరణ శక్తి విలువ …….A) పెరుగుతుందిB) తగ్గుతుందిC) మారదుD) చెప్పలేము","answer":"B) తగ్గుతుంది"},{"question":"Defina a palavra ajudar.","answer":"Ajudar significa prestar socorro ou assistência."},{"question":"এই বাক্যাংশের জন্য একটি ধারাবাহিকতা লিখুন:১৯১৬ সালের সেপ্টেম্বরে আরব বিদ্রোহের","answer":"সময় হাশিমি বাহিনী তাইফ দখল করে। পরে তা হেজাজ রাজতন্ত্রের সাথে যুক্ত করা হয়। তবে হাশিমিরা দীর্ঘসময় তাইফের নিয়ন্ত্রণ ধরে রাখতে পারেনি। হুসাইন বিন আলি এবং আবদুল আজিজ ইবনে সৌদের মধ্যে উত্তেজনাপূর্ণ অবস্থার জন্য দ্রুত সহিংসতা ছড়িয়ে পড়ে। প্রথম হাশিমি-সৌদি যুদ্ধের পর ১৯১৯ সালে চুক্তির মাধ্যমে সাময়িকভাবে সহিংসতা বন্ধ হয়।"},{"question":"Caracas moy péeyu ban réw?","answer":"Caracas moy péeyu réwum Venezuela"},{"question":"රොකිං පුටුවක් යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"පැද්දෙන පුටුවකට සෘජු කකුල් හතරකට වඩා දිගු වක්‍ර කකුල් දෙකක් ඇති නිසා එය ඉදිරියට සහ පසුපසට පැද්දෙයි."},{"question":"Дай відповідь на питання. На якому інструменті грає лідер гурту Стівена Колберта?","answer":"На органі Хаммонда."},{"question":"வினா : முதல் மோட்டார் ரோடுரோலர் எந்த நாட்டில் தயாரிக்கப்பட்டது?","answer":"விடை : இங்கிலாந்து,"},{"question":"Content: న్యూటెల్లా తయారు చేసే ఫెర్రెరో కంపెనీ ఈ హజెల్ నట్స్‌ కొనుగోలు చేసే అతిపెద్ద సంస్థ. కానీ, ఈ గింజలను ప్రధానంగా సేకరించేది వలస వచ్చిన కూలీలు, పిల్లలు. చాలా తక్కువ జీతాలకు ఎక్కువ గంటలు వారు పని చేస్తున్నారు. అయితే, ఫెర్రెరో సంస్థ తన ఉత్పత్తుల కోసం బాల కార్మికులపై ఆధారపడకుండా ఎలాంటి ప్రత్యామ్నాయాలు చేస్తోంది? ''హజెల్ నట్స్‌ పేరు వినగానే నా మనసుకు కష్టంగా అనిపిస్తుంది. ఎందుకంటే అది చాలా కష్టమైన పని'' అని 35 కేజీల గింజలను ఒక సంచిలో భుజానికి మోసుకుంటూ చెప్పారు మెహ్మెట్ కెలేక్కి.టర్కిష్ పర్వతసానువుల్లో అతని చుట్టూ తోటి కుర్దిష్ వలస కార్మికుల కుటుంబం హాజెల్ చెట్ల మధ్య నెమ్మదిగా కదులుతోంది. ఇది చాలా శ్రమతో కూడుకున్నది. రోజుకు సుమారు 10 గంటల పాటు ఏటవాలుగా నడుస్తూ అడుగులు తడబడకుండా గింజలను సేకరించాలి. హజెల్ నట్స్ సేకరిస్తున్న కార్మికుడుకుర్దిష్ వలస కార్మికుల కుటుంబానికి చెందిన ఇద్దరు చిన్నారులు ముస్తఫా, మొహ్మద్ అక్రమంగా పనిచేస్తున్నారు. వారిలో ఒకరికి 12 ఏళ్లు మరికొకరికి 10 ఏళ్లు ఉంటాయి. వారిద్దరికి ఆ దేశ కనీస పని వయస్సు కంటే తక్కువ వయసు ఉంది.టర్కీలోని నల్ల సముద్రం తీరం వెంట ఆగస్టులో పంట చేతికి వస్తుంటుంది. ప్రపంచంలోని హజెల్ నట్ ఉత్పత్తిలో 70శాతం పంట ఇక్కడి నుంచే వస్తుంది. ఇక్కడ హజెల్ నట్ సేకరించేవారిలో చాలా మంది వలసవచ్చిన కుర్దీలే. వెనకబడిన దక్షిణ, తూర్పు టర్కీ ప్రాంతాల నుంచి వారు వస్తుంటారు.గింజల సేకరణకు స్థానిక అధికారులు నిర్ణయించిన వేతన రేటు రోజుకు 95 లీరాలు(రూ.1,067). కానీ, టర్కిష్ కనీస వేతనం చట్టం కంటే ఈ మొత్తం చాలా తక్కువ.కానీ, ఈ ముస్తఫా, మొహ్మద్‌ల కుటుంబం ఇంతకంటే తక్కువ వేతనమే అందుకుంటుంది. రోజుకు గరిష్టంగా 65 నుంచి 50 లీరాలు మాత్రమే వీరి కుటుంబానికి వస్తోంది. పని ఇచ్చే కాంట్రాక్టర్‌కు 10 శాతం కమీషన్, ఇంటి నుంచి ఇక్కడికి రావడానికి రవాణా చార్జీలు, మిగిలిన ఖర్చులు తీసేస్తే వీరికి చాలా తక్కువ మొత్తమే మిగులుతోంది. హజెల్ నట్స్ సేకరిస్తున్న బాలకార్మికులుఇక్కడి పండ్ల తోటల సహయజమాని కాజీమ్ యమన్ మాట్లాడుతూ,  తాను పిల్లలతో పనిచేయించడానికి వ్యతిరేకం అని చెప్పారు. \\"వారు తమ పిల్లలను యంత్రాల్లా పని చేయిస్తున్నారు. ఎంత మంది పిల్లలుంటే ఎంత లాభం వస్తుందని ఆలోచిస్తున్నారు'' అని తల్లిదండ్రుల తీరు గురించి చెప్పుకొచ్చారు. ''ఇక్కడ చాలా మంది పిల్లలను పనిలో పెట్టడాన్ని అంగీకరిస్తున్నారు. .nThe previous content can be summarized as follows:","answer":"ప్రపంచంలో మొత్తం ఉత్పత్తి అయ్యే హజెల్ నట్స్‌లో దాదాపు మూడొంతులు టర్కీ నుంచే వస్తుంది."},{"question":"வினா:”ஆய்” என்ற மன்னர் ஆட்சி புரிந்த மலை?","answer":"விடை: பொதிகை மலை"},{"question":"Jawab soalan teka-teki ini: Saya mampu berlayar di atas laut, dari utara ke selatan, timur ke barat, siapa saya?","answer":"Jawapannya ialah kapal layar"},{"question":"Inona no fetran'ny fahalalahana maneho hevitra ao anatin'ny demokrasia?","answer":"Anisan'ny fetran'ny fahalalahana maneho hevitra ny fanalam-baraka, ny fankahalana ara-poko ary ny famoahana ny tsiambaratelom-panjakana"},{"question":"तलको प्रश्नको उत्तर दिनुहोस् ।कुनै विशेष परिवेशमा व्यतिरेकी भएर आउने ध्वनिलाई के भनिन्छ ?","answer":"कुनै विशेष परिवेशमा व्यतिरेकी भएर आउने ध्वनिलाई वर्ण भनिन्छ ।"},{"question":"सबैभन्दा बढि मतदाता भएको देश कुन हो?","answer":"भारत"},{"question":"أريد إنشاء قصيدة مدح من بحر الكامل. هل يمكنك مساعدتي؟","answer":"أَمُبَلِّغي ما أَطلُبُ الغَزَلُأَم لا فَتُنجِدُني القَنا الذُبُلُوَالسَيفُ أَولى أَن أَعوذَ بِهِمِمّا تَجُرُّ الأَعيُنُ النُجُلُوَأَنا الَّذي نَفَرَ الزَمانُ بِهِوَاِستَأنَسَت بِرِكابِهِ السُبُلُأَسري عَلى غَرَرٍ وَتَصحَبُنيدونَ الرِجالِ الأَينُقُ الذُلُلُلا المالُ يَجذِبُني إِلَيهِ وَلايَعتاقُها الحَوذانُ وَالنَفَلُعَجِلٌ بِيَ الشَدُّ الحَثيثُ إِلى الغاياتِ خَرّاجٌ بِيَ المَهَلُفي غِلمَةٍ تَرَكوا قُعودَهُمُنَزَعوا وَراءَ اللَيلِ وَاِنحَفَلواوَإِذا المَزادُ حَمى صَلاصِلَهُقَنِعوا بِما تَقضي لَنا المُقَلُوَمُقَوَّمِ الأُذُنَينِ تَحسَبُهُطَوداً أَنافَ بِصَدرِهِ جَبَلُمُتَطاوِلٌ يوفي مُعَرِّدُهُعُنقاً تَضاءَلَ خَلفَها الكَفَلُأَجهَدتُهُ وَالكَرُّ يَعصِرُهُوَالماءُ مِن عِطفَيهِ يَنهَمِلُوَنَجيبَةٍ نَهَضَ الزَمانُ بِهامِن بَعدِ ما قَعَدَت بِها العُقُلُصَدَعَت عَرانينَ الرُبى وَنَجَتهَوَجاً وَيُنجِدُ وَخدَها الرَمَلُطَلَبَت أَميرَ المُؤمِنينَ وَلاأَينٌ أَطافَ بِها وَلا مَهَلُحَيثُ العُلى لا يُستَرابُ بِهاوَالجودُ لا يَلوي بِهِ البَخَلُوَالطائِعُ المَرجوُّ إِن حُمِدَتأَيدي الرِجالِ وَقَلَّ مَن يَسَلُمَلِكٌ إِذا حُصِرَ السِماطُ بِهِكَثُرَ العِثارُ وَطَبَّقَ الزَلَلُوَإِذا السَريرُ سَما بِقَدَتِهِغَرِيَت بِظاهِرِ كَفِّهِ القُبَلُجَلَتِ الأَئِمَّةُ عَن مَناقِبِهِوَاِستَودَعَتهُ نورَها الرُسُلُوَإِذا العُيوبُ مَشَت إِلَيهِ بَداوَجهٌ تَخاوَصُ دونَهُ المُقَلُفَاللَحظُ مُحتَبِسٌ وَمُنطَلِقٌوَالقَولُ مُنقَطِعٌ وَمُتَّصِلُطَرِبٌ إِلى النَعماءِ عاهَدهاأَن لا يَمُرَّ بِسَمعِهِ عَذَلُيَلقى الخُطوبَ وَوَجهُهُ طَلِقٌوَيَخوضُهُنَّ وَقَلبُهُ جَذِلُتُخفي بَشاشَتُهُ حَميَّتَهُكَالسُمِّ مَوَّهَ طَعمَهُ العَسَلُمِن مَعشَرٍ كانَت سُيوفُهُمُحَلياً لِمَن ضَرَبوا وَمَن عَطِلوابِالفَخرِ يَكسونَ الَّذي سَلَبواوَالذِكرِ يُحيونَ الَّذي قَتَلواأَنتَ الجَوادُ إِذا غَلا أَمَلٌوَالمُستَجارُ إِذا طَغى وَجَلُوَمُطاعِنٍ بَعَثَت يَداكَ لَهُطَعناً يَذُلُّ لِوَقعِهِ البَطَلُوَعَلِمتَ أَنَّ السَيلَ يَدفَعُهُلَمّا أَطَلَّ العارِضُ الهَطَلُلِلَّهِ رُمحُكَ يَومَ تورِدُهُوَالماءُ لا صَردٌ وَلا عَلَلُخَطِلُ المَناكِبِ لا يَميلُ بِهِمَوجٌ وَمِن نَعتِ القَنا الخَطَلُوَمُطاعِنَينِ إِذا هُما اِعتَرَضايَتَطاعَنانِ وَلِلقَنا زَجَلُنَزَلَ الهَصورُ عَلى فَريسَتِهِوَمَضى يُدَحرِجُ نَجوَهُ الجُعَلُشَيخانِ هَذا فارِسٌ بَطَلٌأَبَداً وَهَذا عاجِزٌ مَذِلُفَإِذا الزَمانُ أَرادَ قَودَهُماحَرَنَ الجَوادُ وَأَصحَبَ الوَعِلُأَمُريدَ زائِدَةِ الأَنامِ أَقِمهَيهاتَ مِنكَ الشَدُّ وَالعَجَلُأَتُريدُ غاياتِ الفَخارِ وَمالَكَ ناقَةٌ فيهِ وَلا جَمَلُفَاِنعَق بِضَأنِكَ عَن أَناطِحِهِوَدَعِ الغَميرَ تَلُسُّهُ الإِبِلُيا قابِضَ الأَيّامِ عَن وَجَلٍبِيَمينِهِ عَن مَسِّها شَلَلُيَئِلُ الَّذي أَمَّنتَ رَوعَتَهُوَالعُصمُ في الأَطوادِ لا تَئِلُلِوَليَّكَ الدُنيا مُزَخرَفَةٌوَلِأُمِّ مَن عادَيتَهُ الهَبَلُاِن قالَ فيكَ عِداكَ مَنقَصَةًقالوا السَماءُ أَديمُها نَغِلُاِحذَر عَدوَّكَ أَن تُقَرِّبَهُمِن قَلبِكَ الخَدَعاتُ وَالحِيَلُلا تُخدَعَنَّ عَلى رُقاهُ وَلَوأَرضاكَ مِنهُ القَولُ وَالعَمَلُفَفُؤادُهُ حَنِقٌ عَلَيكَ وَإِنطاطا وَذَلَّلَهُ لَكَ الوَجَلُإِنَّ المُجَرَّدَ في هَواكَ فَتىًلا اللَومُ يَردَعُهُ وَلا العَذَلُمِثلُ الحُسَينِ فَبَينَ أَضلُعِهِقَلبٌ بِغَيرِكَ ما لَهُ شَغَلُيُثني عَلَيكَ بِكُلِّ عارِفَةٍأَبَداً وَسِترُ الغَيبِ مُنسَدِلُذاكَ الحُسامُ أَطَلتَ جَفوَتَهُوَلَقَلَّ ما ظَفِرَت بِهِ الخِلَلُوَوَعَدتَهُ وَعداً تَعَلَّقَهُوَالوَعدُ مَلويٌّ بِهِ الأَمَلُفَاِنهَض بِهِ في النائِباتِ تَجَدعَضباً تَساقَطُ دونَهُ القُلَلُوَاِسلَم أَميرَ المُؤمِنينَ إِذاشَرَعَ الحِمامُ وَصَمَّمَ الأَجَلُمُتَقَلِّداً بِنِجادِ مَملَكَةٍفي غِمدِها الأَقدارُ وَالدُوَلُوَاِنعَم بِيَومِ المِهرِجانِ وَلانَعِمَ العُداةُ بِهِ وَلا عَقَلوافَلَأَنتَ نَهّاضٌ إِذا قَعَدواأَبَداً وَصَعّادٌ إِذا نَزَلوايَومٌ تُجَدِّدُهُ السُنونَ وَقَددَرَجَت عَلَيهِ الأَعصُرُ الأُوَلُفَالناسُ فيهِ مُعَلَّلٌ طَرِبٌيَرجو الأُوارَ وَشارِبٌ ثَمِلُما اِستَجمَعَت فِرَقُ الهُمومِ بِهِإِلّا وَبَدَّدَ جَمعَها الجَذَلُهُوَ خِطَّةٌ نَزَلَ الشِتاءُ بِهاوَالصَيفُ مُنطَلِقٌ وَمُرتَحِلُوَأَنا الَّذي أَهوى هَواكَ وَلَوضُرِبَت عَلَيَّ البيضُ وَالأَسَلُوَطِئَت قَبائِلُ غالِبٍ عَقِبيوَتَشَرَّفَت بِمَقامِيَ الحِلَلُوَفَقَأتُ عَينَ البُخلِ مُذ كَثُرَتبِنَداكَ عِندي الأَينُقُ البُزُلُوَمُراغِمٍ يَغدو عَلى قَنَصيفَيَحوزُهُ وَيَدايَ مُحتَبِلُخُضتُ الغِمارَ فَجازَ جُمَّتَهادوني وَطَبَّقَ ثَوبِيَ البَلَلُوَمُذَكِّري رَحِماً مُعَنَّسَةًكَالشَمسِ أَخلَقَ ضَوءَها الطَفَلُرَحِمٌ تَعَلَّقُ بِالبَعيدِ كَماعَلِقَ الحِباءَ النازِحُ الطُوَلُاِثنانِ يَقتَطِعانِ مِن فُرَصيوَأَنا الَّذي أُرخي وَأَهتَبِلُغَرَضي بِمَدحِكَ أَن يُطاوِعَنيعِوَجٌ بِأَيّامي وَيَعتَدِلُوَأَقومُ بَينَ يَدَيكَ مُرتَجِلاًلا العَيُّ يَقطَعُني وَلا الخَطَلُوَلَئِن نَما كُلُّ المَديحِ إِلىفَلَتاتِ قَولي وَاِنتَمى الغَزَلُفَالأَرضُ أُمُّ التُربِ أَجمَعِهِوَأَبو البَريَّةِ كُلِّها رَجُلُ"},{"question":"ਗ਼ਦਰ ਪਾਰਟੀ ਨੇ ਆਜ਼ਾਦੀ ਦੀ ਜੰਗ ਲਈ ਕੀ-ਕੀ ਯਤਨ ਕੀਤੇ ?","answer":"ਗ਼ਦਰ ਪਾਰਟੀ ਦੀ ਸਥਾਪਨਾ 1913 ਈ: ਵਿੱਚ ਸਾਨਫਰਾਂਸਿਸਕੋ (ਅਮਰੀਕਾ) ਵਿੱਚ ਹੋਈ । ਇਸ ਦਾ ਪ੍ਰਧਾਨ ਬਾਬਾ ਸੋਹਣ ਸਿੰਘ ਭਕਨਾ ਸੀ । ਲਾਲਾ ਹਰਦਿਆਲ ਇਸ ਦੇ ਮੁੱਖ ਸਕੱਤਰ, ਕਾਂਸ਼ੀ ਰਾਮ ਸਕੱਤਰ ਅਤੇ ਖ਼ਜ਼ਾਨਚੀ ਸਨ । | ਇਸ ਸੰਸਥਾ ਨੇ ਸਾਨਫਰਾਂਸਿਸਕੋ ਤੋਂ ਉਰਦੂ ਵਿੱਚ ਇੱਕ ਸਪਤਾਹਿਕ ਪੱਤਰ ‘ਗਦਰ’ ਕੱਢਣਾ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਕੀਤਾ । ਇਸ ਦੀ ਸੰਪਾਦਨਾ ਦਾ ਕੰਮ ਕਰਤਾਰ ਸਿੰਘ ਸਰਾਭਾ ਨੂੰ ਸੌਂਪਿਆ ਗਿਆ । ਉਸ ਦੀ ਮਿਹਨਤ ਸਦਕਾ ਉਹ ਅਖ਼ਬਾਰ ਹਿੰਦੀ, ਪੰਜਾਬੀ, ਗੁਜਰਾਤੀ, ਬੰਗਾਲੀ, ਪਸ਼ਤੋ ਅਤੇ ਨੇਪਾਲੀ ਭਾਸ਼ਾ ਵਿੱਚ ਵੀ ਛਪਣ ਲੱਗਾ । ਇਸ ਅਖ਼ਬਾਰ ਦੇ ਕਾਰਨ ਇਸ ਸੰਸਥਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਂ “ਗਦਰ ਪਾਰਟੀ’ ਰੱਖਿਆ ਗਿਆ ।ਉਦੇਸ਼-ਇਸ ਸੰਸਥਾ ਦਾ ਮੁੱਖ ਉਦੇਸ਼ ਹਥਿਆਰਬੰਦ ਬਗਾਵਤ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਭਾਰਤ ਨੂੰ ਆਜ਼ਾਦ ਕਰਵਾਉਣਾ ਸੀ । ਇਸ ਲਈ ਇਸ ਪਾਰਟੀ ਨੇ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਕੰਮਾਂ ਉੱਤੇ ਜ਼ੋਰ ਦਿੱਤਾ-1. ਸੈਨਾ ਵਿੱਚ ਬਗਾਵਤ ਦਾ ਪ੍ਰਚਾਰ ।2. ਸਰਕਾਰੀ ਪਿੱਠੂਆਂ ਦੀ ਹੱਤਿਆ ।3. ਜੇਲਾਂ ਤੋੜਨੀਆਂ ।4. ਸਰਕਾਰੀ ਖ਼ਜ਼ਾਨੇ ਅਤੇ ਥਾਣੇ ਲੁੱਟਣੇ ।5. ਕ੍ਰਾਂਤੀਕਾਰੀ ਸਾਹਿਤ ਛਾਪਣਾ ਅਤੇ ਵੰਡਣਾ ।6. ਅੰਗਰੇਜ਼ਾਂ ਦੇ ਦੁਸ਼ਮਣਾਂ ਦੀ ਸਹਾਇਤਾ ਕਰਨੀ ।7. ਹਥਿਆਰ ਇਕੱਠਾ ਕਰਨਾ ।8. ਬੰਬ ਬਣਾਉਣੇ ।9. ਰੇਲਵੇ, ਡਾਕ-ਤਾਰ ਨੂੰ ਕੱਟਣਾ ਅਤੇ ਭੰਨ-ਤੋੜ ਕਰਨੀ ।10. ਕ੍ਰਾਂਤੀਕਾਰੀਆਂ ਦਾ ਝੰਡਾ ਲਹਿਰਾਉਣਾ ।11. ਕ੍ਰਾਂਤੀਕਾਰੀ ਨੌਜਵਾਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਸੂਚੀ ਤਿਆਰ ਕਰਨਾ ।ਆਜ਼ਾਦੀ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤੀ ਦੇ ਯਤਨ – ਕਾਮਾਗਾਟਾਮਾਰੂ ਦੀ ਘਟਨਾ ਮਗਰੋਂ ਕਾਫ਼ੀ ਗਿਣਤੀ ਵਿੱਚ ਭਾਰਤੀ ਲੋਕ ਆਪਣੇ ਦੇਸ਼ ਪਰਤੇ । ਉਹ ਭਾਰਤ ਵਿੱਚ ਗ਼ਦਰ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਅੰਗਰੇਜ਼ਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਦੇਸ਼ ਵਿੱਚੋਂ ਕੱਢਣਾ ਚਾਹੁੰਦੇ ਸਨ । ਅੰਗਰੇਜ਼ ਸਰਕਾਰ ਬੜੀ ਹੀ ਚੌਕਸੀ ਤੋਂ ਕੰਮ ਲੈ ਰਹੀ ਸੀ । ਬਾਹਰੋਂ ਆਉਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਹਰ ਬੰਦੇ ਦੀ ਛਾਣ-ਬੀਣ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਸੀ । ਸ਼ੱਕ ਹੋਣ ‘ਤੇ ਉਸ ਬੰਦੇ ਨੂੰ ਨਜ਼ਰਬੰਦ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਸੀ । ਜਿਹੜਾ ਬੰਦਾ ਬਚ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਸੀ, ਉਹ ਗ਼ਦਰੀਆਂ ਨਾਲ ਰਲ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਸੀ ।ਗ਼ਦਰ ਪਾਰਟੀ ਅਤੇ ਬਾਹਰੋਂ ਪਰਤੇ ਕ੍ਰਾਂਤੀਕਾਰੀਆਂ ਦੀ ਅਗਵਾਈ ਰਾਸ ਬਿਹਾਰੀ ਬੋਸ ਨੇ ਸੰਭਾਲੀ । ਅਮਰੀਕਾ ਤੋਂ ਪਰਤੇ ਕਰਤਾਰ ਸਿੰਘ ਸਰਾਭਾ ਨੇ ਵੀ ਭਾਈ ਪਰਮਾਨੰਦ ਝਾਂਸੀ ਨਾਲ ਸੰਬੰਧ ਕਾਇਮ ਕੀਤੇ ਅਤੇ ਬਨਾਰਸ ਵਿਖੇ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਰਾਸ ਬਿਹਾਰੀ ਬੋਸ ਦੇ ਲੁਕਵੇਂ ਅੱਡੇ ਦਾ ਪਤਾ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਉਸ ਨਾਲ ਵੀ ਸੰਪਰਕ ਕਾਇਮ ਕੀਤਾ ।ਗਦਰ ਪਾਰਟੀ ਦੁਆਰਾ ਆਜ਼ਾਦੀ ਲਈ ਕੀਤੇ ਗਏ ਕੰਮ – ਗ਼ਦਰ ਪਾਰਟੀ ਦੁਆਰਾ ਪੰਜਾਬ ਵਿੱਚ ਆਜ਼ਾਦੀ ਲਈ ਕੀਤੇ ਗਏ ਕੰਮਾਂ ਦਾ ਵਰਣਨ ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਹੈ-1. ਰਾਸ ਬਿਹਾਰੀ ਬੋਸ ਨੇ ਲਾਹੌਰ, ਫ਼ਿਰੋਜ਼ਪੁਰ, ਮੇਰਠ, ਅੰਬਾਲਾ, ਮੁਲਤਾਨ, ਪਿਸ਼ਾਵਰ ਅਤੇ ਕਈ ਹੋਰ ਛਾਉਣੀਆਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਪ੍ਰਚਾਰਕ ਭੇਜੇ ।2. ਕਰਤਾਰ ਸਿੰਘ ਸਰਾਭਾ ਨੇ ਲਾਲਾ ਰਾਮ ਸਰਨ ਦਾਸ ਕਪੂਰਥਲਾ ਨਾਲ ਮਿਲ ਕੇ ‘ਗਦਰ’ ਨਾਂ ਦਾ ਸਪਤਾਹਿਕ ਪੱਤਰ ਕੱਢਣ ਲਈ ਐੱਸ ਚਾਲੂ ਕਰਨਾ ਚਾਹਿਆ ਪਰ ਅਸਫਲ ਰਿਹਾ । ਫਿਰ ਵੀ ਉਹ ‘ਗਦਰ ਗੁਜ’ ਛਾਪਦਾ ਰਿਹਾ ।3. ਗ਼ਦਰ ਪਾਰਟੀ ਨੇ ਲਾਹੌਰ ਅਤੇ ਕੁਝ ਹੋਰਨਾਂ ਥਾਂਵਾਂ ‘ਤੇ ਬੰਬ ਬਣਾਉਣ ਦਾ ਕੰਮ ਵੀ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਕੀਤਾ ।4. ਗ਼ਦਰ ਪਾਰਟੀ ਨੇ ਆਜ਼ਾਦ ਭਾਰਤ ਲਈ ਇੱਕ ਝੰਡਾ ਤਿਆਰ ਕੀਤਾ । ਕਰਤਾਰ ਸਿੰਘ ਸਰਾਭਾ ਨੇ ਇਸ ਝੰਡੇ ਨੂੰ ਥਾਂ-ਥਾਂ ਲੋਕਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਵੰਡਿਆ ।"},{"question":"Trả lời bài toán sau:Năm bạn Alice, Beck, Kevin, Danny và Elisa chia một số viên bi với nhau theo cách sau: Alice lấy 1 viên và 1/5 của số bi còn lại, sau đó Beck lấy 1 viên và 1/5 của số bi còn lại. Kevin, Danny và Elisa cũng làm theo như vậy. Hỏi lúc đầu có ít nhất bao nhiêu viên bi?","answer":"Nếu ngay từ đầu trước khi chia bi ta cho thêm vào 4 viên bi thì Alice sẽ lấy đúng 1/5 số tổng số bi, tiếp đó Beck lấy 1/5 số bi còn lại sau Alice , Kevin lấy 1/5 số bi còn lại sau Beck, Danny lấy 1/5 số bi còn lại sau Kevin và Elisa lấy 1/5 số bi còn lại sau Danny.Do có 5 người nên sau khi thêm 4 viên bi thì số bi nhận được lúc đó phải chia hết cho 55 tức là chia hết cho 3125. Vậy lúc đầu số bi ít nhất là 3125 - 4 = 3121 (viên bi)."},{"question":"Kedu onye izizi rụpụtara ekwentị?","answer":"Onye izizi rụpụtara ekwentị bụ  Alexander Graham Bell "},{"question":"गदर पक्षाची स्थापना कोणी केली ?","answer":"लाला हरदयाळने"},{"question":"Ayat 1: Pada tahun 1996, Jawatankuasa Veteran memilih Bill Foster dari abad ke-19 dan Ned Hanlon dari liga Negro, serta Jim Bunning dan Earl Weaver. Ayat 2: Pada tahun 1996, Jawatankuasa Veteran Ned Hanlon dari abad ke-19 dan Bill Foster dari Negro Ligen, serta Jim Bunning dan Earl Weaver, memilih. Soalan: Adakah ayat 1 dan ayat 2 menyatakan makna yang sama? Ya atau tidak?","answer":"Tidak"},{"question":"Port of Spain mooy péeyu man réew?","answer":"Port of Spain mooy gëblag réewum Trinité-et-Tobago."},{"question":"பாக்டீரியாவால் ஏற்படும் நோய்?","answer":"விடை: பெப்டிக் அல்சர்"},{"question":"असा कोणता देश आहे ज्यामध्ये केवळ २७ लोकच राहतात?","answer":"उत्तर: सिलेंड देशामध्ये केवळ २७ लोकच राहतात ."},{"question":"الجملة 1: أعيد السير هربرت إلى مقعد كرويدون الشرقي الجديد وتم إعادة انتخابه في عام 1951. الجملة 2: أعيد انتخاب السير هربرت إلى مقعد كرويدون الشرقي الجديد وتم إعادة انتخابه في عام 1951. السؤال: هل تعبر الجملة 1 والجملة 2 عن نفس المعنى؟ نعم أم لا؟","answer":"لا، الجملتان لا تعبران عن نفس المعنى."},{"question":"কোন সামুদ্রিক প্রাণী শুধুমাত্র তরুণাস্থি দিয়ে তৈরি","answer":"হাঙ্গরগুলি কেবল তরুণাস্থি দিয়ে তৈরি এবং হাড় নয়"},{"question":"\\"বই পড়া\\" শিরোনামে একটি অনুচ্ছেদ রচনা করো। ","answer":"মানুষের জ্ঞান-বিজ্ঞান, শিল্প ও সাহিত্য সাধনার মৌন সাক্ষী হয়ে দাঁড়িয়ে আছে বিশ্বের অজস্র বই। তার ভেতর দিয়ে মানুষ লাভ করেছে আপন অন্তরতর সত্তার পরিচয়। বইকে সঙ্গী করতে পারলে মানুষের হৃদয়ের ও মনের অনেক অভাব ঘুচে যায়। সুতরাং আধুনিক জগতে সমগ্র বিশ্বকে উপলব্ধি করতে হলে সভ্য মানুষের বইয়ের অবারিত সঙ্গ না হলে চলে না। আবার বইয়ের সূত্র ধরে মানুষ অগ্রসর হয়ে চলে সভ্যতা ও সংস্কৃতির বিবর্তনের পথে। পৃথিবীর ইতিহাস-ঐতিহ্যের অন্যতম অবলম্বন বই। বইয়ের মাধ্যমে আমরা বিশ্বের বিভিন্ন দেশ, জাতি, ভাষা সম্বন্ধে জ্ঞান লাভ করি। বই মানুষকে পৃথিবীতে হাজার বছর পথচলার অনুভূতি দিতে পারে। আবার বইয়ের মধ্য দিয়েই কোনো কবি, সাহিত্যিক বা লেখক মৃত্যুর পরও বেঁচে থাকতে পারেন হাজার বছর। তাই বই পড়া মানুষকে আনন্দ দানের পাশাপাশি দিতে পারে সঠিক সফলতার ছোঁয়াও। বই মানুষের হৃদয়ের দ্বার খুলে দেয়, চিন্তার জগৎকে প্রসারিত করে। আমাদের মননশক্তি ও হৃদয়বৃত্তিকে সম্পূর্ণভাবে জাগ্রত করতে পারি বই পাঠের মাধ্যমেই। তাই বই পড়ার অভ্যাস গঠন করা অবশ্যই উচিত। বইয়ে জ্ঞান-বিজ্ঞান, শিল্প- সাহিত্যের স্রোতধারা একত্র হয়। সেই ধারার সাথে মিললেই মানুষের আত্মপ্রসার ঘটে। তাই আমরা অধিক পরিমাণে বইপাঠে আগ্রহী হব যা দিতে পারে এক সুন্দর ভবিষ্যৎ।"},{"question":"Waxaad Sheegtaa wax ka mid ah cuntooyinkii nabiga jeclaa {NNKH}?","answer":"Cuntooyinkii nabiga jeclaa {NNKH} waxaa ka mid ah: timirta, cinabka, qamadiga, malabka, ruumaanka, qaraha, bocorka iyo hilibka cas ama gaduudan."},{"question":"ලෝක මාධ්‍ය දිනය කවදාද?","answer":"ජූලි 01"},{"question":"महाराष्ट्र राज्यातील मेळघाट व्याघ्र प्रकल्पाचे यंदाचे स्थापनेचे कोणते महोत्सवी वर्ष आहे?(A)  अमृत(B)  सुवर्ण(C)  शतक(D)  हीरक","answer":"(B) सुवर्ण"},{"question":"दिगो विकासले द्वन्द्व रोकथाममा कसरी योगदान पुर्‍याउन सक्छ?","answer":"दिगो विकासले स्रोतको अभाव, असमानता र वातावरणीय ह्रास, स्थायित्व र सहयोगलाई बढावा दिएर द्वन्द्व रोकथाममा योगदान पुर्‍याउन सक्छ।"},{"question":"Fan moy péeyum réwum Maroc","answer":"Péeyum réwum Maroc mu ngi tudu Rabat"},{"question":"కొవ్వు దేహాలు సకశేరుకాల కాలేయంతో ఏవిధంగా సమానం?","answer":"బొద్దింకలోని కొవ్వు దేహాలను సకశేరుకాలలోని కాలేయంతో పోల్చవచ్చును. ఇవి కొన్ని విధులలో సకశేరుకాల కాలేయాన్ని పోలి ఉంటాయి. కొవ్వు దేహా కణాల విధులు.ట్రోఫోసైట్స్ – ఆహారాన్ని నిలువచేసే కణాలు.మైసిటోసైట్స్ – సహ జీవన బాక్టీరియాను కలిగి ఉంటాయి.ఈనోసైట్స్ – కొవ్వులను స్రవిస్తాయి.యూరేట్ కణాలు – యూరిక్ ఆమ్లాన్ని నిలువచేస్తాయి."},{"question":"Iza no mpanjaka voalohany tany Madagasikara?","answer":"I Rafohy sy i Rangita no mpanjaka voalohany tato Madagasikara."},{"question":"Tuliskan satu karangan yang bertajuk Kejayaan Negara dalam Perindustrian Tren Laju Harapan Masa Depan.","answer":"Dalam mendepani era pascaperindustrian dan pascaglobalisasi, pelbagai perkembangan yang telah dicapai oleh tamadun manusia pada hari ini. Dengan perkongsian ilmu dan kemahiran, kajian sains serta ciptaan teknologi telah banyak membantu perkembangan hidup kita. Jika dahulu manusia perlu menaiki kapal laut selama berminggu-minggu untuk melancong atau bergerak ke benua yang lain. Tetapi kini, kemudahan seperti kapal terbang dan tren laju telah memudahkan usaha seseorang untuk bergerak dari satu destinasi ke satu destinasi yang lebih jauh. Masa perjalanan dapat disingkatkan malah keselesaan juga bertambah baik berbanding cara pengangkutan terdahulu. Di Malaysia, penggunaan tren laju masih tidak diimplementasikan kerana jumlah pengguna belum mencapai tahap yang diperlukan. Namun begitu, wajar untuk kita melihat potensi jenis pengangkutan ini kerana ia mampu memangkin kejayaan negara dalam perindustrian dan pengangkutan demi masa depan Malaysia.Pada hemat saya, pengangkutan tren laju mempunyai potensi yang cukup besar di negara kita kerana ia dapat meningkatkan jaringan perhubungan. Perkhidmatan tren sedia ada yang dikendalikan oleh Keretapi Tanah Melayu Berhad (KTM) memerlukan penambahbaikan bagi menampung jumlah pengguna pada masa akan datang. Kita boleh menyaksikan bahawa setiap kali musim perayaan, jalan raya ke Pantai Timur pasti akan sesak dengan kenderaan. Selain alternatif menaiki kapal terbang, penggunaan tren laju pasti dapat membantu mengurangkan kesesakan lalu lintas pada tempoh tersebut. Di luar musim perayaan pula, perkhidmatan tren laju dapat membantu industri pelancongan kerana jarak perjalanan yang jauh dapat dipendekkan masa perjalanannya. Penduduk dari negeri Selangor misalnya dapat berkunjung ke Terengganu dalam masa satu atau dua jam dan pulang pada hari yang sama. Begitu juga potensi yang boleh berlaku sekiranya Negeri Sarawak dan Sabah mempunyai satu perkhidmatan tren laju untuk penduduk dan juga pelancong memanfaatkannya.Kejayaan lain yang menguntungkan negara sekiranya tren laju dilaksanakan adalah ia dapat membuka banyak peluang pekerjaan. Dari pembinaan sehinggalah ke penyelenggaraan perkhidmatan tren, ia pasti memberikan peluang kepada mereka yang mempunyai pengalaman dan latar belakang akademik yang berkaitan untuk bekerja di bawah infrastruktur ini. Projek seperti Laluan Rel Pantai Timur (ECRL) yang telah dilancarkan sebelum ini sewajarnya diberikan kepada syarikat tempatan kerana ia akan memberi peluang kepada tenaga kerja tempatan untuk berkhidmat dan mencurahkan bakti kepada negara tercinta. Sekiranya terdapat jurang pengalaman dan kemahiran, pihak yang berkenaan boleh mencari sumber atau konsultasi daripada pihak luar yang berminat untuk berkongsi kepakaran pada kos yang berpatutan. Hal ini kerana, tren laju merupakan pengangkutan untuk orang awam, menggunakan hasil daripada orang awam dan seharusnya segala manfaat dan kelebihan dinikmati oleh orang awam. Izharnya, jika syarikat tempatan mampu menghasilkan rangkaian tren laju yang terbaik untuk negara, ia pasti berpotensi untuk dipasarkan di peringkat antarabangsa.Perindustrian tren laju juga dapat meningkatkan ekonomi tempatan khususnya sektor pelancongan. Seperti yang telah saya jelaskan, apabila sebuah jaringan perhubungan ditambah baik, pasti pelbagai ekonomi akan bercambah bak cendawan tumbuh selepas hujan. Pusat-pusat tumpuan pelancongan yang sebelum ini sukar untuk dikunjungi kerana perlu menempuh masa perjalanan yang panjang boleh dinikmati oleh semua pelancong. Jumlah inap desa, hotel, restoran pasti akan bertambah bagi menampung kedatangan pelancong domestik mahupun antarabangsa. Pihak berkuasa tempatan boleh bekerjasama dengan masyarakat tempatan untuk merancang aktiviti dan juga pembangunan yang terbaik bagi penduduk untuk mendapat manfaat daripada pembinaan tren laju dan juga stesennya yang berdekatan. Masyarakat tempatan tidak perlu lagi keluar daripada kawasan luar bandar untuk mencari rezeki kerana industri seperti pelancongan dapat dijalankan di kawasan perkampungan mereka. Inisiatif ini secara tidak langsung dapat merealisasikan wawasan kemakmuran bersama yang diwar-warkan oleh pemimpin negara.Pada sudut pandang yang berlainan, perindustrian tren laju dapat mengurangkan pelepasan karbon dalam negara kita. Secara umumnya kita mengetahui jaringan pengangkutan di dalam negara kebanyakannya adalah melalui jalan raya dan diakses menggunakan kereta atau motorsikal. Pengangkutan ini menggunakan bahan api yang melepaskan karbon ke udara dan menjadikan tahap kebersihan udara tercemar. Demi memastikan anak dan cucu kita hidup dalam suasana yang sihat dan sejahtera, kita perlu bertindak sekarang untuk menyelamatkan sumber alam semula jadi daripada tercemar dan mengancam masa hadapan mereka. Dengan teknologi terkini, pembinaan tren laju yang mesra alam dapat dilaksanakan. Sebagai contoh, tren atau keretapi menggunakan elektrik sebagai bahan api dan sumbernya adalah sumber yang boleh diperbaharui seperti tenaga solar dan hidroelektrik. Lalun trek yang akan dibina pula haruslah tidak mengganggu habitat flora dan fauna dan pastikan ia sentiasa dipelihara dengan baik tanpa menerima sebarang akibat daripada pembinaan tren laju.Kesimpulannya, perindustrian tren laju dalam negara bakal memberikan pelbagai kejayaan khusus buat generasi masa hadapan. Jika semua ahli masyarakat berganding bahu ibarat ke bukit sama didaki, ke lurah sama dituruni, pasti visi kudsi ini dapat direalisasikan bersama manfaat yang menguntungkan semua pihak. Pemimpin negara seharusnya meletakkan kehendak politik dalam memberikan infrastruktur yang terbaik untuk rakyat. Elakkanlah menabur janji dan mengaut keuntungan demi kepentingan diri sebaliknya jujur dalam melaksanakn amanah dan percaya kepada tenaga kerja tempatan untuk menghasilkan yang terbaik untuk negara yang tercinta. Jika tidak diberikan peluang, di mana hasil kerja untuk kita menilainya. Persis kata peribahasa Melayu, jika tidak dipecahkan ruyung, manakan dapat sagunya. Semoga segala usaha untuk meningkatkan taraf hidup masyarakat di dalam Malaysia mencapai objektif dan kejayaan dari usaha kolektif seluruh anggota masyarakat di tanah air ini."},{"question":"छत्रपती शिवाजी महाराज कोण होते?","answer":"छत्रपती शिवाजी महाराज (1630-1680) हे एक प्रमुख मराठा योद्धा राजा आणि पश्चिम भारतातील मराठा साम्राज्याचे संस्थापक होते. भारतीय इतिहासातील महान लष्करी नेते आणि रणनीतीकार म्हणून त्यांची ओळख आहे. शिवाजी महाराजांचा जन्म भोंसले कुळात शहाजी भोंसले आणि जिजाबाई यांच्या पोटी पुणे, महाराष्ट्र, भारताजवळील शिवनेरी किल्ल्यावर झाला.शिवाजीचे जीवन आणि कर्तृत्व भारतीय इतिहासाच्या वाटचालीला आकार देणार्‍या उल्लेखनीय कामगिरीने भरलेले आहे:1. मराठा साम्राज्याचा पाया: किल्ल्यांचे मजबूत जाळे आणि सुव्यवस्थित प्रशासकीय यंत्रणा उभारून शिवाजीने मराठा साम्राज्याचा पाया घातला. त्याने अनेक लहान प्रदेशांचे एकत्रिकरण करून एकसंध आणि शक्तिशाली राज्य केले.2. लष्करी नवकल्पना: शिवाजी त्यांच्या नाविन्यपूर्ण लष्करी रणनीती आणि डावपेचांसाठी ओळखले जात होते. त्यांनी गनिमी युद्धाची संकल्पना मांडली, मोठ्या मुघल आणि आदिल शाही सैन्याचा प्रभावीपणे सामना करण्यासाठी हिट-अँड-रन रणनीती वापरून.3. नौदल: त्यांनी एक शक्तिशाली नौदल देखील स्थापन केले आणि भारताचे पहिले नौदल तयार करण्याचे श्रेय त्यांना दिले जाते. यामुळे त्याला त्याचे किनारपट्टीचे प्रदेश सुरक्षित करण्यात आणि सागरी व्यापारात गुंतण्यास मदत झाली.4. प्रशासन: शिवाजीने प्रशासकीय सुधारणा अंमलात आणल्या ज्याचा उद्देश न्याय्य आणि कार्यक्षम शासन व्यवस्था प्रदान करणे होता. त्यांनी स्थानिक स्वराज्य संस्थांना चालना देण्यासाठी आणि त्यांच्या प्रजेच्या कल्याणासाठी कर गोळा करण्यासाठी उपाययोजना सुरू केल्या.5. धार्मिक सहिष्णुता: शिवाजी त्यांच्या धार्मिक सहिष्णुतेच्या धोरणासाठी ओळखले जात होते, विविध धर्माच्या लोकांशी न्यायाने वागतात आणि त्यांना त्यांच्या राज्यामध्ये त्यांचे धर्म मुक्तपणे आचरणात आणू देतात.६. छापे आणि विस्तार: शिवाजीने मुघल आणि आदिल शाही सल्तनतसह शेजारच्या विविध राज्यांविरुद्ध यशस्वी लष्करी मोहिमा राबवल्या. या मोहिमांमुळे त्याचा प्रदेश आणि प्रभाव वाढला.7. छत्रपती म्हणून राज्याभिषेक: १६७४ मध्ये, शिवाजीला त्यांच्या राज्याचे छत्रपती (\\"सर्वोच्च सार्वभौम\\") म्हणून राज्याभिषेक करण्यात आला, ज्यामुळे त्यांचे प्रादेशिक नेत्यापासून पूर्ण राजा बनले.8. वारसा: शिवाजीचा वारसा त्यांच्या लष्करी आणि प्रशासकीय कामगिरीच्या पलीकडे आहे. ते हिंदू राष्ट्रवाद, शौर्य आणि परकीय वर्चस्व विरुद्ध प्रतिकार यांचे प्रतीक म्हणून साजरे केले जातात.शिवाजीच्या जीवनकथेने असंख्य पुस्तके, चित्रपट आणि सांस्कृतिक कार्यांना प्रेरणा दिली आहे. त्यांच्या कर्तृत्वाने मराठा साम्राज्याच्या वाढीसाठी आणि भारताच्या मोठ्या भागावरील प्रभावाचा पाया घातला. त्यांचे नाव भारतीयांमध्ये आदर आणि प्रशंसा निर्माण करत आहे, विशेषत: महाराष्ट्र राज्यात, जिथे त्यांना एक महान व्यक्तिमत्व मानले जाते."},{"question":"أعطنى نبذة عن الحصان العربى.","answer":"من دواعى سرورى. هذا موضوع شائق بالتأكيد.الحصان العربي هو سلالة من الخيول التي نشأت في شبه الجزيرة العربية. يُعرف الحصان العربي بأنه حصان رشيق، يتميز برأسه الصغير وأذنيه الطويلتين وعينيه الواسعة. كان يستخدم في البداية للحرب، ولكن سرعان ما أصبح يستخدم أيضًا للركوب والرياضة.يتميز الحصان العربي بالعديد من الصفات التي تجعله حصانًا رائعًا للحرب والركوب والرياضة، بما في ذلك: السرعة، و الرشاقة، و الذكاء، و الصبر، و الإخلاصتم استخدام الحصان العربي في العديد من الحروب والغزوات، بما في ذلك الفتوحات الإسلامية. كما تم استخدامه في العديد من الرياضات، مثل سباقات الخيل والرياضات القتالية.اليوم، يُستخدم الحصان العربي في العديد من الأنشطة، بما في ذلك الركوب الترفيهي والركوب الرياضي وتربية الخيول. كما أنه يستخدم في بعض الأحيان في الأفلام والبرامج التلفزيونية.يعد الحصان العربي سلالة رائعة من الخيول، يتمتع بالعديد من الصفات التي تجعله حصانًا محبوبًا ومحترمًا.أتمنى أن أكون قد ساعدتك و أخبرتك بما تريد، هل هناك شئ أخر يمكننى أن أساعدك به؟"},{"question":"Inty misy toe-javatra mitranga: “Feno bibikely ny zaridainan’i Sophia, ary malazo ireo zavamaniry.”Valio ny fanontaniana hoe “Inona no dingana azony atao mba hamonjena ny zaridainany?” Inty misy hevitra tsara ho fantatra hahafana mamaly ilay fanontaniana: “Tia manao zaridaina i Sophia ary mandany ny faran’ny herinandrony amin’ny fikarakarana ny zaridainany, izay feno voninkazo sy legioma isan-karazany.”","answer":"Afaka mamonjy ny zaridainany i Sophia amin'ny alalan'ny: Famantarana ireo karazam-bibikely misy ao sy fikarohana fomba mahomby hifehezana azy ireo, mampiasa fomba famonoana bibikely organika, toy ny fampiasana fanafody DDT, fanondrahana rano sy fanasiana zezika araka ny tokony ho izy mba hamelomana indray ireo zavamaniry malazo ary fametrahana sakana ara-materialy, toy ny harato na saron-tava, mba hiarovana ny zaridainany amin'ny bibikely."},{"question":"Indil péeteg waat yi ci kàddu gii: Kenn du léen woyafal mbugal ma, kenn du léen ko yéexalal, lu dul ña tuub ginnaaw loola te sellal séen i jëf.","answer":"Waat yi nekk ci kàddu gii di \\"Kenn du léen woyafal mbugal ma, kenn du léen ko yéexalal, lu dul ña tuub ginnaaw loola te sellal séen i jëf.\\" ak séen i péete ñoo di:Kenn: PRONdu: AUXléen: PRONwoyafal: VERBmbugal: NOUNma: DET,: PUNCTkenn: PRONdu: AUXléen: PRONko: PRONyéexalal: VERB,: PUNCTlu: PRONdul: AUXña: PRONtuub: VERBginnaaw: ADPloola: PRONte: CCONJsellal: VERBséen: PRONi: DETjëf: NOUN.: PUNCT"},{"question":"السؤال: ما هو علم المقذوفات؟","answer":"الإجابة: هو العلم الذي يعنى بشكل الحركة التي يقذف بها جسيم أو كما يسمى قذيفة بالقرب من سطح الأرض، وتتحرك في مسار منحني يخضع لتأثير عجلة الجاذبية فقط."},{"question":"アメリカンコミックのヒーロー、ポパイの腕に彫られている入れ墨は何の模様でしょう？","answer":"錨（いかり）です。"},{"question":"问题：朝鲜是否有旅游景点？","answer":"答案：朝鲜拥有一些旅游景点，如平壤的景福宫和开城的龙城山等。"},{"question":"问题：最常见的家用电器是什么","answer":"答案：电视机"},{"question":"தமிழ்நாட்டின் மிகப்பெரிய அணை எது?","answer":"மேட்டூர் அணை, மேட்டூர் நீர்த்தேக்கம் என்றும் அழைக்கப்படுகிறது, இது தமிழ்நாட்டின் மிகப்பெரிய அணையாகும்."},{"question":"Орой көз чарай ","answer":"Көзмө-көз, бүт баардыгы чогуу турганда, элдин көзүнчө, эл алдында, эч кимден жашыруун эмес. Каалаганымды орой көз чарай ачык таштадым (Бейшеналиев). Качантан бери орой көз чарай, улуу-кичүү дебей элдин тобунда эргүүнү самабады беле (Бейшеналиев). Орой көз чарай дегендей, бардыгыңар мында турасыңар (Жантөшев). Орой көз чарай отурасыңар, силерди туура түшүнүп, жардам берет деп ишенем (Бердикеев)."},{"question":"Чечен деген сөздү кандай түшүнөсүз?","answer":"Сөздү ордун таап сүйлөгөн, сөзмөөр адамды айтышкан. Мисалы,Төлөн мырза \\"Баягы күнү бир кийикти атып жиберсем, ок кулагынын учу менен туягын учуна тийип, кийик аман кутулуп кетти\\"-дейт.Анда Жээренче чечен:\\"Ата балам ай, туягы менен кулагына тийсе, кийик кагынып турганда аткан экенсиң ээ\\"-деп үйүнө келгенден кийин: \\" Ата жаның чыккан балам ,эпсиз жерден калп айтып, эбине келтире албай эсим кетпедиби, мындан кийин адам болом десең,калп айтпа. Калп айтсаң өмүрүң менен ырысыңа чоң зыян келтирет\\"- деп жалгыз баласынын жанына тынчы жок, сөзүндө чындык жок, жаман чыгып калганына капаланды."},{"question":"Terdapat tiga kawan pergi mandi-manda di kolam renang. Selepas mandi, hanya dua orang yang rambutnya basah. Kenapa yang seorang tidak basah?","answer":"Ini kerana dia botak dan tidak mempunyai rambut."},{"question":"અહીં ગુજરાતી નાટક ના કલાકારો વચ્ચેની વાતો નીચે મુજબ આપેલી છે:\\"ભોળા૦-ઓ ! ધગડું ક્યાંથી આવ્યું ? કાંઈ નહિ હમણાં મિળાવી લઈએછ. (મોટેથી) અહિં ! મિયા સાહેબ ! તબીયત અચ્છી હૈં.કમા૦-મહારાજ, આપકા ગુલામ અચ્છા હૈં.ભોળા૦-નારે, મિયાં સાહેબ, અમે તમારા ગુલામ.કમા૦-હમેરા બડા નશીબ કે આપકી મુકાકાત હુઈ.ભોળા૦-નહિરે, મિયાં સાહેબ, અમરા નસીબ. (મનમાં) પૂરાં ભોગ ! ભારા છીનવી લઈ જવનો. કોઈ સ્હસ્હરાની સ્હવારી બવારીની મ્હોંકાણ પડી હોસ્હે. કમા૦-મહારાજ, અમપર મહેરબાની કરનેકા કામ આપકે હાથમેં હૈ. મહારાજ, તુમેરી પાસ એક કામમે મદદ મંગનેકુ અમ આયે હૈ.ભોળા૦-અચ્છા ચિલમ ચહીતી હૈં? બના દેતાહું, મેરા ફક્કડ દોસ્ત. જેસ્હી ઓ દીન બનાઈથી તેસ્હી. (મનમાં) આ ધગડું તો કંઈ નવી તરેહનું દેખું રે! આમના સુરજ આમ ઉગે, પણ જોગલું કે તરકડું નરમાસથી બોલે નહિ.કમા૦-મહારાજ, ગરીબકું ઉડાનેકી બાત?હરિ૦-તમારા સરખા માણસને અમે શોધતા આવિયે એમાં કંઈ નવાઈ જેવું નથી. તમારા જેવા માણસ કંઈ ઢાંક્યા રહેછ?ભોળા૦- (મનમાં) ઓહો ! કચેરીને સીધાં પાણી જોઈતાં દેખું! ભોળાભટ પાસેજ? દહાડો વળ્યો. (કમાલખાંને) અરે, મિયાંસાહેબ, તમે જાણો છો હુંતો ગરીબ મનખછું. આ વેચીને પૈસા લાવા ત્યારે જ હું રોટલા પામા.હરિ૦-વા ! મહારાજ, એમ સું બોલછ!ભોળા૦-મિયાં સાહેબ, જૂઠું નથી કહેતો. જાઓ ! બે આના આપજો. આ ભારો તો જુઓ!કમા૦-સિર મત પાકાઓ સીધી બાત કરો.ભોળા૦-મિયાં સાહેબ, તમે બધીજ મ્હોબત ભૂલી ગયાકે ?ફિકર નહિ. (પાસે જઈને) લે દોસ્ત પૈસાની તાડી પીજે જા. (પૈસો આપવા માંડે છે.) હવે સીધી બાત થઈ.હરિ૦-મહારાજ, કાંઈ કરતાં સમજો. સમજો.ભોળા૦-(ગુસ્સો બતાવી) હાંડી ધોયા, તું દબાવવા આવ્યો છ કે? બચ્ચા, કાયદો કપરો છે, કપરો છે. મોતે માર્યા જશો. આ મિયાં સાહેબ તો અમારા જુના દોસ્ત છે. ક્યું? મિયાં સચને ? ઓ દીન નદીકે કીનારે -કમા૦-બમન, મેરી સાથ એ બાત નહિ ચલેગી.ભોળા૦-ત્યારે લઈ જાઓ ભારો. દામ લેવાશે તો લઈશ.\\"આ કલાકારો ની આગળની વાતો શું હશે?","answer":"હરિ૦-મહારજ, તમે શું ને ભારો શું?ભોળા૦-(ચ્હીડીને) સીધાંપાણી જોઈતાંતાં તો જઈએની સ્હસ્હરા પટેલને ત્હાં કે વેરાગીનું ઝુંડ લખીને તેરા ધરમ તેરે દુવાર કરત. આ હું તો ચાલ્યો. આગળ લગીની હિંમત હોય તે આવી અટકાવે. હું મામલતદાર ને કલેક્ટરના બાપને ઠેઠ પહોંચાડું એવોછું.હજા૦-વૈદરાજ !વૈદરાજ ! એ માથાફોડ મુકીદો.ભોળા૦-આ કોઈ બેવકૂફ છે કે સ્હું ?કમા૦-મહારાજ મ્હેં ઈતની અરજ કરતાહું કે મ્હેરબાની કર કર સબ ઢોંગ છોડદો.હરિ૦-તમને અમે ઓળખ્યા તો ખરા, ઢોંગ હવે શું કામ કરોછો?ભોળા૦-ઓળખ્યા? હું કોણછું?હરિ૦- અમે શું નથી જાણતા ? તમે મોટા વૈદ છો. ભોળા૦-લવેછ સ્હું રે ? હું સ્હસ્હરો વૈદ કહાંથી થિયો.કમા૦-એ તો જીદ નહિ છોડેગા. મહારાજ, મ્હેં પગડી ઉતારકર કહેતા હું, કે અબ ઢોંગ છોડદોજ, નહિતો અમકુ-ક્યા ઓ તો તુમકું માલમ હૈં - ઓ કરનેકી જરૂર પડેગી.ભોળા૦-સ્હું તે જો મને માલમ હોય, તો મારા બાપના સ્હમ ! પણ એટલું તો માલમ છે, કે હું વૈદ નથી.કમા૦-ઓ ઈલાજ બિગર કુચ છુટકા નહિ હૈ.હરિ૦-કરતા હોય તે કરો, ને છાસની દહોંણી ભરો.કમા૦-ક્યું તુમ બૈદ નહિ ક્યા?ભોળા૦-ના!કમા૦-ક્યું તુમ બૈદ નહિ!ભોળા૦-ના, ને કદાપિ વૈદ હોઈશ તોપણ ત્હારું ઓસડ મારાથી નહિ થાય. પલાસ્ટાર મરાવ જા છોડ.કમા૦-(ચ્હમકીને) હા. કબુલતો જરા હુવા.હરિ૦-વૈદરાજ, ચલો, ચલો, ઓસડ કરો, કરોતો ખરા.ભોળા૦-જા, જા, હું નથી કરવાનો; કરું તો મારી જનોઈના સમ. સમજ્યા સૂઅરના સાળાઓ?"},{"question":" Waxaad sheegtaa gabadhii Alle u waxyooday","answer":" Waxay ahayd Nebi muuse hooyadii"},{"question":"Wọn ni Isaac mu nnkan ọmọkunrin Ṣeyi l’Ọta, ni ‘kinni’ ẹ ko ba ṣiṣẹ mọ","answer":"Titi di asiko ti a n kọ iroyin yii, nnkan ọmọkunrin Ṣeyi Azeez, ẹni ọdun marundinlogoji (35) to n gbe ni Ọta, nipinlẹ Ogun, ko ti i ṣiṣẹ. Niṣe lo dẹnukọlẹ ti ọkunrin naa ko si le ṣe bii ọkunrin.Ẹnikan ti wọn jọ n gbele ti wọn pe orukọ ẹ ni Isaac Adetunji ni awọn ọlọpaa sọ pe o ko ba Ṣeyi, nitori alaye ti wọn ni Ṣeyi ṣe fawọn lọjọ keji, oṣu kẹjọ, to waa fẹjọ sun ni teṣan Onipaanu ni pe jẹẹjẹ oun loun fẹẹ lọọ ra ọṣẹ iwe lọjọ naa, boun ṣe pade Isaac lọna to ni oun riran soun niyẹn.O ni Isaac sọ pe ẹnikan yoo foun (Ṣeyi) ni majele jẹ, afi boun ba le sare ṣe awọn etutu kan.Ẹyin tutu atawọn eroja mi-in ni Isaac sọ pe ki Ṣeyi lọọ ra wa kawọn sare fi ṣe iṣẹ iṣẹgun fun un, nitori bi ko ba tete ṣe bẹẹ, ewu nla ni.Eyi ni Ṣeyi loun lọọ ra kiakia, nitori oun gba iran ti Isaac ri soun gbọ. O ni boun ṣe ra ẹyin naa de ni Isaac se e lori ina pẹlu awọn nnkan mi-in, o si gbe e foun pe koun jẹ ẹ.Ṣeyi sọ pe boun ṣe jẹ asejẹ naa tan loun sun lọ fọnfọn. Asiko to sun naa ni Isaac bẹrẹ si i fi nnkan ọmọkunrin ẹ ṣere gẹgẹ bo ṣe wi, o fọwọ pa a titi tiyẹn fi da nnkan ọmọkunrin sara.Atọ to da sara naa ni Isaac fi nnkan nu, to si tọju ẹ, nigba ti Ṣeyi yoo si fi ji loju oorun, kinni ẹ ko ṣiṣẹ mọ, niṣe lo rọ bii eweko tina mu, bi ọrọ ṣe di ariwo niyẹn.Wọn fa a de teṣan ọlọpaa, awọn agbofinro si sọ pe awọn dokita lo le sọ boya nnkan ti ṣe kinni Ṣeyi ni ko fi dide.Wọn ṣayẹwo fun un lati mọ boya kinni naa ṣi wa daadaa, ṣugbọn ayẹwo oyinbo fidi ẹ mulẹ pe nnkan ọmọkunrin Ṣeyi ko ṣiṣẹ mọ, iṣoro kan ti ba a.Eyi lo fa a tawọn ọlọpaa fi tọju Isaac sahaamọ, ibẹ lo ṣi wa titi ta a fi pari akojọpọ iroyin yii.CP Edward Ajogun ti paṣẹ pe ki wọn gbe e lọ si kootu fun igbẹjọ lori ẹsun kinni onikinni ti wọn ni oun lo mu un ọhun."},{"question":"उद्यमशीलताले कसैको वित्तीय प्रक्षेपणलाई कसरी प्रभाव पार्न सक्छ?","answer":"उद्यमशीलताले आय वृद्धि र वित्तीय स्वतन्त्रताको सम्भावना प्रदान गर्दछ। यसले व्यवसायका अवसरहरू सिर्जना गर्न जोखिमहरू लिने समावेश गर्दछ, जसले व्यक्तिको वित्तीय प्रक्षेपणमा सकारात्मक प्रभाव पार्न सक्छ।"},{"question":"Он гүлүнүн бири ачыла элек","answer":"Али жаш, эч нерсени көрө элек, аркы-беркини абдан түшүнө элек, турмуштук тажырыйбасы аз.Он гүлүнүн бири ачыла элек кыз."},{"question":"வினா:முதன் முதலில் பத்மஸ்ரீ விருதை பெற்றவர் யார் ?","answer":"விடை:அன்னை தெரேசா ( 26 ஆகத்து 1910 – 5 செப்டம்பர் 1997), அல்பேனியா நாட்டைப் பூர்வீகமாகக் கொண்டவரும் இந்தியக் குடியுரிமை பெற்ற உரோமன் கத்தோலிக்க அருட்சகோதரியும் ஆவார். இவரின் இயற்பெயர் ஆக்னஸ் கோன்ஜா போஜாஜியூ ஆகும். 1950 ஆம் ஆண்டு, இந்தியாவின் கொல்கத்தாவில் பிறர் அன்பின் பணியாளர் என்ற கத்தோலிக்க துறவற சபையினை நிறுவினார். நாற்பத்தைந்து வருடங்களுக்கு மேலாக ஏழைஎளியோர்களுக்கும், நோய்வாய்ப்பட்டோருக்கும், அனாதைகளுக்கும், இறக்கும் தருவாயிலிருப்போருக்கும் தொண்டாற்றியவர் இவர். முதலில் இந்தியா முழுவதும் பின்னர் வெளிநாடுகளுக்கும் பிறர் அன்பின் பணியாளர் சபையினை நிறுவினார்.1970 ஆம் ஆண்டுக்குள் இவர் சிறந்த சமூக சேவகர் எனவும், ஏழைகளுக்கும் ஆதரவற்றோருக்கும் பரிந்து பேசுபவர் என்றும் உலகம் முழுவதும் புகழப்பட்டார். இதற்கு மேல்கம் முக்கெரிட்ஜ் என்பவரின் சம்திங்க் பியுடிபுல் ஃபார் காட் என்ற ஆவணப்படம் ஒரு முக்கிய காரணமாகும். இவர் 1979 இல் அமைதிக்கான நோபல் பரிசினையும், 1980 இல் இந்தியாவின் சிறந்த குடிமக்கள் விருதான பாரத ரத்னா விருதினையும் பெற்றார். அன்னை தெரேசாவின் பிறர் அன்பின் பணியாளர் சபை அவரது இறப்பின் போது 123 நாடுகளில் 610 தொண்டு நிறுவனங்களை இயக்கிக்கொண்டிருந்தது. இதில் எய்ட்ஸ், தொழு நோய் மற்றும் காசநோயால் பாதிக்கப்பட்டவர்களுக்கான நல்வாழ்வு மையங்கள், இலவச உணவு வழங்குமிடங்கள், குழந்தைகள் மற்றும் குடும்பத்திற்கான ஆலோசனைத் திட்டங்கள், அனாதை இல்லங்கள், பள்ளிக்கூடங்கள் ஆகியவை அடங்கும்.பல்வேறு நபர்கள், அரசுகள் மற்றும் அமைப்புகளெனப் பலர் இவரைப் புகழ்ந்து வந்தாலும், பலவிதமான விமர்சனங்களையும் இவர் சந்தித்தார். இத்தகைய விமர்சனங்கள் கிறித்தபர் ஃகிச்சின்சு, மைக்கேல் பேரன்டி, அரூப் சட்டர்ஜி போன்ற நபர்களாலும் விஸ்வ ஹிந்து பரிஷத் போன்ற அமைப்புகளாலும் சாட்டப்பட்டது. இவர்கள் அன்னை தெரேசாவின் உறுதியான கருக்கலைப்பு எதிர்ப்பு நிலையையும், ஏழ்மை தரும் ஆன்மீக மேன்மையின் மீது அவர் கொண்டிருந்த நம்பிக்கையையும், இறப்பின் வாயிலிலிருப்போருக்கு அவர் ஞானஸ்நானம் அளிக்கிறார் எனவும் குற்றம் சாட்டினர். சில செய்தி ஊடகங்கள் அவரது நல்வாழ்வு மையங்களின் மருத்துவ வசதித் தரத்தைப் பற்றி விமர்சிப்பனவாகவும், நன்கொடைப் பணம் செலவு செய்யப்படுவதின் விதத்தைப் பற்றிக் கவலை எழுப்பியும் செய்திகளை வெளியிட்டன.இவரின் இறப்புக்குப் பின் திருத்தந்தை இரண்டாம் அருள் சின்னப்பரால் முக்திபேறு அடைந்தவராக அறிவிக்கப்பட்டு கொல்கத்தாவின் அருளாளர் தெரேசா என்று பட்டம் சூட்டப்பட்டார்.1962 ல் பத்மஸ்ரீ விருது வழங்கப்படுவதற்கு கால் நூற்றாண்டுக்கு முன்பே இந்திய அரசால் அன்னை தெரேசா அடையாளங்காணப்பட்டுள்ளார். 1972-ல், பன்னாட்டு புரிந்துணர்வுக்கான ஜவகர்லால் நேரு விருது, 1980-ல் இந்தியாவின் உயரிய குடிமக்கள் விருதான பாரத ரத்னா உட்பட இந்திய உயர்விருதுகளை அடுத்த பத்தாண்டுகளில் பெற்றார்.  அவரது அதிகாரபூர்வ வாழ்க்கைச்சரித்திரம், இந்திய ஆட்சிப் பணியாளரான நவீன் சாவ்லாவால் எழுதப்பட்டு 1992இல் வெளியிடப்பட்டது"},{"question":"Waduh... palesanku tugel! Ukara ing dhuwur iku medharake rasa ...A. BungahB. KecewaC. SusahD. SenengJawaban:","answer":"Jawaban: C. Susah"},{"question":"संसारको सबैभन्दा कान्छो देश कुन हो ?","answer":"संसारको सबैभन्दा कान्छो देश दक्षिणी सुडान हो। "},{"question":"Lihatlah bagian di bawah ini dan kemudian jawab pertanyaan setelahnya dalam bahasa yang sama dengan bagian:  Passage: NASA, ESA dan CSA telah berkolaborasi di bidang teleskop sejak 1996. Partisipasi ESA dalam konstruksi dan peluncuran disetujui oleh anggotanya pada tahun 2003 dan perjanjian ditandatangani antara ESA dan NASA pada tahun 2007. Sebagai imbalan atas kemitraan penuh, perwakilan dan akses ke observatorium untuk para astronomnya, ESA menyediakan instrumen NIRSpec, Optical Bench Assembly dari instrumen MIRI, peluncur Ariane 5 ECA, dan tenaga kerja untuk mendukung operasi. CSA akan menyediakan Sensor Fine Guidance dan Near-Infrared Imager Slitless Spectrograph ditambah dengan tenaga kerja untuk mendukung operasi.  Pertanyaan: Apa yang diharapkan ESA sehingga bersedia memberikan kontribusi mereka, instrumen dan tenaga kerja?","answer":"kemitraan penuh, perwakilan dan akses ke observatorium untuk para astronomnya"},{"question":"Em que ano os navegadores portugueses chegaram ao Brasil pela primeira vez?","answer":"Em 1500."},{"question":"Ẹ je ka bẹ Pasitọ Adeboye atawọn olori ẹlẹsin to ku, ki wọn ma ba aṣa Yoruba jẹ o","answer":"Ọjọgbọn agbaye kan, Purofẹsọ Toyin Falọla, ti sọ pe gbogbo ẹni yoowu to ba fẹran aṣa ati idagbasoke ilẹ Yoruba gbọdọ dide, ki wọn bẹ Pasitọ Eunoch Adeboye ti i ṣe olori ijọ Ridiimu, ati awọn olori ẹlẹsin ṣọọṣi igbalode to ku, pẹlu awọn aṣaaju ẹsin Islam ti wọn jẹ ọmọ Yoruba, pe ki wọn ma jẹ ki aṣa ati ede Yoruba bajẹ lati ọwọ wọn, nitori bi mejeeji yii ba bajẹ, iṣoro ni yoo jẹ fun ilọsiwaju gbogbo wa. Falọla ni orilẹ-ede nla kan ni iran Yoruba, ṣugbọn bi aṣa wa ba ti bọ sọnu mọ wa lọwo, a ko le jẹ kinni kan laye.Nibi apero nla kan ti Ọjọgbọn naa ṣe lori ẹrọ ayelujara lati yunifasiti Kembiriiji (Cambridge University) niluu oyinbo lalẹ Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee, yii lo ti sọ bẹẹ, nigba to sọrọ tan ti awọn eeyan bi i leere pe bawo ni ọrọ ẹsin ko ṣe ni i di idagbasoke ilẹ Yoruba lọwọ. O ni awọn olori ẹlẹsin wọnyi ko ṣee ba ja, afi ka bẹ wọn, ka si tubọ ṣalaye fun wọn, ki wọn mọ iyatọ laarin aṣa ati ẹsin, ki wọn yee pe ẹni to ba n ṣe nnkan abalaye wọn ni abọriṣa, nitori pe ko ba ilana ẹsin tiwọn mu.Ọjọgbọn Falọla ni ọtọ ni iṣẹṣe, ọtọ ni aṣa, bẹẹ ọtọ ni ẹsin, ko si si orilẹ-ede aye tabi iran kan ti ko ni aṣa tiwọn, iran yoowu to ba si ti sọ aṣa ati ohun abalaye rẹ nu, iru iran bẹẹ ko le gberi lawujọ awọn orilẹ-ede aye. O ni ohun ti awọn aṣaaju ẹsin wọnyi fi n kọ awọn eeyan wọn nipa aṣa Yoruba ko ba ilana eto ẹsin to ti wa nilẹ tiwa mu, nitori ko si agboole kan laarin awọn Yoruba teeyan ko ni i ri Musulumi ati Kristẹni, pẹlu awọn ẹlẹsin abalaye, ti gbogbo wọn yoo si maa gbe ni igbe-alaafia. Bo ti wa lati ọjọ alaye ti da a niyẹn.Ọkunrin Ọjọgbọn yii to n sọrọ lori iwe itan Yoruba nla kan ti wọn ṣẹṣẹ dawọ ṣe niluu oyinbo nibẹ ni awọn ijọba ati eeyan ni orilẹ-ede Cuba, Brazil ati awọn ibomi-in bẹẹ ti mu aṣa ati iṣe Yoruba wọ inu awọn ẹsin igbalode tiwọn lọhun-un, wọn si ti fi idi awọn nnkan wọnyi mulẹ debi pe aṣa ati awọn ohun abalaye Yoruba ko le parun lọdọ wọn. O ni ki gbogbo awọn ti wọn nifẹẹ Yoruba bẹ awọn olori ẹlesin wọnyi, ki wọn ma sọ aṣa Yoruba di nnkan ibọriṣa lasan, ko ma di ohun ti gbogbo awọn ọmọde ati ọdọ yoo maa sa nidii awọn nnkan adayeba wa."},{"question":"Wọn tun ti kọ lu Ojodu Berger, ọfiisi BRT, VIO ati FRSC","answer":"Bi wọn ti ṣe n jo garaaji BRT ni Ojodu Berger, bẹẹ naa ni wọn ti kọ lu ọfiisi ileeṣẹ ti wọn ti n gba iwe irinna, VIO atawọn ẹṣọ ojupopo, FRSC.Niṣe ni wahala to n ṣẹlẹ lọwọlọwọ kaakiri ipinlẹ Eko tubọ n fẹju si i."},{"question":"Kompletuhin ang ugnayan.dilaw : pinya :: ____:  presa","answer":"Magkaugnaya ang \\"dilaw\\" at \\"pinya\\" dahil kulay dilaw ang mga pinya. Kung gayon, ang katumbas naman para sa presa ay \\"pula\\"."},{"question":"'జీవితంలో ఎప్పుడూ ఎద్దుని కనీసం దగ్గరగా చూడని చాలామంది.. తరతరాలుగా పశువులతో మమేకమై జీవిస్తున్న మాకు వాటి సంరక్షణ గురించి చెప్పడం సరికాదు' అంటారు ముత్తురాజ్ అనే ఓ రైతు. ఎవరి వాదన వారిదన్నట్టు, జల్లికట్టుపై నిషేధాన్ని అమలు చేయాలని 'పెటా' కోరుతోంది. 'జంతువులపై హింస, మనుషుల ప్రాణంపై నిర్లక్ష్య ధోరణి జల్లికట్టులో కనిపిస్తాయి' అంటారు పెటా ఇండియా పబ్లిక్ పాలసీ హెడ్ నికుంజ్ శర్మ. దానికి సాక్ష్యంగా గతంలో పెటా తీసిన వీడియో గురించి ఆయన ప్రస్తావిస్తారు. 'పిల్లలపై హింసను ఎలా సహించకూడదో, అలాన... Write the rest of the article:","answer":"ొదలయ్యాయి. కర్ణాటకలో గేదెల పరుగు పందేలు ఊపందుకున్నాయి. మహారాష్ట్ర కూడా ఎడ్లబండి పరుగు పందేలపై ఉన్న నిషేధాన్నిప్రభుత్వం ఎత్తి వేసింది.'జంతువులకు హాని కలిగించే చాలా సంప్రదాయాలకు ద్వారాలు తెరుచుకున్నాయి. ఈ అంశాలపై అవగాహన కలిగించే భారీ కార్యక్రమాన్ని త్వరలో మొదలు పెట్టాలనుకుంటున్నాం' అంటారు చిన్ని కృష్ణ.ఏదేమైనా ఇతరుల మద్దతు కొరవడడంతో, జంతు ప్రేమికులకు తమ పనిని గోప్యంగా చేసుకోక తప్పట్లేదు. మా ఇతర కథనాలు(బీబీసీ తెలుగును ఫేస్‌బుక్, ఇన్‌స్టాగ్రామ్‌, ట్విటర్‌లో ఫాలో అవ్వండి.  యూట్యూబ్‌లో సబ్‌స్క్రైబ్ చేయండి)"},{"question":"Escreva uma continuação para esse parágrafo- Tanto no romance quanto no filme, o nome da família do casal é Rose, e o título é uma alusão às batalhas entre as Casas de York e Lencastre","answer":"(Guerra Civil Inglesa) durante o final da Idade Média. Nas regiões de língua alemã, desde o lançamento do filme, a palavra \\"Rosenkrieg\\" (que significa \\"Guerra dos Roses\\") veio a denotar uma luta tão amarga por posses materiais, como descrito no filme (e muitas vezes também pela custódia dos filhos) com a maioria dos falantes completamente inconscientes das origens da palavra."},{"question":"Nola eragin du e-merkataritzaren goraldia ohiko denda fisikoen negozioetan?","answer":"E-merkataritzak lehiaketa globala, erosketa 24/7 eta prezio baxuagoak sartu ditu. Denda tradizionalak trafiko gutxituaren erronkak baina ere aukerak integra dezakete erosketa online eta offline."},{"question":"ಮೂಲಕ. ಬಿಯಾಂಕಾ ಲಂಡನ್. ಪ್ರಕಟಣೆ:. 06:20 EST, 8 ಅಕ್ಟೋಬರ್ 2013.. ನವೀಕರಿಸಲಾಗಿದೆ:. 08:04 EST, 10 ಅಕ್ಟೋಬರ್ 2013. ಬೋಳುತನದ ವಿರುದ್ಧದ ಹೋರಾಟವು ಬಾಹ್ಯಾಕಾಶ ಯುಗದ ಹೊಸ ಆಯುಧವನ್ನು ಹೊಂದಿದೆ, ಇದು ಹೈಟೆಕ್ ಹೆಲ್ಮೆಟ್ ರೂಪದಲ್ಲಿ ಲೇಸರ್ಗಳ ಸಹಾಯದಿಂದ ನಿಮ್ಮ ಕೂದಲನ್ನು ಮತ್ತೆ ಬೆಳೆಯಲು ಸಹಾಯ ಮಾಡುತ್ತದೆ ಎಂದು ಭರವಸೆ ನೀಡುತ್ತದೆ. ಐಗ್ರೋವ್ ಹೇರ್ ಗ್ರೋತ್ ಸಿಸ್ಟಮ್ ಕಡಿಮೆ ಮಟ್ಟದ ಲೇಸರ್ ಥೆರಪಿ (ಎಲ್ಎಲ್ ಟಿ) ಅನ್ನು ಬಳಸುತ್ತದೆ - 51 ಕಡಿಮೆ ಮಟ್ಟದ ಕೆಂಪು ಲೇಸರ್ ಮತ್ತು ಎಲ್ಇಡಿ ದೀಪಗಳು, ಇದು ತಯಾರಕರು ಕೂದಲಿನ ಕಿರುಚೀಲಗಳಲ್ಲಿನ ಕೋಶಗಳನ್ನು 'ಮರು-ಶಕ್ತಿ ತುಂಬಲು' ಮತ್ತು ಬಲಪಡಿಸಲು ಸಹಾಯ ಮಾಡುತ್ತದೆ ಎಂದು ಹೇಳುತ್ತಾರೆ. ವೀಡಿಯೊಗಾಗಿ ಕೆಳಗೆ ಸ್ಕ್ರಾಲ್ ಮಾಡಿ. ಬಾಹ್ಯಾಕಾಶ ಯುಗದ ತಂತ್ರಜ್ಞಾನ: ಐಗ್ರೋವ್ ಹೇರ್ ಗ್ರೋತ್ ಸಿಸ್ಟಮ್ ಕಡಿಮೆ ಮಟ್ಟದ ಲೇಸರ್ ಥೆರಪಿ (ಎಲ್ಎಲ್ಟಿ) ಯನ್ನು ಬಳಸುತ್ತದೆ ಮತ್ತು ಒಂಬತ್ತು ತಿಂಗಳಲ್ಲಿ ನಿಮಗೆ ಹೊಸ ತಲೆಯ ಕೂದಲನ್ನು ನೀಡುತ್ತದೆ ಎಂದು ಭರವಸೆ ನೀಡುತ್ತದೆ. ಕೂದಲು ಕೊಳೆಯುವುದು ಮತ್ತು ಆನುವಂಶಿಕ ಬೋಳು, ಹಾಗೆಯೇ ಇತರ ಸಂಬಂಧಿತ ಕೂದಲು ನಷ್ಟ ಪರಿಸ್ಥಿತಿಗಳಿಂದ ಬಳಲುತ್ತಿರುವ ಜನರಿಗೆ ಹೆಲ್ಮೆಟ್ ಗಮನಾರ್ಹವಾದ ಕೂದಲು ಮರು-ಬೆಳವಣಿಗೆಯನ್ನು ನೀಡುವ ಭರವಸೆ ನೀಡುತ್ತದೆ. ಇದನ್ನು 25 ನಿಮಿಷಗಳ ಕಾಲ ಧರಿಸಬೇಕು ಮತ್ತು ಹೆಡ್ಫೋನ್ಗಳು ಮತ್ತು ಅಂತರ್ನಿರ್ಮಿತ ಐಪಾಡ್ ಮತ್ತು ಎಂಪಿ 3 ಇಂಟರ್ಫೇಸ್ನೊಂದಿಗೆ ಸಹ ಬರುತ್ತದೆ, ಇದು ನಿಮಗೆ ಸಮಯವನ್ನು ಕಳೆಯಲು ಸಹಾಯ ಮಾಡುತ್ತದೆ. ಸರಾಸರಿ ವ್ಯಕ್ತಿಯು iGrow ಅನ್ನು ಬಳಸುವಾಗ 6 ರಿಂದ 8 ವಾರಗಳ ನಂತರ ಕಡಿಮೆ ಕೂದಲು ಉದುರುವಿಕೆ ಮತ್ತು 9 ತಿಂಗಳ ನಂತರ ಪೂರ್ಣ ಪರಿಣಾಮವನ್ನು ಕಾಣಲು ಪ್ರಾರಂಭವಾಗುತ್ತದೆ. ಐಗ್ರೋವ್ ಯಾವುದೇ ಅಡ್ಡಪರಿಣಾಮಗಳನ್ನು ಹೊಂದಿಲ್ಲ ಎಂದು ಹೇಳುತ್ತದೆ, ಆದರೆ ತಾಜಾ ಕೂದಲಿನ ತಲೆ ಅಗ್ಗವಾಗಿ ಬರುವುದಿಲ್ಲ - ಐಗ್ರೋವ್ನ ಬೆಲೆ £ 665 ಆಗಿದೆ. ಆದಾಗ್ಯೂ, ಪೂರ್ಣ ಕೂದಲು ಕಸಿ ಮಾಡುವುದಕ್ಕಿಂತ ಇದು ಹೆಚ್ಚು ಸಮಂಜಸವಾಗಿ ತೋರುತ್ತದೆ, ಇದು £4,000 - £30,000 ನಡುವೆ ವೆಚ್ಚವಾಗಬಹುದು. ಮೇನ್ ಆಕರ್ಷಣೆ: ವೇಯ್ನ್ ರೂನಿ ಪ್ರಸಿದ್ಧವಾಗಿ 2011 ರಲ್ಲಿ ಕೂದಲು ಕಸಿ ಮಾಡಿಸಿಕೊಂಡರು, ನಂತರ ಈ ವರ್ಷದ ಜೂನ್ನಲ್ಲಿ ಎರಡನೇ ಕಾರ್ಯವಿಧಾನ. ಭವಿಷ್ಯದ ಸಾಧನದ ಬಗ್ಗೆ ಮಾತನಾಡುತ್ತಾ, ದಿ ಪ್ರೈವೇಟ್ ಕ್ಲಿನಿಕ್ ಆಫ್ ಹಾರ್ಲೆ ಸ್ಟ್ರೀಟ್ ನ ಕೂದಲು ಕಸಿ ಶಸ್ತ್ರಚಿಕಿತ್ಸಕ ಡಾ. ಥೋಮಿ ಕುರೆಮದಾ-ಜಿಯೋಗ ಹೇಳಿದರು: 'ಲೋ ಲೆವೆಲ್ ಲೇಸರ್ ಥೆರಪಿ (ಎಲ್ ಎಲ್ ಎಲ್ ಟಿ) ಸುರಕ್ಷಿತವಾದ ಬೆಳಕಿನ ಚಿಕಿತ್ಸೆಯಾಗಿದ್ದು, ಪುರುಷರು ಮತ್ತು ಮಹಿಳೆಯರಲ್ಲಿ ಸಾಮಾನ್ಯವಾದ ಕೂದಲು ಉದುರುವಿಕೆಯ ಆನುವಂಶಿಕ ಸ್ವರೂಪಗಳಿಗೆ ಸಂಭವನೀಯ ಪರಿಹಾರವಾಗಿ ದೀರ್ಘಕಾಲದವರೆಗೆ ಪರಿಶೋಧಿಸಲಾಗಿದೆ, ಉದಾಹರಣೆಗೆ ಆಂಡ್ರೊಜೆನೆಟಿಕ್ ಅಲೋಪೆಸಿಯಾ ಅಥವಾ ಮಾದರಿ ಬೋಳುತನ. 'ಇದು ಪುರುಷರು ಮತ್ತು ಮಹಿಳೆಯರಿಗೆ ಉದ್ದೇಶಿಸಲಾಗಿದೆ, ಅವರ ಕೂದಲು ತೆಳುವಾಗುವುದು ಅಥವಾ ಆನುವಂಶಿಕ ಸ್ಥಿತಿಯಿಂದ ಉಂಟಾಗುವ ಮಾದರಿ ಬೋಳು, ಮತ್ತು ಯಾವುದೇ ರೀತಿಯ ಕೂದಲು ಉದುರುವಿಕೆಯಿಂದಲ್ಲ. ಕೂದಲು ಇಂದು: ಸರಾಸರಿ ವ್ಯಕ್ತಿಯು ಆರು ರಿಂದ ಎಂಟು ವಾರಗಳ ನಂತರ ಕೂದಲು ಉದುರುವಿಕೆಯನ್ನು ನಿಧಾನಗೊಳಿಸಲು ಪ್ರಾರಂಭಿಸುತ್ತಾನೆ ಮತ್ತು ಕೆಲವು...ಮೇಲಿನ ಲೇಖನವನ್ನು ಸಾರಾಂಶಗೊಳಿಸಿ","answer":"ಐ ಗ್ರೋ ಹೇರ್ ಗ್ರೋತ್ ಸಿಸ್ಟಮ್ ಬೆಲೆ 665 ಪೌಂಡ್. ಕೂದಲಿನ ಕಿರುಚೀಲಗಳಲ್ಲಿನ ಜೀವಕೋಶಗಳನ್ನು 'ಪುನಃ ಶಕ್ತಿಯನ್ನು' ನೀಡಲು ಹೇಳಿಕೊಳ್ಳುತ್ತದೆ. ಕೆಲಸ ಮಾಡಲು ಒಂಬತ್ತು ತಿಂಗಳುಗಳನ್ನು ತೆಗೆದುಕೊಳ್ಳುತ್ತದೆ ಆದರೆ ಫಲಿತಾಂಶಗಳನ್ನು 6 ವಾರಗಳಲ್ಲಿ ಕಾಣಬಹುದು ಎಂದು ವರದಿಯಾಗಿದೆ."},{"question":"ਇਕ ਵਿਆਹ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ ? ਇਸਦੇ ਕਾਰਨਾਂ, ਲਾਭਾਂ ਅਤੇ ਹਾਨੀਆਂ ਦਾ ਵਰਣਨ ਕਰੋ ।","answer":"ਸਾਡੇ ਸਮਾਜ ਵਿੱਚ ਅਤੇ ਹੋਰ ਬਹੁਤ ਸਾਰੇ ਸਮਾਜਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਪ੍ਰਚੱਲਿਤ ਵਿਆਹ ਦੀ ਕਿਸਮ ਹੈ ਇੱਕ ਵਿਆਹ । ਜਦੋਂ ਇੱਕ ਔਰਤ ਨਾਲ ਇੱਕ ਹੀ ਆਦਮੀ ਵਿਆਹ ਕਰਵਾਉਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਤਾਂ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਇੱਕ ਵਿਆਹ ਕਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ । ਜਦੋਂ ਤਕ ਆਦਮੀ ਜਾਂ ਔਰਤ ਜਿਉਂਦੇ ਹਨ ਉਸ ਸਮੇਂ ਤਕ ਉਹ ਦੂਜਾ ਵਿਆਹ ਨਹੀਂ ਕਰਵਾ ਸਕਦੇ । ਤਲਾਕ ਜਾਂ ਮੌਤ ਦੀ ਸੂਰਤ ਵਿੱਚ ਹੀ ਉਹ ਦੂਜਾ ਵਿਆਹ ਕਰਵਾ ਸਕਦੇ ਹਨ । ਹੈਮਿਲਟਨ ਦੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ, “ਇੱਕ ਵਿਆਹ, ਵਿਆਹ ਦੀ ਉਹ ਕਿਸਮ ਹੈ ਜਿਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਕੋਈ ਵੀ ਆਦਮੀ ਇੱਕ ਤੋਂ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਔਰਤਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਇੱਕ ਹੀ ਸਮੇਂ ਵਿਆਹ ਸੰਬੰਧ ਸਥਾਪਿਤ ਨਹੀਂ ਕਰ ਸਕਦਾ ।” ਇਸ ਪਰਿਭਾਸ਼ਾ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵੀ ਇੱਕ ਆਦਮੀ ਇੱਕ ਔਰਤ ਨਾਲ ਅਤੇ ਇੱਕ ਔਰਤ ਇੱਕ ਸਮੇਂ ਇੱਕ ਆਦਮੀ ਨਾਲ ਵਿਆਹ ਕਰਵਾ ਸਕਦੀ ਹੈ ।ਅੱਜ-ਕਲ੍ਹ ਦੇ ਆਧੁਨਿਕ ਅਤੇ ਜਟਿਲ ਸਮਾਜਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਇੱਕ ਵਿਆਹ ਦੀ ਕਿਸਮ ਪਾਈ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ । ਚਾਹੇ ਪੁਰਾਣੇ ਸਮੇਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਵੀ ਅਤੇ ਅੱਜ ਵੀ ਕੁੱਝ ਕਬੀਲਿਆਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਬਹੁ ਵਿਆਹ ਦੀ ਪ੍ਰਥਾ ਚਲਦੀ ਰਹੀ ਹੈ ਪਰ ਇੱਕ ਵਿਆਹ ਦੀ ਪ੍ਰਥਾ ਹਰ ਸਮਾਜ ਵਿੱਚ ਪਾਈ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਰਹੀ ਹੈ । ਭਾਰਤ ਵਿੱਚ ਸਰਕਾਰ ਨੇ ਵੀ ਬਹੁ-ਵਿਆਹ ਖ਼ਤਮ ਕਰ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਹੈ । 1955 ਦੇ ਹਿੰਦੂ ਮੈਰਿਜ ਐਕਟ ਦੇ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਭਾਰਤ ਸਰਕਾਰ ਨੇ ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਖ਼ਤਮ ਕਰ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਇੱਕ ਵਿਆਹ ਦੀ ਪ੍ਰਵਾਨਗੀ ਦਿੱਤੀ ਹੈ । ਆਪਣੇ ਜੀਵਨ ਸਾਥੀ ਦੇ ਮੌਜੂਦ ਹੁੰਦੇ ਹੋਏ, ਜੇਕਰ ਤਲਾਕ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੋਇਆ ਹੈ, ਕੋਈ ਵੀ ਦੂਜਾ ਵਿਆਹ ਨਹੀਂ ਕਰਵਾ ਸਕਦਾ । ਜੇਕਰ ਉਹ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ ਤਾਂ ਉਹ ਗੈਰ-ਕਾਨੂੰਨੀ ਸਮਝਿਆ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਪਿਡੀਗੰਟਨ (Piddington) ਦੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ, “ਇਕ ਵਿਆਹ, ਵਿਆਹ ਦਾ ਉਹ ਸਰੂਪ ਹੈ ਜਿਸਦੇ ਦੁਆਰਾ ਕੋਈ ਵੀ ਵਿਅਕਤੀ ਇਕ ਤੋਂ ਵੱਧ ਔਰਤਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਇਕ ਹੀ ਸਮੇਂ ਵਿਚ ਵਿਆਹਕ ਸੰਬੰਧ ਸਥਾਪਿਤ ਨਹੀਂ ਕਰ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ ।’’ਮੈਲਿਨੈਵਸਕੀ (Malinowski) ਦੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ, “ਇਕ ਵਿਆਹ ਹੀ ਵਿਆਹ ਦਾ ਅਸਲੀ ਪ੍ਰਕਾਰ ਹੈ, ਜੋ ਪਾਇਆ ਜਾ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਪਾਇਆ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਰਹੇਗਾ ।”ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਪਰਿਭਾਸ਼ਾਵਾਂ ਦੇ ਆਧਾਰ ਉੱਤੇ ਅਸੀਂ ਕਹਿ ਸਕਦੇ ਹਾਂ ਕਿ ਜਦੋਂ ਵਿਅਕਤੀ ਇਕ ਸਮੇਂ ਵਿਚ ਇਕ ਹੀ ਔਰਤ ਦੇ ਨਾਲ ਵਿਆਹ ਕਰਵਾਉਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਤਾਂ ਉਸਨੂੰ ਇਕ ਵਿਆਹ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ । ਕਾਨੂੰਨਨ ਕਿਸੇ ਵੀ ਵਿਅਕਤੀ ਨੂੰ ਇਕ ਹੀ ਸਮੇਂ ਵਿਚ ਇਕ ਤੋਂ ਵੱਧ ਪਤਨੀਆਂ ਰੱਖਣ ਦੀ ਆਗਿਆ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੈ । ਜੇਕਰ ਉਹ ਇਕ ਤੋਂ ਵੱਧ ਵਿਆਹ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ ਤਾਂ ਉਹ ਗੈਰ ਕਾਨੂੰਨੀ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਉਸਨੂੰ ਰਾਜ ਦੇ ਕਾਨੂੰਨ ਦੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵੰਡ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਜਾਵੇਗਾ । ਚਾਹੇ ਮੁਸਲਮਾਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਇਕ ਵਿਆਹ ਦੇ ਸੰਕਲਪ ਨੂੰ ਵੱਧ ਮਹੱਤਵ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਇਕ ਵਿਆਹ ਨੂੰ ਅਸਥਾਈ ਕਰਾਰ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਹੈ । ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਬਾਲ ਵਿਆਹ ਦੀ ਪ੍ਰਥਾ ਪ੍ਰਚਲਿਤ ਹੈ । ਮੁਸਲਮਾਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਚਾਰ ਵਿਆਹ ਤਕ ਕਰਵਾ ਸਕਦੇ ਹਨ ਪਰ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਛੱਡ ਕੇ ਬਾਕੀ ਸਾਰੇ ਲੋਕ ਸਿਰਫ ਇਕ ਹੀ ਵਿਆਹ ਕਰਵਾ ਸਕਦੇ ਹਨ ।ਇਕ ਵਿਆਹ ਦੇ ਕਾਰਨ (Causes of Monogamy)1. ਆਦਮੀਆਂ ਅਤੇ ਔਰਤਾਂ ਦੀ ਸਮਾਨ ਗਿਣਤੀ (Same Population of males and females) – ਜੇਕਰ ਅਸੀਂ ਜਨਸੰਖਿਆ ਦੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵੇਖੀਏ ਤਾਂ ਮਰਦਾਂ ਅਤੇ ਔਰਤਾਂ ਦੀ ਜਨਸੰਖਿਆ ਬਰਾਬਰ ਮੰਨੀ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ । ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਇਸ ਦੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਇੱਕ ਵਿਆਹ ਜ਼ਰੂਰੀ ਹੈ । ਜੇਕਰ ਇੱਕ ਵਿਆਹ ਦੀ ਥਾਂ ਬਹੁ-ਵਿਆਹ ਹੋ ਜਾਵੇ ਤਾਂ ਕੁਝ ਲੋਕਾਂ ਦੇ ਬਹੁ-ਵਿਆਹ ਹੋ ਜਾਣਗੇ ਅਤੇ ਕੁੱਝ ਲੋਕ ਕੁਆਰੇ ਹੀ ਰਹਿ ਜਾਣਗੇ । ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਅਨੁਪਾਤ ਦੇ ਬਰਾਬਰ ਹੋਣ ਕਰਕੇ ਇੱਕ ਵਿਆਹ ਦੀ ਲੋੜ ਪੈਂਦੀ ਹੈ ।2. ਏਕਾਧਿਕਾਰ ਅਤੇ ਈਰਖਾ (Monopoly and Jealousy) – ਮੁੱਢਲੇ ਸਮਾਜਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਇੱਕ ਵਿਆਹ ਪ੍ਰਚੱਲਿਤ ਸੀ ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਆਦਮੀ ਔਰਤ ਉੱਤੇ ਸੰਪੱਤੀ ਵਾਂਗ ਪੂਰਨ ਅਧਿਕਾਰ ਰੱਖਣਾ ਚਾਹੁੰਦਾ ਸੀ । ਆਦਮੀ ਔਰਤ ਤੋਂ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਤਾਕਤਵਰ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਉਹ ਔਰਤ ਉੱਤੇ ਆਪਣਾ ਰੋਆਬ ਜਮਾਉਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਈਰਖਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਵੀ ਉਹ ਆਪਣੀ ਔਰਤ ਨੂੰ ਦੂਜੇ ਆਦਮੀ ਕੋਲ ਜਾਣ ਨਹੀਂ ਦਿੰਦਾ । ਸ਼ਕਤੀਸ਼ਾਲੀ ਹੋਣ ਕਰਕੇ ਵਿਅਕਤੀ ਔਰਤ ਉੱਤੇ ਆਪਣਾ ਅਧਿਕਾਰ ਜਮਾਉਣ ਵਿੱਚ ਸਫਲ ਹੋਇਆ ਅਤੇ ਹੌਲੀ-ਹੌਲੀ ਸਮੇਂ ਦੇ ਬੀਤਣ ਨਾਲ ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਸਮਾਜ ਦੀ ਪ੍ਰਵਾਨਗੀ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਹੋ ਗਈ ।3. ਆਰਥਿਕ ਸਹਿਯੋਗ (Economic Cooperation) – ਪੁਰਾਣੇ ਜ਼ਮਾਨੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਕਬੀਲੇ ਹੁੰਦੇ ਸਨ ਅਤੇ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਕਬੀਲਿਆਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਇਹ ਰਿਵਾਜ ਪ੍ਰਚਲਿਤ ਸੀ ਕਿ ਵਿਅਕਤੀ ਨੂੰ ਲੜਕੀ ਦੇ ਪਿਤਾ ਨੂੰ ਕੰਨਿਆ ਮੁੱਲ ਦੇਣਾ ਪਵੇਗਾ ਜੋ ਕਿ ਬਹੁਤ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਸੀ । ਇਸ ਮੁੱਲ ਦੇ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਹੋਣ ਕਰਕੇ ਇੱਕ ਵਿਆਹ ਪ੍ਰਚਲਿਤ ਹੋਇਆ ਹੋਵੇਗਾ । ਇਸ ਦੇ ਨਾਲ-ਨਾਲ ਆਦਮੀ ਅਤੇ ਔਰਤ ਦੇ ਸਹਿਯੋਗ ਨਾਲ ਹੀ ਜੀਵਨ ਚਲਦਾ ਹੈ ਚਾਹੇ ਉਹ ਕਿਸੇ ਪ੍ਰਕਾਰ ਦਾ ਸਹਿਯੋਗ ਹੀ ਕਿਉਂ ਨਾ ਹੋਵੇ | ਸਹਿਯੋਗ ਖ਼ਾਸ ਤੌਰ ‘ਤੇ ਆਰਥਿਕ ਵੇਖਿਆ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ । ਜੇਕਰ ਦੋ ਵਿਆਹ ਹੋਣਗੇ ਤਾਂ ਆਪਣੀ ਕਮਾਈ ਦੋ ਭਾਗਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਵੰਡਣੀ ਪਵੇਗੀ ਜਿਸ ਕਰਕੇ ਵਿਅਕਤੀ ਆਪ ਮੁਸ਼ਕਿਲ ਵਿੱਚ ਫਸ ਜਾਵੇਗਾ । ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਆਰਥਿਕਤਾ ਵੀ ਇੱਕ ਵਿਆਹ ਦਾ ਕਾਰਨ ਬਣੀ ।4. ਸਮਾਜਿਕ ਪ੍ਰਗਤੀ (Social Progress) – ਅੱਜ-ਕੱਲ੍ਹ ਦੇ ਸਮੇਂ ਵਿਚ ਸਾਰੇ ਸਮਾਜਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਇਕ ਵਿਆਹ ਦੀ ਪ੍ਰਥਾ ਪ੍ਰਚਲਿਤ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਇਸ ਵਿਆਹ ਦੇ ਕਾਰਨ ਹੀ ਸਮਾਜ ਪ੍ਰਤੀ ਦੇ ਵੱਲ ਵੱਧਿਆ ਹੈ । ਜਿਸ ਕਿਸੇ ਵੀ ਸਮਾਜ ਵਿਚ ਇਕ ਵਿਆਹ ਦੀ ਪ੍ਰਥਾ ਪਾਈ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ ਉੱਥੇ ਸਮਾਜਕ ਪ੍ਰਤੀ ਵੱਧ ਹੋਈ ਹੈ । ਇਸ ਲਈ ਵੀ ਇਕ ਵਿਆਹ ਦੀ ਪ੍ਰਥਾ ਨੂੰ ਸਮਾਜ ਦੇ ਲਈ ਜ਼ਰੂਰੀ ਸਮਝਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ ।ਇਕ ਵਿਆਹ ਦੇ ਲਾਭ (Merits of Monogamy)1. ਸਥਿਰਤਾ (Stability) – ਇੱਕ ਵਿਆਹ ਵਾਲੇ ਪਰਿਵਾਰਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਸਥਿਰਤਾ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਪਤੀ-ਪਤਨੀ ਆਪਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਹਰ ਗੱਲ ਸਾਂਝੀ ਕਰ ਸਕਦੇ ਹਨ । ਦੋਵੇਂ ਮਿਲ ਕੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਜੀਵਨ ਨੂੰ ਸਹੀ ਢੰਗ ਨਾਲ ਚਲਾ ਸਕਦੇ ਹਨ । ਇਸਦੇ ਨਾਲ ਹੀ ਨਾਲ ਦੋਹਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਲੜਾਈ ਝਗੜਾ ਘੱਟ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਭਾਵਨਾਤਮਕ ਰਿਸ਼ਤਾ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ । ਬਹੁਵਿਆਹ ਦੀ ਸੂਰਤ ਵਿੱਚ ਹਮੇਸ਼ਾ ਲੜਾਈ ਝਗੜਾ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਆਪਣੇਪਨ ਦੀ ਭਾਵਨਾ ਘੱਟ ਹੀ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ । ਇੱਕ ਵਿਆਹ ਵਿੱਚ ਆਪਣੇਪਨ ਦੀ ਭਾਵਨਾ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ । ਬਹੁ-ਵਿਆਹ ਵਿੱਚ ਮੈਂਬਰਾਂ ਦੀ ਗਿਣਤੀ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ ਜਿਸ ਕਰਕੇ ਲੜਾਈ ਝਗੜੇ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਹੁੰਦੇ ਹਨ ਅਤੇ ਸੰਬੰਧ ਗੁੜੇ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੁੰਦੇ ਅਤੇ ਰਸਮੀ ਹੁੰਦੇ ਹਨ ।2. ਬੱਚਿਆਂ ਦੀ ਸਹੀ ਦੇਖ-ਭਾਲ (Good uppringing of children) – ਇੱਕ ਵਿਆਹ ਵਾਲੇ ਪਰਿਵਾਰਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਬੱਚਿਆਂ ਦੀ ਦੇਖ-ਭਾਲ ਸਹੀ ਹੋ ਸਕਦੀ ਹੈ ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਪਤੀ-ਪਤਨੀ ਦੀ ਆਪਣੇ ਬੱਚਿਆਂ ਪਤੀ ਇੱਕੋ ਜਿਹੀ ਆਪਣੇਪਨ ਦੀ ਗੁੜੀ ਭਾਵਨਾ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਉਹ ਆਪਣੇ ਬੱਚਿਆਂ ਦੇ ਸਹੀ ਧਿਆਨ ਅਤੇ ਲੋੜਾਂ ਦਾ ਧਿਆਨ ਰੱਖਦੇ ਹਨ । ਬੱਚੇ ਦੇ ਹਰ ਪੱਖ ਪੜਾਈ, ਸਿਹਤ ਆਦਿ ਦਾ ਚੰਗੀ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਧਿਆਨ ਰੱਖਿਆ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ । ਬਹੁ-ਵਿਆਹੀ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਬੱਚੇ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਹੁੰਦੇ ਹਨ ਇਸ ਲਈ ਸਾਰੇ ਬੱਚਿਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਸਹੀ ਤਰੀਕੇ ਨਾਲ ਪਿਆਰ ਨਹੀਂ ਮਿਲਦਾ ।3. ਸੰਪੱਤੀ ਦੀ ਸਹੀ ਵੰਡ (Correct distribution of wealth) – ਇੱਕ ਵਿਆਹ ਵਿੱਚ ਸੰਪੱਤੀ ਦੀ ਸਹੀ ਵੰਡ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਇਹ ਪਤਾ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਜੇਕਰ ਦੋ ਬੱਚੇ ਹਨ ਤਾਂ ਦੋਹਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਬਰਾਬਰ ਜਾਇਦਾਦ ਵੰਡੀ ਜਾਵੇਗੀ ਅਤੇ ਜੇਕਰ ਬਹੁਵਿਆਹ ਹੋਵੇਗਾ ਤਾਂ ਹਰ ਕੋਈ ਪਤੀ ਜਾਂ ਪਤਨੀ ਆਪਣੇ ਵੱਲ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਸੰਪੱਤੀ ਕਰਨ ਦੀ ਕੋਸ਼ਿਸ਼ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ ਜਿਸ ਨਾਲ ਸੰਪੱਤੀ ਦਾ ਸਹੀ ਵਿਤਰਣ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੋ ਪਾਂਦਾ । ਇਕ ਵਿਆਹ ਵਿੱਚ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਦਾ ਮੁਖੀ ਚਾਹੇ ਮਾਤਾ ਹੋਵੇ ਜਾਂ ਪਿਤਾ ਅਜਿਹਾ ਕੋਈ ਵਿਵਾਦ ਪੈਦਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਅਤੇ ਸੰਪੱਤੀ ਦੀ ਵੰਡ ਸਹੀ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ ।4. ਚੰਗਾ ਜੀਵਨ ਪੱਧਰ (Good status of living) – ਅੱਜ-ਕਲ੍ਹ ਮਹਿੰਗਾਈ ਕਾਫ਼ੀ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਇਸ ਮਹਿੰਗਾਈ ਦੇ ਜ਼ਮਾਨੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਇੱਕ ਵਿਆਹ ਹੀ ਠੀਕ ਹੈ ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਅੱਜ-ਕਲ ਇੱਕ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਪਾਲਣਾ ਮੁਸ਼ਕਿਲ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ਵਿਅਕਤੀ ਦੋ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਕਿਵੇਂ ਪਾਲੇਗਾ ? ਅੱਜ-ਕਲ੍ਹ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਦੀਆਂ ਜ਼ਰੂਰਤਾਂ ਇੰਨੀਆਂ ਵੱਧ ਗਈਆਂ ਹਨ ਕਿ ਬਹੁ-ਵਿਆਹੀ ਪਰਿਵਾਰਾਂ ਦਾ ਗੁਜ਼ਾਰਾ ਲਗਪਗ ਨਾਮੁਮਕਿਨ ਹੈ । ਜੇਕਰ ਇਹ ਹੋਣ ਤਾਂ ਆਰਥਿਕ ਸੰਕਟ ਵੱਧ ਜਾਵੇਗਾ ਅਤੇ ਵਿਅਕਤੀ ਉੱਨਾ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਰਿਸ਼ਤੇਦਾਰਾਂ ਦੀ ਸਹੀ ਦੇਖ-ਭਾਲ ਨਹੀਂ ਕਰ ਪਾਏਗਾ ।5. ਸਮਾਨ ਸਥਿਤੀ (Same Status) – ਇੱਕ ਵਿਆਹ ਵਿੱਚ ਇਸਤਰੀ ਅਤੇ ਪੁਰਸ਼ ਦੀ ਸਥਿਤੀ ਪਿਆਰ ਅਤੇ ਹਮਦਰਦੀ ਦੇ ਰਿਸ਼ਤੇ ਉੱਤੇ ਆਧਾਰਿਤ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ । ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਮਿੱਤਰਤਾ ਦਾ ਕਾਫ਼ੀ ਭਾਵ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ । ਇਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੋਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਸਥਿਤੀ ਸਮਾਨ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ । ਦੋਹਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਕੰਮਾਂ ਦੀ ਵੰਡ ਸਹੁਲਤ ਦੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ । ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਆਦਮੀ ਅਤੇ ਔਰਤ ਦੀ ਸਥਿਤੀ ਸਮਾਨ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਪੁਰਸ਼ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਦੀ ਚੰਗੀ ਦੇਖ-ਭਾਲ ਕਰ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਇੱਕ ਵਿਆਹ ਦੀਆਂ ਹਾਨੀਆਂ (Demerits of Monogamy)1. ਮੈਂਬਰਾਂ ਦੀ ਘੱਟ ਸੁਰੱਖਿਆ (Less Protection of Members) – ਇੱਕ ਵਿਆਹ ਦੁਆਰਾ ਬਣੇ ਪਰਿਵਾਰਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਬਿਮਾਰੀ ਜਾਂ ਕਿਸੇ ਹੋਰ ਮੁਸੀਬਤ ਸਮੇਂ ਕਾਫ਼ੀ ਮੁਸ਼ਕਿਲ ਆ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ । ਜੇਕਰ ਔਰਤ ਬਿਮਾਰ ਹੋ ਜਾਵੇ ਤਾਂ ਘਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਹੋਰ ਕੋਈ ਕੰਮ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਅਤੇ ਨਾ ਹੀ ਕੋਈ ਬਿਮਾਰ ਨੂੰ ਸੰਭਾਲਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਆਦਮੀ ਨੇ ਤਾਂ ਬਾਹਰ ਨੌਕਰੀ ਜਾਂ ਵਪਾਰ ਕਰਨ ਜਾਣਾ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ । ਅਜਿਹੇ ਹਾਲਾਤਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਬੱਚਿਆਂ ਦਾ ਵੀ ਬੁਰਾ ਹਾਲ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ । ਆਦਮੀ ਦੇ ਮਰ ਜਾਣ ਦੀ ਸੂਰਤ ਵਿੱਚ ਜੀਵਨ ਬੋਝ ਬਣ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਆਰਥਿਕ, ਸਮਾਜਿਕ ਅਤੇ ਮਨੋਵਿਗਿਆਨਿਕ ਕਈ ਪ੍ਰਕਾਰ ਦੀਆਂ ਮੁਸ਼ਕਿਲਾਂ ਪੈਦਾ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੀਆਂ ਹਨ ।2. ਲਿੰਗ ਅਨੁਕੂਲਨ ਦੀ ਸਮੱਸਿਆ (Problem of sexual Satisfaction) – ਅੱਜ-ਕਲ਼ ਲਿੰਗ ਵਾਸਨਾ ਦੀ ਤ੍ਰਿਪਤੀ ਉੱਤੇ ਕਾਫੀ ਜ਼ੋਰ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ । ਕੁਝ ਲੋਕ ਤਾਂ ਇੱਥੋਂ ਤਕ ਕਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ ਕਿ ਲਿੰਗ ਸੰਬੰਧਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਵਿਵਿਧਤਾ ਜ਼ਰੂਰੀ ਹੈ। ਜਿਸ ਕਾਰਨ ਵਿਆਹ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਹਰ (Extra Marital) ਲਿੰਗ ਸੰਬੰਧ ਵੱਧਦੇ ਜਾ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ ਜਿਸ ਨਾਲ ਸਮਾਜ ਵਿੱਚ ਅਨੈਤਿਕਤਾ ਵੱਧਦੀ ਹੈ । ਵੇਯਾਵਾਂ ਅਤੇ ਕਾਲ ਗਰਲਜ਼ ਦਾ ਚਲਨ ਸਾਡੇ ਸਮਾਜਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਇਸੇ ਕਰਕੇ ਕਾਫ਼ੀ ਵੱਧ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ ।3. ਲਿੰਗਕ ਅਸੰਤੁਸ਼ਟੀ (Sexual dissatisfaction) – ਇੱਕ ਵਿਆਹ ਦੀ ਪ੍ਰਥਾ ਨਾਲ ਜਦੋਂ ਔਰਤ ਬਿਮਾਰ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ ਜਾਂ ਬਿਮਾਰ ਰਹਿੰਦੀ ਹੈ ਤਾਂ ਉਹ ਆਦਮੀ ਨੂੰ ਆਪਣਾ ਪੂਰਾ ਸਹਿਯੋਗ ਨਹੀਂ ਦੇ ਸਕਦੀ । ਆਦਮੀ ਆਪਣੀ ਲਿੰਗਕ ਇੱਛਾ ਦੀ ਪੂਰਤੀ ਲਈ ਘਰੋਂ ਬਾਹਰ ਜਾਣਾ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਹੋ ਗਿਆ । ਇਸ ਨਾਲ ਵੇਸ਼ਯਾਵਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਸਮਾਜ ਦੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਜਗ੍ਹਾ ਮਿਲ ਗਈ ਅਤੇ ਅਨੈਤਿਕਤਾ ਦਾ ਫੈਲਾਅ ਵੱਧ ਗਿਆ ।4. ਘਰ ਦਾ ਬਿਖਰਨਾ (Scattered houses) – ਇੱਕ ਵਿਆਹ ਦੀ ਪ੍ਰਥਾ ਵਿੱਚ ਜੇਕਰ ਪਤੀ ਜਾਂ ਪਤਨੀ ਦੋਵਾਂ ਵਿੱਚੋਂ ਕੋਈ ਇੱਕ ਬਿਮਾਰ ਹੋ ਜਾਵੇ ਜਾਂ ਮਰ ਜਾਵੇ ਤਾਂ ਘਰ ਬਿਲਕੁਲ ਹੀ ਰੁਲ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ । ਬੱਚਿਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਖਾਣ-ਪੀਣ ਦੀ ਸਮੱਸਿਆ ਦਾ ਸਾਹਮਣਾ ਕਰਨਾ ਪੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਕਈ ਮਨੋਵਿਗਿਆਨਿਕ ਸਮੱਸਿਆਵਾਂ ਵੀ ਪੈਦਾ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੀਆਂ ਹਨ ।"},{"question":"मल्लकालमा सिपाहीलाई के भनिन्थ्यो ?","answer":"उम्राब"},{"question":"Awọn obi ati olukọ ta ko bijọba ṣe kọ lati ṣi ileewe ni Kwara","answer":"Nitori bijọba ṣe kọ lati ṣi awọn ileewe pada nipinlẹ Kwara, awọn obi ati olukọ ileewe aladaani ni igbesẹ naa ko bojumu rara.Ọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee, ọsẹ yii, lawọn eeyan ọhun fẹhonu niluu Ilọrin. Wọn ni ebi ti fẹẹ lu awọn pa bawọn ṣe n jokoo sile, nitori idi eyi, kijọba ṣaanu awọn, ki wọn ṣi awọn ileewe ni kiakia.Alaga ẹgbẹ awọn oludasilẹ ileewe aladaani ni Kwara, National Association of Proprietors of Private Schools, Dokita Rahaman Adetunji, ṣalaye pe jijokoo sile lai ṣe nnkan kan ti su awọn akẹkọọ atawọn olukọ.O ni pẹlu bi ijọba ṣe ṣi ileewe fun idanwo aṣekagba, WASCE, o fi han pe awọn ileewe ti ṣee ṣi, nitori pe ko si akẹkọọ kankan to jokoo ṣedanwo to lugbadi arun Korona laarin asiko ti idanwo naa fi waye.Adetunji ni, “Awọn ileejọsin, ọja atawọn mi-in to jẹ pe o rọrun lati ko arun Korona nitori ero rẹpẹtẹ to maa n wa nibẹ gan-an ti di ṣiṣi, ki waa lo fa a ti ileewe ṣe maa wa ni titi.”O ni o kere tan, bii ida marundinlọgọrun-un awọn ileewe aladaani to wa ni Kwara lo ti ṣeto ilana ti wọn yoo fi daabo bo awọn akẹkọọ ati olukọ lọwọ lilugbadi arun naa.O rọ ijọba Kwara lati gbe igbesẹ kia, ko si kede asiko ati ilana iwọle awọn akẹkọọ"},{"question":"Awọn Fulani fi maaluu jẹ ọpọlọpọ eeka oko ẹ̀gẹ́ ni Kwara","answer":"Awon àgbẹ̀ nipinlẹ Kwara ti ke si Gomina Ìpínlẹ̀ naa, Abdulrazak Abdulrahaman, pe ko jọwọ, gba awọn lọwọ awọn Fulani darandaran to n fi maaluu jẹ oko wọn.Ninu Fodio kan tawọn eeyan naa ṣe to n ja ran-in lori ẹrọ ayelujara ni wọn ti ṣàlàyé pe gbogbo ẹ̀gẹ́ ti awọn gbin àtàwọn ire oko mi-in lawọn Fulani yii ko maaluu wọn wọ, ti wọn si ba a jẹ kanlẹ̀.Wọn ni ti nnkan ba n lọ bayii, iyan le ṣẹlẹ niluu.Eyi lo mu wọn kegbajare pe ki gbogbo aye gba awọn kale lọwọ awọn Fulani darandaran yii.Bẹẹ ni wọn bẹ Ààrẹ Buhari ati Gomina Kwara pẹlu awọn alẹnulọrọ gbogbo lati tete da sọrọ naa.Tẹ o ba gbagbe, aipẹ yii làwọn eeyan Oro naa pariwo pe awọn Fulani yii ko jẹ kawọn gbádùn, awọn obinrin wọn si ṣeleri pe bi Kábíyèsí ko ba wa nnkan ṣe si i, awọn maa fi ilu naa sile.Ọsẹ yii kan naa làwọn eeyan ilu Igbaja, nipinlẹ Kwara kan naa fẹhonu han lọ si àafin ọba ilu naa, wọn làwọn ko le fara da ọṣẹ ti Fulani n ṣe fawọn mo, afi ki wọn filu naa silẹ."},{"question":"Àjàkáyé-àrùn èrànkòrónà ọdún 2019-2020","answer":"Àjàkáyé-àrùn èrànkòrónà ọdún 2019-2020 tàbí Àjàkáyé-àrùn COVID-19 ni àjàkáyé-àrùn tí ó ṣẹlẹ̀ ní ààrin ọdún 2019 àti 2020 tí ò ń tàn káàkiri orílẹ̀ èdè gbogbo àgbáyé lọ́wọ́lọ́wọ́. Kòkòrò àìlèfojúrí afàìsàn kòrónà tí ó ń ṣàkóbá fún èémí ọ̀wọ́ kejì (SARS-CoV-2) ló ṣokùnfà àjàkálẹ̀ àrùn náà. Àgbègbè Wuhan, ní ìlú Hubei, lórílẹ̀-èdè China ní àjàkálẹ̀ àrùn yìí tí kọ́kọ́ farahàn lóṣù Kejìlá ọdún 2019, tí ó sìn ti di nǹkan tí àjọ tí ó ń rí sì ètò ìlera ní àgbáyé, World Health Organization tí kéde rẹ̀ gẹ́gẹ́ bí àrùn pàjáwìrì gbogboògbò lágbàáyé tí wọ́n gbọdọ̀ mójú tó. Titi di ọjọ́ kẹwàá oṣù ó ti ọdún 2020, ó ti ju ènìyàn 118,000 tí ó ti kó àrùn yìí káàkiri gbogbo àgbáyé, tí 5,800 nínú wọn jẹ èyí tí wọ́n kà sí pé àrùn náà tí wọ̀ wọ́n lára jù. Ó ti ju orílẹ̀-èdè àádọ́fà (115) tó ti kàgbákó ìbẹ́sílẹ̀ àjàkálẹ̀-àrùn ẹ̀ràn kòrónà lọ́dún yìí, pàápàá jùlọ àárín gbùngbùn orílẹ̀-èdè China, Italy, South Korea àti Iran. Ó ti ju ènìyàn ìgbàlélẹ́gbẹ̀rúnmẹ́rin, 4,200 tí àrùn yìí ti pa ní ìfọnnáfòṣu, ó tó ènìyàn ọgọ́rùn-ún-lé-lẹ́gbẹ̀ta, (3100) tí wọ́n kú ní orílẹ̀ èdè China nìkan, àti ẹgbẹ̀rún kan ènìyàn káàkiri àwọn orílẹ̀ èdè op kù káàkiri àgbáyé. Bẹ́ẹ̀ náà, ó ti ju ènìyàn mẹ́rìnlélọ́gọ́ta ẹgbẹ̀rún (64,000) tí wọ́n ti mórí bọ́ nínú àjàkálẹ̀ àrùn yìí. Ẹ̀rà yìí máa ń ràn láti ara enikan sí ẹlòmíràn nípa èémí ìpọ̀jáde bí a bá ń wúkọ̀ tàbí bí a bá ń sín.Àkókò tí ènìyàn bá kó àrùn yìí àti ìgbà tí ó máa farahàn ma ń sábà máa ń tó Ọjọ́ márùn-ún, ṣùgbọ́n nígbà mìíràn ẹ̀wẹ̀, ó lè tó nǹkan bí ọjọ́ méjì sí mẹ́rìnlá. Àwọn àmìn ìfarahàn rẹ̀ sáà a máa ń wá bí, àìsàn ibà, ikọ́ wúwú, àti àìlèmí kánlẹ̀. Ìpeléke àrùn yìí máa ń fà àrùn ẹ̀dọ̀fóró, àti ìnira èémí. Lọ́wọ́lọ́wọ́ báyìí, àrùn yìí kò gbóògùn kankan. Ṣùgbọ́n ìwádìí ìjìnlẹ̀ ń lọ lórí rẹ̀ lọ́wọ́lọ́wọ́. Ìgbìyànjú láti mójú tó àwọn àmìn ìfarahàn rẹ̀ ni àwọn oníṣẹ́ ìwòsàn ń ṣe. Àwọn ọ̀nà tí wọ́n là kalẹ̀ láti dẹ́kun àrùn yìí fífọwọ́ déédé, jíjìnnà sí ara ẹni, pàápàá jùlọ ẹni tí ó bá ń ṣàìsàn tàbí fura sí pé wọ́n ní àrùn yìí àti ìyaraẹnisọ́tọ̀ ẹni tí ó fura pé òun ní àrùn yìí.Lára àwọn ọ̀nà ìdẹ́kun mìíràn tí wọ́n ń gbà láti dẹ́kun jíjàkálẹ̀ àrùn yìí káàkiri àgbáyé ni dídẹ́kun ìrìn-àjò, ìyà sọ́tọ̀ ẹni-afurasí, òfin kónílé-ó-gbélé, àti títi àwọn ilé-ìwé pa. Àwọn ìlú bíi Hubei lórílẹ̀ èdè China àti gbogbo orílẹ̀ èdè Italy ló wà ní ìyàsọ́tọ̀-àmójútó lọ́wọ́ báyìí, bẹ́ẹ̀ náà òfin kónílé-ó-gbélé ń lọ lọ́wọ́ lórílẹ̀ èdè China àti South Korea; bẹ́ẹ̀ náà, àyẹ̀wò fínnífínní ní pápákọ̀-òfuurufú àti ìdíkọ̀ ọkọ̀ ojúrìn;àti ìmọ̀ràn ìrìn-àjò ní ìlú tàbí àgbègbè tí àrùn yìí bá ti ń jàkálẹ̀. Ilé-ìwé títìpa pátápátá ní gbogbo orílẹ̀-èdè tàbí àgbègbè tí àrùn yìí ti ṣẹ́yọ ní àwọn orílẹ̀ èdè mìíràn, èyí tí ṣe àkóbá fún ìkẹ́kọ̀ọ́ ọ̀ọ́dúnrún mílíọ́nù (300 million) àwọn akẹ́kọ̀ọ́ jákèjádò àgbáyé. Àkóbá ńlá mìíràn tí Ìbẹ́sílẹ̀ àjàkálẹ̀-àrùn ẹ̀ràn kòrónà lọ́dún 2019-20 yìí ni ìfàsẹ́yìn ètò ọ̀rọ̀-aje àti ìbágbépọ̀, bẹ́ẹ̀ náà Ìbẹ́sílẹ̀ àjàkálẹ̀-àrùn ẹ̀ràn kòrónà lọ́dún 2019-20 ti fa ẹlẹ́yàmẹ̀yà àti ìjà-aòfẹ́-ọ-nílùú wá sí àwọn ọmọ orílẹ̀-èdè China àti àwọn ọmọ ìran ìlà oòrùn Asia, bákan náà ìròyìn òfegè lórí ìkànnì ayélujára nípa Ìbẹ́sílẹ̀ àjàkálẹ̀-àrùn ẹ̀ràn kòrónà lọ́dún 2019-20 àti àwọn aríjẹ-nídìí ìbàjé lórí àjàkálẹ̀ àrùn náà kò gbẹ́yìn.Titi di ọjọ́ Kejìlá oṣù kẹta ọdún 2020, ó ti ju ènìyàn 126000 tí ó ti kó àrùn yìí káàkiri gbogbo àgbáyé, Ìwòye wà pé wọn kò jábọ̀ tó bí àrùn yìí ṣe ń ṣọsẹ́ pàápàá jùlọ àwọn tí àmìn ìfarahàn ṣì ṣẹ̀pẹ̀rẹ̀.Ní àtiparí oṣù Kejìlá lọ́dún 2019, àwọn onímọ̀ ìlera kéde pé àìsàn ẹ̀dọ̀fóró ṣẹ́yọ sí àwọn ènìyàn ní Wuhan, lágbègbè Hubei, lórílẹ̀-èdè China ṣùgbọ́n tí wọn kò mọ ohun tí ó ṣòkùnfà rẹ̀. Ní ìbẹ̀rẹ̀ pẹ̀pẹ̀ àjàkálẹ̀ àìsàn yìí, wọ́n tọpinpin rẹ̀ ọjà kan tí wọ́n ti wọ́n ń pè ní Huanan Seafood Wholesale Market, wọ́n sìn ṣàkíyèsí pé láti ara zoonotic ní kòkòrò àìfojúrí tí ó ń fa àìsàn náà ti ṢẸ̀ wá. Kòkòrò Àìfojúrí yìí tí ó fa àjàkálẹ̀ àìsàn ni wọ́n ń pè ní SARS-CoV-2, kòkòrò àìfojúrí tuntun tí ó fara pẹ́ kòkòrò àìfojúrí kòrónà láti ara àdán, pangolin coronaviruses àti SARS-CoV. Ìgbàgbọ́ wà pé, ó ṣeé ṣe kí kòkòrò àìfojúrí yìí wá láti ara àwọn ẹ̀yà àdán tí wọ́n pè ní Rhinolophus.Àjàkálẹ̀ àìsàn yìí kọ́kọ́ ṣẹ́yọ ní Ọjọ́ kìíní Oṣù Kejìlá ọdún 2019, láti ara ẹnìkan tí kò dé ọjà oúnjẹ òkun, (Huanan Seafood Wholesale Market) tàbí ní ìbáṣepọ̀ kankan pẹ̀lú àwọn ogójì àwọn mìíràn tí àyẹ̀wò ọ̀wọ́ àkọ́kọ́ fihàn pé wọ́n ní kòkòrò àìfojúrí náà. Nínú àyẹ̀wò ọ̀wọ́ àkọ́kọ́, ìpín méjì nínú mẹ́ta ni àyẹ̀wò fihàn pé wọ́n ìbáṣepọ̀ pẹ̀lú wet (wet market), tí ó máa ń ẹran lóòyẹ̀.Àjọ ìlera àgbáyé World Health Organization (WHO) kéde àjàkálẹ̀ àìsàn náà gẹ́gẹ́ bí àjàkálẹ̀ àrùn gbogboògbò tí ó nílò ìmójútó pàjáwìrì ní ọgbọ̀njọ́ oṣù kìíní ọdún 2020. Olùdarí àjọ ìlera àgbáyé, Who, Ọ̀gbẹ́ni Tedros Adhanom, gbóríyìn fún ìjọba orílẹ̀ èdè China fún akitiyan àti ìgbésẹ̀ wọ́n láti rí i pé àjàkálẹ̀ àrùn tí kòkòrò àìfojúrí kòrónà ń fà kò tàn kálẹ̀ ju bó ṣe yẹ lọ lórílẹ̀-èdè naa, bí ó tilẹ̀ jẹ́ pé ó ń jà rànyìnrànyìn ní àwọn àgbègbè orílẹ̀-èdè mìíràn.Ní ìbẹ̀rẹ̀ pẹ̀pẹ̀ àrùn yìí, iye àwọn ènìyàn tí ó ń lùgbàdì àìsàn yìí tó ìlọ́po méjì láàárín Ọjọ́ méje àti àbọ̀. Ní ìbẹ̀rẹ̀ oṣù kìíní ọdún 2020, kòkòrò àìfojúrí yìí ti jàkálẹ̀ dé àwọn àgbègbè China, ọdún Chunyun, tí ó jẹ́ ayẹyẹ àìsùn ọdún tuntun ní China, tí wọ́n ṣe ní ìlú Wuhan lo ṣe àkóbá fún ọ̀pọ̀lọpọ̀ àwọn tí wọ́n lùgbàdì àìsàn yìí, nítorí pé ìlú Wuhan ni ìlú tí ìgbòkègbodò ọkọ́ tí gbòde jù ní China. Àsìkò yìí ni ọ̀pọ̀lọpọ̀ fara kàṣà àrùn náà. Lógúnjọ́ oṣù kìíní ọdún 2020, orílẹ̀-èdè China kéde ogóje ènìyàn tí wọ́n lùgbàdì àrùn yìí lọ́jọ́ kan ṣoṣo, àti ènìyàn méjì mìíràn ní Beijing, pẹ̀lú enikan ní Shenzhen.Lọ́jọ́ kẹrìndínlọ́gbọ̀n oṣù kejì ọdún 2020, àjọ ìlera àgbáyé, WHO kéde ìdí kù nínú àwọn tí ó ń kó àrùn yìí ní China, ṣùgbọ́n tí àjàkálẹ̀ àrùn náà gbìnàyá ní orílẹ̀-èdè Italy, Iran àti South Korea. Iye àwọn ènìyàn tuntun tí ó ń kó àrùn náà ní orílẹ̀ èdè mìíràn tí ju ti China lọ.Pínníṣín ni iye àwọn ọmọdé tí àyẹ̀wò ti fihàn pé wọ́n ní àjàkálẹ̀ àrùn yìí títí di ọjọ́ kẹrìndínlọ́gbọ̀n oṣù kejì ọdún 2020. Ìkéde kan láti ọwọ́ àjọ ìlera àgbáyé WHO fihàn pé ìdá 2.4 ni àwọn ọmọdé tí ọjọ́ orí wọn kò ju mọ́kàndínlógún lọ ló ní àrùn COVID-19 yìí káàkiri àgbáyé.Láàárín Ọjọ́ mẹ́fà sí mọ́kànlélógójì, tí àmìn àrùn náà ṣẹ́yọ àti àsìkò tí àrùn COVID-19 hànde ni àwọn tí wọ́n lùgbàdì rẹ̀ ń kú, àgbálògbábọ̀, ọjọ́ mẹ́rìnlá .Titi di ọjọ́ Mẹ́rìnlélogun oṣù kẹjọ ọdún 2020, ó ti ju ènìyàn 800,000 tí àrùn COVID-19 tí pá. Gẹ́gẹ́ bí NHC tí orílẹ̀ èdè China tí sọ, àgbàlagbà ni ó pọ̀jù nínú àwọn tí àrùn náà pa. Ó tó ìdá ọgọ́rin, 80% àwọn àgbàlagbà tí ọjọ́-orí ti kọjá ọgọ́ta tó kú, àti ìdá márùndínlọ́gọ́rin àwọn tí wọ́n ti ní àìsàn mìíràn lára tẹ́lẹ̀, pàápàá jùlọ àìsàn ọkàn, cardiovascular diseases àti itọ̀ ṣúgà, diabetes.Ẹni àkọ́kọ́ tí àìsàn yìí pa kú lọ́jọ́ kẹsàn-án oṣù kìíní ọdún 2020 ní ìlú Wuhan. Ẹlòmíràn tó kú ní orílẹ̀ èdè mìíràn yàtọ̀ sí China kú ní orílẹ̀-èdè Philippines, ẹlòmíràn tí ó tún kú, tí kì í ṣe láti ilẹ̀ Asia kú ní Faransé. Lẹ́yìn China, ó ti ju ènìyàn méjìlá. Mẹ́jìlá lọ tí wọ́n ti kú ní Iran, South Korea, àti Italy. Bákan náà, ọ̀pọ̀lọpọ̀ ènìyàn ìròyìn tí fìdí rẹ̀ múlẹ̀ pé wọ́n tí kú ikú àrùn kòrónà apá àríwá Amẹ́ríkà (North America), Australia, San Marino, Spain, Iraq, àti United Kingdom. Ìwé ìròyìn Daily NK jábọ̀ pé àwọn ọmọ-ogun tó ti ju igba (200) ni àrùn kòrónà ti pa lórílẹ̀-èdè North Korea.Kòsí àmìn kan pàtó tí kòkòrò àìfojúrí kòrónà, COVID-19 máa ń gbé yọ lára ẹni tí ó bá kó o. Àwọn tí ó bá kó o lè máa ní àmìn kankan tàbí kí ó bẹ̀rẹ̀ sí ní ṣàìléra bí i ikọ́, ibà, àìlèmí kanlẹ̀, ara riro, àìlókun, àwọn àmìn àti ìfarahàn rẹ̀ ló wà nínú tábìlì yìí.l.Bí àrùn yìí bá ti ń peléke, ó máa ń fà àrùn ẹ̀dọ̀fóró, ìnira láti mí, ìjayà àti ikú. Ìwádìí tí fihàn gbangba pé àwọn mìíràn lè ní àrùn yìí láìsí àmìn tàbí Ìfarahàn kankan, nítorí ìdí èyí ni àwọn onímọ̀ ìlera gbà á ní lmọ̀ràn pé ẹnikẹ́ni tí ó bá ti sún mọ́ enití àyẹ̀wò fihàn pé ó ní àrùn náà gbọ́dọ̀ wà ní ìmójútó láti ríi dájú pé kò lùgbàdì àrùn náà.Àsìkò ìyàsọ́tọ̀ fún ẹni tí ó bá kó àrùn náà àti ìgbà tí àwọn àmìn rẹ̀ máa bẹ̀rẹ̀ sí ní jáde máa ń tó ọjọ́ kan sí mẹ́rìnlá, ọjọ́ márùn-ún ló sáà à máa ń jẹyọ jù. In one case, it had an incubation period of 27 days. Nígbà mìíràn ẹ̀wẹ̀, àrùn COVID-19 kìí ní àmìn ìfarahàn lára ẹlòmíràn."},{"question":"Wọn ti mu Aafaa Jamiu to fẹẹ fọmọ ọdun mẹẹẹdogun  ṣoogun owo ni Sango","answer":"Aafaa Amọdu Jamiu ree, ẹni ọdun mẹtadinlogoji ni. Awọn ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Ogun ti mu un bayii, wọn lo ji ọmọbinrin ọmọ ọdun mẹẹẹdogun kan gbe pẹlu erongba ati fi i ṣe etutu ọrọ, oogun owo, ni Sango.Ọjọ karun-un, oṣu kẹrin yii, lọwọ ba Aafaa Jamiu, iyẹn lẹyin ti ọmọbinrin to ji gbe naa lọọ fẹjọ sun ni teṣan ọlọpaa Sango. DSP Abimbọla Oyeyẹmi ṣalaye pe ọmọ naa sọ fawọn ọlọpaa pe jẹẹjẹ oun loun n ti ibi iṣẹ bọ lọjọ naa, boun ṣe pade aafaa yii niyẹn ni nnkan bii aago marun-un aabọ irọlẹ.Ọmọbinrin yii ṣalaye pe Aafaa Jamiu da oun duro, o si fi kinni kan gba oun, bẹẹ lo paṣẹ pe koun ka lọ, oun si tẹle e wọ ile akọku kan to mu oun wọ.Ninu ile naa lo ni Aafaa Jamiu ti ja oun sihooho, o si fi ankaṣiifu funfun kan nu oju ara oun, bẹẹ lo fi nu gbogbo ara oun kari pẹlu.Aṣe ẹnikan n ri wọn latọọkan, gbogbo ohun ti aafaa n ṣe fọmọ naa ni tọhun n wo. Nigba to si di pe ọmọbinrin naa ko mọ ibi to wa mọ, to kan wa nibẹ bẹẹ ni ẹni naa yọju si wọn, bawọn ọlọpaa ṣe wi, n lo ba pariwo le Aafaa Jamiu lori.Nigba tọwọ ọlọpaa ba aafaa, o jẹwọ pe loootọ loun ṣe ohun ti wọn fẹsun ẹ kan oun yii.Aafaa Amọdu sọ pe oun fẹẹ fi aisan buruku kan ṣe ọmọbinrin naa ni, to bẹẹ ti yoo maa ṣe aarẹ, ti awọn obi rẹ yoo fi gbe e wa sọdọ oun, toun yoo si maa gba owo buruku lọwọ wọn fun itọju rẹ.Aafaa sọ pe oun ti ṣe bẹẹ fawọn meji kan ri to jẹ owo nla loun fi gba lọwọ awọn eeyan wọn.Awọn ọlọpaa lọ sile aafaa yii lati yẹ ẹ wo, oriṣiiriṣii apẹ ijoogun ni wọn ba nibẹ, wọn si ya fọto rẹ ki gbogbo aye le ri ohun ti Aafaa Jamiu Amọdu fi n ṣagbara.Ni bayii ṣa, wọn ti taari aafaa si ẹka iwadii, wọn fẹ ko ṣalaye siwaju si i nipa awọn itu to ti pa ri ki wọn too mu un."},{"question":"යාන්ත්‍රික තරංග ලෙස හඳුන්වන්නේ මොනවාද?","answer":"ප්‍රචාරණය සඳහා මාධ්‍යක් අවශ්‍ය වන තරංග යාන්ත්‍රික තරංග ලෙස හඳුන්වනු ලැබේ."},{"question":"Dame un ejemplo de trivia para esta categoría: videogames","answer":"La pregunta para esa categoría sería ¿Cuántos juegos hay en la serie de Uncharted? Y la respuesta es: 5"},{"question":"Ará Ilú Nigeria: “Fi Ẹ̀tẹ̀ Silẹ̀ Pa Làpálàpá”","answer":"Ẹ̀tẹ̀ tó mbá ilú jà ni ‘iwà-ibàjẹ́’.  Ìyà ti ará ilú njẹ lọ́wọ́lọ́wọ́, ki i ṣe èrè iwà-ibàjẹ́ ọdún kan, ṣùgbọ́n  ti ọ̀pọ̀lọpọ̀ ọdún.  Kò si ìfẹ́ ilú, nitori eyi, àwọn oniwà ibàjẹ́ ni àwọn ará ilú nyin bi wọn bá ti ẹ fi èrú kó owó jọ pàtàki ni ilé ìjọ́sìn, wọn kò ri ẹni ba wọn wi.Fún akiyesi, ilé iṣẹ́ ti ó n pèsè iná mọ̀nàmọ́ná, owó ti Ìjọba àpa-pọ̀ ba pin lati pèsè iná mọ̀nàmọ́ná fún gbogbo ará ilú, ọ̀gá ilé-iṣẹ́ á pin pẹ̀lú àwọn Ìjọba Ológun tàbi Òṣèlú Alágbádá.  Ni bi ọgbọ̀n ọdún sẹhin, nigbati àwọn ọmọ iṣẹ́ ri pé àwọn ọ̀gá ti ó nji owó, kò si ẹni ti ó mú wọn, àwọn na a brẹ̀rẹ̀ si lọ yọ nkan lára ẹ̀rọ ti ó gbé iná wọ àdúgbò lati lè gba àbẹ̀tẹ́lẹ̀ lọ́wọ́ ará àdúgbò.  Ará àdúgbò á dá owó ki àwọn òṣiṣẹ́ ilé-iṣẹ́ mọ̀nàmọ́ná tó wá tú ohun ti ó bàjẹ́ tàbi ohun ti wọn yọ ṣe.Kàkà ki ará ilú para-pọ̀ lati wo ẹ̀tẹ̀ san, nipa gbi gbé ogun ti iwà-ibàjẹ́ ni ilé-iṣẹ́ mọ̀nàmọ́ná, onikálùkù bẹ̀rẹ̀ si ṣètò fún ará wọn nipa ri ra ẹ̀rọ́ iná mọ̀nàmọ́ná ti àwọn Òyinbó ngbe dani nigbati wọn bá fẹ lọ pàgọ́.  Àwọn ẹ̀rọ wọnyi kò lágbára tó lati dipò iná mọ̀nàmọ́ná ti ó yẹ ki Ìjọba pèsè.  Àwọn ará ilú kò ro ìnáwó ti ó kó wọn si, ariwo, àti èéfín burúkú ti ẹ̀rọ yi nfẹ sinú afẹ́fẹ́.  Àwọn ti ó nja ilú lólè ni ó nkó ẹ̀rọ wọnyi wọlé, wọn kò gbèrò ki iná mọ̀nàmọ́ná wa nitori wọn kò ni ri ẹni ra ọjà wọn.   Wọn rò wi pé àwọn lè dá ilé-iṣẹ́ ti ó n pèsè iná mọ̀nàmọ́ná silẹ̀ ti ó lè lo atẹ́gùn, omi, epo rọ̀bì, oòrùn lati pèsè iná ti kò léwu bi ẹ̀rọ́ iná mọ̀nàmọ́ná.Ẹ̀tẹ̀ ṣòro lati wòsàn ju làpálàpá lọ, ibàjẹ́ ló yára lati ṣe ju lati tú nkan ṣe lọ. O ye ki ará ilú para pọ̀ pẹ̀lú Ìjọba lọ́wọ́lọ́wọ́, lati gbé ogun ti iwà ibàjẹ́ àti àwọn aṣèbàjẹ́, ju pé ki wọn fi ara gbi gbóná kọ ìyà ọgbọ̀n ọdún laarin ọdún kan tàbi meji."},{"question":"ਸਾਲ 2016 - 2017 ਵਿੱਚ ਫੌਜ ਨੇ ਉੱਤਰੀ ਰਖਾਇਨ ਸੂਬੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਘੱਟ-ਗਿਣਤੀ ਭਾਈਚਾਰੇ ਰੋਹਿੰਗਿਆ ਖ਼ਿਲਾਫ਼ ਹਮਲਾਵਰ ਕਾਰਵਾਈ ਕੀਤੀ, ਜਿਸ ਕਾਰਨ ਰੋਹਿੰਗਿਆ ਮੁਸਲਮਾਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਮਿਆਂਮਾਰ ਤੋਂ ਭੱਜਣਾ ਪਿਆ।ਇਸ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਹਲਾਇੰਗ ਨੂੰ ਕਥਿਤ 'ਨਸਲਕੁਸ਼ੀ' ਲਈ ਕੌਮਾਂਤਰੀ ਪੱਧਰ 'ਤੇ ਨਿੰਦਾ ਦਾ ਸਾਹਮਣਾ ਕਰਨਾ ਪਿਆ।ਅਗਸਤ, 2018 ਵਿੱਚ ਯੂਐੱਨ ਮਨੁੱਖੀ ਅਧਿਕਾਰ ਕੌਂਸਲ ਨੇ ਕਿਹਾ ਕਿ \\"ਮਿਆਂਮਾਰ ਫੌਜ ਦੇ ਕਮਾਂਡਰ ਇੰਨ ਚੀਫ਼ ਮਿਨ ਔਂਗ ਹਲਾਇੰਗ ਸਣੇ ਹੋਰਨਾਂ ਸੀਨੀਅਰ ਜਨਰਲਾਂ ਖਿਲਾਫ਼ ਰਖਾਇਨ ਪ੍ਰਾਂਤ ਵਿੱਚ ਕਤਲੇਆਮ ਅਤੇ ਰਖਾਇਨ, ਕਚਿਨ ਅਤੇ ਸ਼ਾਨ ਪ੍ਰਾਂਤ ਵਿੱਚ 'ਮਨੁੱਖਤਾ ਖ਼ਿਲਾਫ਼ ਅਪਰਾਧ' ਅਤੇ 'ਜੰਗੀ ਅਪਰਾਧਾਂ ਲਈ ਜਾਂਚ ਹੋਣੀ ਚਾਹੀਦੀ ਹੈ।","answer":"ਹਲਾਇੰਗ ਨੇ ਇਸ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਮਿਆਂਮਾਰ ਦੀ ਸੱਤਾ ਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੇ ਹੱਥ ਵਿੱਚ ਲੈ ਕੇ ਚੋਣਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਕਥਿਤ ਘੁਟਾਲੇ ਦੇ ਮੁੱਦੇ ਨੂੰ ਪਹਿਲ ਦੇ ਅਧਾਰ 'ਤੇ ਰੱਖਿਆ।ਹਲਾਇੰਗ ਦੀ ਅਗਵਾਈ ਵਾਲੀ ਨੌਸ਼ਨਲ ਡਿਫੈਂਸ ਅਤੇ ਸਕਿਊਰਿਟੀ ਕੌਂਸਲ ਦੀ ਬੈਠਕ ਵਿੱਚ ਇਹ ਕਿਹਾ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਕੌਂਸਲ ਚੋਣਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਘੁਟਾਲੇ ਦੇ ਇਲਜ਼ਾਮਾਂ ਦੀ ਜਾਂਚ ਕਰੇਗੀ ਅਤੇ ਨਵੀਂਆਂ ਚੋਣਾਂ ਕਰਵਾਏਗੀ। ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਐੱਨਐੱਲਡੀ ਦੀ ਜਿੱਤ ਨੂੰ ਗੈਰ-ਕਾਨੂੰਨੀ ਐਲਾਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ।ਮਿਨ ਔਂਗ ਹਲਾਇੰਗ ਇਸ ਸਾਲ ਜੁਲਾਈ ਵਿੱਚ ਕਮਾਂਡਰ ਇੰਨ ਚੀਫ਼ ਵਜੋਂ ਸੇਵਾਮੁਕਤ ਹੋਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਸੀ ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਉਹ 65 ਸਾਲ ਦੀ ਉਮਰ ਪਾਰ ਕਰ ਚੁੱਕੇ ਹਨ। ਪਰ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਖੁਦ ਨੂੰ ਇੱਕ ਹੋਰ ਸਾਲ ਦੇ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਹੈ। ਪਰ ਮਿਆਂਮਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਫੌਜੀ ਸ਼ਾਸਨ ਪਰਤਣ ਕਾਰਨ ਹਲਾਇੰਗ ਸੰਭਾਵੀ ਤੌਰ 'ਤੇ ਲੰਬੇ ਸਮੇਂ ਲਈ ਬਣੇ ਰਹਿ ਸਕਦੇ ਹਨ।ਕੀ ਸਾਰੇ ਰੋਹਿੰਗਿਆ ਸ਼ਰਨਾਰਥੀ ਵਾਪਸ ਜਾਣਾ ਚਾਹੁੰਦੇ ਹਨ?"},{"question":"Em 2021, qual foi o IDH de Laos?","answer":"0,607."},{"question":"කනෙක්ටොමික්ස් යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"කනෙක්ටොමික්ස් යනු සම්බන්ධක නිෂ්පාදනය සහ අධ්‍යයනයයි: ජීවියෙකුගේ ස්නායු පද්ධතිය තුළ සම්බන්ධතා පිළිබඳ විස්තීර්ණ සිතියම්. වඩාත් සාමාන්‍යයෙන්, එය ව්‍යුහාත්මක සම්බන්ධතාවය, පුද්ගල උපාගමයන්, සෛලීය රූප විද්‍යාව සහ සෛලීය අල්ට්‍රාස්ට්‍රැක්චර් ජාලයක් සෑදීමට දායක වන ආකාරය කෙරෙහි අවධානය යොමු කරමින් නියුරෝන රැහැන් රූප සටහන් අධ්‍යයනයක් ලෙස සැලකිය හැකිය. ස්නායු පද්ධතිය යනු සම්බන්ධතා බිලියන ගණනකින් සෑදී ඇති ජාලයක් වන අතර අපගේ සිතුවිලි, හැඟීම්, ක්‍රියා, මතකයන්, ක්‍රියාකාරිත්වය සහ අක්‍රියතාව සඳහා මෙම සම්බන්ධතා වගකිව යුතුය. එබැවින්, ස්නායු පද්ධතියේ සෛල සම්බන්ධ වී සන්නිවේදනය කරන ආකාරය අවබෝධ කර ගැනීමෙන් මානසික සෞඛ්‍යය සහ සංජානනය පිළිබඳ අපගේ අවබෝධය වැඩිදියුණු කිරීම සම්බන්ධක අධ්‍යයනයේ අරමුණයි. මෙම ව්‍යුහයන් අතිශයින් සංකීර්ණ බැවින්, මෙම ක්ෂේත්‍රය තුළ ඇති ක්‍රම මගින් වේගය, කාර්යක්ෂමතාව සහ විභේදනය වැඩි කිරීම සඳහා ක්‍රියාකාරී සහ ව්‍යුහාත්මක ස්නායු රූප, බහුලවම චුම්භක අනුනාද රූප (MRI), ඉලෙක්ට්‍රෝන අන්වීක්ෂය සහ හිස්ටොලොජිකල් ශිල්පීය ක්‍රමවල ඉහළ ප්‍රතිඵලයක් භාවිතා කරයි. මෙම ස්නායු පද්ධතියේ සිතියම් වලින්. අද වන විට, බාහිකයේ විවිධ ප්‍රදේශ, මස්තිෂ්ක, දෘෂ්ටි විතානය, පර්යන්ත ස්නායු පද්ධතිය සහ ස්නායු මාංශ පේශි හන්දි ඇතුළු ස්නායු පද්ධතිය පුරා විහිදෙන මහා පරිමාණ දත්ත කට්ටල දස ගණනක් එකතු කර ඇත. සාමාන්යයෙන් කථා කිරීම, සම්බන්ධක වර්ග දෙකක් තිබේ; macroscale සහ microscale. මැක්‍රොස්කේල් කනෙක්ටොමික්ස් යනු රුධිර ප්‍රවාහය (ක්‍රියාකාරී) සහ ජල විසරණය (ව්‍යුහාත්මක) අනුව මොළයේ ඇති විශාල තන්තු පත්‍රිකා සහ ක්‍රියාකාරී අළු පදාර්ථ ප්‍රදේශ සිතියම්ගත කිරීම සඳහා ක්‍රියාකාරී සහ ව්‍යුහාත්මක MRI දත්ත භාවිතා කිරීමයි. ක්ෂුද්‍ර පරිමාණ සම්බන්ධක විද්‍යාව යනු අන්වීක්ෂය සහ හිස්ටොලොජි භාවිතයෙන් කුඩා ජීවීන්ගේ සම්පූර්ණ සම්බන්ධක සිතියම්ගත කිරීමයි. එනම්, ඔවුන්ගේ මධ්යම ස්නායු පද්ධතියේ පවතින සියලුම සම්බන්ධතා."},{"question":"පළමු ඔලිම්පික් තරගාවලියේ ජයග්‍රහණය කළ රට කුමක්ද?","answer":"පළමු නවීන ඔලිම්පික් ක්‍රීඩා උළෙල 1896 දී ග්‍රීසියේ ඇතන්ස් නුවරදී පැවැත්විණි. වැඩිම පදක්කම් දිනූ රට අනුව ග්‍රීසිය ප්‍රමුඛයා විය. ග්‍රීක ක්‍රීඩක ක්‍රීඩිකාවන් සමස්ත පදක්කම් 46ක් (රන් 10ක්, රිදී 17ක් සහ ලෝකඩ 19ක්) සමගින් සමස්ත පදක්කම් සංඛ්‍යාව දිනා ගත්හ.කෙසේ වෙතත්, අපි වැඩිපුරම රන් පදක්කම් දිනූ රට ගැන සාකච්ඡා කරන්නේ නම්, එක්සත් ජනපදය රන් පදක්කම් 11 ක් සමඟින් පෙරමුණ ගෙන ඇත. අද අප දන්නා පරිදි පදක්කම් වගු මුල් ඔලිම්පික් තරඟ වලදී භාවිතා නොකළ නමුත් මෙම ගණන් ප්‍රත්‍යාවර්තී වර්ගීකරණය මත පදනම් වේ."},{"question":"การลอยกระทงโฟมมีผลเสียต่อสิ่งแวดล้อมอย่างไร","answer":"มีผลเสียดังต่อไปนี้- ขัดขวางทางน้ำ- เป็นขยะที่ย่อยสลายได้ยาก- สารพิษในโฟมเป็นอันตรายต่อมนุษย์และสัตว์น้ำ- สามารถก่อให้เกิดไมโครพลาสติกมีผลต่อสิ่งแวดล้อม"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"badan sihat otak cerdas\\"? Berikan contoh ayat untuk peribahasa \\"badan sihat otak cerdas\\".","answer":"Ia bermaksud kesihatan yang baik membolehkan seseorang melahirkan idea yang bernas.Contoh ayat:Kementerian Pelajaran Malaysia melancarkan Dasar 1 Murid 1 Sukan kerana memegang prinsip badan sihat otak cerdas."},{"question":"ગુરુપૂર્ણિમાની શાળામાં કરેલી ઉજવણીનો અહેવાલ આશરે 100 શબ્દોમાં લખો.","answer":"શાળામાં ઉજવાયેલ ગુરુપૂર્ણિમા ઉત્સવશહેરતારીખ [dd-mm-yyyy][મંગળવાર] ના દિવસે શાળાના વિદ્યાર્થીઓએ મળીને ગુરુપૂર્ણિમાનો ઉત્સવ ઊજવવાનું નક્કી કર્યું. શાળાના આચાર્યની પરવાનગી મળતાં સોએ સાથે મળીને આખી શાળાને તેમજ શાળાના સભાગૃહને રંગબેરંગી તોરણોથી સજાવ્યો. સભાગૃહના દ્વાર પાસે સુંદર રંગોળી બનાવી. સભાગૃહના મંચની જમણી બાજુએ ટેબલ પર ફૂલો પાથરીને તેના પર દીવી મૂકી. બાજુમાં અગરબત્તી અને અબીલ-ગુલાલ મૂક્યાં હતાં.સવારના 9.00 વાગ્યે શાળાના આચાર્ય સૌ શિક્ષકોની સાથે મંચ ઉપર ઉપસ્થિત થતાં જ સૌ પર ફલની વૃષ્ટિ કરવામાં આવી. આચાર્ય, વરિષ્ઠ શિક્ષકો અને વિદ્યાર્થીઓ વતી એક પ્રતિનિધિઓ મળીને દીપ પ્રાકટ્ય કર્યું. એ પછી પાયલ દેસાઈએ ગુરુપૂર્ણિમાનું મહત્ત્વ સમજાવતાં કહ્યું, “અજ્ઞાનરૂપી અંધકારમાંથી જે જ્ઞાનરૂપી પ્રકાશ તરફ લઈ જાય તે સાચા ગુરુ. આપણા સૌના સદ્દનસીબે આપણને સાચા ગુરુ મળ્યા છે.તેમણે આપણા સૌમાં સંસ્કારના અને જ્ઞાનનાં બીજા રોપ્યાં છે. તેમનું ઋણ યથાશક્તિ ચૂકવવા આપણે સૌ અહીં ભેગાં થયાં છીએ”. સૌએ ઊભા થઈ આચાર્ય અને શિક્ષકોને નમન કર્યા અને હું એમના આશીર્વાદ મેળવ્યા. એ પછી શાળાના આચાર્ય અને વરિષ્ઠ શિક્ષકે પ્રસંગોચિત વક્તવ્ય રજૂ કર્યું. આચાર્ય અને દરેક શિક્ષકનું શાલ અને ફુલતોરાથી સમ્માન કરવામાં આવ્યું.અંતમાં સુયશ શાળાના આચાર્ય, શિક્ષકો, શાળાના તમામ કર્મચારીઓ તેમજ આ ઉત્સવને સફળ બનાવવામાં સાથ આપનાર નાનામોટા સૌનો આભાર માન્યો. એ પછી ભોજન સાથે આ કાર્યક્રમ પૂર્ણ થયો."},{"question":"ස්පාඤ්ඤයේ ජාතික සංකේතය වනුයේ කුමක්ද?","answer":"ස්පාඤ්ඤයේ ජාතික සංකේතය වනුයේ රතු කානේෂන්‌ මලයි. ස්පාඤ්ඤය, නිල වශයෙන් ස්පාඤ්ඤ රාජධානිය ලෙස හැඳින්වෙන්නේ නිරිතදිග යුරෝපයේ අයිබීරියන් අර්ධද්වීපයේ පිහිටි ස්වෛරී රාජ්‍යයකි. එය සතු දූපත් මධ්‍යධරණී මුහුදේ සහ අත්ලන්තික් සාගරයේ පවතී. තවද ස්පාඤ්ඤ රාජධානියට අයත් භූමිප්‍රදේශ උතුරු අප්‍රිකානු වෙරළාසන්නයේ ද පිහිටා ඇත."},{"question":"Inona no loko mahazatra mifandray amin'ny mpanjaka sy ny andriana?a) Mangab) volomparasyd) Orangee) Volondavenina","answer":"b) volomparasy no loko mahazatra mifandray amin'ny mpanjaka sy ny andriana"},{"question":"Alaharo araka ny tokony ho izy ireto fanao  ireto : fanambadiana, mivoaka itany, fandevenana, famoràna, famadihana.","answer":"Toy izao ny filaharanan'ireo fanao ireo : mivoaka itany, famoràna, fanambadiana, fandevenana, famadihana."},{"question":"Faa’iidada Shaaha Cagaaran (Green Tea).","answer":"Faa’iidada Shaaha Cagaaran (Green Tea).Waa maxay faa’iidada shaaha cagaaran (green tea)? Muxuu faa’iido u leeyahay shaaha cagaaran dhanka caafimaadka? Jawaabta waa mid fudud. Markad aad bilaawdo cabista shaaha cagaaran waxaad caafimaadkaaga ka dareemi doonto waxyaabo badan oo aan halkaan ku xusi doono. Faa’iidada shaaha cagaaran ee afka qalaad lagu yiraahdo green tea dad badan oo inaga mid ah waxba kama ogo, waana sababta keentay in aan halkaan ugu faa’iideyno.1. Shaaha cagaaran (green tea)  iyo caafimaadka guud.Shaaha cagaaran waxa uu maskaxda ka ilaaliyaa asaasaq iyo guud ahaan calaamadaha gabowga.Hadaad rabto in aad u ekaato 20 jir deeqsan ah oo jalaqsan, badso cabida shaaha cagaaran.  Haddii aan nahay Soomaali, runtii wey nagu yartahay cabista shaaha cagaaran mana garaneyno faaiidadiisa. Marka laga soo tago faa’iidada shaaha cagaaran waxaa inoo sii dheer marka aan shaah cabeyno in aan isticmaalno sokor aad u fara badan, taasoo aanan u fiicaneyn caafimaadka guud.2. Soomaalida iyo shaaha cagaaran.Waxaa inta badan la sheegaa in dadka ugu badan ee Soomaalida ah ee isticmaalo shaaha cagaaran in ay yihiin Soomaalida ku nool qurbaha gaar ahaan Soomaalida Minnesota. Tolow Farxiyo Kabayare iyo Hodan Cabdiraxmaan maka mid yihiin?Dhanka kale shaaha cagaaran aad loogama isticmaalo dalkeena Somalia, maxaa yeelay dadka inta badan uma lahan wax dhadhan ah, waana sababta ay ku doorbidaan cabista caleenta shaaha madow.Shaaha cagaaran waxaa ku jiro maaddooyin awood u leh in ay gaaraan maskaxda oo ay ka hortagaan in barootiinta dhibaatada ku keenysaa ay ku uruurto, waana sababta ay culimada saynisku u sheegayaan in Shaaha Cagaaran uu ka hortag u yahay isku-dhex daadashada maskaxda iyo in xusuustu ay yaraato, sidoo kale waxaa ku jira maaddo afka cilmiga lagu yiraahdo EGCG oo yareysa mid ka midah xanuunnada ugu khatarsan ee dumarka ku dhaca , kaasoo ah lafo-burburka. Intaas waxaa sii dheer sida daraasadaha cusub sheegayaan in shaaha cagaaran oo yareeya gabowga maqaarka, kana ilaaliya raadka khatarta ah ee kaga iman kara fallaaraha qorraxda.3. Shaaha cagaaran wuxuu kaa saacidayaa dhimista miisaanka.Haddii aad tahay qof cayilan oo cayilka ka batay, midana aad dooneyso waxyaabaha miisaanka yareeya ama sida cayilka loo dhimo, shaaha cagaaran aad buu kuu anfacayaa. Haddii aad sidoo kale raadineyso waxyaabaha lagu cayilo, shaaha caraan miisaan uun buu kaa dhimayaa ee kuguma siyaadinayo.  Faa’iidada shaaha cagaaran, waxauu gubaa dufanka iyo xaydha jidhka ku ururta, waxa uu dhimaa doonista cuntada, calashaan wuuu kaa xirayaa amateedka, baahi fara badan kuma qabaneyso, taasina waxa ay kuu suurto galineysaa in aad qaadato kalooriinka laguugu talo galay in ka yar, arrimahaas oo dhammaantood ka qayb qaata dhimista miisaanka.4. Yareynta ilawga iyo GariirkaShaaha cagaaran ayaa qeyb weyn ka qaata inuu hormariyo shaqada maskada, waxaa kale oo uu ka hortagaa in ay gabawdo. Alzheimer’s waa xanuun waxyeeleeya neerfayaasha waxaanu badanaa ku dhaca dadka, xanuunka oo keena dementia.Parkinson’s xanuunkan ayaa ah kan labaad ee ugu badan dunida kuna dhaca neerfayaasha waxa lala xidhiidhiyaa inuu dilo unugyada soo saara dopamine ee maskaxda.5. Waxa uu ka hortagaa burooyinka kansarka ahCilmibaadhisaha ugu waaweyn ee lagu sameeyey shaaha cagaarani waxa ay isku waafaqsan yihiin in uu yareeyo heerka khatarta ah in qofka uu ku dhaco cudurka kansarka.In kasta oo ay jiraan saynisyahanno kale oo iyagu dood ka qaba in uu shaaha cagaarani awooddaas inta le’eg leeyahay, haddana sida lagu ogaaday daraasad soo baxday sannadkii 2015 ka, waxa ay khubarada sayniska badankoodu aaminsan yihiin in shaahacagaarani uu yareeyo suurtogalnimada in qofka kansar ku dhaco, maadaama oo uu la dagaalamo koritaanka xidhmooyika iyo wasladaha kansarka, haddii ay qofka hayaanna u u diido in ay jidhka ku faafaan.6. Shaaha Cagaaran waxa uu afka ka kaxeeyaa urtaShaaha cagaaran waxa uu gaar u leeyahay awood dili karta dhammaan bakteeriyada afka ku dhalata, sidaa awgeed waxa uu ka hortagaa in ilkaha uu ku samaysmo lakabka dhagaxa ah, waxa uuna kor u qaadaa caafimaadka cirridka.7. Wuxuu la dagaalama cudurka Caabuqa/ InfekshankaSida lagu sheegay daraasado xidhiidh ah waxaa uu shaaha cagaran uu la dagaalamo bakateriyooyinka qaar, gaar ahaana kuwa afka ku dhasha sida sterptoccocus mutans iyo qeyb ka mid ah viruska keena Durayga/Hargabka ee influenza virus.8. Wuxuu kaa caawinayaa ka hortaga macaankaWaxa uu ka caawiyaa ganaca inuu soo saaro insulin ku filan isaga fudeydiya in xadiga sonkorta ah ee dhiiga la dhimo. 48% japan.9. Caafimaadka Wadnaha ayuu sara u qaadaaShaaha cagaaran waxa uu sara u qaadaaa caafimaadka wadnaha, waxa uuna difaaaa xanuunada ku dhaca wadnaha, waxa uu sidoo kale shaaha cagaaran hoos u dhigaa duxda dhiiga sida cholesterol sha.10. Talada caafimaadkaHadaba badso shaaha cagaaran, si uu caafimaadkaaga u noqdo mid wanaagsan. Xusuusnow caafimaadka waa sheey qaali ah, waana wax aan la iibsan karin balse waa lagu dadaali karaa. Haddii aad maanta bilaawdo cabista shaaha cagaaran, waxaa suurto gal ah in aad noloshaada ku dhameysto nolol caafimaad leh, waana tan qof walbaa uu rajeeyo."},{"question":"Maxay yihiin nafaqeeyayaalka yar yar?","answer":"Nafaqeeyayaalka yar yar waa nafaqeeyayaalka muhiimka u ah koritaan caafimaad leh ee jirka iyo horumarkiisaba, hase yeeshee jirku wuxuu uga baahan yahay xadiyo yaryar. Waxay doormuhiim ah ka ciyaaraan shaqooyinka Jirka ka socda. Waxay saameeyaan wax soo saarka dadka waa weyn (Qaangaarka), u adkeysig acudurada, horumarka waxbarasho (cognitive development), badbaadada ilmaha iyo caafimaadka hooyada. Nafaqeeyayaalka yar yaree Muhiimka ah. Iron, Vitamin A, Iodine,Vitamin C and Zinc."},{"question":"Andersen đã sáng tác bao nhiêu truyện cổ tích?","answer":"Andersen đã viết 156 truyện cổ tíchtrong sự nghiệp, Andersen đã viết 156 truyện cổ tích, in trong 9 tập và được dịch ra hơn 120 ngôn ngữ. Nếu tính cả tiểu thuyết và các cuốn sách nói về kinh nghiệm sống, du lịch, Andersen để lại 168 tác phẩm. Với số lượng lớn truyện cổ tích để lại, ông được coi đã giúp tuổi thơ của nhiều thế hệ trẻ em có thêm màu sắc, hướng đến những điều tích cực, tốt đẹp.Andersen chủ yếu sáng tác trong giai đoạn 1835-1870 và gần như không viết thêm được gì trong những ngày cuối đời. Khi bị rụng chiếc răng cuối cùng vào năm 1873, ông đã ghi vào nhật ký: \\"Những câu chuyện kỳ diệu không tới cùng tôi nữa. Tôi chỉ còn lại trơ trọi một mình\\". Andersen qua đời ngày 1/8/1875 tại biệt thự Rolighed ở thủ đô Copenhaghen, Đan Mạch. Ông được an táng tại nghĩa trang Assistens trong cùng thành phố."},{"question":"පළමු වැනි ලෝක යුද්ධය පැවති කාල සීමාව?","answer":"1914 සිට 1918"},{"question":"शेतकऱ्याचे आत्मवृत्त.","answer":"मला शाळेला सुट्टी लागली होती म्हणून आम्ही आमच्या गावी जायचे ठरवले, आम्ही फारसे आमच्या गावात जात नाही कारण बाबा इथे शहरात नोकरी करतात, पूर्वी बाबांचे वडील म्हणजे माझे आजोबा शेती करायचे. माझ्या गावात सगळे शेतकरी आहेत पण आम्ही आता शेती करत नाही.मी गाव मदे बाहेर पडला आणि इकडे-तिकडे फिरू लागला आणि एका झाडा खाली बसला तिथेच एक शेतकरी बसला होतो त्यांनी मला काही प्रश्न विचारले जसे तू कोण आहे ? कोणाचा मुलगा ? त्यांणी जेव्हा मला ओळखले तेव्हा मी त्यांना शेती बदल विचारले आणि त्यांनी मला त्यांचे मनोगत सांगायला सुरवात किले.मी तुकाराम आणि हि संपूर्ण शेती माझी आहे, आमचे घर संपूर्णपाने शेती वरच अवलंभून आहे, माझेच नाही तर सर्व गावातील शेतकरी शेती वरच अवलंभून आहेत. आज शेती पहिल्या सारखी राहिली नाही, पहिले माझे वडील आणि मी शेती करायला खूप कष्ट करत असे पण आता शेती तितकी अवघड राहिली नाही.आज शेतीत पूर्वी इतके कष्ट करावे लागत नाही, सर्व सोई आहेत आत्ता तर. पहिले आम्ही नांगराने जे काम करत होते ते आता ट्रक्टर ने करतो ते अगदि जलद होते आणि जास्ती काही मेहनत हि करावी लागत नाही. ते माझे ट्रक्टर तिथे उभे आहे. शेतकऱ्यांना आता सरकार ची खूप साथ आहे.शेतकऱ्यांना शेती साठी योग्य बियाणे, खत सरकार द्वारे पुरवले जातात पहिला इथे पाण्या साठी काही सोय नोव्हती पण आता इथे पंप बसवले आहेत ज्याने आम्हा शेतकऱ्यांना खूप मदत मिळते. वेळो वेळी आता जमिनीचे नमुने घेऊन खताचा वापर कसा आणि किती करावा कधी कोणत्या पिकांची लाघवड करावी ह्याची सर्व सोय सरकारने शेतकऱ्यांन साठी केली आहे.आता प्रतेक गावात आम्हा शेतकऱ्यांच्या संघटना आहेत ज्याच्या सहायाने आम्हला शेती तील पिकाला योग्य मान-धन मिळतो. तीन महिन्यातून एकदा ह्या संघटने द्वारा काही कार्यक्रम आयोजित केले जातात, जिथे आम्हाला आधुनिक शेतीची माहिती दिली जाते आणि शेतीच्या नवीन पदधती शिकवल्या जातात. आम्हाला ह्या कार्यक्रमाचा भरपूर फायदा होतो.आम्ही शेतकरी शेती तर करतोच पण त्या बरोबर आम्ही ह्या गायी, म्हशी, बकर्या आणि कोंबड्या हि पाळतो ह्याचा आम्हला फार फयदा होतो शेती साठी उत्कृष्ट शेण खत हि मिळते त्याबरोबर दुध आणि अंडी तर आम्ही विकतोच.आता शेती आणि शेतकरी पूर्वी सारखे राहिले नाही ते बग माझे घर, माझी गाडी आणि माझी मुले आता मोठ्या कॉलेज मधे डिग्री घेत आहेत ते हि शेतीवरच. आता शेती हा एक मोठा व्यवसाय झाला आहे आणि मला हा शेतीचा व्यवसाय करायला आवडतो आणि मला सरकारची साथ असल्याने मी उत्कृष्ट शेती करतो.असे मनोगत मला तुकारम काकांनी सांगितले हे ह्या शेतकऱ्याचे आत्मवृत्त ऐकून मला देखील शेती मधे आवड निर्माण झाली आहे."},{"question":"3/5 बाट 1/4 घटाउनुहोस् र परिणामलाई सरलीकृत अंशको रूपमा व्यक्त गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"भिन्नहरू घटाउनको लागि, एउटा साझा भाजक फेला पार्नुहोस्, जुन यस अवस्थामा 20 हो। त्यसैले, (3/5) - (1/4) = (12/20) - (5/20) = 7/20।"},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਅਸਟਪਦੀ ॥ਮਾਨੁਖ ਕੀ ਟੇਕ ਬ੍ਰਿਥੀ ਸਭ ਜਾਨੁ ॥ਦੇਵਨ ਕਉ ਏਕੈ ਭਗਵਾਨੁ ॥ਜਿਸ ਕੈ ਦੀਐ ਰਹੈ ਅਘਾਇ ॥ਬਹੁਰਿ ਨ ਤ੍ਰਿਸਨਾ ਲਾਗੈ ਆਇ ॥ਮਾਰੈ ਰਾਖੈ ਏਕੋ ਆਪਿ ॥ਮਾਨੁਖ ਕੈ ਕਿਛੁ ਨਾਹੀ ਹਾਥਿ ॥ਤਿਸ ਕਾ ਹੁਕਮੁ ਬੂਝਿ ਸੁਖੁ ਹੋਇ ॥ਤਿਸ ਕਾ ਨਾਮੁ ਰਖੁ ਕੰਠਿ ਪਰੋਇ ॥ਸਿਮਰਿ ਸਿਮਰਿ ਸਿਮਰਿ ਪ੍ਰਭੁ ਸੋਇ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਬਿਘਨੁ ਨ ਲਾਗੈ ਕੋਇ ॥੧॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 281 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਹੇ ਮਨ!) (ਕਿਸੇ) ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦਾ ਆਸਰਾ ਉੱਕਾ ਹੀ ਵਿਅਰਥ ਸਮਝ, ਇਕ ਅਕਾਲ ਪੁਰਖ ਹੀ (ਸਭ ਜੀਆਂ ਨੂੰ) ਦੇਣ ਜੋਗਾ ਹੈ;ਜਿਸ ਦੇ ਦਿੱਤਿਆਂ (ਮਨੁੱਖ) ਰੱਜਿਆ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਮੁੜ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਲਾਲਚ ਆ ਕੇ ਦਬਾਉਂਦਾ ਨਹੀਂ ।ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਆਪ ਹੀ (ਜੀਵਾਂ ਨੂੰ) ਮਾਰਦਾ ਹੈ (ਜਾਂ) ਪਾਲਦਾ ਹੈ, ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੇ ਵੱਸ ਕੁਝ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੈ ।ਉਸ ਮਾਲਕ ਦਾ ਹੁਕਮ ਸਮਝ ਕੇ ਸੁਖ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ । ਉਸ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਹਰ ਵੇਲੇ ਯਾਦ ਕਰ ।ਉਸ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨੂੰ ਸਦਾ ਸਿਮਰ । ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ! (ਸਿਮਰਨ ਦੀ ਬਰਕਤਿ ਨਾਲ) (ਜ਼ਿੰਦਗੀ ਦੇ ਸਫ਼ਰ ਵਿਚ) ਕੋਈ ਰੁਕਾਵਟ ਨਹੀਂ ਪੈਂਦੀ ।੧।\\""},{"question":"Menene teku mafi girma a duniya?","answer":"Tekun Pasifik ne mafi girma."},{"question":"Apakah maksud dan contoh ayat untuk \\"bagai kambing diseret ke air\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud \\"orang yang enggan mengerjakan sesuatu pekerjaan.\\" Contoh ayatnya ialah \\"kami sudah tidak mahu bekerjasama dengan  Laila kerana dia bersikap bagai kambing diseret ke air apabila disuruh melakukan sesuatu tugas.\\""},{"question":"Hãy đặt một tiêu đề phù hợp với đoạn văn sau: Bảng xếp hạng của Báo cáo Hạnh phúc Thế giới năm 2022 phần lớn dựa trên những đánh giá về cuộc sống từ Cuộc thăm dò của Gallup World. Theo CNN, Phần Lan là quốc gia xếp hạng đầu. Các nước láng giềng Đan Mạch, Na Uy, Thụy Điển và Iceland đều đạt điểm rất cao về các chỉ số quan trọng như: tuổi thọ trung bình, GDP bình quân đầu người, hỗ trợ xã hội trong thời kỳ khó khăn, tham nhũng thấp và lòng tin xã hội cao, lòng vị tha và quyền tự do đưa ra các quyết định quan trọng trong cuộc sống. Đan Mạch đứng ở vị trí thứ 2 trong bảng xếp hạng năm nay, tiếp theo là Iceland ở vị trí thứ 3. Thụy Điển và Na Uy lần lượt đứng thứ 7 và 8. Vậy đâu là bí quyết để sưởi ấm trái tim và rèn luyện sức khỏe của người dân xứ sở này? Quan điểm của người dân vùng Bắc Âu luôn đề cao phong cách sống đơn giản cùng phẩm chất khiêm nhường. Họ sống tiết kiệm, ăn uống thanh đạm và dùng đồ giản dị. Khi một đứa trẻ chào đời, bạn bè, hàng xóm sẽ tặng lại cho em bé những bộ quần áo cũ đã được giặt ủi thơm tho. Chính những điều thường nhật này đã làm nên một phong cách sinh hoạt đặc trưng. Thay vì xây nhà cao cửa rộng, sắm siêu xe đắt tiền, người Bắc Âu thường không đặt nặng vật chất. Mọi người chú trọng cuộc sống tự nhiên, chừng mực và hướng đến sự cân bằng, hài hòa. Do đó, họ thích sống trong những ngôi nhà tiện nghi vừa đủ, di chuyển bằng xe đạp hoặc ô tô cá nhân cỡ nhỏ hơn. Phương châm cuộc sống của họ là \\"Tiền không thể không có nhưng không nhất thiết phải có quá nhiều, cơm không thể không ăn nhưng không nhất thiết phải ăn quá ngon.\\" Do đó, người dân Bắc Âu luôn tìm thấy niềm vui từ những điều bé nhỏ, giản dị nhất. Họ không cần tất bật làm thêm, mải mê kiếm tiền mà thong thả thư giãn tại nhà hoặc đi uống cà phê cùng bè bạn khi có thời gian rảnh. Gia đình là nền tảng vững chắc của một cuộc sống thành công và hạnh phúc. Đây là điều mà ai cũng ý thức được. Nhưng với người Bắc Âu, tầm quan trọng của gia đình được họ ưu tiên hàng đầu. Sau giờ làm, đàn ông Bắc Âu luôn chủ động chơi đùa cùng con hay phụ vợ nấu ăn, dọn dẹp. Nếu công việc còn chưa hoàn thành, người chồng cũng sẽ lựa chọn tăng ca vào lúc nửa đêm để dành thời gian chăm sóc gia đình trước nhất. Trong một cuộc phỏng vấn với Insider, Fanny Aberg, đến từ Phần Lan và hiện đang sống tại Thụy Điển, đã mô tả tư duy của người Bắc Âu và sự khác biệt trong lối sống - văn hóa làm việc so với các quốc gia khác. \\"Gia đình luôn là trên hết\\", Aberg nói. \\"Giờ làm việc được tùy chỉnh linh hoạt để đảm bảo bạn có đủ thời gian cho gia đình.\\" Cô chia sẻ, mình tắt máy tính và rời văn phòng vào lúc 4 giờ chiều để đón con từ nhà trẻ, dành cả buổi chiều tối để chơi cùng con, sau đó cả nhà ăn tối với nhau. \\"Nếu vẫn còn việc phải làm, bạn có thể hoàn thành nó sau khi bọn trẻ đã đi ngủ\\", cô khẳng định. Theo pháp luật Phần Lan, nam giới được nghỉ thai sản trong vòng 9 tuần và nhận 70% tiền lương trung bình trong giai đoạn này. Vào mỗi kỳ nghỉ, các gia đình đều có thói quen cùng nhau sum họp ăn uống, đi dã ngoại, tắm biển, trượt tuyết, cưỡi ngựa… Khi được hỏi từ nào mô tả \\"văn hóa làm việc ở Bắc Âu\\", Aberg nhận định bằng những từ như: cởi mở, trung thực, cá nhân và minh bạch. \\"Tại nơi làm việc, chúng tôi đảm bảo sự chuyên nghiệp, nhưng không cứng nhắc\\", cô nói. \\"Nếu bạn tình cờ gặp ai đó mặc một chiếc quần jean và áo hoodie ở hành lang, đó có thể là một nhân viên, cũng có thể chính là CEO.\\" Các công ty ở các nước Bắc Âu có xu hướng ít phân cấp hơn, Aberg nói. \\"Ở đây, mọi người đều có tiếng nói, dù là cấp cơ sở hay cấp quản lý. Hệ thống như vậy giúp chúng tôi có thể làm việc hiệu quả hơn.\\" Aberg cũng cho biết, công ty có rất nhiều cuộc họp nhưng thường diễn ra nhanh chóng, không dài dòng. Đặc biệt, mọi người còn có thời gian dành cho \\"fika\\". Đây là thói quen \\"quốc dân\\" vốn đã thấm nhuần vào nền văn hóa Thụy Điển từ bao đời nay, sau đó lan rộng trong khu vực Bắc Âu. Khái niệm này mô tả khoảnh khắc giải lao tuy ngắn ngủi nhưng trọn vẹn niềm vui bên tách cà phê ấm áp cùng những chiếc bánh ngọt thơm ngon. Khoảng thời gian ý nghĩa này giúp mọi người thư giãn, kết nối, xốc lại tinh thần để tiếp tục công việc, góp phần tăng cường mức độ hài lòng, hạnh phúc. Tắm hơi vốn là một phong tục truyền thống đặc trưng, góp phần xây dựng dấu ấn thương hiệu của đất nước Na Uy, Đan Mạch, Thụy Điển… Hoạt động này phổ biến đến mức có tới gần 2 triệu phòng tắm hơi ở Phần Lan, trong khi dân số tại đây chỉ khoảng 5,5 triệu người. Hầu như mọi người đều yêu thích hoạt động này vì nó giúp giảm cân, loại bỏ độc tố, tạo giấc ngủ ngon, thư giãn tinh thần, cải thiện hệ thống miễn dịch cũng như tăng cường sức khỏe tim mạch. Tại các quốc gia Bắc Âu, hình ảnh người dân đi lại bằng xe đạp là vô cùng phổ biến. Thói quen này vừa tiện lợi, tiết kiệm, rèn luyện sức khỏe và không gây ô nhiễm môi trường, lại vừa được coi là một phần truyền thống đáng trân trọng, tự hào của mọi người. Đan Mạch được mệnh danh là vương quốc của những người đạp xe khi có tới 90% dân số sở hữu phương tiện này. Bất chấp điều kiện thời tiết, họ thường xuyên đạp xe đi làm, dạo chơi, cắm trại, thậm chí là vận chuyển hàng hóa nếu có thể. Người Thụy Điển cũng yêu thích việc đi xe đạp đến nỗi họ có nhiều làn đường khang trang dành riêng cho phương tiện này cùng hệ thống cho thuê – chia sẻ xe đạp rộng khắp. Thủ đô Stockholm và thành phố Malmö của đất nước này luôn thuộc top 10 trong danh sách những đô thị lý tưởng nhất đối với tín đồ xe đạp trên toàn thế giới. Chế độ ăn truyền thống của cư dân Bắc Âu luôn tuân thủ những bí quyết đảm bảo cuộc sống khỏe mạnh và hạnh phúc. Khẩu phần ăn của họ giàu đạm, ít béo và hạn chế tinh bột, thường bao gồm cá thu, cá trích, cá hồi cùng bánh mì lúa mạch và rau củ theo mùa. Các dịch vụ ăn uống, nhà hàng tại đây đều cam kết sử dụng nguyên liệu hữu cơ tươi ngon, bổ dưỡng. Tiêu chuẩn vệ sinh và an toàn thực phẩm được đặt lên hàng đầu để đảm bảo sức khỏe cho thực khách. Đặc biệt, khu vực Bắc Âu cũng là nơi sản xuất nguồn nhiên liệu sạch hàng đầu thế giới. Chẳng hạn như, 98% sản lượng điện của Na Uy đến từ năng lượng tái tạo, chủ yếu là thủy điện, gió, địa nhiệt. Hơn 50% lượng điện tiêu thụ của Thụy Điển có nguồn gốc là năng lượng xanh. Nhờ vào việc chủ động sản xuất và tái tạo năng lượng, bầu không khí của khu vực Bắc Âu luôn trong lành, sạch sẽ. Điều này góp phần làm giảm đáng kể nguy cơ đột quỵ, bệnh tim mạch và ung thư phổi ở người dân. *Theo BI, CNN…","answer":"Bí quyết sống hạnh phúc nhất thế giới của người Bắc Âu: Coi trọng phẩm chất hơn vật chất, gia đình hơn công việc"},{"question":"नेपालको अक्षांश रेखा कुन हो ?","answer":"नेपालको अक्षांश रेखा २६ डिग्री २२ उत्तर- ३० डिग्री २७ उत्तर हो।"},{"question":"આ કહેવત નો અર્થ જાણવો: \\"લોભિયા હોય ત્યાં ધુતારા ભૂખે ન મરે.\\"","answer":"આ કહેવતનો અર્થ એ છે કે જ્યાં લોભી હોય છે, ત્યાં ધુતારાઓને ભોગ બનવાની તકો વધુ હોય છે. લોભી લોકો હંમેશા વધુ મેળવવા માટે ઉત્સુક હોય છે, અને તેઓ સરળતાથી ધુતારાઓના શિકાર બને છે. ધુતારાઓ એવા લોકો હોય છે જેઓ લોભી લોકોની લાલચનો ફાયદો ઉઠાવવાનો પ્રયાસ કરે છે.આ કહેવતનુ ઉદાહરણ: જો કોઈ લોભી વ્યક્તિ કોઈ ધુતારા વ્યક્તિને ઉછીના પૈસા આપે છે, તો તે લોભી આપેલા પૈસા પર વ્યાજ વસૂલવાનો પ્રયાસ કરશે. પરંતુ વધારે પૈસા મળવાના ચક્કરમા (એટલે કે વ્યાજ આવશે) એવુ બની શકે કે ધૂતારો પૈસા લઇ ને જતો રહે અને લોભીને પોતાના પૈસા પાછા જ ના મળે."},{"question":"Алыкул Осмоновтун калемине таандык ыр саптардан жазып бере аласыңбы ?","answer":"БИРГЕ ЖҮРДҮКБирге жүрдүк бирге жайлап, бир айлап,Кайык минсек сен олтуруп, мен айдап,Мен арчадай жаш эсебин билгизбей,Сен кайыңдай жаңы гана бүр байлап.Уялбадым тартынчактык кылбадым,Шек билгизип, атыңды атап ырдадым.Тик карабай, чырайыма, түсүмө,Сен уялып жерди карап кызардың.Кетпейт, кетпейт ал уяттын кызылы,Мына ошондо ашыктыктын кызыгы.Кубартпаса, бозортпосо кокустанФрунзенин аптабы курч ысыгы."},{"question":"จงเขียนประโยคต่อจากข้อความต่อไปนี้ - ในช่วงที่ตกอยู่ใต้การปกครองของจักรวรรดิอะคีเมนิด เซสทอสและบิแซนเทียมเป็นสองเมืองท่าที่สำคัญของจักรวรรดิ ในปี 480 ก่อนคริสต์ศักราช กองทัพของจักรพรรดิเซิร์กซีสมหาราชใช้จุดนี้ข้ามช่องแคบเฮลเลสปอนต์ด้วยสะพานลอยน้ำเพื่อไปทำสงครามกับนครรัฐกรีซ","answer":"เช่นเดียวกับกองทัพพระเจ้าอเล็กซานเดอร์มหาราชที่ใช้จุดนี้ข้ามช่องแคบด้วยเรือในปี 334 ก่อนคริสต์ศักราช"},{"question":"次の文章に書かれている内容に基づいて、少なくとも200語の段落を書いてください。： 日本で初めてのジェット機　開発はできなかった","answer":"三菱重工業は、客を乗せて飛ぶジェット機を日本で初めてつくるため、2008年に開発を始めました。国も500億円を出して協力していました。しかし、技術が足りなくて、開発は計画のとおりに進みませんでした。航空会社にジェット機を渡す約束にも何度も遅れました。三菱重工業は7日、開発をやめると言いました。開発を続けるために1年に1000億円ぐらいかかることや、ジェット機ができても、売って利益を出すのが難しいことなどが理由です。国も協力して日本の技術でジェット機をつくる計画は、成功することができませんでした。"},{"question":"Yaushe aka rushe majalisar masu kishin kasa ta Asturian?","answer":"An rushe majalisar masu kishin kasa ta Asturian a shekarar 1976."},{"question":"ලොව මිල අධිකතම දොඩම් වර්ගය ","answer":"ඩෙකොපොන්"},{"question":" இப் போர் எரிமலை மற்றும் ரியுகுயு தீவுக் கூட்டத்தில் நடைபெற்றது. இப்போரின் முக்கிய சண்டைகளாக இவோ ஜீமா சண்டை (பெப்ரவரி 16-மார்ச் 26, 1945) ஒகினவா சண்டை (ஏப்ரல் 1-ஜூன் 21, 1945) என்பவற்றையும் முக்கிய கடற் சமராக","answer":"தென்கோ நடவடிக்கையையும் குறிப்பிடலாம்."},{"question":"س174- إمتى بدات الحرب العالمية الثانية ؟","answer":"ج174- 1939"},{"question":"Awọn alagbara to ju temi lọ lo wa nidii iṣẹlẹ to ṣẹlẹ ni Lẹkki-Sanwo-Olu","answer":"Gomina ipinle Eko, Babajide Sanwo-Olu ti sọ pe awọn agbara kan to ju toun lọ lo wa nidii iṣẹlẹ aburu to ṣẹlẹ ni Lẹkki lọjọ Iṣẹgun, Tusidee, ọsẹ yii, nibi ti awọn ọlọpaa ti dana ibọn fun awọn oluwọde ti wọn duro soju kan naa, ti mọkandinlaaadọta si ku ninu wọn, ti ọpọ ninu wọn fara pa.Gomina ni, ‘‘Aṣaalẹ ọjọ Iṣẹgun yii jẹ aṣaalẹ to lagbara ju ninu itan ilẹ wa, nigba ti awọn alagbara ti agbara wa ko ka, ti agbara wọn ju tiwa lọ waa fi itan buruku balẹ fun wa. Ṣugbọn a ṣetan lati koju rẹ, a oo si jade kuro ninu iṣoro naa gẹgẹ bii akọni ju bi a ṣe wa bayii lọ.‘‘Mo ṣẹṣẹ pari abẹwo kaakiri awọn ileewosan ti wọn gbe awọn to fara gba ninu ijamba naa lọ ni.‘‘Awọn mẹwaa lo wa nileewosan ijọba, mọkanla wa ni ileewosan Reddington, awọn mẹrin ti ipalara wọn ko pọ pupọ wa ni Vedic, nigba ti awọn meji mi-in wa nibi ti wọn ti n gba itọju pajawiri, iyẹn ẹka to jẹ pe ọwọ Ọlọrun nikan ni ẹmi wọn wa.‘‘Awọn mẹta ni wọn ti da silẹ lọsibitu pe ki wọn maa lọ sile. A maa tẹsiwaju lati maa ṣamojuto awọn to wa nileewosan yii lati ri i pe wọn gba itọju to peye.‘‘Gẹgẹ bii gomina, mo mọ pe gbogbo ẹbi ọrọ yii, ori mi lo wa, ṣugbon mo maa ṣiṣẹ pẹlu ijọba apapọ lati ri i pe a ridii okodoro ọrọ naa, ki a si ri i pe eto aabo to dara fẹsẹ mulẹ lati daabo bo ẹmi ati dukia awọn araalu.’’"},{"question":"માધવ રામાનુજ \\"ઘેલી ગોવાલણ\\" કવિતા લખો.","answer":"હો તેઁ તો મટકીમાં મૂક્યું અંકાશ, ઘેલી ગોવાલણહોં તેં તો આખ્યું આંજ્યો ઉજાસ, ઘેલી ગોવાલણકોરી મટકી મહીં ભરેલી છલક છલક થાયપાંપણ જેવી પાંપણ વચ્ચે દરિયા હિલોળાય.મારગ મળીયા માધવ ગોપી આકળ વિકળ થાયતન તો એનું તરણા જેવું વાંસળી થઈ વાય.હો મોરપીંછાનો મુકટ લહેરાય, ઘેલી ગોવાલણતારી મનમાં મન ના માય, ઘેલી ગોવાલણતને કાનુડે નજરી ન્યાલી રે, હો રસ લેવા છેઅલી આવી તું ક્યાંથી રૂપાળી રે, દલડા દેવા છેભાન ભૂલી ગઈ આંખડી ઢાલી રે, હો રસ લેવા છેપછી અંદર ને બહાર વનમાળી રે, દલડાં દેવા છેહો તું ગોરીને મટકી કાળી, ઘેલી ગોવાલણકાન બેઠા કદંબની ડાલી, ઘેલી ગોવાલણમહીંને બદલે માધવ લ્યો રે, વેચે રજની નારકોણ મુલવે મૂલ અમુલા, કૌતક અપરંપારગોકુળ ગોરસ વનરાવન ને હૈયાનાં ધબકારઆસુંની યમુના ઓળંગી કોણ ઉતર્યું પારહો તેં કેવા તે સાંધ્યા રે તાર, ઘેલી ગોવાલણત્રીભુવનમાં થઈ ગઈ કાર, ઘેલી ગોવાલણ"},{"question":"Oraah.","answer":"Dhib maleh in aad keligaa noqotid xilliyada qaar, waayo kelinnimadu marar badanwaxa ay ku siisaa awood iyo geesinnimo."},{"question":"प्रश्न : दिइएका शब्दको अर्थ लेख्नुहोस् :भरोसा , जमदार , गर्व ","answer":"उत्तर  :भरोसा ➡ आश्रयजमदार ➡ जमादारगर्व ➡ मै जान्ने सुन्ने हुँ भन्ने घमण्ड"},{"question":"Kodi mtundu wa gwape wamkulu kwambiri ku Africa ndi chiyani?","answer":"Kodi eland ndi chiyani? Nyama yooneka ngati ng’ombe ndiyo mtundu wa gwape yaikulu kwambiri padziko lonse lapansi. Komabe, ili ndi chipiriro chosunga mayendedwe mpaka kalekale ndipo imatha kudumpha mpanda wa 1.5 mita (4 mapazi) kuchokera pakuyima. Zonse zazimuna ndi zazikazi zili ndi nyanga zomwe zimazungulira mwamphamvu, ngakhale kuti nyanga zazikazi zimakhala zazitali komanso zowonda."},{"question":"ما إسم زوجة الرسول التي توفيت بعده وقبل سائر زوجاته ؟","answer":" السيدة زينب بنت جحش"},{"question":"Terjemahkanlah penggalan teks Bahasa Inggris yang disadur dari kumpulan cerita anak dunia berikut ke teks dalam Bahasa Indonesia.At first, Toot-Toot was scared of the water. But when she saw all the other goats splashing around, she jumped in!Terjemahan:","answer":"Semula, Toot-Toot takut air. Namun, ketika dia lihat kambing-kambing lainnya bermain air, dia ikut menceburkan diri. "},{"question":"Qual é a capital do estado da Bahia?","answer":"Salvador."},{"question":"සාදික්කා යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"සාදික්කා (Nutmeg) යනු කුළු බඩු විශේෂයකි. සාදික්කා ගෙඩියෙහි ඇති මදය හා මද ආවරණය චූ කවචය වටා ඇති රතු පැහැ කොටස එනම් වසාවාසි ප්‍රධාන වශයෙන් කුළු බඩු ලෙස භාවිත කරයි.සාදික්කා ශාකය නිවර්තන කලාපීය ප්‍රදේශවල ව්‍යාප්තව පවතී.සාදික්කා තෙල් හා සාදික්කා බටර් වලට ලෝක වෙළදපොලේ ඉහළ ඉල්ලුමක් පවතී."},{"question":"What does \\"arm fighting\\" mean?","answer":"\\"Arm fighting\\" is a colloquial term for arm wrestling. Arm wrestling is a sport where two opponents face each other with their elbows placed on a table and their hands firmly gripped. The goal of the sport is to force the opponent's hand down to the table top.The term \\"arm fighting\\" is often used in a casual or informal setting, while \\"arm wrestling\\" is the more formal term for the sport. However, both terms have the same meaning and refer to the same activity.Here are some examples of how the term \\"arm fighting\\" is used in a sentence:\\"I want to arm fight the strongest guy in the bar.\\"\\"I used to arm fight with my friends all the time when I was a kid.\\"\\"I'm not very good at arm fighting, but I'm always up for a challenge.\\""},{"question":"Napisz kontynuację:  Według Justyna Męczennika Apokalipsa powstała podczas","answer":"wojny żydowskiej (\\"Dial.\\" 81.4). Apokryficzne Dzieje Jana oraz Tertulian podają, że Jan został zesłany na Patmos przez Nerona. W tym samym okresie umiejscawia powstanie księgi Teofilakt, biskup Ochrydy, w swoim komentarzu do Ewangelii Jana (PG, CXXIII, 1133-1134). W wydaniach Peszitty autoryzowanych przez Kościół syryjski we wstępie do Apokalipsy podaje się: „Objawienie, które zostało dane Janowi Ewangeliście przez Boga na wyspie Patmos, na którą został zesłany przez cesarza Nerona”."},{"question":"Таң калыштуу факты жазып бере аласыңбы?","answer":"Сауд Арабияда жашаган аял күйөөсү ага кофе даярдап бербегендиги үчүн ажырашкан."},{"question":"Dame un ejemplo de trivia en esta categoría: Historia.","answer":"¿Qué país tiene un parlamento más grande: Canadá o Gran Bretaña? Gran Bretaña.Gran Bretaña (Reino Unido) tiene un parlamento más grande que Canadá. El parlamento británico incluye dos cámaras: la Cámara de los Comunes y la Cámara de los Lores, lo que lo hace más grande en términos de número total de miembros, en comparación con el parlamento de Canadá."},{"question":"Có thể tính nhẩm hiệu bằng cách thêm vào số bị trừ và số trừ cùng một số thích hợp.Ví dụ: 427 – 98 = (427 + 2) – (98 + 2) = 429 – 100 = 329Hãy tính nhẩm:a) 321 – 96;b) 1 454 – 997;c) 561 – 195;d) 2 572 – 994.","answer":"a) 321 – 96 = (321 + 4) – (96 + 4) = 325 – 100 = 225.b) 1 454 –  997 = (1 454 + 3) – (997 + 3) = 1 457 – 1 000 = 457.c) 561 – 195 = (561 + 5) – (195 + 5) = 566 – 200 = 366.d) 2 572 – 994 = (2 572 + 6) – (994 + 6) = 2 578 – 1000 = 1 578."},{"question":"ショパン、コペルニクス、キュリー夫人、ザメンホフ、ヨハネ＝パウロ２世といえば、現在のどこの国の出身者でしょう？","answer":"ポーランド"},{"question":"A maa fẹnikẹni tọwọ ba tẹ pe o n ji dukia ijọba jofin- Ileesẹ ọlọpaa Kwara ","answer":"Ileesẹ ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Kwara ti ṣekilọ pe eyikeyii ọdaran ti awọn ba gba mu to n ji dukia ijọba, tabi ba dukia ijọba jẹ, awọn yoo fi irufẹ ẹni bẹẹ jofin.Ninu atẹjade kan ti Alukoro ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Kwara, Ọgbẹni Ọkasanmi Ajayi, fi sita, eyi to tẹ ALAROYE lo ti ṣeikilọ naa.O ni awọn ọdaran kan ti bẹrẹ si i ji ẹrọ amuna wa tu ni nnkan bii aago mẹta orun Ọjọruu, Wẹsidee, ni agbegbe ile Adajọ Mustapha Akanbi, niluu Ilọrin, ti wọn si fẹsẹ fẹ ẹ nigba ti wọn kofiri awọn ọlọpaa, eyi ti ko jẹ ki wọn ri ẹrọ ti wọn tu ọhun gbe lọ.O tẹsiwaju pe awọn ti gbe ẹrọ amunawa naa le awọn alaṣẹ (IBEDC) to wa ni agbegbe (Challenge), n’Ilọrin lọwọ. Ọgbẹni Olumide to jẹ ọga agba ẹka agbegbe ọhun lo tẹwọ gba a lọwọ awọn.Ni igunlẹ ọrọ rẹ, o parọwa si gbogbo olugbe ipinlẹ Kwara pe ti wọn ba kẹẹfin iwa aitọ ni agbegbe wọn, ki wọn maa fi to agbofinro leti."},{"question":"નીચેના રૂઢિપ્રયોગ નો અર્થ આપો:હૃદય ભરાઈ જવું","answer":"શોક કે દુ:ખથી વ્યથિત થઈ જવું"},{"question":"வினா:தமிழ்நாட்டில் முதன் முதலாக பன்னிரெண்டாம் வகுப்பு தேர்வுகள்  தொடங்கப்பட்ட வருடம் என்ன?1. 19772. 19783. 19794. 1980","answer":"விடை:   தமிழ்நாட்டில் முதன் முதலாக பன்னிரெண்டாம் வகுப்பு தேர்வுகள்  10,12 வகுப்புகள், 1978ல் தொடங்கப்பட்டது"},{"question":" \\"Ny tsindry hihoatra ny fanantenan'ny fianakaviako dia nanosika ahy hahatratra, kanefa niteraka fotoana tebiteby ihany koa izy io.\\" inona ny fihetseham-po tamin'ny fanambarana teo aloha?","answer":"Ny andian-teny dia mampifangaro ny fihetseham-po tsara amin'ny fanatanterahana ny fahombiazana amin'ny fihetseham-po ratsy ateraky ny fanantenana lehibe."},{"question":"DPO àtàwọn ọlọ́pàá míì fara gbọta níbí aáwọ̀ tó tún bẹ́ sílẹ̀ láàrin Ifon àti Ilobu l'Osun","answer":"Rogbodiyan to n ṣẹlẹ laarin Ilobu ati Ifon nipinlẹ Osun tun bẹyin yọ lẹyin ti DPO ọlọpaa atawọn akẹgbẹ rẹ fara gbọta nigba ti aawọ mii tun bẹ silẹ ni Ọjọrọ.O ti to bi ọjọ mẹta tawọn eeyan ilu mejeeji ti n ba ara wọn ja lori ilẹ.Iroyin fidi rẹ mulẹ pe ọpọ ile niluu mejeeji ni wọn ti dana sun, koda wọn sun ọkọ ọlọpaa bakan naa.Agbẹnusọ ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Osun, Yemisi Opalola ṣalaye pe DPO agọ ọlọpaa to wa ni ilu kan lara ilu mejeeji fara gba ọta, nigba tawọn ọlọipaa mẹrin mii si n gba itọju lọwọ nile iwosan lẹyin tawọn naa fara gbọta.Alukoro ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa fidi rẹ mulẹ pe awọn eeyan kan lo lọ gẹgun de awọn ọlọpaa to n lọ pẹtu sija nibẹ ti wọn si ṣina ibọn fun wọn.Opalola ni ‘’wọn ti dana sun ọkọ ọlọpaa tuntun, ọwọ ni wọn si ti yinbọn fun DPO ọlọpaa.Oun naa si wa ni ile iwosan nibi ti o ti n gba itọju.Ohun ti awọn eeyan ti iṣẹlẹ ọhun ṣoju wọn sọ ni pe aawọ bẹ silẹ ni Ọjọru nigba ti iroyin kan gbalẹ pe awọn eeyan Ilobu ti gbẹmi ẹnikan ni Ifon.Lẹyin naa ni a gbọ pe awọn ara Ilobu naa ko oriṣiriiṣi ohun ija oloro ti wọn si lọ kọju ija si awọn eeyan Ifon.Iroyin kan tiẹ sọ pe ko din ni eeyan meji to ba iṣẹlẹ naa lọ nigba ti ọpọ eeyan si ti sa kuro ni ilu ti wọn si ti morile awọn ilu to sun mọ bii Osogbo, Ilajue, Erin-Osun, Agunbelewo atawọn ilu mii lagbegbe.Ijọba Osun gba ilẹ ti Ifon ati Ilobu n ja siẸwẹ, gomina ipinlẹ Osun, Ademola Adeleke ti sẹ ipade pọ pẹlu awọ ẹṣọ eleto abo atawọn adari ilu Ifon ati Ilobu lati wa ojutuu si aawọ to n ṣẹlẹ laarin ilu mejeeji.Iroyin kan tun fidi rẹ mulẹ pe gomina Adeleke ni ijọba ipinlẹ Osun ti gba ilẹ tawọn ilu mejeeji n ja le lori.Gomina ipinlẹ Osun sọ ninu ‘’ipade imọlẹ’’ naa to waye niluu Osogbo pe igbesẹ yii ṣe pataki ki asọyepọ le waye laarin gbogbo eeyan tọrọ kan.Bakan naa ni gomina ipinlẹ Osun sọ pe olori ọmogun oriilẹ, Ọgagun Taoreed Lagbaja ti ṣeleri pe gbogbo awọn to wa nidi aawọ yii ni yoo jẹ iyan wọn ni iṣu.‘’Awọn ẹṣọ eleto abo yoo da ṣeria fun ẹnikẹni to ba tun fẹ da rogbodiyan silẹ.Mi o le maa wo kawọn kan maa fẹmi awọn eeyan mi ṣofo.Ẹnikẹni ti a ba ri ni ori ilẹ ti a n sọrọ rẹ yii yoo dara rẹ lẹbi,’’ Adeleke lo sọ bẹẹ.Gomina ipinlẹ Osun wa kepe awọn ọba nipinlẹ naa lati kilọ fawọn eeyan wọn.Bakan naa ni gomina tun fidi rẹ mulẹ pe ofin konle o gbele ti ijọba kede si wa sibẹ."},{"question":"6: Waxaad sheegtaan laba Nabi oo loogu abtiriyo (ama loogu yeero) magaca hooyadood?","answer":"Labadii Nabi ee loogu abtiriyo (ama loogu yeero) magacyada  hooyadood waa :1) Yuunis Ibnu Mataa  2) Ciisa Ibnu Maryam.    "},{"question":"\\"Dharma dia foto-kevitra fototra amin'ny Bodisma sy ny Hindoisma. Azo adika ho toy ny lamina ara-môraly, ara-piaraha-monina ary kosmika na lalàna na fotopampianarana tsotra izao izany.\\"Inona ny fanontaniana azo tsogaina amin'io andian-teny io?","answer":"Fanontaniana: Iza amin'ireo fivavahana ireo no foto-kevitra ijoroan'ny Dharma?"},{"question":"Кубаныч Ажыбаев аткаруусундгы Кенжегул Мендебаировтун обону Жолочу Рысбаевтин калемине таандык  \\"Сулууларга суктанууга акым бар\\" ырынан үзүндү жаз.","answer":"\\"Сулууларга суктанууга акым бар\\" ырынан үзүндү :Сулууларды көчөлөрдөн көп көрөм,Суктанамын, көз электен өткөрөм.Жылмаңдаймын баарысына тийишип,Жыйырмамда мен мынчалык көппөгөм.Шектенбесин көрүп-билген жакындар,Шериктешим, менде да бар асыл жар.Сууруп алам чечекейиң десең да,Сулууларга суктанууга акым бар.Олоң чачты көчөлөрдөн көп көрөм,Толкуп-ташып ошол замат өзгөрөм.Оолукканды сурабагын, айтпагын,Отуз жашта мен мынчалык көппөгөм.Шектенбесин көрүп-билген жакындар,Шериктешим, үйүмдө бар асыл жар.Сууруп алам чечекейиң десең да,Сулууларга суктанууга акым бар.Кыркма чачты көчөлөрдөн көп көрөм,Кызыгамын, күйүп-жанып өрттөнөм.Кыялымда жанашамын бир басып,Жаш кезимде мен мынчалык көппөгөм.Шектенбесин көрүп-билген жакындар,Шериктешим, үйүмдө бар асыл жар.Сууруп алам чечекейиң десең да,Сулууларга суктанууга акым бар."},{"question":"أين وُلد القائد والديكتاتور أدولف هتلر؟ ","answer":" وُلد في مدينة براونو أم إن في دولة النمسا."},{"question":"= जैविक विविधता र दिगो विकास बीचको सम्बन्धको बारेमा छलफल गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"= जैविक विविधता दिगो विकासको लागि आवश्यक छ किनकि यसले पारिस्थितिक प्रणाली सेवाहरूलाई समर्थन गर्दछ, खाद्य सुरक्षामा योगदान गर्दछ, र प्राकृतिक प्रणालीहरूको लचिलोपन बढाउँछ।"},{"question":"Slutför den här frasen: Viita växte upp i Pispala och gick några år i läroverk i Tammerfors. Som lyriker debuterade han med \\"Betonimylläri\\" 1947 och blev snart känd för sina smidiga och kraftiga rytmer; diktspråket var enkelt och fast, tonfallet ofta satiriskt. Hans","answer":"huvudarbete, \\"Moreeni\\" (1950, svensk översättning \\"Morän\\", 1965), en episk skildring av Pispala under kriget 1918, är en av efterkrigstidens stora romaner. År 1948 belönades han med Kalevi Jäntti-priset och 1956 med Aleksis Kivipriset."},{"question":"زي العديد من مشاريع البناء، قد يتطلب تركيب موقد خشب ترخيص من حكومتك المحلية للتأكد من امتثالك لقوانين السلامة. ومع ذلك، القواعد بتختلف من مدينة إلى مدينة، لذا، قبل أن تشتري موقد أو تبدأ في تعديل بيتك، اتصل بإدارة البناء أو التخطيط في مدينتك أو حكومة المدينة للحصول على إحساس عما هو قانوني وما هو غير قانوني. لو محتاج تصريح بناء لتثبيت موقدك، الموظفين في القسم ده ممكن يساعدوك في الحصول عليه. ممكن ترغب بردو في تتصل بمدير مكافحة الحرائق المحلي، لأن، في بعض الولايات القضائية، تثبيت موقد خشب يتطلب تفتيش لتصديق صحة التثبيت. أخيرًا، ممكن ترغب أيضًا في الاتصال بمنشر تأمين مالك بيتك، لأن تركيب موقد خشب قد يغير مسؤوليتك. بتعتبر سدادات الأرضية ضرورية لتشغيل موقد الخشب الآمن ، لأنها بتضمن إن أي شرارات أو جمرات مش مش مهمة بتسقط من الموقد هتتصل بس بالسدادة ، وليس بالطابق ، مما يقلل من خطر الحريق. بيعتبر سدادات الأرضية مهمة بشكل خاص في حالة المنازل اللي فيها أرضيات خشبية أو سجادية بجانب الموقد مباشرة. بتفرض بعض القوانين استخدام وسادات الأرضية - في الولايات المتحدة وكندا ، يجب أن تمتد وسادة الأرضية على الأقل 18 بوصة (45 سم) أمام باب الموقد و 8 بوصة (20 سم) من الجوانب التانية. تثبيت دروع حرارية على الجدران حول موقع موقدك ممكن يقلل زيادة من خطر التلف أو الحريق. غالبًا ما بيتم صنع دروع الحرارة من ورق معدني، واللي بسهولة نسبيًا تطبيقه على الجدران الموجودة. تحقق من قواعد البناء المحلية الخاصة بك لمعرفة إذا كان هناك حاجة لأي تصريح خاص لتثبيت الدرع بالإضافة إلى أي متطلبات تصريح أخرى ذات صلة. لاحظ إن تركيب درع حرارة ممكن يقلل من متطلبات الإزالة من موقدك. لو لم تستأجر محرك محترف عشان يساعدك في وضع موقدك في مكانه، لازم تحمله بنفسك. مطبخات الخشب مصنوعة من المعدن وممكن تكون ثقيلة بشكل كبير، فتاكد من اتخاذ كل الإجراءات اللازمة لحماية نفسك لما تحرك المطبخ. عربية قوية أو شاحنة يدوية بتقدر فوق وزن الموقد الخاص بك هي طريقة رائعة لإحضار الموقد لموقعه من دون إيذاء نفسك. ممكن تكون هناك حاجة لتعديلات بسيطة على وضع الموقد في موقع التركيب باليد، وفي الحالة دي يجب عليك طلب مساعدة صديق أو أحد أفراد العائلة حتى لا تضطر إلى تحمل وزن الموقد بالكامل بنفسك. ممكن تجرب كمان تدوير الموقد للوضع على طول من أنابيب بي في سي قوية. المدخنة اللي بتعمل كويسة مهمة جداً علشان تستفيد أكتر ما في موقد الخشب بتاعك. مفخخك لازم يحمل الدخان والترسبات بأمان خارج بيتك - فالمفخخ المثبت بشكل سيئ قد لا يزيل الدخان بفعالية، ويترك غرفة المعيشة الخاصة بك فوضى قاتمة ومدخنة. ممكن تكون المدخنة جزء موجود من بناء المنزل أو ممكن تتم تركيبها مع الموقد، لكن في كل الحالتين، يجب أن تكون المدخنة معزولة بشكل جيد ومصنوعة من مادة غير قابلة للاحتراق. في الغالب بتتعمل المداخن الجديدة اللي بتتعمل للمواقد الخشبية من أنابيب فولاذية غير قابلة للصدأ معزولة خاصة. ممكن تكون محتاجين تستخدمي طول أنبوب الموقد لتوصيل موقد الخشب بتاعك بالمدخنة. ده كويس، بس تذكري إن قناة الموقد رقيقة نسبياً ومعزولة بشكل ضعيف، عشان كده مستحيل استخدام قناة الموقد كبديل عن مدخنة معزولة فعلية. عموماً، كلما كانت المدخنة أطول وأكثر مستقيمة، كلما كان أحسن. كلما زادت المسافة اللي لازم يتسافر فيها الدخان أفقيا (من خلال الأجزاء المنحنية من أنابيب الموقد ، على سبيل المثال) ، كلما قل فعالية المدخنة في إزالة الدخان من الموقد. عند تركيبها بشكل صحيح ، يمكن أن تكون الموقد الخشبية بمثابة نعمة هائلة لمنزلك ، لكن عند تركيبها بشكل غير صحيح ، يمكن أن تكون متاعب وحتى خطر خطير. لو واجهت أي مشاكل أثناء تثبيت موقد الخشب أو ما كنتش متأكد من كيفية المتابعة بأمان، اطلب مساعدة محترف. وبالمثل ، إذا ، بعد التثبيت ، كان لديك أدنى شك حول سلامة الموقد الخاص بك ، حدد موعد لفحص مع خبير. سلامة بيتك وعائلتك تستحق التكلفة البسيطة بتوظيف مساعدة خارجية. معهد الموقد الوطني (NFI) هو وكالة بتشهد خبراء الموقد والفرن. لو كان عندك أي شكوك بخصوص من تتواصل معه عشان تثبيت و/أو تفتيش موقد الخشب الجديد بتاعك، ابحث عن خبير معتمد من المؤسسة الوطنية للتعليم في منطقتك على موقع المؤسسة الوطنية للتعليم.  ملخص:","answer":"قبل ما تبدأ، ابلغ المسؤولين المحليين. حط وسادة أرضية تكون مش قابلة للاشتعال في المكان اللي هتكون فيه الموقد. الوسادة دي، اللي مصنوعة من الطوب أو البلاط السيراميكي أو الخرسانة أو مادة أخرى غير قابلة للاشتعال، لازم تكون متساوية مع الأرضية الموجودة في بيتك. ضيف كمان درع حراري لحماية الجدران القابلة للاحتراق. حرك الفرن بحرص في مكانه. حط مدخنة وربطها بخزانك، لو لزم. فكر بتوظيف محترفين معتمدين علشان يثبتوا ويفتشوا موقدك."},{"question":"Kể tên các tác phẩm thần thoại của Việt Nam","answer":"Sau đây là tên một vài tác phẩm thần thoại của Việt Nam:1. Thần Trụ Trời“Thần Trụ Trời” là truyện thần thoại được lưu truyền khá sớm trong dân gian Việt Nam, giải thích sự hình thành trời đất tự nhiên có cả biển, hồ, sông, núi...2. Sự tích cây lúaNữ thần Lúa là con gái Ngọc hoàng, nàng là một cô gái xinh đẹp, dáng người ẻo lả và có tính tình hay hờn dỗi. Sau những trận lũ lụt ghê gớm xảy ra, sinh linh cây cỏ đều bị diệt hết, trời bèn cho những người còn sống sót sinh con để cái trên mặt đất và sai Nữ thần Lúa xuống trần gian để nuôi sống con người. Khi giáng trần, nàng đã làm phép cho những hạt giống gieo xuống đất nảy mầm, mọc thành cây, kết bông mấy hạt. Lúa chín tự về nhà không cần phải gặt và không phải phơi gì cả. Cần ăn, cứ ngắt bông bỏ vào nồi là lúa sẽ thành cơm.3. Nữ thần Mặt Trời và Mặt TrăngTruyện kể rằng Mặt Trời và Mặt Trăng là hai chị em, con của Trời. Công việc được giao phó hàng ngày là phải thay phiên nhau đi xem xét thế gian. Gặp phải bọn khiêng kiệu già đi chậm, cô Mặt Trời phải ngồi lâu, ngày ở dưới trần hóa dài ra.4. Sự tích con rồng cháu tiênLạc Long Quân và Âu Cơ ở với nhau, cách một năm sinh được một bọc trứng, cho là điềm không hay nên bỏ ra ngoài đồng nội. Hơn bảy ngày, trong bọc trăm trứng nở ra trăm con trai. Âu Cơ đem về nuôi nấng, lũ trẻ chóng lớn, khỏe mạnh, trí dũng hơn người. Long Quân thường ở Thủy Phủ để Âu Cơ cùng các con trong cung điện trên đất. Một ngày nọ, Lạc Long Quân nhận ra người và Âu Cơ thủy hỏa khác nhau, người thuộc giống rồng ưa ở nước, người là giống tiên thích ở cạn, tính tình đôi bên khác nhau, không thể ở cùng với nhau một nơi lâu được. Nên Lạc Long quân ngỏ ý một nửa các con theo người, một nửa các con theo Âu Cơ. Sau này, có nguy khố gian nan thì gọi nhau ứng cứu. Từ đó, những người được sinh ra trong bọc trăm trứng được gọi là con rồng cháu tiên, theo dân giân thì đó chính là ông bà tổ tiên của loài người chúng ta.5. Mười hai bà mụVề việc nặn ra giống người, Ngọc Hoàng khoán trắng cho mười hai nữ thần khéo tay mà sau này chúng ta thường gọi là mười hai Bà mụ. Sự tích của mười hai vị nữ thần ấy hiện nay chúng ta chỉ còn biết một cách khái quát. Có thuyết nói đó là những thần giúp việc cho Ngọc Hoàng từ úc ông ta mới có ý định sáng tạo ra loài người. Nhưng cũng có thuyết lại cho đó là những thần được Ngọc Hoàng giao phó cho trách nhiệm sau khi ông ta đã tạo ra đủ số lượng người và vật ở hạ giới."},{"question":"ஒலிம்பிக் ஹாக்கியில் இந்தியா முதல் தங்கப் பதக்கம் வென்ற ஆண்டு எது?","answer":"1928"},{"question":" ما نوع الحيوانات التي لم تركب في سفينة نوح ؟","answer":"الحيوانات البحرية"},{"question":"Geedi socodka qoraal curinta.","answer":"Geedi socodka qoraal currinta waxaa kamid ah.1: waa in aad baadi goobtaa mawduuc xiiso leh.2: Xog farabadan waa in aad ka haysataa mawduuca aad qorayso.3: isku jaan goyn dhismaha qoraalka.4: Buug qoristu marka aad dhammayso, ku llaabo buugga.5: Tifaftir ayuu u baahan yahay buugga aad qorayso, sidoo kale, mawduuca aad ka hadlayso iyo qofka tifaftirka waa in uu aqoon u leeyahay mawduuca buugga.6: Qoritaanka buugga marka aad dhammayso, isku day in aad kor u akhriso waxa ku qoran buugga.7: Qoraaga waa in uu isticmaalaa jumlooyinka isku dhafka.8: Waa in aad haysataa agabyadii loo baahnaay."},{"question":"I am trying to figure out the answer to the question \\"2017లో లోకనాథం నందికేశ్వరరావు ఏ రాష్ట్ర ప్రభుత్వం చే ఉగాది పురస్కారంను అందుకున్నాడు?\\"I found this text about లోకనాథం నందికేశ్వరరావు on Text: 1984 లో తొలిసారి జాతీయ కళాకారునిగా గుర్తింపు పొందాడు.సిమ్లాలో ప్రదర్శన నిస్తుండగా అప్పటి ప్రధాని పి.వి.నరసింహారావు జాతీయ కల్చరల్ అసోషియేషన్ సభ్యునిగా నియమించాడు.ఉత్తమ మిమిక్రీ కళాకారునిగా ఎనిమిది సార్లు పురస్కారాలు, రాష్ట్ర స్థాయిలో మూడు బంగారు పతకాలు అందుకున్నాడు.మిమిక్రీ కళను క్యాసెట్ల ద్వారా ప్రజలకు పరిచయం చేసిన మొదటి వ్యక్తి ఆయన. 22 క్యాసెట్లను వివిధ ప్రక్రియలలో చేసి విడుదల చేసాడు.ఆంధ్ర, ఒడిషా, తమిళనాడు, కేరళ, భూపాల్, పశ్చిమ బెంగాల్, మధ్య ప్రదేశ్, ఉత్తర ప్రదేశ్, పంజాబ్, హిమాచల ప్రదేశ్ లలో తన ప్రదర్శనలిచ్చాడు.మాజీ ముఖ్య మంత్రి.ఎన్.టి.రామారావు చే ఆయన పుట్టిన రోజు సందర్భంగా రాష్ట్ర కళాకారునిగా సత్కారం పొందాడు.జిల్లాలో పలు సంస్థలు ఆయనకు అనేక సార్లు అవార్డులనిచ్చి సత్కరించాయి.ఆలిండియా రేడియోలో అనేక ప్రదర్శనలిచ్చాడు.క్లియోపాత్రా నాటకంలోని ఏంటొని స్పీచ్ ను తన అనుకరణ ద్వారా ప్రేక్షకులకు వినిపించటమే కాక క్యాసేట్ కూడా తయారు చేసాడు.పలు సాంఘిక నాటకాలలో నటించి తన ప్రతిభను చాటుకున్నాడు.ఎనిమిదవ తరగతి లో ఉండగానే 'విముక్తులు ' అనే నాటకంలో నటించి ఉత్తమ బాల నటుని అవార్డును స్వతం చేసుకున్నాడు.ఆంధ్ర ప్రదేశ్ ముఖ్యమంత్రులైన జలగం వెంగళరావు, మర్రి చెన్నారెడ్డి, ఎన్.టి.రామారావు, నారా చంద్రబాబునాయుడుల ద్వారా అనేక సార్లు సన్మానించ బడ్డాడు.అప్పటి రాష్ట్ర గవర్నర్ కుముదబెన్ జోషి చేతుల మీదుగా సన్మానించ బడ్డాడు.అప్పటి కేంద్ర మంత్రి కె.యర్రంనాయుదు చెతుల మీదుగా సన్మానించ బడ్డాడు.అనకాపల్లి, రాజమండ్రి, పొద్దుటూరు, హైదరాబాద్ సభలలో ఆయనకు బంగారు పతకాలు వచ్చాయి.తన ప్రదర్శనలలో జాతర, ట్రిపుల్ మ్యూజిక్, ఓంకారం, రుద్రవీణ, రామాయణ మహాభారత యుద్దాల ప్రక్రియలు అనేక అవార్డులు తెచ్చి పెట్టాయి.ఆయన 'నవ్వుల పల్లకి ' అనే టెలిఫిలిం ను రచించి, నిర్మించి నటించారు. ఇది స్థానిక సిటి కేబుల్ ద్వారా ప్రదర్శించ బడింది.ఆయన రచించిన ' అక్షరం శరణం గచ్చామి\\" అనే టెలి ఫిలిం డి.డి.1 ద్వరా ప్రదర్శించబడింది.ఆయన నిర్మించిన 'ప్రగతికి పంచ సూత్రాలు ' అనే టెలిఫిలిం స్థానిక సిటి కేబుల్ ద్వారా ప్రదర్శించ బడింది.ఆయనకు పిల్లలంటే ఎంతో యిష్టం. ఆ మమకారంతోనే పిల్లలను నవ్వించి వారిలోని ప్రతిభను వెలికి తీయడానికి 2003 లో స్థానిక రివర్ వ్యూ పార్క్ వద్ద చిల్డ్రన్ లాఫింగ్ క్లబ్ ను ఏర్పాటు చేసారు.2017లో ఆంధ్రప్రదేశ్ ప్రభుత్వం చే ఉగాది పురస్కారం.[2]","answer":"ఆంధ్రప్రదేశ్"},{"question":"Inona ny famaritana ny teny atao hoe ompa ?","answer":"Ny ompa dia teny ratsy izay avantana amin’olona matetika; io teny io diamifono fanambaniana, fanaratsiana, fanevatevana, fanebahana."},{"question":"Aşağıdaki ifadeyi tamamlayın: Kim 2007-2008 sezonunda Cup of China ve Cup of Russia Grand Prix yarışmalarını kazandı. Cup of Russia'da ISU'nun yeni puanlama sisteminde elde edilmiş en yüksek serbest program puanını elde etti ve bir rekor daha kırdı.. Kim son şampiyon olarak gittiği Grand Prix Finali'ni yeniden kazandı. 2008 Dört Kıta Artistik Patinaj Şampiyonası'ndan ise sakatlık sebebiyle çekildi. Kim","answer":"2008 Dünya Şampiyonasında Serbest programı birinci, kısa programı ise beşinci sırada bitirdi ve toplamda yeniden bronz madalya ladı."},{"question":"ما هي عاصمة إيران؟","answer":"عاصمة إيران هي طهران."},{"question":"صياغة إجابة على السؤال المفصل ده: طريق السكك الحديدية نيويورك وأطلنطي يتبادلون في أي قرية ومقاطعة نيويورك المحددة حسب التعداد؟","answer":"الاجابة: مقاطعة سافولك."},{"question":"Jubbantil mbind mii:Xale bu sob, te xamadi, mas naa sonal seen waa kër ci fàwwu ngeen wutal ma ab jàngalekatub diine ma laaj ko sama ñetti laaj yii.","answer":"Mbind mi jub a ngi nii:Xale bu sob, te xàmadi, mas na a sonal séen waakër ci fàww ngéen wutal ma ab jàngalekatub diine ma laaj ko sama ñett i laaj yii."},{"question":"Obinrin kan padanu ẹmi rẹ, awọn ọmọde mẹta fara pa, ninu ijamba mọto lọjọ ọdun tuntun n’Ikire","answer":"Agbẹnusọ ẹṣọ ajọ ojupopo nipinlẹ Ọṣun, Agnes Ogungbemi, ti fidi rẹ mulẹ pe obinrin kan lo jade laye, nigba ti awọn ọmọde mẹta fara pa yanna-yanna nibi ijamba mọto to ṣẹlẹ niluu Ikire lọsan-an ọjọ kin-in-ni, oṣu kin-in-ni, ọdun tuntun yii.Ogungbemi ṣalaye pe ere asapajude ti mọto akoyọyọ kan ati Toyota Corolla kan sa pade ara wọn lo fa ijamba naa.O ni ṣe lawọn ọkọ mejeeji sọ ijanu wọn nu, ti wọn si fori sọ ara wọn. Eeyan mẹrin lo fara pa; obinrin kan atawọn ọmọde mẹta.ALAROYE gbọ pe wọn gbe obinrin naa lọ sileewosan Ọbafẹmi Awolọwọ University Teaching Hospital, Ile Ifẹ, ṣugbọn ko pẹ ti wọn gbe e debẹ lo jade laye.Awọn ajọ O’Ambulance la gbọ pe wọn kọkọ ṣetọju awọn ọmọde keekeeke naa, ki wọn too gbe wọn lọ sileewosan fun itọju."},{"question":"கீழே கொடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ள பொருட்களைவைத்து கார்லிக் சீஸ் பிரட் ஸ்டிக்ஸ் செய்வது எப்படி?தேவையான பொருட்கள்:4 சாண்ட்விட்ச் பிரட்100 கிராம் வெண்ணெய்1 குடை மிளகாய்4 தேக்கரண்டி பொடியாக நறுக்கிய பூண்டு1 தேக்கரண்டி ரெட் சில்லி ஃப்ளேக்ஸ்2 தேக்கரண்டி ஒரேகானோதேவையான அளவு சோள விதைகள்தேவையான அளவு சீஸ்சிறிதளவு கொத்தமல்லி","answer":"செய்முறை:1. முதலில் குடை மிளகாய், பூண்டு, மற்றும் கொத்தமல்லியை நறுக்கி எடுத்து ஒரு தட்டில் வைத்து கொள்ளவும்.2. அடுத்து நாம் நறுக்கி வைத்திருக்கும் பூண்டை ஒரு மிக்ஸி ஜாரில் போட்டு அதை நன்கு அரைத்து பேஸ்ட் ஆக்கி ஒரு கிண்ணத்தில் எடுத்து வைத்து கொள்ளவும்.3. பின்பு அதில் ஒரு மேஜைக்கரண்டி அளவு நறுக்கிய கொத்தமல்லி, வெண்ணெய், மற்றும் அவரவர் விருப்பத்திற்கேற்ப ரெட் சில்லி ஃப்ளேக்ஸ்ஸை சேர்த்து அதை நன்கு கலந்து வைத்து கொள்ளவும்.4. பிறகு 2 சாண்ட்விச் பிரட்டை எடுத்து அதன் ஒரு புறம் நாம் செய்து வைத்திருக்கும் வெண்ணெய் கலவையை ஒரு கத்தியின் மூலம் நன்கு பரப்பி தடவி விடவும். (வெண்ணெய் கலவையை சிறிதளவு தடவினால் போதும் அதிகமாக தடவி விடக்கூடாது.)5. பின்னர் அதில் அவரவர் விருப்பத்திற்கேற்ப சீஸ்ஸை, சோள விதைகள், மற்றும் நாம் நறுக்கி வைத்திருக்கும் குடை மிளகாயை வைத்து அதன் மீது மற்றொரு பிரட்டை வைத்து அதன் மேலே கையை வைத்து லேசாக அழுத்தி விடவும்.6. அடுத்து நாம் தயார் செய்து வைத்திருக்கும் பிரட்டின் வெளிப்புறத்திலும் நாம் செய்து வைத்திருக்கும் வெண்ணெய் கலவையைத் தடவி அதை தயாராக ஒரு தட்டில் வைத்து கொள்ளவும்.7. இவ்வாறே மீதமுள்ள 2 சாண்ட்விச் பிரட்களையும் தயார் செய்து தட்டில் வைத்து கொள்ளவும்.8. இப்பொழுது ஒரு பாத்திரத்தை மிதமான சூட்டில் அடுப்பில் வைத்து அதை சுட வைக்கவும்.9. தோசைக்கல் சுட்ட பின் அதில் நாம் தயார் செய்து வைத்திருக்கும் சாண்ட்விச்சை எடுத்து வைத்து அதை நன்கு பொன்னிறமாகும் வரை சுமார் 2 லிருந்து 3 நிமிடம் வரை வேக விடவும். (சாண்ட்விட்ச் மேக்கர் இருந்தால் தோசைக்கல்லுக்கு பதிலாக நாம் அதிலும் செய்து கொள்ளலாம்.)10. அது வெந்து கொண்டிருக்கும் போதே அதன் மேலே ஒரு மேஜைக்கரண்டி அளவு ஒரேகானோ பொடியைப் போட்டு அதை நன்கு ஒரு கத்தியின் மூலம் பரப்பி விட்டு பின்பு அரை மேஜைக்கரண்டி அளவு வெண்ணெய்யை அதில் வைக்கவும்.11. 3 நிமிடத்திற்கு பிறகு அதை பக்குவமாக ஒரு கரண்டியின் மூலம் திருப்பி போட்டு மீண்டும் சுமார் 2 லிருந்து 3 நிமிடம் வரை வேக விடவும்.12. 3 நிமிடத்திற்கு பிறகு அடுப்பை அணைத்து விட்டு கார்லிக் சீஸ் ப்ரெட்டை எடுத்து ஒரு தட்டில் வைத்து அதை ஒரு கத்தியின் மூலம் பக்குவமாக 4 துண்டுகளாக வெட்டி அதை சுட சுட பரிமாறவும்.13. இப்பொழுது உங்கள் சூடான மற்றும் மிகவும் அட்டகாசமாக இருக்கும் கார்லிக் சீஸ் ப்ரெட் ஸ்டிக்ஸ் தயார். இதை கட்டாயம் உங்கள் வீட்டில் செய்து பார்த்து உங்கள் குடும்பத்தாருடன் சேர்ந்து உண்டு மகிழுங்கள்."},{"question":"வினா:     \\"ஒழுக்கம் உயர்வு தரும்\\" என்னுந் தலைப்பில் கட்டுரை வரைக. ","answer":"விடை: ‘ஒழுக்கத்தின் எய்துவர் மேன்மை இழுக்கத்தின்எய்துவர் எய்தாப் பழி’திருவள்ளுவர், இந்தக் குறளில் ‘ஒழுக்கத்தால் மேன்மை கிடைக்கும் என்றும், ஒழுக்கம் தவறுவதால் பழி ஏற்படும்’ என்றும் ஒழுக்கத்தின் சிறப்பை வலியுறுத்துகிறார். கல்வி கற்கும் மாணவர்களாகிய நாம் ஒழுக்கத்தையும், கல்வியையும் இரு கண்களாக கடைப்பிடித்து வாழ்க்கைக் கல்வியை பயின்று சிறப்புற வேண்டும். ஒழுக்கத்தை காலம்தோறும் பேணிக் காக்க வேண்டும்.நம்மை நல்வழிகளில் நெறிப்படுத்தி, மேன்மையோடு கூடிய வாழ்வில் தழைக்கச் செய்யும் பண்பே ஒழுக்கம் ஆகும். வாழ்வில் ஒழுங்கைக் கடைப்பிடித்து வாழ்வதே நாம் தலைச்சிறந்து வாழ வழிவகுக்கும். ஒழுங்கு என்பது சாட்சிகள் இல்லாத இடத்திலும் தவறிழைக்காமல் நேர்மையாக நடப்பதாகும். இதை முன்னோர் அறநெறிகள், அனுபவங்கள் மூலம் ஒழுக்கத்தை உணர்த்திச் சென்றுள்ளனர். நீதி நூல்களாக எழுதி வைத்து உள்ளனர்.மாணவர்களாகிய நாம், நேர்மையுடன், பொறுப்புடன், சமூகப் பொறுப்பு கொண்டோராக வளர வேண்டும். ஆசிரியர்கள், பெரியோர்கள் வழிகாட்டும் பழக்க வழக்கங்களை பின்பற்றி, அறிவினால், திறமையினால் சிறந்த சிந்தனை கொண்டோராக செயல்பட வேண்டும்.நீதி நூல்கள்:நீதி நெறிகளை நமக்கு வலியுறுத்தும் நோக்குடன் நம் சான்றோர்கள் இயற்றிய நீதிநூல்கள் பல நீதிக்கருத்துகளை எளிய நடையில் நமக்கு எடுத்துரைப்பதாக உள்ளன. அவைகளில் ஆத்திச்சூடி, கொன்றைவேந்தன், திருக்குறள், நாலடியார், திரிகடுகம், சிறுபஞ்ச மூலம், பழமொழி முதலிய நூல்கள் தமிழ் இலக்கிய வரலாற்றில் முத்திரை பதித்தவை ஆகும். இவற்றில் திருக்குறள், உலகளவில் தமிழர்களின் ஒழுக்க நெறிகளை பறைசாற்றும் ஒப்பில்லா நூலாக புகழப்படுகிறது. அதனால்தான் அதை ‘உலக பொதுமறை’ என போற்று கிறார்கள். உலக மொழிகள் பலவற்றில் மொழிப்பெயர்க்கப்பட்டு பயிலப்படுகிறது.‘ஒழுக்கம் விழுப்பம் தரும்’ என்பது குறள் நெறி. விழுப்பம் என்றால் உயர்வு என்று பொருள். ஒழுக்கம் வாழ்வில் உயர்வைத் தருவதால் ஒழுக்கத்தை உயிரினும் பெரியதாய் மதித்துப் போற்ற வேண்டும் என்று வள்ளுவர் குறளின் வழியே வலியுறுத்துகிறார். ஒருவர் தம் வாழ்வில் நன்மை அடைய வேண்டுமென்றால் நல் ஒழுக்கத்தை கடைப்பிடித்து வாழ்தல் அவசியமானது. இக்கருத்தையே வள்ளுவர் “நன்றிக்கு வித்தாகும் நல்லொழுக்கம்” என்று விளக்குகிறார். நல்லொழுக்கத்தோடு கூடிய உயர்வே நிலைக்கும், தழைக்கும்.ஒழுக்கக் கல்வி:பள்ளிப்பருவத்தில் கவனத்துடனும், ஒழுக்கத்துடனும் நடந்து கொள்ளாவிட்டால், வாழ்க்கைப் பாதையில் வழுக்கி விழ நேரும். நம்மை வழுக்கி விழாமல் தாங்கிப்பிடிக்கும் ஊன்றுகோல் ஒழுக்கமுடையோர் வாய்ச்சொல்லும், நம் தமிழ் நீதி நூல்களும்தான். எந்த நிலையிலும் நமக்கு தீர்க்கமான வழியை அறம் சார்ந்தே போதித்து வழிநடத்தும் வழிகாட்டிகள், நீதிநூல்கள் தான்.மாணவர்களாகிய நாம், பாடங்களில் கற்கும் நீதிக் கருத்துக்களைத் தேர்வு முடிந்தவுடன் மறந்து விடுதல்கூடாது. மாணவ பருவத்திலேயே ஒழுங்கையும், கட்டுப்பாட்டையும், நாட்டுப்பற்றையும் மேலும் வளர்த்து, எந்த வித பேதங்களும் இன்றி அனைவரையும் மதிக்க வேண்டும். வாழ்க்கை முழுவதும் கற்ற நெறிப்படி நடக்க வேண்டும். இதையே வள்ளுவர், “கற்க கசடற கற்பவை கற்றபின் நிற்க அதற்குத் தக” என்று அழகாகவும், தெளிவாகவும் உலக மாந்தருக்கு எடுத்துரைக்கிறார்.மாணவர்களாகிய நாம் திரைப்படம், தொலைக்காட்சி போன்ற புறக் கவர்ச்சிகளில் அடிமையாகி நம் வாழ்வை வீணடிக்காமல் உயிரினும் மேலான ஒழுக்கத்தையும், அறிவூட்டும் கல்வியையும் செம்மையாக்கி கற்று, கற்ற நல்நெறிகளை வாழ்வில் கடைப்பிடித்து வாழ்ந்தால் சிறக்கலாம். நெறி தவறாமல் வாழ்ந்து சிறப்போம்! நாட்டின் பெருமை காப்போம்!"},{"question":"Which animal is known as the king of the jungle?","answer":"The lion is often referred to as the \\"king of the jungle.\\" This title is largely symbolic and is based on the lion's majestic appearance and perceived characteristics such as strength, courage, and leadership. Interestingly, lions don't typically inhabit jungles; they are more commonly found in the grasslands, savannas, and open woodlands of Africa and in the Gir Forest of India."},{"question":"ادينى مثال لمعلومة في الفئة دي: الموسيقى.","answer":"فيفتى سنت هو فنان موسيقي نزل ألبومه الاول في سنة 2003 وظهر في فيلم حيت ريتش أور داي ترينج فى سنة 2005، "},{"question":"ఆహారపు గొలుసులో శక్తి బదిలీ జరిగేటప్పుడు జరిగే నష్టమెంత?","answer":"ఆహారపు గొలుసులో శక్తి బదిలీ జరిగేటప్పుడు 80 నుండి 90% శక్తి వృథా అవుతుంది. ఇది శ్వాసక్రియలోనూ, ఇతర క్రియల ద్వారా ఉత్పత్తి అయిన ఉష్ణరూపంలో నష్టపోవటం జరుగును."},{"question":"Zer da immunologia?","answer":"Immunologia biologia eta medikuntzaren adar bat da, non organismo baten immun sistemaren funtzionamendua aztertzen den. Immunologiak infekzioen kontra babesten duten mekanismoak, autoinmunitatea, alergiak eta transplantazioen atzerritzea ikertzen ditu."},{"question":"Суроо: Француз революциясынын натыйжалары кандай болду?","answer":"Жооп: Француз революциясынын кесепеттери Наполеон Бонапарттын көтөрүлүшүн, революциячыл идеалдардын жайылышын, Францияда жана андан тышкары жерлерде олуттуу социалдык жана саясий өзгөрүүлөрдү камтыды."},{"question":"தமிழ்த் திரைப்பட வரலாற்றில் அரசியலின் தாக்கம் பற்றி குறிப்பு எழுதுக.","answer":"அரசியலின் தாக்கம்:மு.கருணாநிதி வசனம் எழுதி வெளியான பராசக்தி (1952)யின் வெற்றிக்குப் பாத்திரப் பேச்சு முக்கிய காரணமானது. இந்த படத்தின் அடுக்குமொழி வசனம், ஒலிநாடாவில் இன்றளவும் விற்பனையாகிறது. சிவாஜி கணேசனின் முதல் படம் என்றும், இந்த படத்திற்குத் தமிழ் திரைப்பட வரலாற்றில் ஒரு சிறப்பிடம் உண்டு. கருணாநிதி திரும்பிப்பார் (1953), மனோகரா (1954) உள்ளிட்ட சில படங்களுக்கு வசனம் எழுதிப் புகழ் ஈட்டினார். திராவிட இயக்கத்தைச் சேர்ந்த முரசொலி மாறன், ஏ. வி. பி. ஆசைத்தம்பி, கண்ணதாசன் போன்றோரும் திரைப்பட உலகில் வசனகர்த்தாக்களாக பிரவேசம் செய்தனர். இந்தக் காலகட்டத்தில் வசனமே திரைப்படங்களில் மேலோங்கியிருந்தது. காட்சி பிம்பங்களுக்கு முக்கியத்துவம் குறைந்தது. திராவிட முன்னேற்ற கழகத் தலைவர்கள் திரையுலகில் பிரவேசித்தது தமிழ்த் திரைப்படத்திற்கும் அரசியலுக்குமான உறவை உறுதிப்படுத்துவதாக அமைந்தது. திரைப்பட வசனங்கள் மூலம் அரசியல் பிரச்சாரம் செய்யும் பாணி ஆரம்பம் ஆனது.1951இல் தென்னகத்தில் முதல் முதலாக நட்சத்திர அந்தஸ்தைப் பெற்ற கே. பி. சுந்தராம்பாள், தமிழ்நாட்டு மேல்சபையில் உறுப்பினராக்கப்பட்டு, சட்ட சபையில் நுழைந்த முதல் திரைப்படக் கலைஞர் என்ற சிறப்பையும் பெற்றார். 1952இல் இந்தியாவின் முதல் சர்வதேச திரைப்பட விழா நடைபெற்றது. சென்னை உட்பட மும்பை, கல்கத்தா, தில்லி போன்ற நகரங்களில் பன்னாட்டுத் திரைப்படங்கள் காட்டப்பட்டன. இந்திய திரைப்பட வரலாற்றில் இது ஒரு முக்கிய கட்டமாக அமைந்தது.1918 இல் அமுல்படுத்தப்பட்ட இந்தியன் \\"சினிமாட்டோகிராப்\\" சட்டம் 1952ல் மறுவடிவில் தோன்றினாலும், உள்ளடக்கத்தில் மாற்றம் இல்லை. இதே வருடம், தென்னிந்தியாவில் தயாரிக்கப்பட்ட முதல் ஆங்கிலத் திரைப்படமான \\"காடு\\" சேலம் மாடர்ன் தியேட்டர்சாரின் கூட்டுடன் தயாரானது. 1955ல் திரைபடத்திற்கான தேசிய விருதுகள் அளிக்கும் மரபு உருவானது. அந்த வருடம் நாமக்கல் ராமலிங்கம் பிள்ளையின் கதையான மலைக் கள்ளன் (எம்.ஜி.ஆர்., பானுமதி நடித்தது) தேசிய விருது பெற்றது. 1956ல் தென்னிந்தியாவின் முதல் திரைப்படக் குழுமம் \\"தி மெட்ராஸ் பிலிம் சொசைட்டி\\", திருமதி அம்மு சுவாமிநாதனால் அமைக்கப்பட்டது.1959 ஆம் ஆண்டு, திரைப்படக் கலைஞர்களுக்கென்று ஒரு தொழில்முறை அமைப்பு, தமிழ் நடிகர் சங்கம் இயக்குநர் கே. சுப்பிரமணியம் அவர்களால் நிறுவப்பட்டது. எனினும் தொழிற்சங்க இயக்கம் திரையுலகில் வேரூன்ற பல ஆண்டுகள் ஆயின. (ஏற்கனவே 1940ல் சினி டெக்னீஷியன்ஸ் அசோசியேஷன்ஸ் என்ற அமைப்பை இயக்குனர் கே. ராம்நாத் நிறுவியிருந்தமை குறிப்பிடத்தக்கது)."},{"question":"නමිනම් යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"හරිත වර්ණයෙන් යුත් පොළොව දෙසට නැමුණු යුගල පත‍්‍ර වලින් ගැවසුණු දර්ශනීය නමිනම් ප‍්‍රියතම පලතුරු ශාකයක් ලෙසින් නමිනම් හැඳින්විය හැක. මලයාසියාව මව්බිම කර ගනිමින් ලෙගුමයිනෝසියේ (LEGUMINOSAE)  ශාක කුලයට අයත් නමිනම් ගසේ උද්භිද විද්‍යා නාමය සයිනොටෙට‍්‍රා නෝලිප් ලෝරා නම් වේ.තෙත් කලාපයේ සාරවත්ව වැඩෙන නමිනම් ගස මුහුදු මට්ටමේ සිට මීටර් 370 ක් පමණ උස් ප‍්‍රදේශවල වැඩෙන අතර, නියඟයට ඔරොත්තු දීමේ ශක්තියක් ඇත. ශ‍්‍රී ලංකාව, ඉන්දියාව, ඉන්දුනීසියාව, ජාවා, මලයාසි ආදී නිවර්තන කලාපීය රටවල වැඩෙන අතර මීටර් 5 - 7 පමණ වැඩේ.මලයාසි භාෂාවෙන් මෙම ශාකය හඳුන්වනු ලබන්නේ නමි නන් වශයෙනි. එහෙත් අප රටේ බොහෝ දෙනෙකු නමි නම් යනුවෙන් හඳුන්වනු ලැබේ. මෙහි ව්‍යාප්තිය බීජ මගින් සිදුවන අතර, බීජය දුඹුරු පාටින් යුක්ත වේ. සෙ. මී. 3 ක් දිගු වූ බීජය මි. මී. 5 ක් පමණ ඝනකමින් යුක්ත වන අතර ප‍්‍රරෝහන කාල සීමාව සති දෙකක් පමණ ගත වේ. පැළ සිටවනවාට වඩා බීජය වගා බිම් තුළ කෙළින්ම සිටවීම තුළින් වැඩි වර්ධනයක් දැකිය හැකි වේ. සාරවත්ව වැඩුණු ගසක වර්ෂ පහක් ගතවීමෙන් මල් හටගෙන ඵලදාව හටගනී.නමිනම් ගසෙ මල් ලා රෝස පාටින් යුක්ත වන අතර, ගසේ මුල සිට මීටරයක පමණ උසට කඳේ මල් හට ගන්නා අතර, ඒ තුළින් ඵලදාව හට ගනියි. නමිනම් ගෙඩි මේරීමට මාස 03 ක් ගතවන අතර, කුඩා අවදියේ ගෙඩි කොළ පාටින් යුක්ත වන අතර ඉදුණු විට කහපාට වේ. ගෙඩිය සම්පූර්ණයෙන් රැලි සහිතය.නමිනම් ශාකයේ පොත්ත තද දුඹුරු පාටින් යුක්ත වන අතර එම සුඹුල ඉවත් කළ විට කොළ පාටින්ද යුක්ත වන අතර, ශාකයේ ලීය සවි ශක්තියෙන් යුක්ත වුවත් කිසිදු ප‍්‍රයෝජනයකට ගත නොහැක.නමිනම් කෑමට දුවලා පුතාල ඉතා ප‍්‍රිය කරන අතර අමුවෙන් කෑමේ දී ලුණු මිශ‍්‍ර කර කෑමට ගන්නා අතර අච්චාරු දැමීම කළ හැකිය. ඉන්දියානු ජනයා ඖෂධීය බෙහෙතක් වශයෙන් තෙල් නිෂ්පාදනය කර ගන්නා බව ඇෆ්. එච්. මැක්මිලන් මහතා සිය ග‍්‍රන්ථයේ සඳහන් කර ඇත. අප හට පහත රට තෙත් කලාපයේ සැම නිවසකම පැතිර පවතින ශාකයක් ලෙස නමිනම් හැඳින්විය හැක."},{"question":"Jawab soalan teka-teki berikut: Apa yang boleh membakar mata, menyengatkan mulut, tetapi dimakan juga.","answer":"Jawapannya ialah lada putih. Lada putih, juga dikenali sebagai lada sulah atau merica, ialah lada hitam yang direndam untuk mengeluarkan kulitnya. Lada merujuk kepada buah yang berasa pedas dan merupakan perisa makanan yang penting."},{"question":"બ્રહ્માનંદ ની \\"તારી મૂર્તિ રે છે\\" કવિતા લખો.","answer":"તારી મૂર્તિ રે છે જો નૈણુ શણગાર,નૈણુ શણગાર, મારા હૈયા કેરો હાર,તારી મૂર્તિ રે છે જો..મોહન તારી મૂર્તિ જોઈને ભૂલ શું તન ભાન,નીરખતા નજરામાં થઈ છું ગજરામાં ગુલદાન.તારી મૂર્તિ રે છે જો..માથે શોભી વાંક મનોહર, સુંદર શ્યામ શરીર,નદી રે થી તારું રૂપ નીહાળી પ્રેમીજનોને ભીર.તારી મૂર્તિ રે છે જો..બાંય ચડાવું બાંધેલ બાજું કાજુ ધર્મકિશોર,બ્રહ્માનંદ થઈ મોહી છું, નૈણે જાદુ જોર.તારી મૂર્તિ રે છે જો.."},{"question":"Atsakyk į šį sudėtingą klausimą: Kas yra deoksiribozė?","answer":"Atsakymas: Tai cukrus, esantis DNR molekulėje, kuris kartu su fosfato grupe ir azoto baze sudaro nukleotidą. Deoksiribozė yra svarbi DNR struktūros palaikymui, genetinės informacijos perdavimui, DNR replikacijai ir baltymų sintezei."},{"question":"ఓవర్ డ్రాఫ్ట్ గురించి సంక్లిప్తంగా వివరించండి","answer":"ఖాతాదారుని ఖాతాలో మొత్తం కంటే ఎక్కువగా తీసుకొనే సౌకర్యం. వాణిజ్య బ్యాంకులు తమ ఖాతాదార్లు సౌలభ్యార్థం కల్పించిన వసతి. ఈ ఓవర్ డ్రాఫ్ట్ సౌకర్యం కరెంట్ ఖాతా మీద మాత్రమే ఉంటుంది. దీని మీద కొంత వడ్డీని కూడా వసూలు చేస్తుంది."},{"question":"Sheeg magaca guddoomiyihii Baarlamaanka Dawladdii 1968kii","answer":" Waxa uu ahaa Sh"},{"question":"Manana ity teny nakorontana ity ianao:\\"ASMAANYN\\" Fantaro ny teny marina.","answer":"Ny teny voalamina: MANANASY"},{"question":"විභාජක පටක ශාකයේ විශේෂිත ස්ථාන තුනක ස්ථානගත වී පවතී. ඒවා නම් කරන්න.","answer":"විභාජක පටක ශාඛයේ හට ගන්නා ස්ථානය අනුව වර්ග තුනකි.- අග්‍රස්ථ විභාජක - ශාක මූලාග්‍රාස්ථ හා ප්‍රරෝහ අග්‍රස්ථවල පිහිටයි.- අන්තරස්ථ විභාජක - කාෂ්ඨිය ශාක කඳන් හා මුල් වටා පිහිටයි.- පාර්ශ්වික විභාජක - තෘණ ශාක වැනි ඇතැම් ඒකබීජ පත්‍රි ශාක කඳන් (පර්ව) පාදස්ථයේ හා පත්‍ර පාදස්ථයේ (ගැට) පිහිටයි."},{"question":"මූදු කවියක් සඳහා උදහරණයක් දෙන්න ","answer":"මූදු කවියක් සඳහා උදහරණයක්:වාරයා වාරකන් මයි බහින්නේහරහයා උතුරුකන් මයි බහින්නේමාරියා ගෙඩිය පස්සේ දුවන්නේලිහිණියා කඩුල්ලෙන් තංගලු යන්නේ"},{"question":"Inona no tanàna faharoa be mponina indrindra eto Madagasikara?","answer":"Toamasina   no tanàna faharoa be mponina indrindra eto Madagasikara"},{"question":"කොප්පරා යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"කොප්පරා යනු වියැලුනු පොල් මාංශය හෝ මදය හෝ වෙයි. පොල් තෙල් මෙයින් උකහා ගන්නා බැවින් බොහෝ පොල්-නිෂ්පාදනය කරන රටවල වැදගත් කෘෂිකාර්මික වෙළෙඳ භාණ්ඩයක් බවට කොප්පරා පත් වී ඇත. පශු සම්පත සඳහා පෝෂ්‍යයක් ලෙසින් භාවිතා කෙරෙන පුන්නක්කුද මෙහිදී නිපැයේ."},{"question":"ما هي عاصمة البحرين؟","answer":"عاصمة البحرين هي المنامة."},{"question":"أكمل الفقرة التالية:  في حين ترويج فيلمها السينمائي الأول \\"باتلشيب\\"، زارت ريانا اليابان، وأدت \\"وي فاوند لوف\\" في برنامج تلفزيوني موسيقي ياباني بعنوان ميوزك ستايشن. في 24 أبريل، 2012، قامت ريانا بغناء الأغنية بنسخة الأكوستك في حفل تايم 100 لمجلة تايم التي تحتفل بمناسبة 100 شخص الأكثر نفوذاً في تلك السنة والتي كانت ريانا في هذه القائمة. في 24 مايو، 2012، قامت بغناء الأغنية في مهرجان راديو 1 هاكني ويك إند في المملكة المتحدة. في 9 سبتمبر، 2012، قامت ريانا بغناء الأغنية (جنباً إلى جنب مع \\"برنسس أوف تشاينا\\" و\\"رن ذس تاون\\") في الحفل الختامي لألعاب بارالمبية صيفية 2012","answer":"في لندن. في 9 ديسمبر، 2012، قامت ريانا بغناء الأغنية جنباً إلى جنب مع النسخة المنفردة لأغنية \\"ستاي\\" في النهائيات للموسم التاسع من برنامج إكس فاكتور النسخة البريطانية."},{"question":"Shin yaya za a rubuta ɗari tara da casa'in da ɗaya a matsayin lamba?","answer":"Amsa: 991"},{"question":"Jawab soalan teka-teki berikut: Siapakah yang melahirkan Mickey Mouse?","answer":"Jawapannya ialah Walt Disney."},{"question":"ਸਿਰੀਰਾਗੁ ਮਹਲਾ ੩ ॥ ਹਰਿ ਭਗਤਾ ਹਰਿ ਧਨੁ ਰਾਸਿ ਹੈ ਗੁਰ ਪੂਛਿ ਕਰਹਿ ਵਾਪਾਰੁ ॥ ਹਰਿ ਨਾਮੁ ਸਲਾਹਨਿ ਸਦਾ ਸਦਾ ਵਖਰੁ ਹਰਿ ਨਾਮੁ ਅਧਾਰੁ ॥ ਗੁਰਿ ਪੂਰੈ ਹਰਿ ਨਾਮੁ ਦ੍ਰਿੜਾਇਆ ਹਰਿ ਭਗਤਾ ਅਤੁਟੁ ਭੰਡਾਰੁ ॥੧॥ ਭਾਈ ਰੇ ਇਸੁ ਮਨ ਕਉ ਸਮਝਾਇ ॥ ਏ ਮਨ ਆਲਸੁ ਕਿਆ ਕਰਹਿ ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਨਾਮੁ ਧਿਆਇ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ ਹਰਿ ਭਗਤਿ ਹਰਿ ਕਾ ਪਿਆਰੁ ਹੈ ਜੇ ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਕਰੇ ਬੀਚਾਰੁ ॥ ਪਾਖੰਡਿ ਭਗਤਿ ਨ ਹੋਵਈ ਦੁਬਿਧਾ ਬੋਲੁ ਖੁਆਰੁ ॥ ਸੋ ਜਨੁ ਰਲਾਇਆ ਨਾ ਰਲੈ ਜਿਸੁ ਅੰਤਰਿ ਬਿਬੇਕ ਬੀਚਾਰੁ ॥੨॥ ਸੋ ਸੇਵਕੁ ਹਰਿ ਆਖੀਐ ਜੋ ਹਰਿ ਰਾਖੈ ਉਰਿ ਧਾਰਿ ॥ ਮਨੁ ਤਨੁ ਸਉਪੇ ਆਗੈ ਧਰੇ ਹਉਮੈ ਵਿਚਹੁ ਮਾਰਿ ॥ ਧਨੁ ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਸੋ ਪਰਵਾਣੁ ਹੈ ਜਿ ਕਦੇ ਨ ਆਵੈ ਹਾਰਿ ॥੩॥ ਕਰਮਿ ਮਿਲੈ ਤਾ ਪਾਈਐ ਵਿਣੁ ਕਰਮੈ ਪਾਇਆ ਨ ਜਾਇ ॥ ਲਖ ਚਉਰਾਸੀਹ ਤਰਸਦੇ ਜਿਸੁ ਮੇਲੇ ਸੋ ਮਿਲੈ ਹਰਿ ਆਇ ॥ ਨਾਨਕ ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਹਰਿ ਪਾਇਆ ਸਦਾ ਹਰਿ ਨਾਮਿ ਸਮਾਇ ॥੪॥੬॥੩੯॥ ","answer":" ਹੇ ਭਾਈ! (ਆਪਣੇ) ਇਸ ਮਨ ਨੂੰ ਸਮਝਾ (ਤੇ ਆਖ–) ਹੇ ਮਨ! ਕਿਉਂ ਆਲਸ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈਂ? ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪੈ ਕੇ (ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ) ਨਾਮ ਸਿਮਰ।1। ਰਹਾਉ।ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਭਗਤੀ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲੇ ਬੰਦਿਆਂ ਪਾਸ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਹੀ ਧਨ ਹੈ ਨਾਮ ਹੀ ਸਰਮਾਇਆ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਆਪਣੇ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਿੱਖਿਆ ਲੈ ਕੇ (ਨਾਮ ਦਾ ਹੀ) ਵਣਜ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ। ਭਗਤ-ਜਨ ਸਦਾ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਸਲਾਹੁੰਦੇ ਹਨ, ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ-ਵੱਖਰ ਹੀ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਜੀਵਨ ਦਾ ਆਸਰਾ ਹੈ। ਪੂਰੇ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਨੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਪੱਕਾ ਕਰ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਹੈ, ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਹੀ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਪਾਸ ਅਮੁੱਕ ਖ਼ਜ਼ਾਨਾ ਹੈ।1।ਜੇ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪੈ ਕੇ (ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਦਿੱਤੀ ਸਿੱਖਿਆ ਦੀ) ਵਿਚਾਰ ਕਰਦਾ ਰਹੇ ਤਾਂ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਅੰਦਰ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਭਗਤੀ ਵੱਸ ਪੈਂਦੀ ਹੈ, ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਪਿਆਰ ਟਿਕ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ। ਪਰ ਪਖੰਡ ਕੀਤਿਆਂ ਭਗਤੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੋ ਸਕਦੀ, ਪਖੰਡ ਦਾ ਬੋਲ ਖ਼ੁਆਰ ਹੀ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ। ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੇ ਅੰਦਰ (ਖੋਟੇ ਖਰੇ ਦੇ) ਪਰਖਣ ਦੀ ਸੂਝ ਪੈਦਾ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਮਨੁੱਖ (ਪਖੰਡੀਆਂ ਵਿਚ) ਰਲਾਇਆਂ ਰਲ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਕਦਾ।2।ਉਹੀ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਸੇਵਕ ਆਖਿਆ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ, ਜੇਹੜਾ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ (ਦੀ ਯਾਦ) ਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੇ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਟਿਕਾਈ ਰੱਖਦਾ ਹੈ, ਜੇਹੜਾ ਆਪਣੇ ਅੰਦਰੋਂ ਹਉਮੈ ਦੂਰ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਆਪਣਾ ਮਨ ਆਪਣਾ ਸਰੀਰ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਹਵਾਲੇ ਕਰ ਦੇਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਅੱਗੇ ਰੱਖ ਦੇਂਦਾ ਹੈ। ਜੇਹੜਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ (ਵਿਕਾਰਾਂ ਦੇ ਟਾਕਰੇ ਤੇ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਜਨਮ ਦੀ ਬਾਜ਼ੀ) ਕਦੇ ਹਾਰ ਕੇ ਨਹੀਂ ਆਉਂਦਾ, ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸਨਮੁਖ ਹੋਇਆ ਉਹ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਭਾਗਾਂ ਵਾਲਾ ਹੈ, ਉਹ (ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਹਜ਼ੂਰੀ ਵਿਚ) ਕਬੂਲ ਪੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ।3।ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ (ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੂੰ) ਆਪਣੀ ਮਿਹਰ ਨਾਲ ਹੀ ਮਿਲੇ ਤਾਂ ਮਿਲਦਾ ਹੈ, ਮਿਹਰ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਉਹ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੋ ਸਕਦਾ। ਚੌਰਾਸੀ ਲੱਖ ਜੂਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਜੀਵ (ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨੂੰ ਮਿਲਣ ਲਈ) ਤਰਸਦੇ ਹਨ, ਪਰ ਉਹੀ ਜੀਵ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨੂੰ ਮਿਲ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ ਜਿਸ ਨੂੰ ਉਹ ਆਪ (ਆਪਣੇ ਨਾਲ) ਮਿਲਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ।ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ! ਜੇਹੜਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਉਹੀ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨੂੰ ਲੱਭ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਸਦਾ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਵਿਚ ਲੀਨ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ।4।6। 39।"},{"question":"கீழ்க்காணும் புதுக்கவிதைக்குப் பொருந்தும் திருக்குறளைக் தேர்ந்தெடுக்க:உயர் அலுவலரின் வருகைஅலுவலகமே அல்லாடும்அவருடைய சினம் அனைவரும் அறிந்ததேகோப்புகளை விரைந்து முடிக்கஒழுங்கு செய்யநேரத்தில் இருக்க வேண்டும்விரைகிறது மனம்பரபரப்பும் மனவழுத்தமுமாய்வண்டியை எடுக்கிறேன்காலைக் கட்டிக் கொள்கிறது குழந்தை‘போ அந்தப் பக்கம்’உதறிச் செல்கிறேன் குழந்தையை.","answer":"விடை: செல் இடத்துக் காப்பான் சினம்காப்பான் அல்இடத்துக்காக்கின்என் காவாக்கால் என்?"},{"question":"કોલકાતા શહેર વિષે માહિતી આપો.","answer":"કોલકાતા , એ ભારતનાં પૂર્વ ભાગમાં આવેલા રાજ્ય પશ્ચિમ બંગાળનું પાટનગર છે જે હુગલી નદીનાં પૂર્વ કાંઠે વસેલું છે. જ્યારે કોલકાતાનો ઉલ્લેખ થાય ત્યારે, તેમાં આસપાસનાં પરાં વિસ્તારોનો પણ સમાવેશ થઈ જતો હોય છે અને માટે તેની કુલ વસ્તીનો આંક દોઢ કરોડને વટાવી જાય છે, જેને કારણે કોલકાતા ભારતનું ત્રીજા ક્રમે આવતું સૌથી મોટું શહેર બને છે. અને તેનો આ દરજ્જો જ તેને સંયુક્ત રાષ્ટ્ર  દ્વારા વ્યખ્યાયિત કરેલા વિશ્વનાં સૌથી વધુ વસ્તી ધરાવતા શહેરોની યાદીમાં ૭માં ક્રમે મુકે છે.બ્રિટિશ રાજ દરમ્યાન ઇ.સ. ૧૯૧૧ સુધી કલકત્તા ભારતની રાજધાની રહ્યું. એક સમયે આધુનિક શિક્ષણ, ઉદ્યોગો, વિજ્ઞાન, સંસ્કૃતિ અને રાજકારણનું કેન્દ્ર રહી ચુકેલું કોલકાતા ૧૯૫૪થી લાંબા ગાળા સુધી તીવ્ર રાજકારણીય હિંસા, સંઘર્ષ અને મંદ અર્થતંત્ર વિગેરેનું મુક સાક્ષી બની રહ્યું. વર્ષ ૨૦૦૦ પછી ફરીથી બેઠાં થયેલાં અર્થતંત્રને કારને શહેરનો વિકાસ ફરી એક વખત વધવા માંડ્યો છે. ભારતનાં અન્ય મહાનગરોની જેમજ કોલકાતા પણ ગરીબી, પ્રદુષણ અને વાહનોની ભીડ જેવી શહેરીકરણની સમસ્યાઓનો સતત સામનો કરી રહ્યું છે."},{"question":"最近，世界遗产委员会第24届会议决定把龙门石窟列入《世界遗产名录》，龙门石窟在","answer":" 洛阳"},{"question":"Курманжан Датка энебиз таажысыз ханыша. Кыргызстан тарыхын Курманжан Датка энебизсиз элестетүү мүмкүн эмес. Кырыргызстан тарыхы дегенде эле Көпчүлүгүнүн ээсине алгачкы Курманжан Датка келээри анык. Өмүрү ар кандай легендаларга жана миф сыяктуу уламарга ширелип бул инсандын өмүрү өткөн.Суроо: Курманжан Датка кайсыл жерде жана канчанчы жылы туулган?","answer":"Жооп: 1811 жылы, Ош шаарынын түштүк батыш тарапта жайгашкан Оорке кыштагында Мунгушуруусунан жапалак  уругунан чыккан."},{"question":"Ounjẹ aarọ l’Ọlọrunwa n lọọ ra ti ibọn awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ okunkun fi pa a n’Ileṣa","answer":"Ọmọdekunrin kan ti gbogbo eeyan n pe ni Ọlọrunwa ni ọta ibọn ba lasiko ti awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ okunkun doju ija kọra wọn laaarọ Ọjọruu, Wẹsidee, ọsẹ yii, lagbegbe Irojo, niluu Ileṣa.Ounjẹ aarọ la gbọ pe Ọlọrunwa lọọ ra ti ọta ibọn fi ba a, loju-ẹsẹ lo si jade laye lai de ileewosan rara.Lati irọlẹ ọjọ Iṣẹgun, Tusidee, la gbọ pe awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ Ẹyẹ laduugbo Irojo ti bẹrẹ si i doju ija kọ awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ Aye ni Iwara, ti wọn si tun bẹrẹ wahala naa laago mẹsan-an aarọ Ọjọruu.Gẹgẹ bi ẹnikan tiṣẹlẹ ti aarọ Wẹsidee ṣoju ẹ, Adebayọ, ṣe ṣalaye, o ni ileeṣẹ pako kan, Sawmill, to wa lagbegbe Irojo, ni Ọlọrunwa ti n ṣiṣẹ, lẹyin to de ṣọọbu to fẹẹ lọọ ra ounjẹ aarọ lo ṣagbako ibọn awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ okunkun naa.Arojo ti Irojo, Oluṣẹgun Akẹju, sọ pe oun pe awọn ọlọpaa ni kete ti oun gbọ iro ibọn laaarọ yii, o si rọ awọn araalu lati ṣe ṣuuru lori iṣẹlẹ naa."},{"question":" Tixdu maxey leedahey ","answer":" Tixdu :waxay leedahey xaraf raac"},{"question":"把以下的古文成现代汉字：甘戊使于齐，渡大河。船人曰：“河水间耳，君不能自渡，能为王者之说乎？”甘戊曰：“不然，汝不知也。物各有短长，谨愿敦厚，可事主不施用兵；骐骥、騄駬，足及千里，置之宫室，使之捕鼠，曾不如小狸；干将为利，名闻天下，匠以治木，不如斤斧。今持楫而上下随流，吾不如子；说千乘之君，万乘之主，子亦不如戊矣。”","answer":"甘戊出使齐国，要渡过一条大河。船户说：“河水那么浅，你都不能靠自己的力量渡河，又怎么能做出使齐王高兴的事呢？”甘戊说：不是这样的，你不知道这其中的道理。事物各有长处和短处；老实谨慎地做事，辅助主人不战而胜；骐骥、騄駬这样的好马，可以日行千里，而把它们放在家里，让它们去捕老鼠，还不如小猫；干将这样锋利的好剑，工匠用来伐木还不如斧头的作用大。而现在在河中摇船，进退自如，我不如你；游说那些国君，国王，你就不如我了。"},{"question":"Dame un ejemplo de trivia en está categoría : películas. ","answer":"¿Quién es el personaje principal de Marley y yo?. "},{"question":"ලංකාවේ ලියාපදිංචි මුල්ම පුවත්පතවූ \\" ලක්මිණි පහන \\" හි ආරම්භක සංස්කාරවරයා කවුද ?","answer":"ජොහැන්නස් ධම්මතිලක පඬිතුමා ( කොග්ගල පඬිතුමා )."},{"question":"Σε ποιο σημαντικό γεγονός αναφέρεται το κείμενο: Ο Μάικλ Όουεν είχε συμμετοχές με τις μικρές εθνικές ομάδες της χώρας του. Την πρώτη του εμφάνιση στην Εθνική Αγγλίας την πραγματοποιεί σε ηλικία 18 ετών και 59 ημερών στις 11 Φεβρουαρίου 1998 σε ένα φιλικό παιχνίδι εναντίον της Χιλής. Η συμμετοχή τον έκανε αυτόματα τον νεότερο παίκτη που εκπροσώπησε την Εθνική Αγγλίας τον 20ό αιώνα. Συμμετέχει στο Παγκόσμιο Κύπελλο Ποδοσφαίρου 1998, όπου εντυπωσιάζει με τις εμφανίσεις του. Αγωνίστηκε επίσης με την Εθνική Αγγλίας στο Ευρωπαϊκό Πρωτάθλημα Ποδοσφαίρου 2000 στο Παγκόσμιο Κύπελλο Ποδοσφαίρου 2002 και στο Ευρωπαϊκό Πρωτάθλημα Ποδοσφαίρου 2004, σκοράροντας σε όλες τις διοργανώσεις και στο Παγκόσμιο Κύπελλο Ποδοσφαίρου 2006 χωρίς να σκοράρει. Τραυματίστηκε στο τελευταίο παιχνίδι του ομίλου. Τον Απρίλιο του 2002 φόρεσε για πρώτη φορά το περιβραχιόνιο του αρχηγού της Εθνικής ομάδας.","answer":"Η καριέρα του Μάικλ Όουεν."},{"question":"Erantzun galdera honi. Zer esan nahi dute parentesiek ekuazio kimiko batean?","answer":"Formula kimiko baten ikusten diren parentesiak sub-operazio bat dagoela esan nahi dute. Formula kimikoek hainbat sub-operazio izan ahal dituzte"},{"question":"fenoy ny banga :\\"Ny vary tsy fotsy adidiny laona, _\\"","answer":"\\"Ny vary tsy fotsy adidiny laona ny zanaka adala adidin'ny Ray aman-dReny\\"."},{"question":"පෙරදිග යන වචනයට අදහසක් ගෙන දෙන වචනය ලියා  දක්වන්න.","answer":"පෙරදිග යන්නට විරුද්ධ අර්ථයක් ඇති පදය අපරදිග වේ. "},{"question":"ఈ పేరాకు కొనసాగింపును వ్రాయండి - బ్రిటిష్ సంఘటనలపై చైనీయులు ఆసక్తి చూపుతున్నారు. ఇటీవలి రాజ వివాహాన్ని 30 మిలియన్ల మంది చైనీయులు చూశారు","answer":".చైనీయులు"},{"question":"Which food is known to be the most stolen in the world?","answer":"Cheese is known to be most stolen."},{"question":"కింది ప్రశ్నకు సమాధానం ఇవ్వండిఏ విధంగా గాజు క్వార్ట్జ్ నుంచి విభిన్నంగా ఉంటుంది?","answer":"కింద విధంగా గాజు క్వార్ట్జ్ నుంచి విభిన్నంగా ఉంటుంది:గాజు ఒక అస్ఫాటిక ఘన పదార్థం. ఇందులో కణాల అమరిక లఘు విస్తృతి క్రమంలో ఉంటుంది.క్వార్ట్జ్ ఒక స్ఫటిక ఘన పదార్థం. ఇందులో కణాల అమరిక దీర్ఘ విస్తృతి క్రమంలో ఉంటుంది."},{"question":"أريد إنشاء قصيدة حزينه من بحر الطويل. هل يمكنك مساعدتي؟","answer":"هُمُ خَلَّفوا دَمعي طَليقاً وَغادَروافُؤادي عَلى داءِ الغَرامِ حَبِيساطِلاعُ الحَشى لَم يَترُكوا فيهِ فَضلَةًتَضُمُّ جَوىً مِن بَعدِهِم وَرَسيسايَخافُكُمُ قَلبي وَأَنتُم أَحِبَّةٌكَأَنَّ الأَعادي يَنظُرونِيَ شوسالَقَد خِفتُ عَيني أَن تَكونَ طَليعَةًلَكُم وَفُؤادي أَن يَكونَ دَسيسا"},{"question":"Skriv en fortsättning till detta stycke - Mats Josten Frøshaug, född 31 juli 1988 i Oslo, är en norsk ishockeyspelare som spelar för Frisk Asker i Eliteserien. Efter att ha gjort seniordebut vid 17 års ålder med Sunne IK i Division 1, spelade han därefter för Linköping HC:s juniorsektioner. Han gjorde SHL-debut 2007 men lyckades aldrig ta","answer":"någon ordinarie plats i laget, varför han under åren med Linköping lånades ut till Nyköpings Hockey i Hockeyallsvenskan, Luleå HF i SHL samt Sparta Sarpsborg och Manglerud Star i Eliteserien. Vid NHL-draften 2008 valdes han i den sjätte rundan, som nummer 161 totalt, av Vancouver Canucks."},{"question":"Ka amsa tambayar da ke gaba. jirage masu saukar ungulu nawa Burtaniya take da su?","answer":"Amsa: Tanada jirage 138"},{"question":"வினா: கைவிளக்கு ஏந்திய யார் என்று அழைக்கப்பட்டவர்?","answer":"விடை: பிளாரன்ஸ் நைட்டிங்கேல்"},{"question":"Энелер билим дэңгээлин жогорулатып илимге кызыгуусун артып туруш керекпи?","answer":"Эне аттуу инсан аң сезими,ой жүгүртүүсун кеңейтүүсу келечек коомдун өнүгүүсү.Себеби эне билимдүү болсо, балдардын жашоого болгон көз карашы калыптанат.🥰 Балдарыңыз сизге аманат, аларга жакшы тарбия берүү, коомдо ордун таап бактылуу жашоодогу  жашоосу ар  бир эненин тилеги🤲.Эч качан бир да эне өзүнүн баласын тарбиясыз, ийгиликсиз болуусун каалабайт.🤭Андыктан ар дайыма балдарынын келечеги үчүн өнүгүү өсүү жана баардык жумуштарга жетишүүгө бир гана өзүңүздөр каалоо болуш керек.💃🏿 Жашоодо  өзүнүзгө болгон ишенуу, жүрөгүбүздө ыйман ,жаркын жашоо каалаймын🤲"},{"question":"වර්තමානයේ ලෝකයේ ප්‍රධානතම කහ නිෂ්පාදකයා වන්නේ කිනම් රට ද?","answer":"වර්තමානයේ ප්‍රධානතම කහ නිෂ්පාදකයා වන්නේ ඉන්දියාව යි"},{"question":"शिवका विशेषताहरू उल्लेख गर्नुहोस् ।","answer":"तेस्रो आँखा भएका (त्र्यम्बकम्)निलो घाँटी भएका (नीलकण्ठ)जटा परेको कपाल (जटाधारी)शिरमा गंगा भएका (गङ्गाधर),शरीरमा खरानी धस्ने (भष्मांगर),बाघको छाला ओढ्ने (बाघम्बर),शरीरमा सर्पहरूको माला बेर्ने (नगेन्द्र हार),डमरू तथा त्रिशुल बोक्ने,साँढे (नन्दी) चढ्ने,कैलासमा बस्ने,पार्वतीका पति,तृनेत्र,"},{"question":"د افغانستان توکمیز ویش د دې کلتوري موزیک او ټولنیزو نورمونو څنګه اغیزه کړې؟","answer":"د افغانستان بډایه توکمیز ټیپیسټي، چې پښتانه، تاجک، هزاره، ازبک او یو شمیر کوچني ګروپونه پکې شامل دي، د پام وړ د هیواد کلتوري موزیک او ټولنیز نورمونه بدل کړي دي. هره توکمه ټولنه د دودونو، ژبو او دودونو یوه بیلګه لري، چې د افغانستان د متنوع میراثونو سره مرسته کوي. د ګډو تاریخي او جغرافیوي اړیکو سره سره، دا ډلې ځانګړي کلتوري پیژندنه ساتي چې په ورځني ژوند، مذهبي کړنو، او ټولنیزو تعاملاتو اغیزه کوي. ژبه، په ځانګړې توګه، د هویت د یو مهم مارکر په توګه کار کوي، پښتو او دري د رسمي ژبو په توګه، د مختلفو قومونو ترمنځ ژبني تنوع منعکس کوي. د مختلفو توکمونو د کلتوري عناصرو متقابل عمل یو پیچلی مګر متحرک ټولنیز جوړښت رامینځته کړی چې د بهرنیو فشارونو او داخلي تنوع په وړاندې د افغان کلتور انعطاف او تطابق څرګندوي."},{"question":"Imisa sano ayey dhisneyd boqortoyadi nabi Suleymaan CS?","answer":"Waxey dhisneyd 40sano ."},{"question":"కింద ఇచ్చిన భావం వచ్చేలాగా ఒక పద్యాన్ని రాయండి మరియు రాసిన పద్యంలో ప్రతి పదంకి అర్ధము రాయండి:దేశమంటే కేవలం మట్టి కాదని దేశమంటే మనుషులని పేర్కొన్న దేవకవి గురజాడ అప్పారావు నీవోడు. ప్రజల కవిత్వాన్ని పాడి చూపాడు. అతని మాటను మరువకుండా నిరంతరం స్మరించాలి.","answer":"దేశమంటే వట్టిమట్టి కాదన్నాడుమనుషులన్నా మాటమరువబోకన్నాడు.అమరకవి గురజాడ నీవోడూప్రజల కవితను బాడి చూపేడోయ్.ప్రతిపదార్థం :అమరకవి = దేవకవి"},{"question":"Andrea Quynhgiao Nguyen ဆိုတာ ဘယ်သူလဲ။","answer":"Andrea Quynhgiao Nguyen သည် အစားအစာနှင့် အချက်အပြုတ်ရေးရာ စာရေးဆရာတစ်ဦးဖြစ်သည်။ သူမကို ၁၉၆၉ ခုနှစ်တွင် ဗီယက်နမ်တွင် မွေးဖွားခဲ့ပြီး ဆိုင်ဂုံမြို့ ကျဆုံးချိန်တွင် မိသားစုဝင် ၇ ဦးနှင့်အတူ ထွက်ပြေးခဲ့ရသည်။ ၁၉၇၅ တွင် ကွန်မြူနစ် အုပ်ချုပ်မှုကနေ လွတ်မြောက်ဖို့ မိသားစုဟာ အားလပ်ရက်အတွက် လုံလောက်တဲ့ ပိုင်ဆိုင်မှုတွေနဲ့အတူ ရွှေ့ပြောင်းခဲ့ပေမဲ့ သူတို့နဲ့အတူ သူ့အမေရဲ့ ဟင်းချက်နည်းတွေ ပြည့်နေတဲ့ မှတ်စုစာအုပ်တစ်အုပ်ယူလာခဲ့တယ်။ ကယ်လီဖိုးနီးယား တောင်ပိုင်းမှာ အခြေချခဲ့ပြီး သူတို့နဲ့ ရင်းနှီးနေတဲ့ အစားအစာတွေဝယ်ဖို့ ကြိုးစားပေမဲ့ ဟင်းလျာတွေဟာ အသင့်စားပြင်ဆင်ထုတ်လုပ်ထားပြီး သိပ်အရသာမရှိပါဘူး။ Nguyen ရဲ့အမေက သူတို့ရဲ့မိခင်နိုင်ငံက အစားအစာတွေကို ပြန်လည်ဖန်တီးဖို့ အကြံပြုခဲ့တယ်။ ဟင်းလျာတွေကို သူတို့ကိုယ်တိုင်ချက်ပြုတ်ရင်းပေါ့။ ဆန်ကလီမန်တီမြို့တွင် ကလေးဘဝကို ကုန်ဆုံးခဲ့ပြီးနောက် Nguyen သည် ကယ်လီဖိုးနီးယားတောင်ပိုင်းတက္ကသိုလ်သို့ တက်ရောက်ခဲ့ပြီး ဘဏ်လုပ်ငန်းနှင့် ဘဏ္ဍာရေးတွင် ဘွဲ့လွန်ဘွဲ့၊ ဆက်သွယ်ရေးစီမံခန့်ခွဲမှုတွင် မဟာဘွဲ့ ရရှိခဲ့သည်။"},{"question":"Napisz ciąg dalszy: David Oteo z reprezentacją Meksyku brał udział w Letnich Igrzyskach Olimpijskich 1996, Pucharze Konfederacji 2001 i Copa América 2004. W kadrze narodowej grał ","answer":"w latach 1996–2004 – zdobył w tym czasie jednego gola w 12 meczach."},{"question":"Dublin mooy péeyu man réew ?","answer":"Dublin mooy péeyu réewum Irlande"},{"question":"અહીં નરસિંહ મહેતા રચિત કૃતિ એક \\"હિંડોળે હિંચે મારો વહાલો\\" ના શરૂઆતની પંકતિઓ આપેલ છે:\\"હિંડોળે હિંચે મારો વહાલો, હિંચંતાં રંગ લાગ્યો રે;શામાને શામળિયા સાથે લાજતણો ભય ભાગ્યો રે. હિંડોળે.\\"આ કૃતિની આગળની પંકતિઓ લખો.","answer":"હિંડોળે હિંચે મારો વહાલો, હિંચંતાં રંગ લાગ્યો રે;શામાને શામળિયા સાથે લાજતણો ભય ભાગ્યો રે. હિંડોળે.શામાને સોહાવે દંપતી, રસિયાશું રસ વાધ્યો રે;લેહેરી લેતાં અંગસમાગમ, વીચંતડો વર લાધ્યો રે. હિંડોળે.દીનોનાથ હિંડોળે હિંચે, ફૂલ્યો મદન મદમાતો રે;નરસૈયાચો સ્વામી ભલે મળિયો, માનુનીમાં રંગરાતો રે. હિંડોળે."},{"question":"What are the main factors that determine whether a project is worth starting?","answer":"The relevance of a project depends on the value it generates and the associated risks, with considerations for direct and indirect value, sustainability, and alignment with strategic objectives."},{"question":"Bagaimanakah saya menerima wang dari seseorang dalam Paypal?","answer":"Untuk terima bayaran duit dari seseorang:1. Klik menu Send & Request di bahagian atas2. Klik tab Request3. Masukkan email orang yang akan berikan kita duit4. Masukkan amaun dalam matawang yang dikehendaki5. Semak jumlah wang yang dipinta6. Tekan butang Request Payment7. Selesai "},{"question":"Marka tescil 25 sınıf ne demek?","answer":"Ev tekstil ürünleri, perde, örtü, nevresim, yorgan, havlu gibi ürünler için 24. Sınıf tescil sınıfı iken, iç çamaşırı, çorap, şal, bandana, eşarp, kemer gibi ürünleri üretenler ise 25. Sınıfta markalarını tescil ettirmelidir."},{"question":"Qual o sentimento expresso nesse email?Prezado Departamento de Marketing,        Gostaria apenas de aproveitar esse momento para demonstrar meu mais sincero agradecimento e admiração pelo trabalho que vocês realizam. Seus esforços de marketing têm sido essenciais pelo sucesso de nossa empresa, e sempre fico impressionada com a criatividade e dedicação do time de vocês.        Continuem com esse trabalho incrível e saibam que toda a empresa aprecia seus esforços. Obrigado por todo o trabalho duro!        Abraços,    Joane","answer":"O sentimento expresso no e-mail é de gratidão pelo trabalho realizado pela equipe de marketing"},{"question":"Le point le plus lumineux du ciel qu’on aperçoit la nuit correspond-il à la Station spatiale internationale ?","answer":"Vous voulez sans doute parler du point lumineux présent vers l’ouest, le soir, assez haut dans le ciel. Ce point lumineux est fixe dans le ciel. Il s’agit de la planète Vénus. Il est facile de faire la différence entre une étoile (ou une planète) et un objet en orbite autour de la Terre. Les astres tournent lentement dans le ciel. Ils se lèvent vers l’est et se couchent vers l’ouest, comme le Soleil. Ce mouvement est dû à la rotation de la Terre.En revanche, un satellite défile rapidement et traverse le ciel en 2 à 3 minutes tout au plus, un peu comme un avion. Cette fois-ci, c’est bien l’objet qui tourne autour de la Terre. La Station spatiale internationale, qui tourne à 400 km au-dessus de nous, n’échappe pas à cette règle."},{"question":"Mohammed ṣa ọmọ bibi inu rẹ pa, ladajọ ba ju u sẹwọn ni Kwara","answer":"Ile-ẹjọ Magistreeti kan niluu Ilọrin, ti ni ki arakunrin Yahaya Mohammed maa lọọ gbafẹfẹ lọgba ẹwọn fẹsun pe o ṣa ọmọ bibi inu rẹ ti ko ju ọdun mẹwaa lọ, Aliyu Mohammed, lada, to si gbabẹ ku.Mohammed to jẹ olujẹjọ ni wọn sọ pe o ran ọmọkunrin rẹ niṣẹ, to si ni ko sare jiṣẹ naa, eyi ti baba rẹ ka si iwa igberaga, lo ba binu lẹ ada mọ ọ, ada naa ba ọmọ rẹ ni koko ẹṣẹ, ni ẹjẹ ba n tu jade bii agbara, wọn sare gbe e lọ sileewosan, sugbọn nibi ti wọn ti n tọju ẹ lo ti dagbere faye.Olupẹjọ, Moshood Agboola, waa rọ Ile-ẹjọ lati fi ọkunrin ọdaran naa si ahamọ tori pe ẹsẹ rẹ lagbara kọja eyi ti wọn le gba beeli rẹ.Magistreeti Saliu ti waa paṣẹ pe ki wọn lọọ fi Mohammed si ọgba ẹwọn, to si sun igbẹjọ si ọjọ kẹrin, oṣu kẹjọ, ọdun yii."},{"question":"Jawab soalan teka-teki berikut: Mengapakah doktor bedah menutupkan mulutnya ketika menjalankan pembedahan?","answer":"Kerana kalau matanya yang ditutup, doktor bedah tidak dapat melihat dan melakukan prosedur pembedahan!"},{"question":"Uyagula yini baba awakhuluma nje namuhla?Usebuyile yini umakoti?Akakabuyi. Kusho ukuthi ngabe uphethwe kabi ukuhamba kwaloluhlanya lwengane?Cha impela kwenzeke into embi mkami. Okokuqala asiyazi nokuthi iphile ngane. Kokunye izithele phezu kwezigebengu zayenzakalisa.Phela lapho ngabe umvundla ziyawunqanda phambili. Yona yiniingasilaleli uma siyitshela ngesiko lesintu.Namasiko lawa asefuna ukubhekisiswa. Sengathi akhona asephelelwayisikhathi manje. Amanye kufuneka achazwe kahle aziwe yibo bonkeabantu.Ubona sengathi umakoti akalazi leli siko. Ulazi kahle uyazihlanyisa.Mina ngibona sengathi sinecala manje.Icala lani? Musa ukudlala wena Manzini. Phela thina asiyixoshanga lengane lapha ekhaya. Izihambele. Uyangizwa? Izihambele.UMsindo onjengalo uzosixabanisa namadlozi.Nawo ngabe ayaganga lawo madlozi. Angayeka ukubuyisa uhlanyalukamakoti, axabane nathi? Kanti awalazi yini wona leli siko esilitshelale ntombazane.Mina ngisafuna ukuhlala phansi ngiyichazele kahle intombazane.Kokunye uma isizwe kahle iyobubona ubuhle baleli siko.Wena ubona sengathi izokulalela njengoba isiwumdlwembe nje? (Athiukuhleka) Kodwa ungichazile uDumisani. Wajika eduzenjengenkalankala.Nami ungimangazile impela lo mfana.1. Kwaba namthelela muni empilweni kaNondumiso ukwesekela kwakheuThenjiiwe ezinkingeni ayebhekene nazo emzini? Sekela impendulo yakhongamaphuzu AMABILI.","answer":"Amaphuzu AMABILI kwalandelayo: Inkulumo kaMthofi iyona emvezayo ukuthi ungumuntu onjani njengobaezincoma ngokubulala uMbhele. Inkulumo mpendulwano iyasiza ngokusivezela isizinda njengoba sibonalapha ukuthi oMthofi basendaweni engalapho kwenzeke khona isigamekosokubulala uMbhele. Inkulumo mpendulwano iyasiza ngokusivezela ukuthi abantu bakusiphiisimo njengoba kuvela ukuthi uSonto wayethokozile ngomsebenziowenziwe nguMthofi. Inkulumo mpendulwano iyasiza ngokuveza udweshu olwalukhonaendabeni ngoba uSonto wayesehluleka ukufeza izethembiso zakhezokukhokhela uMthofi. Iyasiza ngokuveza izigameko ezazisazokwenzeka njengokuthi uSontowayesazokhokha enhle imali.(Nokunye okunembayo okungashiwo ngumfundi)."},{"question":"Алыкул Осмоновтун калемине таандык ырлардан жазып бере аласыңбы ?","answer":"ЖАШТЫККАКүнөөсү жок махабаттай мөлтүлдөп,Жаштык менден өмүрлүккө бөлүнөт.Эң акыркы ажырашуу элесиӨз баламдан ысыгыраак көрүнөт.Кетти, кетти, жибек боосун чече албайм,Кечкен сууну кайра экинчи кече албайм.Учкан куштай суу шаарындай жаштыкты,Самолёт минип кууган менен жете албайм."},{"question":"Tohizo izao ohabolana izao : \\"aza manao toy ny boloky lahy homam-boatseva,ka  ..................... \\"","answer":"\\" Aza manao toy ny boloky lahy homam-boatseva,ka mamy ny atsy sady fy ny eroa.\\" "},{"question":"தமிழ்ச் சமூகத்தின் உயிர் சாட்சியாக விளங்கும் மரம்அ) பலா மரம்ஆ) புன்னை மரம்இ) பனை மரம்ஈ) வேப்ப மரம்","answer":"இ) பனை மரம்"},{"question":"دلیل وجود فیلتر هوا در یخچال‌های خانگی چیست؟","answer":"در مدل‌های جدیدتر یخچال برای جلوگیری از ترکیب بوی غذاها با یک دیگر و داشتن هوای مطبوع داخل یخچال به فیلتر هوا مجهز شده‌اند. این فیلترها علاوه بر جلوگیری از پخش بو به از بین بردن باکتری و کپک نیز کمک می‌کنند."},{"question":"What was the significance of ‘The Tennis Court Oath’ in the French Revolution?","answer":"The Tennis Court Oath, sworn on June 20, 1789, was a pivotal event in the early stages of the French Revolution and holds significant historical importance. Here's why it was so consequential:1. Defiance Against Royal Authority:   - The Oath represented a direct challenge to the authority of King Louis XVI and the ancien régime. By taking this oath, the members of the Third Estate (who had begun to call themselves the National Assembly) were asserting their independence from the king and claiming the right to represent the people of France.2. Birth of a Representative Assembly:   - The Oath marked the transition of the Third Estate from being just a part of the Estates-General to becoming a self-declared National Assembly. This was a radical move, as they effectively declared that they had the authority to make laws and reforms on behalf of the French people, a role traditionally reserved for the king and his advisors.3. Unity and Resolve:   - The deputies of the Third Estate, joined by some from the clergy and nobility, swore \\"not to separate, and to reassemble wherever circumstances require, until the constitution of the kingdom is established\\". This showed a remarkable level of unity and determination among the representatives of the Third Estate, who were mostly commoners.4. Beginning of Democratic Governance:   - The Tennis Court Oath can be seen as the first step towards establishing a constitutional democracy in France. It was a move towards a government based on the will of the people rather than the divine right of kings.5. Symbol of Popular Sovereignty:   - The Oath became a symbol of the power of popular sovereignty and the right of the people to constitute a government and make laws.6. Catalyst for Further Revolutionary Action:   - This event was a catalyst that set off a series of actions leading to the fall of the Bastille in July and further revolutionary events. It demonstrated that the common people could take organized, collective action against the established order.7. Iconic Moment in French History:   - The Tennis Court Oath is remembered as an iconic moment in French history, symbolizing the ideals of unity, equality, and liberty that would come to define the Revolution.In summary, the Tennis Court Oath was significant as it marked a clear break from the feudal and monarchical traditions of the past, laying the groundwork for the development of a new, democratic form of governance in France. It embodied the revolutionary spirit and set in motion the events that would radically transform French society and politics."},{"question":"ਬੰਗਲੌਰ, 28 ਫਰਵਰੀਪਾਕਿਸਤਾਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਜੈਸ਼ ਦੇ ਦਹਿਸ਼ਤੀ ਕੈਂਪ ’ਤੇ ਕੀਤੇ ਹਵਾਈ ਹਮਲਿਆਂ ਦਾ ਭਾਜਪਾ ਨੂੰ ਆਗਾਮੀ ਲੋਕ ਸਭਾ ਚੋਣਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਲਾਹਾ ਮਿਲਣ ਸਬੰਧੀ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਬਿਆਨ ਦੀ ਨੁਕਤਾਚੀਨੀ ਹੋਣ ਮਗਰੋਂ ਕਰਨਾਟਕ ਭਾਜਪਾ ਦੇ ਪ੍ਰਧਾਨ ਬੀ.ਐਸ.ਯੇਦੀਯੁਰੱਪਾ ਨੇ ਅੱਜ ਕਿਹਾ ਕਿ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਬਿਆਨ ਦਾ ਗ਼ਲਤ ਅਰਥ ਕੱਢਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਲਈ ਪਾਰਟੀ ਨਾਲੋਂ ਮੁਲਕ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਹੈ। ਯੇਦੀਯੁਰੱਪਾ ਨੂੰ ਇਸ ਬਿਆਨ ਲਈ ਕਰਨਾਟਕ ਦੇ ਸਿਆਸੀ ਆਗੂਆਂ ਸਮੇਤ ਕੇਂਦਰ ਸਰਕਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਵੀ.ਕੇ.ਸਿੰਘ ਦੀ ਆਲੋਚਨਾ ਝੱਲਣੀ ਪਈ ਸੀ। ਸਾਬਕਾ ਥਲ ਸੈਨਾ ਮੁਖੀ ਸਿੰਘ ਨੇ ਯੇਦੀਯੁਰੱਪਾ ਦੇ ਇਸ ਬਿਆਨ ਦੀ ਖੁੱਲ੍ਹ ਕੇ ਨਿਖੇਧੀ ਕੀਤੀ ਹੈ।ਕਰਨਾਟਕ ਦੇ ਸਾਬਕਾ ਮੁੱਖ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਯੇਦੀਯੁਰੱਪਾ ਨੇ ਲੰਘੇ ਦਿਨ ਇਕ ਬਿਆਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਕਿਹਾ ਸੀ ਕਿ ਭਾਰਤ ਵੱਲੋਂ ਪਾਕਿਸਤਾਨ ਦੇ ਧੁਰ ਅੰਦਰ ਜਾ ਕੇ ਕੀਤੇ ਹਵਾਈ ਹਮਲਿਆਂ ਨਾਲ ਭਾਜਪਾ ਨੂੰ ਆਗਾਮੀ ਲੋਕ ਸਭਾ ਚੋਣਾਂ ਦੌਰਾਨ ਕਰਨਾਟਕਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਕੁੱਲ 28 ਸੀਟਾਂ ’ਚੋਂ 22 ਤੋਂ ਵੱਧ ਸੀਟਾਂ ਜਿੱਤਣ ਵਿੱਚ ਮਦਦ ਮਿਲੇਗੀ। ਪਾਕਿਸਤਾਨੀ ਮੀਡੀਆ ਤੇ ਮੁਲਕ ਦੀ ਪੀਟੀਆਈ ਦੀ ਅਗਵਾਈ ਵਾਲੀ ਸੱਤਾਧਾਰੀ ਪਾਰਟੀ ਨੇ ਯੇਦੀਯੁਰੱਪਾ ਦੇ ਇਸ ਬਿਆਨ ’ਤੇ ਉਜਰ ਜਤਾਉਂਦਿਆਂ ਸਵਾਲ ਕੀਤਾ ਸੀ ਕਿ ਕੀ ਜੰਗ ਚੋਣ ਬਦਲ ਵਜੋਂ ਲੜੀ ਜਾ ਰਹੀ ਸੀ। ਯੇਦੀਯੁਰੱਪਾ ਨੇ ਅੱਜ ਲੜੀਵਾਰ ਟਵੀਟ ਕਰਦਿਆਂ ਕਿਹਾ, ‘ਮੈਂ ਇਹ ਸਾਫ਼ ਕਰ ਦੇਣਾ ਚਾਹੁੰਦਾ ਹਾਂ ਕਿ ਮੇਰੇ ਲੰਘੇ ਦਿਨ ਦੇ ਬਿਆਨ ਨੂੰ ਗ਼ਲਤ ਅਰਥਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਮੈਂ ਹਥਿਆਰਬੰਦ ਬਲਾਂ ਦਾ ਪੂਰਾ ਸਤਿਕਾਰ ਕਰਦਾ ਹਾਂ। ਮੁਲਕ ਦੀ ਸੁਰੱਖਿਆ ਲਈ ਲੜ ਰਹੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਬਹਾਦਰ ਜਵਾਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਮੈਂ ਸਲਾਮ ਕਰਦਾ ਹਾਂ। ਮੈਂ ਆਪਣੇ ਦੇਸ਼ਵਾਸੀਆਂ ਨਾਲ ਖੜ੍ਹਾ ਹਾਂ ਤੇ (ਵਿੰਗ) ਕਮਾਂਡਰ ਅਭਿਨੰਦਰ ਵਰਤਮਾਨ ਦੀ ਸੁਰੱਖਿਅਤ ਵਾਪਸੀ ਲਈ ਦੁਆ ਕਰਦਾ ਹਾਂ। ਮੇਰੇ ਲਈ ਪਾਰਟੀ ਨਾਲੋਂ ਦੇਸ਼ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਹੈ।’ਕਿਸ ਦੇ ਬਿਆਨ ਲਈ  ਆਲੋਚਨਾ ਹੋਈ?","answer":" ਕਰਨਾਟਕ ਭਾਜਪਾ ਦੇ ਪ੍ਰਧਾਨ ਬੀ.ਐਸ.ਯੇਦੀਯੁਰੱਪਾ ਦੇ ਬਿਆਨ ਲਈ ਆਲੋਚਨਾ ਹੋਈI "},{"question":"வினா:  கீழநந்த வம்சத்தின் கடைசி அரசர் யார் ?1. காலசோகன்2. அகாபத்ம நந்தர்3. தனநந்தர்4. கௌடில்யர்","answer":" விடை:3. தனநந்தர்"},{"question":"فين كاتعيش الذئاب الحمراء؟","answer":"شرق القارة الأمريكية الشمالية."},{"question":"CGST/SGST अधिनियमात तरतूद करण्यात आलेले शिक्षा/दंडाचे परिमाण काय आहे?","answer":"कलम 122(1) मध्ये केलेल्या तरतुदींनुसार एखाद्या करपात्र व्यक्‍तीने जर कलम 122 मध्ये निर्देशित केलेल्या गुन्‍हा /अपराध यापैकी कोणताही गुन्‍हा /अपराध केल्यास त्याला दंड अदा करण्याची शिक्षा होईल, जी खालील नमूद केलेल्या रकमांपेक्षा जास्त असेल :चुकविलेल्या कराची रक्‍कम , लबाडीने परतावा म्हणून मिळविलेली रक्‍कम , जमा लाभ म्हणून उपभोगलेली रक्‍कम  किंवा कपात न केलेली किंवा जमा न केलेली रक्‍कम  किंवा कमी कपात केलेली किंवा कमी संकलित केलेली रक्‍कम ; किंवारु.10,000/-ची रक्‍कमतसेच, कलम 122(2) मधील तरतुदींनुसार एखादी नोंदणीकृत करपात्र व्यक्‍ती, ज्या व्यक्‍तीने कर अदा केला नाही किंवा पुरवठ्यांवर कमी कर अदा केला, तर सदर व्यक्‍ती शिक्षा/दंडास पात्र होईल, सदर दंड खाली नमूद करण्यात आलेल्या रकमेपेक्षा अधिक असेल;अदा न केलेल्या कराच्या किंवा कमी अदा केलेल्या कराच्या 10 टक्‍के; किंवारु. 10,000/-"},{"question":"\\"Тойбогон карек\\" деген темада макала жазып бере аласыңбы?","answer":"Тойбогон карек:Калк үчүн кан-жанын берүүгө даяр болгон падыша жан-жөөкөрлөрү менен бир күнү балык уулоого барат. Көл жээгинде бир бечаранын кайырмак салып олтурганын көргөн падыша ага боору ооруйт.— Эй букарам, менин бүгүн жомарттыгым кармап турат. Биз кайткыча кайырмагыңа эмне илешсе, ошонун оордугунча алтын берем, – дейт падыша каткыра.Керели-кечке кудайга жалынганына карабай жанакы жардынын кайырмагына эч нерсе илинбейт. Падыша кайтар мезгилде гана тегерек сөөк илинет. Журт башынын кеби эки болот беле. Жан-жөөкөрлөр менен биргеликте жакыр да хансарайга келет.Тараза алынып келинет. Сөөк бир жагына коюлат. Экинчи жагына алтын салына баштайт. Бир, эки, он, элүү, жүз, эки жүз килограмм алтын коюлса да таразанын наркы тарабы былк этпейт. Мында бир сыр бар дейт сарайдагылар. Хандын буйругу менен бүт даанышмандар, акылмандар, олуялар чогултулат. Сөөктүн сырын эч кимис таба албай эстери оойт.Акыры алыскы-алыскы айылдан келген бир даанышман сөз сурайт табышмактын сырын чечкени. Ал:– Падышам, бул сөөктүн эч кандай деле сыры жок. Болгону бул сөөк эч нерсеге тойбогон, сук адамдын карегинин сөөгү экен. Бул нерсе топуракка гана тоет. Таразынын бир жагына бир ууч гана топурак салдыртыңыз, ошондо иш ордуна келет, — дейт.Даанышмандын айтканы аткарылат. Тойбогон карек менен бир ууч топурак тең келет.Анын сыңарындай, калк кызматын кылган жетекчилер, журт жүгүн көтөргөн депутаттар, имамдар, айыл башчылар, жөнөкөй жарандар арасында да тойбогон каректер көбөйгөндөн көбөйүп барат. Бирок, бир күнү баарыбыздын каректерибиз бир ууч топуракка тоет, ушун унутпасак."},{"question":"Millainen maapallon ilmasto on 50 vuoden päästä?","answer":"Maapallon lämpötila oli 2000-luvun kahtena ensimmäisenä vuosikymmenenä asteen korkeampi kuin 1800-luvun loppupuoliskon aikana. Viime vuosikymmeninä lämpenemisen on havaittu kiihtyneen etenkin pohjoisella pallonpuoliskolla. 50 vuoden kuluttua maapallon keskilämpötilan arvioidaan olevan keskimäärin 1,5 - 3,5 astetta korkeampi kuin vertailukautena, vuosina 1850 - 1900, riippuen kasvihuonekaasujen tulevista päästöistä.Lämpötilan kohoaminen ei ole tasaista maapallon eri puolilla eikä eri vuodenaikoina. Eniten lämpenevät pohjoisten leveysasteiden maa-alueet talvisin. Pohjois-Euroopan talvien odotetaan lämpenevän 2060-luvulle tultaessa 2 - 7 asteella. Nykyään vielä poikkeukselliset helleaallot tulevat Euroopassa kesäisin yleistymään.Monissa maapallon osissa yhteiskunnan ja ympäristön sopeutumista ilmastonmuutokseen vaikeuttaa se, että lämpenemisen lisäksi sateiden esiintyminen muuttuu. Vaikka sademäärät keskimäärin maapallolla kasvavat, monia tiheästi asuttuja alueita Afrikassa ja Aasiassa uhkaa entistä pahempi vesipula kuivien kausien ja toisaalta veden laatua heikentävien tulvien yleistyessä. Lisäksi alavimpia rannikkoalueita ja saaria koettelee valtamerten pinnan kohoaminen ilmaston lämmetessä.Euroopassa etenkin Välimeren maissa kesät kuivuvat entisestään. Mallitulokset viittaavat siihen, että Keski-Euroopassa vähentyvistä kesäsateista ja pidentyvistä poutajaksoista huolimatta viime kesien kaltaiset tulvat tulevat aiempaa yleisimmiksi. Ilmastonmuutoksen ennakoidaan siis lisäävän monien sään ja ilmaston ääri-ilmiöiden esiintymistä ja voimakkuutta.Seuraavan 50 vuoden aikana toteutuvat ilmastonmuutokset ennakoivat vielä paljon suurempia muutoksia tulevina vuosisatoina. Niinpä mitä tehokkaammin kasvihuonekaasujen päästöjä pystytään hillitsemään, sitä enemmän nykyistä muistuttaa se ilmasto, jossa tulevien vuosisatojen ihmiset, eläimet ja kasvit elävät."},{"question":"Kahvaltı masasında çatal bıçak nasıl konur?","answer":"Kahvaltı sofra düzeni için çatal, çay kaşığı ve tereyağı bıçağı yeterli olacaktır. Çatal tabağın sol tarafına, tereyağı bıçağı ve çay kaşığı tabağın sağ tarafına yerleştirilmelidir. Bıçak ve çay kaşığının sağ üstünde çay servisi için çay fincanı yer almalıdır."},{"question":"Anong numero ang makukuha mo kapag pinarami mo ang lahat ng posibleng numero sa isang calculator?","answer":"Ang numerong makukuha mo ay 0. Ang anumang numero na pinarami kasama ng 0 ay magiging 0 rin."},{"question":"اعطيني صياغة إجابة على السؤال المفصل ده: هويكسيان ومقاطعة هانغو، تيانجين، موجودين في أي بلد؟","answer":"في الصين أكيد."},{"question":"ਹਿਮਾਲਿਆ ਤੇ ਪ੍ਰਾਇਦੀਪੀ ਪਠਾਰ ਦੇ ਧਰਾਤਲੀ ਲੱਛਣਾਂ ਦੀ ਤੁਲਨਾ ਕਰੋ ਤੇ ਅੰਤਰ ਸਪੱਸ਼ਟ ਕਰੋ ।","answer":"ਹਿਮਾਲਿਆ ਅਤੇ ਪ੍ਰਾਇਦੀਪੀ ਪਠਾਰ ਦੀ ਤੁਲਨਾ ਭੂਗੋਲ ਦੇ ਪੱਖ ਤੋਂ ਬੜੀ ਰੌਚਕ ਹੈ ।1. ਬਨਾਵਟ-ਹਿਮਾਲਿਆ ਤਲਛੱਟੀ ਚੱਟਾਨਾਂ ਤੋਂ ਬਣਿਆ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਇਹ ਸੰਸਾਰ ਦਾ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਜਵਾਨ ਪਰਬਤ ਹੈ । ਇਸ ਦੀ ਉਚਾਈ ਵੀ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਵੱਧ ਹੈ । ਇਸ ਦੀ ਔਸਤ ਉਚਾਈ 5000 ਮੀਟਰ ਹੈ । ਇਸ ਦੇ ਉਲਟ ਪ੍ਰਾਇਦੀਪੀ ਪਠਾਰ ਦਾ ਜਨਮ ਅੱਜ ਤੋਂ 50 ਕਰੋੜ ਸਾਲ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਕੈਬੀਅਨ ਮਹਾਂਕਾਲ ਵਿਚ ਹੋਇਆ ਸੀ । ਇਹ ਅਗਨੀ ਚੱਟਾਨਾਂ ਤੋਂ ਬਣਿਆ ਹੋਇਆ ਹੈ ।2. ਵਿਸਥਾਰ-ਹਿਮਾਲਿਆ ਜੰਮੂ-ਕਸ਼ਮੀਰ ਤੋਂ ਅਰੁਣਾਚਲ ਪ੍ਰਦੇਸ਼ ਤਕ ਫੈਲਿਆ ਹੋਇਆ ਹੈ । ਇਸ ਦੇ ਪੂਰਬ ਵਿਚ ਪੂਰਬੀ ਸ਼ੇਣੀਆਂ ਅਤੇ ਪੱਛਮ ਵਿਚ ਪੱਛਮੀ ਸ਼੍ਰੇਣੀਆਂ ਹਨ | ਪੂਰਬੀ ਸ਼੍ਰੇਣੀਆਂ ਵਿਚ ਖਾਸੀ, ਗਾਰੋ, ਐੱਤੀਆ ਅਤੇ ਪੱਛਮੀ ਸ਼ੇਣੀਆਂ ਵਿਚ ਹਿੰਦੁਕੁਸ਼, ਕਿਰਥਾਰ ਅਤੇ ਕੈਥਰ ਸ਼ੇਣੀਆਂ ਪਾਈਆਂ ਜਾਂਦੀਆਂ ਹਨ ।ਹਿਮਾਲਿਆ ਦੇ ਪੰਜ ਭਾਗ ਹਨ-ਟਰਾਂਸ ਹਿਮਾਲਿਆ, ਮਹਾਨ ਹਿਮਾਲਿਆ, ਛੋਟਾ ਹਿਮਾਲਿਆ, ਬਾਹਰੀ ਹਿਮਾਲਿਆ ਅਤੇ ਪਹਾੜੀ ਸ਼ਾਖ਼ਾਵਾਂ । ਇਸ ਦੇ ਉਲਟ ਪ੍ਰਾਇਦੀਪੀ ਪਠਾਰ ਦੇ ਦੋ ਭਾਗ ਹਨ-ਮਾਲਵਾ ਦੀ ਪਠਾਰ ਅਤੇ ਦੱਖਣ ਦੀ ਪਠਾਰ ।ਇਹ ਅਰਾਵਲੀ ਪਰਬਤ ਤੋਂ ਲੈ ਕੇ ਸ਼ਿਲਾਂਗ ਦੇ ਪਠਾਰ ਤਕ ਅਤੇ ਦੱਖਣ ਵਿਚ ਕੰਨਿਆ-ਕੁਮਾਰੀ ਤਕ ਫੈਲਿਆ ਹੋਇਆ ਹੈ । ਇਸ ਵਿਚ ਮਿਲਦੀਆਂ ਮੁੱਖ ਪਰਬਤ ਸ਼੍ਰੇਣੀਆਂ ਹਨ-ਅਰਾਵਲੀ ਪਰਬਤ ਸ਼੍ਰੇਣੀ, ਵਿਧਿਆਚਲ ਪਰਬਤ ਸ਼੍ਰੇਣੀ ਅਤੇ ਸਤਪੁੜਾ ਪਰਬਤ ਸ਼੍ਰੇਣੀ । ਇਸ ਤੋਂ ਇਲਾਵਾ ਇੱਥੇ ਪੂਰਬੀ ਘਾਟ ਦੀਆਂ ਪਹਾੜੀਆਂ, ਪੱਛਮੀ ਘਾਟ ਦੀਆਂ ਪਹਾੜੀਆਂ ਅਤੇ ਨੀਲਗਿਰੀ ਪਰਬਤ ਆਦਿ ਮਿਲਦੇ ਹਨ । ਨਦੀਆਂ-ਹਿਮਾਲਿਆ ਤੋਂ ਨਿਕਲਣ ਵਾਲੀਆਂ ਨਦੀਆਂ ਬਰਫ਼ੀਲੇ ਪਰਬਤਾਂ ਤੋਂ ਨਿਕਲਣ ਦੇ ਕਾਰਨ ਸਾਰਾ ਸਾਲ ਵਗਦੀਆਂ ਹਨ ।ਪ੍ਰਾਇਦੀਪੀ ਪਠਾਰ ਦੀਆਂ ਨਦੀਆਂ ਬਰਸਾਤੀ ਨਦੀਆਂ ਹਨ । ਖ਼ੁਸ਼ਕ ਰੁੱਤ ਵਿੱਚ ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਪਾਣੀ ਦੀ ਘਾਟ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ । ਆਰਥਿਕ ਮਹੱਤਵ-ਪ੍ਰਾਇਦੀਪੀ ਪਠਾਰ ਵਿਚ ਅਨੇਕਾਂ ਕਿਸਮ ਦੇ ਖਣਿਜ ਪਦਾਰਥ ਮਿਲਦੇ ਹਨ । ਇਸ ਦੇ ਉਲਟ ਹਿਮਾਲਿਆ ਖੇਤਰ ਵਿਚ ਵਣ-ਸੰਪੱਤੀ ਵਧੇਰੇ ਹੈ ।"},{"question":"Andeha tongotra ody aho kanefa avy be ny orana. Tokony itondra elo ve aho? Valio eny sa tsia.","answer":"Eny, tokony itondra elo ianao."}]`),M={name:"App",components:{PoemCard:N},data(){return{searchQuery:"",visibleCount:6,poemsData:S,isLoading:!1}},computed:{filteredPoems(){return this.searchQuery.trim()?this.poemsData.filter(e=>{const a=this.searchQuery.toLowerCase();return e.question.toLowerCase().includes(a)||e.answer.toLowerCase().includes(a)}).slice(0,this.visibleCount):this.poemsData.slice(0,this.visibleCount)},hasMorePoems(){return this.visibleCount<this.poemsData.length}},methods:{async loadMore(){this.isLoading=!0,await new Promise(e=>setTimeout(e,1e3)),this.visibleCount+=6,this.isLoading=!1}}},I={class:"search-container"},B={class:"card-container"},O=["disabled"],K={key:0},H={key:1};function L(e,a,s,m,o,r){const k=c("PoemCard");return i(),t("section",null,[a[3]||(a[3]=n("div",{class:"top-banner"},[n("div",{class:"top-banner-title"},[n("div",{class:"top-banner-title-text"},"🤔 AI effective tips collection 🧠")])],-1)),n("div",I,[a[2]||(a[2]=n("span",{class:"search-icon"},null,-1)),y(n("input",{type:"text",class:"search-input","onUpdate:modelValue":a[0]||(a[0]=u=>o.searchQuery=u),placeholder:"Search..."},null,512),[[b,o.searchQuery]])]),n("div",B,[(i(!0),t(w,null,p(r.filteredPoems,(u,d)=>(i(),f(k,{key:d,poem:u},null,8,["poem"]))),128))]),r.hasMorePoems?(i(),t("button",{key:0,class:"load-more-button",disabled:o.isLoading,onClick:a[1]||(a[1]=(...u)=>r.loadMore&&r.loadMore(...u))},[o.isLoading?(i(),t("span",H,"Loading...")):(i(),t("span",K,"See more"))],8,O)):v("",!0)])}const P=g(M,[["render",L],["__scopeId","data-v-4770b3ca"]]),R=JSON.parse('{"title":"","description":"","frontmatter":{"page":true},"headers":[],"relativePath":"chatai/25.md","filePath":"chatai/25.md"}'),D={name:"chatai/25.md"},V=Object.assign(D,{setup(e){return(a,s)=>(i(),t("div",null,[j(P)]))}});export{R as __pageData,V as default};
